{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/17/ex-president-using-personal-funds-for-overseas-travel-expenses/",
  "time_ut": 1660707480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ex-President using personal funds for overseas travel expenses",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ex-President using personal funds for overseas travel expenses",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lankan Government is not bearing any expenses for Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's overseas travels, said the Government Information Department.",
        "A statement issued on Tuesday (16) said that the Former President is using his personal funds for his travel expenses.",
        "The former Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled overseas to escape protests against his government, arrived in Thailand last week on a flight from Singapore, where he had been staying since mid-July.",
        "The land may divide us, but the sky and the ocean unites us all: Wimal at the welcome ceremony for Yuan Wang 5"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා විදේශ ගමන් වියදම් සඳහා පුද්ගලික අරමුදල් භාවිතා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ විදෙස් සංචාර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය කිසිදු වියදමක් දරන්නේ නැති බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා (16) නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙන්නේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගමන් වියදම් සඳහා ඔහුගේ පෞද්ගලික මුදල් යොදවන බවයි.",
        "තම රජයට එරෙහි විරෝධතාවලින් බේරීම සඳහා විදේශගත වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පසුගිය සතියේ තායිලන්තයට පැමිණියේ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට ගුවන් යානයකින් වන අතර එහිදී ඔහු ජූලි මැද සිට නැවතී සිටියේය.",
        "ගොඩබිම අපිව බෙදන්න පුළුවන්, නමුත් අහසයි සාගරයයි අපි හැමෝම එකතු කරනවා: යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයේදී විමල්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி வெளிநாட்டு பயணச் செலவுகளுக்காக தனிப்பட்ட நிதியைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணங்களுக்கான எந்தவொரு செலவையும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் ஏற்கவில்லை என அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது பயணச் செலவுகளுக்காக தனது தனிப்பட்ட நிதியைப் பயன்படுத்துவதாக செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (16) வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தனது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான போராட்டங்களில் இருந்து தப்பிக்க வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்ற இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில் இருந்து தங்கியிருந்த சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து விமானம் மூலம் கடந்த வாரம் தாய்லாந்து வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "நிலம் நம்மைப் பிரிக்கலாம், ஆனால் வானமும் கடலும் நம்மை ஒன்றிணைக்கிறது: யுவான் வாங் 5-க்கு வரவேற்பு விழாவில் விமல்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}