{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/வந்துவிட்டீர்களா-வணக்கம்-வாருங்கள்/175-303340",
  "time_ut": 1661953463,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "வந்துவிட்டீர்களா? வணக்கம் வாருங்கள்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "have you come hello come",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "13 members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna decided to act independently in Parliament and sat in the opposition.",
        "Among them was Member of Parliament Dallas Alagaperuma, who jumped into the fray during the voting for the presidential election held in Parliament.",
        "It is to be noted that his name was suggested by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna's Thavisalar and the opposition leader Sajith Premadasa.",
        "When he also came to the opposition side today (31), Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa welcomed him with open arms."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dallas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඔබ පැමිණ තිබේද? ආයුබෝවන් එන්න",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනෙකු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කිරීමට තීරණය කර විපක්ෂයේ අසුන් ගත්තා.",
        "ඒ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණයට අදාළ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී සටනට පැන්න පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම ද විය.",
        "ඔහුගේ නම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ තවිසලර් සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස විසින් යෝජනා කර ඇති බව සඳහන් කළ යුතුය.",
        "අද (31) ඔහු ද විපක්ෂය පැත්තට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේදී විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඔහුව විවෘතව පිළිගත්තේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வந்துவிட்டீர்களா? வணக்கம் வாருங்கள்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவைச் சேர்ந்த 13 பேர், பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்பட தீர்மானித்து எதிர்க்கட்சியில் அமர்ந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "அதில், பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவுக்கான வாக்களிப்பின் போது, களத்தில் குதித்திருந்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகபெருமவும் அடங்குவார்.",
        "அவரது பெயரை, ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தவிசாளர் முன்மொழிய, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ வழிமொழிந்திருந்தார் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "அவரும் எதிரணியின் பக்கம் இன்று (31) வந்தபோது, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ, அவரை இருகரம் கூப்பி வரவேற்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}