{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Summon-PUCSL-Chairman-before-COPE-over-his-statement-on-fuel-import-Wijeyadasa/342-240393",
  "time_ut": 1657018478,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Summon PUCSL Chairman before COPE over his statement on fuel import: Wijeyadasa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Summon PUCSL Chairman before COPE over his statement on fuel import: Wijeyadasa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapaksa today requested the Speaker to take steps to summon Chairman of the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) before Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) tomorrow to clarify his claim that a litre of fuel could be sold at Rs. 250.",
        "He told Parliament that they got to know that the PUCSL Chairman had made a statement that a litre of fuel could be sold at Rs. 250 and said he should be summoned before the COPE to know the methodology of doing so.",
        "\"PUCSL Chairman has said that a litre of fuel could be sold at Rs. 250. We are not aware of this methodology. I request the Speaker to summon him through the COPE Chairman before the COPE tomorrow so that we can know the methodology,\" he said.(Ajith Siriwardana and Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wijeyadasa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය ගැන කළ ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ සභාපති කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවන්න: විජයදාස",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 10කට අලෙවි කළ හැකි බවට කරන ප්‍රකාශය පැහැදිලි කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා හෙට දිනයේදී පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (කෝප්) හමුවට කැඳවීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද කථානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. 250",
        "ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට කියා සිටියේ ඉන්ධන ලීටරයක් ​​රු. 250 ක් ද, එසේ කරන ක්‍රමවේදය දැන ගැනීම සඳහා තමා කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවිය යුතු බවද කීවේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 250 ට අලෙවි කළ හැකි බව PUCSL සභාපති පවසා තිබෙනවා. මේ ක්‍රමවේදය ගැන අපි දන්නේ නැහැ. මම කතානායකතුමාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා කෝප් කමිටු සභාපතිවරයා මාර්ගයෙන් ඔහුව හෙට කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවා ක්‍රමවේදය දැන ගන්න කියලා. ඔහු පැවසීය.(අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන සහ යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විජයදාස ය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්යාපාර පිළිබඳ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி தொடர்பான அறிக்கை தொடர்பாக PUCSL தலைவரை கோப் முன்னிலையில் அழைக்கவும்: விஜயதாச",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒரு லீற்றர் எரிபொருளை ரூபாவிற்கு விற்பனை செய்ய முடியும் என்ற தனது கூற்றை தெளிவுபடுத்துவதற்காக இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவரை நாளை பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான குழு (கோப்) முன்னிலையில் அழைக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ சபாநாயகரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார். 250",
        "ஒரு லீற்றர் எரிபொருளை ரூ.10க்கு விற்கலாம் என PUCSL தலைவர் அறிக்கை வெளியிட்டதாக தமக்கு தெரியவந்ததாக அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். 250 மற்றும் அவ்வாறு செய்வதற்கான வழிமுறையை அறிய அவரை கோப் முன் அழைக்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "\"ஒரு லீற்றர் எரிபொருளை 250 ரூபாய்க்கு விற்கலாம் என PUCSL தலைவர் கூறியுள்ளார். இந்த வழிமுறை பற்றி எங்களுக்குத் தெரியாது. நாளை கோப் குழுவின் தலைவர் ஊடாக அவரை வரவழைக்குமாறு சபாநாயகரை கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன். அவர் கூறினார்.(அஜித் சிறிவர்தன மற்றும் யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விஜயதாச",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}