{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/බිත්තර-වී-කිලෝව-150-ට-මිලදී ගනී/1-615786",
  "time_ut": 1656842452,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බිත්තර වී කිලෝව 150 ට මිලදී ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Eggs and rice are bought at 150 per kg",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera has instructed the Department of Agriculture to buy egg rice grown in the yala season at 150 rupees per kilo.",
        "Currently, the price set by the Department of Agriculture for a kilo of eggs and rice is 140 rupees, but it is not a fair price from the farmers' side, so the Minister should arrange to purchase 150 per kilo and prepare a cabinet paper to get the approval of the cabinet in this regard. Further advised.",
        "The Ministry of Agriculture says that the amount of egg rice required for the 2022/2023 season is 40 lakh bushels and the amount of egg rice obtained by government egg rice farms is between 10-12 percent of the total requirement and the remaining egg rice is obtained from farmers.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture said that information has been received that some farmers who cultivated egg rice are selling their harvest to traders at a higher price for processing rice.",
        "The Minister said that they are requested not to sell egg rice to traders for processing rice and if they do so, there is a possibility of a shortage of egg rice in the next season, so the Minister said that the Department of Agriculture should immediately intervene to buy the egg rice owned by the farmers.",
        "Meanwhile, the Minister of Agriculture Mahinda Amaraweera said that the Paddy Marketing Board is working to purchase more paddy crops in the early season and for that, a Cabinet paper has been prepared to get the approval of the Cabinet."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the yala season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2022/2023 season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 lakh bushels",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-12 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "egg",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Paddy Marketing Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිත්තර වී කිලෝව 150 ට මිලදී ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යල කන්නයේ වගා කරන ලද බිත්තර වී කිලෝවක් රුපියල් 150 බැගින් මිල දී ගන්නා ලෙස කෘෂිකර්ම වනජීවි හා වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට උපදෙස් ලබා දී තිබේ.",
        "දැනට බිත්තර වී කිලෝවක් සඳහා කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නියම කර ඇති මිල රුපියල් 140ක් වුවත් එය ගොවි ජනතාවගේ පැත්තෙන් ගත් කළ සාධාරණ මිලක් නොවන හෙයින් කිලෝව 150 බැගින් මිලදී ගැනීම⁣ට කටයුතු කරන ලෙසත්, ඊට අදාලව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල පත්‍රිකාවක් සකස් කරන ලෙසත් අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "2022 /2023 මහ කන්නය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය බිත්තර වී ප්‍රමාණය බුසල් ලක්ෂ 40ක් බවත් රජයේ බිත්තර වී  ගොවිපොළ මගින් ලබා ගන්නා බිත්තර වී ප්‍රමාණය සමස්ත අවශ්‍යතාවයෙන් සියයට 10-12ක් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් වන අතර ඉතිරි බිත්තර වී ගොවීන් වෙතින් ලබා ගන්නා බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "මේ වනවිට බිත්තර වී වගා කළ ඇතැම් ගොවීන් තම අස්වැන්න සහල් සැකසීම සඳහා වැඩි මිලකට වෙළෙඳුන්ට අලෙවි කරන බවට තොරතුරු ලැබී ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "බිත්තර වී  සහල් සැකසීම සඳහා  වෙළෙඳුන්ට අලෙවි නොකරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර එසේ කළහොත්  මීළඟ මහ කන්නයට බිත්තර වී හිඟයක් ඇතිවීමට ඉඩකඩ ඇති බැවින් ගොවීන් සතු බිත්තර වී මිල දී ගැනීමට කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වහාම මැදිහත් වී කටයුතු කරන ලෙස උපදෙස් දුන් බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර යල කන්නයේ වී අස්වනු වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් මිල දී ගැනීම සඳහා වී අලෙවි මණ්ඩලය කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින අතර ඒ සඳහා ද අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල පත්‍රිකාවක් සකසා තිබෙන බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යල කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023 සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුසල් ලක්ෂ 40යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10-12 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිත්තරය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වී අලෙවි මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුල් සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முட்டை, அரிசி கிலோ 150க்கு வாங்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "விவசாயம், வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீர, ஒரு கிலோ, 150 ரூபாவிற்கு, யலா பருவத்தில் விளைவிக்கப்படும் முட்டை அரிசியை கொள்வனவு செய்யுமாறு விவசாய திணைக்களத்திற்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது ஒரு கிலோ முட்டை மற்றும் அரிசிக்கு விவசாயத் திணைக்களம் நிர்ணயித்த விலை 140 ரூபாவாக இருந்தாலும், விவசாயிகள் தரப்பில் நியாயமான விலை கிடைக்காததால், கிலோ 150க்கு கொள்முதல் செய்து அமைச்சரவை பத்திரம் தயாரிக்க அமைச்சர் ஏற்பாடு செய்ய வேண்டும். இது தொடர்பாக அமைச்சரவையின் ஒப்புதலைப் பெறவும்.மேலும் ஆலோசனை.",
        "2022/2023 பருவத்திற்குத் தேவையான முட்டை அரிசியின் அளவு 40 லட்சம் புசல்கள் என்றும், அரசாங்க முட்டை அரிசி பண்ணைகள் மூலம் பெறப்படும் முட்டை அரிசியின் அளவு மொத்தத் தேவையில் 10-12 சதவீதம் என்றும் மீதமுள்ள முட்டை அரிசி விவசாயிகளிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்டது.",
        "முட்டை அரிசியை பயிரிட்ட சில விவசாயிகள் அரிசியை பதப்படுத்துவதற்காக அதிக விலைக்கு வியாபாரிகளிடம் மகசூல் விற்பனை செய்வதாக தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரிசியை பதப்படுத்தும் வியாபாரிகளுக்கு முட்டை அரிசியை விற்பனை செய்ய வேண்டாம் எனவும் அவ்வாறு விற்பனை செய்தால் அடுத்த பருவத்தில் முட்டை அரிசிக்கு தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்பட வாய்ப்புள்ளதாகவும் எனவே விவசாய திணைக்களம் உடனடியாக தலையிட வேண்டுமென அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். விவசாயிகளுக்கு சொந்தமான முட்டை அரிசியை வாங்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இதேவேளை, முற்காலத்தில் அதிகளவு நெற்செய்கைகளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு நெல் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் சபை நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருவதாகவும், அதற்காக அமைச்சரவையின் அங்கீகாரத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கான அமைச்சரவைப் பத்திரம் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "150",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யலா பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023 சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 லட்சம் புதர்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-12 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முட்டை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நெல் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரம்ப பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}