{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Brombil-Estates-achieves-highest-price-of-Rs-10-950-for-tea-sold-at-public-auction/34-738834",
  "time_ut": 1660780998,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Brombil Estates achieves highest price of Rs. 10,950 for tea sold at public auction",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Brombil Estates achieves highest price of Rs. 10,950 for tea sold at public auction",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In the Premium Flowery catalogues, an invoice of FBOPFEXSP1 grade from Brombil Estate, Kalutara improved its own record to Rs. 10,950 per kg this week at the tea auctions.",
        "“This is an extraordinary price for a specialty grade for any tea sold at the public auction and sets a new standard for the category,” said Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC which marketed the tea.",
        "Brombil factory is part of Evergreen Group, chaired by Aruna de Silva. The factory is managed by Director Dr. Indika Nallaperuma, Director Senal de Silva, Manager Tyron Rathnayake, Production Manager Aruna Edirisooriya and Factory Officer Chamil Ruchira."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Brombil Estates",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10,950",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Premium Flowery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOPFEXSP1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brombil Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,950 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Brombil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Evergreen Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aruna de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika Nallaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senal de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tyron Rathnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aruna Edirisooriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamil Ruchira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Brombil Estates ඉහළම මිල රු. ප්‍රසිද්ධ වෙන්දේසියේ අලෙවි වූ තේ සඳහා රුපියල් 10,950 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Premium Flowery නාමාවලියෙහි, කළුතර Brombil Estate වෙතින් FBOPFEXSP1 ශ්‍රේණියේ ඉන්වොයිසියක් එහි වාර්තාව රු. මේ සතියේ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී කිලෝග්‍රෑම් එකක් රුපියල් 10,950කි.",
        "\"ප්‍රසිද්ධ වෙන්දේසියේ අලෙවි කරන ඕනෑම තේ වර්ගයක් සඳහා විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා මෙය අසාමාන්‍ය මිලක් වන අතර එම කාණ්ඩය සඳහා නව ප්‍රමිතියක් සකසයි\" යනුවෙන් තේ අලෙවි කළ Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC පවසයි.",
        "Brombil කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව අරුණ ද සිල්වා විසින් සභාපතිත්වය දරන Evergreen සමූහයේ කොටසකි. කම්හල කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෛද්‍ය ඉන්දික නල්ලපෙරුම, අධ්‍යක්ෂ සෙනාල් ද සිල්වා, කළමනාකරු ටිරෝන් රත්නායක, නිෂ්පාදන කළමනාකරු අරුණ එදිරිසූරිය සහ කර්මාන්තශාලා නිලධාරි චමිල් රුචිර විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්‍රොම්බිල් වතු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10,950 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරික මල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOPFEXSP1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රොම්බිල් වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,950 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රොම්බිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සදාහරිත සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුණ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික නල්ලපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනාල් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිරෝන් රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුණ එදිරිසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමිල් රුචිර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Brombil Estates இன் அதிகபட்ச விலையான ரூ. பொது ஏலத்தில் விற்கப்பட்ட தேயிலை 10,950 ரூபாய்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரீமியம் ஃப்ளவரி பட்டியல்களில், களுத்துறை, ப்ரோம்பில் தோட்டத்திலிருந்து FBOPFEXSP1 தரத்தின் விலைப்பட்டியல் அதன் சொந்த சாதனையை ரூ. தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் இந்த வாரம் கிலோ ரூ.10,950.",
        "\"பொது ஏலத்தில் விற்கப்படும் எந்தவொரு தேயிலைக்கும் இது ஒரு சிறப்பு தரத்திற்கான ஒரு அசாதாரண விலையாகும், மேலும் அந்த வகைக்கு ஒரு புதிய தரத்தை அமைக்கிறது\" என்று தேயிலையை சந்தைப்படுத்திய Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "Brombil தொழிற்சாலை, அருண டி ​​சில்வா தலைமையில் Evergreen குழுமத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும். இத்தொழிற்சாலை பணிப்பாளர் கலாநிதி இந்திக்க நல்லபெரும, பணிப்பாளர் செனல் டி சில்வா, முகாமையாளர் டைரோன் ரத்நாயக்க, உற்பத்தி முகாமையாளர் அருண எதிரிசூரிய மற்றும் தொழிற்சாலை அதிகாரி சமில் ருச்சிர ஆகியோரால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Brombil எஸ்டேட்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10,950",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரீமியம் பூக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOPFEXSP1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ரோம்பில் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 10,950",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா சியாக்கா கமாடிடீஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ரோம்பில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எவர்கிரீன் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருண டி ​​சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க நல்லபெருமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனல் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டைரன் ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருணா எதிரிசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமில் ருசிரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}