{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62213051",
  "time_ut": 1658281246,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ:වැඩි ඡන්දයෙන් අට වන විධායක ජනපති ලෙස පත්වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickramasinghe: Becomes the eighth Executive President with more votes",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliament General Secretary Dhammika Dasanayake said that Ranil Wickramasinghe was elected as the eighth Executive President by the majority of the members of the Parliament of Sri Lanka. The total number of votes he got is 134.",
        "Accordingly, today he won with a majority of 52 votes. Dallas lost 82 votes. Anura Kumara Dissanayake got 3 votes.",
        "Today (July 20) the voting began after the session of the Parliament started at 10 am, where the MKK MP cast their votes by calling out the name of each MP and the Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena was the first to vote, followed by the Prime Minister, Acting President Ranil. Wickramasinghe cast his vote.",
        "Samanpriya Herath and D. were two members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna who were very ill. Weerasinghe and elderly Dravida National Alliance leader R Sambandan were seen being taken to cast their votes with the help of parliamentary workers.",
        "Meanwhile, Selvaraja Kajendran and G. G. Ponnambalam abstained from casting his vote.",
        "During the counting of votes, four votes were declared invalid and the total number of valid votes declared today is 223."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "eighth",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "D.",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravida National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "R Sambandan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Selvaraja Kajendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. G. Ponnambalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ:වැඩි ඡන්දයෙන් අට වන විධායක ජනපති ලෙස පත්වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අට වන විධායක ජනපතිවරයා ලෙස  ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ වැඩි ඡන්දයෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පත් වූ බවට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහ ලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක පැවසීය.  ඔහු ලද සමස්ත ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 134 කි.",
        "ඒ අනුව අද ඔහු වැඩි ඡන්ද 52කින් ජයග්‍රහණය කළේ ය. ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම ලැබූ ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 82කි. අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක ලැබූ ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 3 කි.",
        "අද (ජූලි 20) උදැසන 10ට පාර්ලිමේන්තු සභාවාරය ආරම්භ වීමෙන් පසුව ඡන්ද විමසීම ආරම්භ වූ අතර එහිදී එක් එක් මන්ත්‍රී වරයාගේ නම අඬගැසීමෙන් එම් එක් එක් මන්ත්‍රී වරයා තම ඡන්ද ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර පළමුව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශකළේ කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන වන අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව අගමැති, වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ තම ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉතාමත් අසනීප තත්ත්වයෙන් පසුවූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනකු වූ සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත් හා ඩී. වීරසිංහ හා වයෝවෘද්ධ ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සංධානයේ නායක ආර් සම්බන්දන්ව පාර්ලිමේන්තු සේවකයින් ගේ ආධාරය ඇතිව තම ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට රැගෙන යන අයුරු දිස්විය.",
        "මේ අතර අකිල ඉලංකෙයි තමිල් කොංග්‍රසයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙපලක් වූ  සෙල්වරාජා කජේන්ද්‍රන් හා ජී. ජී. පොන්නම්බලම් තම ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වැලකි සිටියේය.",
        "ඡන්දය ගනන්කිරිමේදී ඡන්ද හතරක් අවලංගු ලෙස ප්‍රකාශ වූ අතර අද ප්‍රකාශිත සමස්ත වලංගු ඡන්ද ප්‍රමාණය 223 කි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අටවැනි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් සම්බන්ධන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වරාජා කජේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ජී.පොන්නම්බලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க: அதிக வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி ஆனார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பெரும்பான்மை உறுப்பினர்களால் எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதாக பாராளுமன்ற பொதுச் செயலாளர் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார். அவர் பெற்ற மொத்த வாக்குகள் 134 ஆகும்.",
        "அதன்படி இன்று அவர் 52 வாக்குகள் பெரும்பான்மையில் வெற்றி பெற்றார். டல்லாஸ் 82 வாக்குகளை இழந்தார். அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 3 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "இன்று (ஜூலை 20) பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு காலை 10 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பமானதை அடுத்து வாக்கெடுப்பு ஆரம்பமானது, அங்கு MKK எம்பி ஒவ்வொரு எம்பியின் பெயரையும் கூறி வாக்களித்தார் மற்றும் சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன முதலில் வாக்களித்தார், அதைத் தொடர்ந்து பிரதமர் அமைச்சர், பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க வாக்களித்தார்.",
        "மிகவும் சுகவீனமுற்றிருந்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவைச் சேர்ந்த சமன்பிரியா ஹேரத் மற்றும் டி. வீரசிங்கம் மற்றும் வயோதிபர் திராவிட தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் தலைவர் ஆர் சம்பந்தன் ஆகியோர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் உதவியுடன் வாக்களிக்க அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டதை காணமுடிந்தது.",
        "இதேவேளை செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன் மற்றும் ஜி. ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம் வாக்களிக்காமல் புறக்கணித்தார்.",
        "வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கையின் போது நான்கு வாக்குகள் செல்லாதவை என அறிவிக்கப்பட்டு இன்று அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட மொத்த வாக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 223 ஆகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "எட்டாவது",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிட தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர் சம்பந்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.ஜி.பொன்னம்பலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}