{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රඹුක්කන-එස්-එස්-පීගේ-ඇප-දීම-නීතිපති-විරුද්ධයි/101-615493",
  "time_ut": 1656327368,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රඹුක්කන එස්.එස්.පීගේ ඇප දීම නීතිපති විරුද්ධයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rambukkana SSP's bail granted by Attorney General",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Kegalle SSP K. Wijewardena has been remanded in connection with the Rambukkana shooting incident. B. The Attorney General informed the Court of Appeal today (27) that he was opposed to the release on bail of Keerthiratne and four other police officers.",
        "Deputy Solicitor General Janaka Bandara, appearing before the Court of Appeal on behalf of the Attorney General, said, B. Keerthiratne and four other police officers filed a fundamental rights petition in court.",
        "The writ petition was heard by a bench of Justices of the Court of Appeal comprising Sobhitha Rajakaruna and Dhammika Ganepola today (27).",
        "Accordingly, the petition was scheduled to be reconsidered on the 29th.",
        "Former SSP in charge of Kegalle Division K. B. The writ petition filed by Mr. Keerthiratne and three other police constables named the Attorney General, the Inspector General of Police and the Director of the CID as respondents.",
        "The petitioners have stated that the order issued by the Kegalle Magistrate to arrest and remand them in connection with the shooting death of a person during a riot that took place during a protest in Rambukkana regarding the increase in fuel prices is against the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rambukkana SSP's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle SSP K. Wijewardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Court of Appeal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keerthiratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janaka Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Court of Appeal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "B. Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sobhitha Rajakaruna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Ganepola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle Division K. B.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kegalle Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රඹුක්කන එස්.එස්.පීගේ ඇප දීම නීතිපති විරුද්ධයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රඹුක්කන වෙඩිතැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර සිටින කෑගල්ල හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ. බී. කීර්තිරත්න මහතා ඇතුළු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සිව් දෙනා ඇප මත මුදා හැරීමට විරුද්ධ බව නිතිපතිවරයා අභියාචනාධිකරණයට අද (27) දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "නිතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අභියාචනාධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටි නියෝජ්‍ය සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් ජනක බණ්ඩාර මහතා මෙලෙස දැනුම් දුන්නේ, කෑගල්ල හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි කේ. බී. කීර්තිරත්න මහතා ඇතුළු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සිව් දෙනකු ගොනු කර තිබූ මුලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමක් අධිකරණය හමුවේ  කැදවූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මෙම රිට් පෙත්සම, සෝභිත රාජකරුණා සහ ධම්මික ගනේපොළ යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත අභියාචනාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල හමුවේ අද (27) සලකා බැලිණී.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම පෙත්සම ලබන 29 වැනිදා නැවත සලකා බැලිම සදහා දින නියම කෙරිණී.",
        "කෑගල්ල කොට්ඨාස භාර හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ. බී. කීර්තිරත්න මහතා ඇතුළු පොලිස් කොස්තාපල්වරුන් තිදෙනකු ගොනු කර තිබූ මෙම රිට් පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කරනු ලැබ සිටියේ, නිතිපතිවරයා, පොලිස්පතිවරයා සහ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂකවරයා ඇතුළු පිරිසකි.",
        "තෙල්මිල වැඩීවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රඹුක්කන ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවැති උද්ඝෝෂණයක් අතරතුරදී ඇතිවූ නොසන්සුන්කාරී සිද්ධියේදී පොලිස් වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරයකින් පුද්ගලයකු මියයෑමේ සිද්ධියට අදාළව තමන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයට පත් කිරීමට කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා නිකුත් කර ඇති නියෝගය නිතියට පටහැනි බව පෙත්සම්කරුවන් සිය පෙත්සමෙන් දක්වා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රඹුක්කන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කීර්තිරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනක බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝභිත රාජකරුණා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික ගනේපොල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල කොට්ඨාසයේ කේ.බී.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කීර්තිරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரம்புக்கன சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகருக்கு சட்டமா அதிபரினால் பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டு சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கேகாலை முன்னாள் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் கே. பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன மற்றும் நான்கு பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களை பிணையில் விடுவிக்க தாம் எதிர்ப்பதாக சட்டமா அதிபர் இன்று (27) மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அறிவித்தார்.",
        "சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜரான பிரதி சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் ஜனக பண்டார, பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன மற்றும் நான்கு பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் நீதிமன்றில் அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்தனர்.",
        "மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்ற நீதியரசர்களான சோபித ராஜகருணா மற்றும் தம்மிக்க கணேபொல ஆகியோர் முன்னிலையில் இந்த ரிட் மனு இன்று (27) விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "அதன்படி, மனுவை வரும் 29ம் தேதி மீண்டும் பரிசீலனை செய்ய திட்டமிடப்பட்டது.",
        "கேகாலை பிரிவுக்கு பொறுப்பான முன்னாள் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கே. பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன மற்றும் மூன்று பொலிஸ் கான்ஸ்டபிள்களால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட ரிட் மனுவில் பிரதிவாதிகளாக சட்டமா அதிபர், பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் மற்றும் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் பணிப்பாளர் ஆகியோர் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "எரிபொருள் விலையேற்றம் தொடர்பில் ரம்புக்கனையில் இடம்பெற்ற போராட்டத்தின் போது இடம்பெற்ற கலவரத்தின் போது சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் தம்மை கைது செய்து விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கேகாலை நீதவான் பிறப்பித்த உத்தரவு சட்டத்திற்கு முரணானது என மனுதாரர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரம்புக்கனை எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை SSP கே.விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனக பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோபித ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க கணேபொல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை பிரிவு கே.பி.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}