{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/13/president-has-left-the-country-pms-office/",
  "time_ut": 1657683300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President has left the country – PMs Office",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President has left the country – PMs Office",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Prime Minister’s Office confirmed that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has left the country.",
        "It was reported on Wednesday (13) morning that Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa left the country on a military jet, amid mass protests over its economic crisis.",
        "The 73-year-old President arrived in the capital of the Maldives, Male, at around 03:00 local time (22:00 GMT).",
        "Rajapaksa’s departure ends a family dynasty that has ruled Sri Lanka for decades.",
        "The president had earlier pledged to resign on Wednesday 13 July.",
        "It is reported that the President left the country with his wife and two security officers.",
        "The Sri Lanka Air Force said it provided a SLAF plane for the President, the First Lady and Two Security Personnel to leave the country for the Maldives.",
        "The statement said that it was done based on the powers vested with an Executive President, and as per request made by the Government, subject to the approval of the Ministry of Defence.",
        "It added that all Immigration and Emigration, and customs laws were followed when providing the aircraft."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Male",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22:00 GMT",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday 13 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති රට ගියා – අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රට හැර ගිය බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකින් රට හැර ගිය බව බදාදා (13) උදෑසන වාර්තා විය.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි ජනාධිපතිවරයා එරට වේලාවෙන් පස්වරු 03.00 ට (GMT 22:00) මාලදිවයිනේ අගනුවර වන මාලේ වෙත ළඟා විය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂගේ නික්ම යාමෙන් දශක ගණනාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පාලනය කළ පවුල් රාජවංශයක් අවසන් වේ.",
        "ජූලි 13 බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා මීට පෙර ප්‍රතිඥා දී තිබුණි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනකු සමඟ රටින් පිටව ගිය බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා, ආර්යාව සහ ආරක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව යාමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට ගුවන් යානයක් ලබා දුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට පැවරී ඇති බලතල මත පදනම්ව සහ රජය විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අනුමැතියට යටත්ව එය සිදු කර ඇති බවයි එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වෙන්නේ.",
        "ගුවන් යානා සැපයීමේදී සියලුම ආගමන විගමන සහ රේගු නීති අනුගමනය කළ බව එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22:00 GMT",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார் – பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "சிறிலங்காவின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பில் பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இராணுவ ஜெட் விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதாக புதன்கிழமை (13) காலை தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "73 வயதான ஜனாதிபதி, உள்ளூர் நேரப்படி சுமார் 03:00 மணியளவில் (22:00 GMT) மாலைதீவின் தலைநகரான மாலேயை வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சேவின் விலகல் பல தசாப்தங்களாக இலங்கையை ஆண்ட ஒரு குடும்ப வம்சத்தை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டுவருகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி முன்னதாக ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாக உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தனது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு உத்தியோகத்தர்களுடன் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி, முதல் பெண்மணி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு உத்தியோகத்தர்களுக்கு மாலத்தீவுக்கு செல்வதற்காக இலங்கை விமானப்படை விமானத்தை வழங்கியதாக இலங்கை விமானப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரங்களின் அடிப்படையில், அரசாங்கத்தின் கோரிக்கையின்படி, பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு உட்பட்டு இது மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "விமானத்தை வழங்கும்போது அனைத்து குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு மற்றும் சுங்கச் சட்டங்கள் பின்பற்றப்பட்டதாக அது மேலும் கூறியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22:00 GMT",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}