{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131348",
  "time_ut": 1657635371,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பிரதமர் வீட்டிற்கருகில் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் -விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்த சி.சி.டி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Attack on journalists near Prime Minister's residence - CCD initiates investigations",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Amidst the protests that started demanding the resignation of the President and the Prime Minister, Sirasa, Shakthi R.V., who went for media activities. The Colombo Crime Prevention Unit has started investigations into the incident in which four journalists were assaulted in front of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe's house.",
        "In this regard, the officers of the Colombo Crime Prevention Unit presented the matter through a report to Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kegunawala today (12) and received orders for investigations.",
        "Accordingly, Justice Harshana Kekunawala ordered all the media to provide the unedited videos related to the attack to the investigators.",
        "On the night of the 9th, video cameraman of Sirasa TV Varuna Sampath, office reporter Sarasi Peiris, internet journalist Jannitha Mendis Shakthi R.V. went to collect information about the tension near the Prime Minister's residence. Journalist Sindhujan and others were assaulted by the police on duty there.",
        "While this incident has caused a great shock, it is also noteworthy that Romesh Lienake, who is said to have acted as the commanding officer of the Police Special Action Force who participated in the attack, has been temporarily suspended."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shakthi R.V.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Crime Prevention Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Prevention Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kegunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa TV Varuna Sampath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarasi Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jannitha Mendis Shakthi R.V.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sindhujan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Police Special Action Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති නිවස අසලදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට ප්‍රහාරයක් - CCD පරීක්ෂණ අරඹයි",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ අගමැතිට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ආරම්භ වූ විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ මාධ්‍ය කටයුතු සඳහා ගිය සිරස, ශක්ති ආර්.වී. අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවස ඉදිරිපිටදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සිව් දෙනෙකුට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ ඒකකය පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ ඒකකයේ නිලධාරීන් අද (12) කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැගුණවල මහතා වෙත වාර්තාවක් මගින් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර එහිදී විමර්ශන සඳහා නියෝග ලැබිණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ප්‍රහාරයට අදාළ සංස්කරණය නොකළ වීඩියෝ දර්ශන විමර්ශන නිලධාරීන්ට ලබාදෙන ලෙස විනිසුරු හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල මහතා සියලු මාධ්‍යවලට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "09 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ අගමැති නිවස අසල ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාව පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු රැස් කිරීමට සිරස රූපවාහිනියේ වීඩියෝ කැමරා ශිල්පී වරුණ සම්පත්, කාර්යාල වාර්තාකාරිනී සරසි පීරිස්, අන්තර්ජාල මාධ්‍යවේදී ජන්නිත මෙන්ඩිස් ශක්ති ආර්.වී. මාධ්‍යවේදී සින්ධුජන් ඇතුළු පිරිසට එහි රාජකාරියේ යෙදී සිටි පොලිසිය පහර දුන්නා.",
        "මෙම සිදුවීම දැඩි කම්පනයක් ඇති කර ඇති අතර ප්‍රහාරයට එක්වූ පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ අණදෙන නිලධාරියා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ බව කියන රොමේෂ් ලියනකේගේ තාවකාලික වැඩ තහනම් කර තිබීමද විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්ති ආර්.වී.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ මර්දන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැගුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස TV වරුණ සම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරසි පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන්නිත මෙන්ඩිස් ශක්ති ආර්.වී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සින්ධුජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් විශේෂ ක්‍රියාකාරී බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் வீட்டிற்கருகில் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் -விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்த சி.சி.டி",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை பதவி விலக வலியுறுத்தி ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட போராட்டத்தின் இடையே, ஊடக நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக சென்ற சிரச, சக்தி ரி.வி. ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் நால்வர், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின்  வீட்டின்  முன்பாக வைத்து தாக்கப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் இன்று (12) கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதிவான் ஹர்ஷன கெக்குனவலவிடம் அறிக்கை ஊடாக விடயங்களை முன் வைத்த நிலையில்,  விசாரணைகளுக்கான உத்தரவுகளையும் பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "அதன்படி குறித்த தாக்குதல் தொடர்பிலான  செம்மைப்படுத்தப்படாத காணொளிகளை விசாரணையாளர்களுக்கு வழங்குமாறு நீதிவான் ஹர்ஷன கெக்குனவல அனைத்து ஊடகங்களுக்கும் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 9 ஆம் திகதி இரவு வேளையில், பிரதமரின் இல்லத்தை அண்மித்த பதற்ற நிலை தொடர்பில் தகவல் சேகரிக்க சென்ற சிரச   தொலைக்காட்சியின் வீடியோ படப் பிடிப்பாளர் வருன சம்பத்,  அலுவலக செய்தியாளர் சரசி பீரிஸ், இணைய ஊடகவியலாளர்  ஜன்னித்த மெண்டிஸ் சக்தி ரி.வி.  ஊடகவியலாளர் சிந்துஜன்  உள்ளிட்டோர் அங்கு கடமையில் இருந்த பொலிஸாரால் தாக்கப்பட்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் பெரும் அதிர்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்திய நிலையில், தாக்குதலின் போது அதில் பங்கேற்ற அங்கிருந்த பொலிஸ் விஷேட அதிரடிப் படைக்கு கட்டளை அதிகாரியாக செயற்பட்டதாக கூறப்படும் ரொமேஷ் லியனகே தற்காலிகமாக பணி இடை நிறுத்தம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளமையும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி ஆர்.வி.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச டிவி வருணா சம்பத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரசி பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன்னிதா மெண்டிஸ் சக்தி ஆர்.வி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்துஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}