{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කබ්රාල්ට-එරෙහි-විදෙස්-ගමන්-තහනම-දිර්ඝ කරයි/11-395714",
  "time_ut": 1658725944,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කබ්රාල්ට එරෙහි විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම දිර්ඝ කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The travel ban against Cabral is extended",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawela ordered today (25th) to extend the travel ban imposed against former Central Bank Governor Mr. Ajith Nivard Cabral until the 26th of October.",
        "Ajit Nivard Cabral, former Governor of the Central Bank, for criminal breach of trust, criminal breach of trust by a banker, dishonest and misappropriation of money, Ordinance No. 07 of 1937 (Amendment) No. 56 (a) ( 1) This foreign travel ban was imposed in relation to the complaint filed by the former Mr. Rajith Keerthy Tennakoon that he had committed an offense under (a)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "October",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajit Nivard Cabral",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ordinance No",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "07 of 1937",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajith Keerthy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කබ්රාල්ට එරෙහි විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම දිර්ඝ කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතාට එරෙහිව පනවා ඇති විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම ලබන ඔක්තෝබර් මස 26 දා තෙක් දීර්ඝ කිරීමට කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවෙල මහතා අද (25දා) නියෝග කෙළේය.",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති වන අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් යන අය සාපරාධි විස්වාසය කඩ කිරීම, බැංකු කරුවෙකු විසින් සිදු කරණු ලබන සාපරාධි විස්වාසය කඩ කිරීම, මුදල් වංක ලෙස හා සාවද්‍ය ලෙස පරිහරණය කිරීම, 1937 අංක 07 දරණ (සංශෝධිත) ආඥා පනතේ අංක 56 (අ) (1) (අ) යටතේ වරදක් සිදු කර ඇති බවට හිටපු රජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් මහතා ගොනු කර ඇති පැමිණිල්ලට අදාළව මෙම විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම පැනවීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවෙල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආඥාපනත අංක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1937 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජිත් කීර්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கப்ராலுக்கு எதிரான பயணத்தடை நீடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவாட் கப்ராலுக்கு எதிராக விதிக்கப்பட்ட பயணத் தடையை எதிர்வரும் ஒக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் திகதி வரை நீடிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுணாவெல இன்று (25) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால், குற்றவியல் நம்பிக்கை மீறல், வங்கியாளரால் குற்றவியல் நம்பிக்கை மீறல், நேர்மையற்ற மற்றும் துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்தல், 1937 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 07 ஆம் இலக்க கட்டளைச் சட்டம் (திருத்தம்) இலக்கம் 56 (அ) ( 1) இது (அ) ​​கீழ் குற்றத்தை செய்ததாக முன்னாள் திரு.ரஜித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தாக்கல் செய்த முறைப்பாடு தொடர்பில் வெளிநாட்டு பயணத்தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவெல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாணை எண்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "07 இன் 1937",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஜித் கீர்த்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}