{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-petroleum-sector-trade-unions-to-launch-protest-on-aug-22-against-new-reforms-98833/",
  "time_ut": 1661085840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s petroleum sector trade unions to launch protest on Aug 22 against new reforms",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s petroleum sector trade unions to launch protest on Aug 22 against new reforms",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s Ceylon Petroleum Corporation trade unions will hold a protest on Monday (21) against the recent reforms made in the sector, Minister for Power and Energy said.",
        "“CPC Trade unions affiliated with all political parties are to oppose the proposed reforms,” Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said in a Tweet.",
        "He said he has met all the Unions and discussed the proposed reforms and their importance.",
        "However, the minister said the protest march against the proposed reforms will still occur tomorrow (August 22).",
        "“CPC & CPC reforms are a must & will continue to work to implement them.”",
        "Minister Wijesekara in early August said that there are multiple reasons for the CPC to operate under losses, with selling at subsidized rates, rupee depreciation, dues from government-owned institutes and overpaid, inefficient and bloated staffing being prominent reasons.",
        "CPC provides fuel for transport services in the country including, the Transportation Board, Railway Department, and Sri Lankan Airlines while also providing fuel for the Ceylon Electricity Board for thermal power generation.",
        "Dues from SriLankan airlines which values up to 300 million US dollars and 60 billion rupees from CEB is also contributing factor to the losses of CPC."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC Trade",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Unions",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC & CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Transportation Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "300 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඛනිජ තෙල් අංශයේ වෘත්තීය සමිති අගෝස්තු 22 වැනිදා විරෝධතාවක් දියත් කිරීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ මෑතකාලීන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ වෘත්තීය සමිති සඳුදා (21) විරෝධතාවක් පවත්වන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "\"සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට අනුබද්ධ CPC වෘත්තීය සමිති යෝජිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලට විරුද්ධ වීමට නියමිතයි\" යනුවෙන් අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "තමන් සියලුම වෘත්තීය සමිති හමුවී යෝජිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ඒවායේ වැදගත්කම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, යෝජිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලට එරෙහි විරෝධතා පාගමන හෙට (අගෝස්තු 22) ද පැවැත්වෙන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "\"CPC සහ CPC ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන අතර ඒවා ක්‍රියාවට නැංවීම සඳහා දිගටම කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.\"",
        "සහන මිලට විකිණීම, රුපියල අවප්‍රමාණය වීම, රජයට අයත් ආයතනවලින් ගෙවිය යුතු මුදල් සහ අධික වැටුප් සහිත, අකාර්යක්ෂම සහ පුම්බාගත් කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ප්‍රමුඛ හේතූන් ලෙස තෙල් සංස්ථාව පාඩු යටතේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට විවිධ හේතු තිබෙන බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර අගෝස්තු මස මුලදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "CPC විසින්, ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය, දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය ඇතුළුව රටේ ප්‍රවාහන සේවා සඳහා ඉන්ධන සපයන අතරම, ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට තාප විදුලිය නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා ඉන්ධන ද සපයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයෙන් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 300ක් සහ ලංවිමෙන් රුපියල් බිලියන 60ක් දක්වා ගෙවිය යුතු මුදල්ද CPC හි පාඩුව සඳහා දායක වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC වෙළඳාම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සමිති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC සහ CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 300 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 60 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கு எதிராக இலங்கையின் பெட்ரோலியத் துறை தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் ஆகஸ்ட் 22 ஆம் தேதி போராட்டத்தை நடத்தவுள்ளன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் திங்கட்கிழமை (21) திங்கட்கிழமை (21) போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடவுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடன் இணைந்த CPC தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தங்களை எதிர்க்க வேண்டும் என அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அனைத்து தொழிற்சங்கங்களையும் சந்தித்து முன்மொழியப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் அவற்றின் முக்கியத்துவம் குறித்து விவாதித்ததாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், உத்தேச சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கு எதிராக நாளையும் (ஆகஸ்ட் 22) எதிர்ப்பு ஊர்வலம் நடைபெறும் என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"CPC & CPC சீர்திருத்தங்கள் அவசியம் & அவற்றை செயல்படுத்த தொடர்ந்து செயல்படும்.\"",
        "மானிய விலையில் விற்பனை செய்தல், ரூபாய் மதிப்பு சரிவு, அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களின் நிலுவைத் தொகை மற்றும் அதிக ஊதியம், திறமையற்ற மற்றும் வீங்கிய பணியாளர்கள் ஆகியவை முக்கிய காரணங்களாக CPC நஷ்டத்தில் இயங்குவதற்கு பல காரணங்கள் இருப்பதாக ஆகஸ்ட் மாத தொடக்கத்தில் அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர கூறினார்.",
        "CPC ஆனது, போக்குவரத்து சபை, புகையிரத திணைக்களம் மற்றும் இலங்கை விமான சேவைகள் உட்பட நாட்டின் போக்குவரத்து சேவைகளுக்கு எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதுடன், அனல் மின் உற்பத்திக்காக இலங்கை மின்சார சபைக்கு எரிபொருளையும் வழங்குகிறது.",
        "300 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் மற்றும் CEB யிடமிருந்து 60 பில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் விமான சேவைகள் செலுத்த வேண்டிய நிலுவைத் தொகையும் CPC இன் இழப்புகளுக்கு காரணியாக உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொழிற்சங்கங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC & CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அது வரை",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "300 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}