{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131443",
  "time_ut": 1657793698,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பிரதமர் ரணில் பதவி விலகாவிட்டால் அவருக்கு எதிராக நம்பிக்கையில்லா பிரேரணை - சுதந்திர கட்சி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No-confidence motion against Prime Minister Ranil if he does not step down - Freedom Party",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Not only President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, but also Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe must resign.",
        "On the contrary, Sri Lanka Freedom Party General Secretary Dayasiri Jayasekara said that if the Prime Minister does not step down, steps will be taken to submit a no-confidence motion against him in Parliament.",
        "Due to people's protests, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa announced his resignation on Wednesday.",
        "However, due to the delay in handing over the resignation letter to the Speaker, massive demonstrations were held in many parts of the country including Colombo.",
        "A special party leader's meeting was held under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yaba Abeywardhana yesterday after the emergence of a restless situation in the country.",
        "Dayasiri Jayasekara mentioned the above while giving the position of the Freedom Party regarding the issues emphasized during the party leader's meeting and the current situation of the country. In this regard, he further informed,",
        "We have clearly emphasized that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should also resign in the party leader's meeting. Apart from that, we have also requested to convene the Parliament as soon as possible.",
        "Despite the continuous demands of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to step down by the demonstrators and the majority of the people of the country, if he does not listen to it, we will submit a motion of no confidence against him.",
        "That is why we have urged to convene Parliament immediately. We will also request the Speaker to submit a no-confidence motion against the Prime Minister in the Parliament soon and take it up for debate and vote on the same day. If the no-confidence motion is passed, he will lose the post of Prime Minister.",
        "The post of Acting President will also disappear. He said that we will continue to take action to remove both Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and the President without a mandate from the people.",
        "However, in the meeting held between the cabinet members and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe at the Prime Minister's Office last Monday, all the ministers who participated in the meeting agreed to hand over responsibilities to the government once an agreement is reached to form an all-party government.",
        "Accordingly, it is noteworthy that the Prime Minister's Office has informed the Acting President and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena that the ruling party and the opposition should form an all-party government together and appoint a prime minister who can be accepted by the government and the opposition."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Freedom Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yaba",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති රනිල් ඉවත් නොවන්නේ නම් ඔහුට එරෙහිව විශ්වාසභංගයක් - නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පමණක් නොව අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහද ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුය.",
        "ඊට පටහැනිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් දයාසිරි ජයසේකර කියා සිටියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉවත් නොවන්නේ නම් ඔහුට එරෙහිව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට විශ්වාසභංග යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "ජනතා විරෝධය හේතුවෙන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව බදාදා නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායකවරයාට භාරදීම ප්‍රමාද වීම හේතුවෙන් කොළඹ ඇතුළු දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ රැසක දැවැන්ත විරෝධතා පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "රට තුළ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් මතුවීමත් සමඟ විශේෂ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් කථානායක මහින්ද යාබා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ඊයේ පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී අවධාරණය කළ කරුණු සහ රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ ස්ථාවරය ප්‍රකාශ කරමින් දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා ඉහත කරුණු සඳහන් කළේය. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් දන්වා සිටියේ,",
        "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාද ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී අපි පැහැදිලිවම අවධාරණය කර තිබෙනවා. ඒ හැරුණු විට හැකි ඉක්මනින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවන ලෙසත් ඉල්ලා තිබෙනවා.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට අගමැති ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස උද්ඝෝෂකයින් සහ රටේ බහුතර ජනතාව දිගින් දිගටම ඉල්ලීම් කළත් ඊට සවන් නොදුන්නොත් අපි ඔහුට එරෙහිව විශ්වාසභංගයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරනවා.",
        "ඒ නිසා තමයි අපි වහාම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවන්න කියලා කිව්වේ. ඒ වගේම අගමැතිවරයාට එරෙහිව විශ්වාසභංග යෝජනාවක් ළඟදීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කර එය විවාදයට ගෙන එදිනම ඡන්දය දෙන ලෙස අපි කතානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා. විශ්වාසභංගය සම්මත වුණොත් අගමැතිකම නැති වෙනවා.",
        "වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති තනතුරත් නැති වෙනවා. ජනවරමක් නොමැතිව අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා දෙදෙනාම ඉවත් කිරීමට අපි ඉදිරියටත් ක්‍රියා කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පසුගිය සඳුදා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අතර පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී සර්ව පාක්ෂිකයෙකු පිහිටුවීමට එකඟතාවකට පැමිණි පසු ඊට සහභාගී වූ සියලුම අමාත්‍යවරුන් රජයට වගකීම් භාරදීමට එකඟ වුණා. ආණ්ඩුව.",
        "ඒ අනුව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය සහ විපක්ෂය එක්ව සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවා තමන්ට පිළිගත හැකි අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයෙකු පත් කළ යුතු බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය විසින් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන වෙත දැනුම්දීම විශේෂත්වයක්. ආණ්ඩුව සහ විපක්ෂය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාබ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் ரணில் பதவி விலகாவிட்டால் அவருக்கு எதிராக நம்பிக்கையில்லா பிரேரணை - சுதந்திர கட்சி",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மாத்திரமின்றி, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் உடன் பதவி விலக வேண்டும்.",
        "மாறாக பிரதமர் பதவி விலகாவிட்டால் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அவருக்கு எதிராக நம்பிக்கையில்லா பிரேரணையை சமர்ப்பிக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்று ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திர கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மக்களின் போராட்டங்களினால் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாக அறிவித்தார்.",
        "எனினும் பதவி விலகல் கடிதத்தினை சபாநாயகரிடம் கையளிப்பதில் காணப்பட்ட இழுபறி நிலைமை காரணமாக கொழும்பு உட்பட நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளிலும் பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இவ்வாறு நாட்டில் அமைதியற்ற நிலைமை தோற்றம் பெற்றதையடுத்து நேற்றுமு சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாபா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் விசேட கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டம் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தின் போது வலியுறுத்தப்பட்ட விடயங்கள் மற்றும் நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைவரம் தொடர்பில் சுதந்திர கட்சியின் நிலைப்பாட்டினை தெரிவிக்கும் போதே தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர மேற்கண்டவாறு குறிப்பிட்டார். இது தொடர்பில் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில் ,",
        "கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்பதை தெளிவாக வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளோம். அது தவிர துரிதமாக பாராமன்றத்தைக் கூட்டுமாறும் கோரியுள்ளோம்.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களினாலும் , நாட்டின் பெரும்பாலான மக்களாலும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்று தொடர்ச்சியாக வலியுறுத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்ற போதிலும் , அவர் அதனை செவிமடுக்கவில்லை எனில் அவருக்கு எதிராக நம்பிக்கையில்லா பிரேரணையை சமர்ப்பிப்போம்.",
        "எனவே தான் உடனடியாக பாராளுமன்றத்தைக் கூட்டுமாறு வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளோம். விரைவில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதமருக்கு எதிராக நம்பிக்கையில்லா பிரேரணையை சமர்ப்பித்து, அதனை ஒரே நாளில் விவாதத்திற்கு எடுத்து வாக்கெடுப்பிற்கு செல்லுமாறும் சபாநாயகரைக் கோருவோம். அவ்வாறு நம்பிக்கையில்லா பிரேரணை நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டால் அவருக்கு பிரதமர் பதவியும் இல்லாமல் போகும்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியும் அற்றுப்போகும். மக்கள் ஆணை அற்ற பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி ஆகிய இருவரையும் பதவியிலிருந்து விலக்குவதற்கான செயற்பாடுகளை நாம் தொடர்ந்தும் முன்னெடுப்போம் என்றார்.",
        "எவ்வாறிருப்பினும் கடந்த திங்கள்கிழமை பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் அமைச்சரவை உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் , பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கும் இடையில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பில் , சர்வகட்சி ஆட்சி அமைக்க உடன்பாடு ஏற்பட்டவுடன் அந்த அரசிடம் பொறுப்புகளை ஒப்படைப்பதற்கு சந்திப்பில் பங்கேற்ற அனைத்து அமைச்சர்களும் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அதன்படி, ஆளும் கட்சியும் எதிர்க்கட்சியும் இணைந்து சர்வ கட்சி ஆட்சியை அமைக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அரசாங்கமும் எதிர்க்கட்சியும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய பிரதமரை நியமிக்குமாறு பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகிந்த யபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}