{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131475",
  "time_ut": 1657816221,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தனியார் பேருந்து சேவைகள் தொடர்ந்தும் பாதிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Private bus services continue to suffer",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Private bus services continue to suffer due to ongoing tension in the country and shortage of diesel.",
        "Due to this, only 10 percent of the buses were put into service on Thursday, the 14th, said Kemunu Wijeratne, President of Sri Lanka Private Bus Owners Association.",
        "Meanwhile, it has been reported that about 3,000 buses of Sri Lanka Transport Board have been put into service yesterday.",
        "5000 buses will be put into service by the Sri Lanka Transport Board on normal days. However, Sri Lanka Transport Board has informed that only about 3000 buses have been put into service on the 14th due to the decrease in the number of passengers and employees.",
        "The Railway Department had informed that the trains would run as usual yesterday afternoon. The Railway Department mentioned that the train was running as usual.",
        "Meanwhile, it is noteworthy that the curfew was enforced at 12 noon on the 14th in Colombo and public transport services were limited and people were facing various problems in going to their homes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "only 10 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "normal days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only about 3000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෞද්ගලික බස් සේවා තවදුරටත් අඩාල වේ",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට තුළ පවතින උණුසුම්කාරී තත්ත්වය සහ ඩීසල් හිඟය හේතුවෙන් පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ සේවා තවදුරටත් අඩාල වී තිබේ.",
        "මේ හේතුවෙන් 14 වැනි බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා දින බස් රථවලින් සියයට 10ක් පමණක් ධාවනයට යෙදවූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති කෙමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර ඊයේ දිනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ බස් රථ 3000ක් පමණ ධාවනයට යොදවා ඇති බවද වාර්තා වේ.",
        "සාමාන්‍ය දිනවල ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය මගින් බස් රථ 5000ක් ධාවනයට යොදවනු ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මගීන් සහ සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව අඩුවීම හේතුවෙන් 14 වැනිදා බස් රථ 3000ක් පමණ ධාවනයට යොදවා ඇති බව ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය දන්වා ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ධාවනය වන බව දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දැනුම් දී තිබුණා. දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ධාවනය වන බවයි දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "මේ අතර පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා මධ්‍යහ්න 12ට කොළඹ ඇඳිරි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමත් සමඟ පොදු ප්‍රවාහන සේවා සීමා කර තිබූ අතර ජනතාව තම නිවෙස් කරා යාමට විවිධ ගැටලුවලට මුහුණ පා සිටීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමාන්ය දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனியார் பேருந்து சேவைகள் தொடர்ந்தும் பாதிப்பு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் தொடர்ந்து நிலவிவரும் பதற்ற நிலை மற்றும் டீசலுக்கான தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக தனியார் பேருந்து சேவைகள் தொடர்ந்து பாதிக்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றது.",
        "இதன் காரணமாக 14 ஆம் திகதி வியாழக்கிழமை 10 வீதமான பஸ்கள் மாத்திரமே சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் சுமார் 3,000 பஸ்கள்  நேற்றைய தினம் சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சாதாரண நாட்களில் இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையால் 5000 பேருந்துகளின் சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்தபடுத்தப்படும். ஆனால் பயணிகள் மற்றும் ஊழியர்களின் வருகை குறைவடைந்துள்ளமை காரணமாக 14 ஆம் திகதி சுமார் 3000 பஸ்கள் மாத்திரமே சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நேற்றைய தினம் பிற்பகலிலும் ரயில்கள் வழமை போன்று இயங்கும் என ரயில்வே திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்திருந்தது.  ரயில் வழமை போன்று இயங்கியதாக ரயில்வே திணைக்களம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, கொழும்பில் 14 ஆம் திகதி நண்பகல் 12 மணிக்கு ஊரடங்கு சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டதால் பொதுப் போக்குவரத்து சேவைகள் மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அளவிலேயே காணப்பட்டதால் மக்கள் தங்கள் வீடுகளுக்கு செல்வதில் பல்வேறு சிக்கல்களை எதிர்கொண்டிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 சதவீதம் மட்டுமே",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாதாரண நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நண்பகல் 12",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}