{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130280",
  "time_ut": 1656327362,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அமெரிக்காவின் ஒத்துழைப்புக்கள் முழுமையாகக் கிடைக்கப் பெறும் - பிரதமருடனான சந்திப்பில் அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திரிகள் உறுதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US cooperation will be fully available - US diplomats confirm meeting with PM",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "US diplomats visiting Sri Lanka have pledged US cooperation to make the negotiations with the International Monetary Fund a success and will extend the full support needed for public finance management.",
        "A diplomatic team comprising US Assistant Secretary of State for the Asian Region Robert Cabrot and US Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asian Affairs Kelly Gaitling arrived in the country on Sunday, the 26th.",
        "The group first met with the President and the Prime Minister today and held crucial discussions on what assistance could be provided to Sri Lanka in recovering from the current economic crisis.",
        "During its meeting with the Prime Minister on Monday, it pledged its full support for talks with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Sang also attended the meeting between the Prime Minister and US Diplomats.",
        "\"We met with US diplomats to meet with President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to discuss Sri Lanka's economic crisis,\" he tweeted.",
        "At a time when Sri Lanka is facing serious challenges, we will continue to assist and extend long-term partnerships to help achieve a prosperous, secure and democratic future. ' said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Cabrot",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Sang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් ජනපද සහයෝගීතාවය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පවතිනු ඇත - එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් අගමැති හමුව තහවුරු කරයි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡා සාර්ථක කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් ඇමෙරිකානු සහයෝගීතාවය ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇති අතර රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බව ද ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත.",
        "ආසියානු කලාපය සඳහා වන අමෙරිකානු සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් රොබට් කැබ්‍රොට් සහ දකුණු හා මධ්‍යම ආසියානු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ ඇමෙරිකානු සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් කෙලී ගේට්ලින් යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික කණ්ඩායමක් 26 වැනි ඉරිදා දිවයිනට පැමිණියහ.",
        "මෙම පිරිස අද ප්‍රථමයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවී පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදිය හැකි සහය මොනවාද යන්න පිළිබඳව තීරණාත්මක සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූහ.",
        "සඳුදා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සමඟ පැවති රැස්වීමේදී, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්නේය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ අමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික නිලධාරීන් අතර පැවති හමුවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී සැන්ග් ද සහභාගී වූවාය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හමුවීමට අපි එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් හමුවෙමු,\" ඔහු ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බරපතල අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දී සිටින අවස්ථාවක, සෞභාග්‍යමත්, සුරක්ෂිත සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අනාගතයක් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා දිගු කාලීන හවුල්කාරිත්වයන්ට සහාය වීමට සහ දිගු කිරීමට අපි දිගටම කටයුතු කරන්නෙමු. කිව්වා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කැබ්රොට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලී සංග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவின் ஒத்துழைப்புக்கள் முழுமையாகக் கிடைக்கப் பெறும் - பிரதமருடனான சந்திப்பில் அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திரிகள் உறுதி",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான கலந்துரையாடல்கள் வெற்றியளிப்பதற்கு அமெரிக்காவின் ஒத்துழைப்புக்கள் கிடைக்கப் பெறும் என உறுதியளித்துள்ள இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திரிகள் , அரச நிதி முகாமைத்துவத்திற்கு தேவையான முழுமையான ஒத்துழைப்பை வழங்குவதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அமெரிக்க திறைசேரியின் ஆசியப்பிராந்தியத்துக்கான பிரதி உதவிச்செயலாளர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரொத் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத்திணைக்களத்தின் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியப்பிராந்தியத்துக்கான பிரதி உதவிச்செயலாளர் கெலி கெய்டெலிங் ஆகியோரை உள்ளடக்கிய இராஜதந்திர குழு 26 ஆம் திகதி ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை நாட்டை வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "இக்குழு முதற்கட்டமாக இன்று ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை சந்தித்து  தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு எத்தகைய உதவிகளை வழங்கமுடியும் என்பது குறித்து தீர்க்கமான கலந்துரையாடல்களை முன்னெடுத்திருந்தது.",
        "அதற்கமைய பிரதமருடன் இன்று திங்கட்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே , சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளுக்கு முழுமையான ஆதரவினை வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமர் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திரகளுக்கிடையிலான இந்த சந்திப்பில் இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சங்கும் கலந்து கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் டுவிட்டர் பதிவிட்டுள்ள அவர் , ' இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடல்களை முன்னெடுப்பதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திரிகளுடன் சந்தித்தோம்.",
        "இலங்கை கடும் சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள இந்த சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் , வளமான, பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் ஜனநாயகம் மிக்க எதிர்காலத்தை அடைய உதவும் வகையில் நாம் தொடர்ந்தும் உதவுவதோடு , நீண்ட கால கூட்டாண்மையையும் வழங்குவோம்.' என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}