{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ග්‍රහලෝක-පහක්-හෙට-අලුයම-එකම-රේඛාවක/1-615559",
  "time_ut": 1656424573,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ග්‍රහලෝක පහක් හෙට අලුයම එකම රේඛාවක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Five planets in the same line tomorrow morning",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is possible to see the five planets belonging to the solar system in the same line these days and that phenomenon will be better seen from 4.40 am tomorrow (29) until sunrise tomorrow, says the lecturer at the Planetarium Geethanjana Wanigasekara.",
        "He noted that the planets Mercury, Venus, Mars, Jupiter and Saturn were observed in the sky at the same time, and that the effect of the moon's light was less visible this morning.",
        "Mr. Wanigasekara said that although it is difficult to identify Saturn, which is located slightly above the sky, Venus and Jupiter can be seen very brightly and other planets can also be identified by connecting those planets with the mind.",
        "He added that this opportunity could be seen until the first week of July.",
        "Thus, the five planets will be seen in the same line again in the year 2040."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "morning",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.40 am tomorrow",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Planetarium Geethanjana Wanigasekara",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mercury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Venus",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mars",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jupiter",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wanigasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Venus",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jupiter",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first week of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2040",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ග්‍රහලෝක පහක් හෙට අලුයම එකම රේඛාවක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෞර ග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයට අයත්ග්‍රහ ලෝක පහක් එකම රේඛාවක පිහිටා ඇති ආකාරය දැකගැනීමේ හැකියාව මේ දිනවල පවතින අතර, එම සංසිද්ධිය හෙට (29) අලුයම 4.40 සිට හිරු උදාව දක්වා වඩාත් හොඳින් දැකගත හැකි බව ග්‍රහලෝකාගාරයේ කථිකාචාර්ය ගීතාංජන වනිගසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව බුධ, සිකුරු, අඟහරු, බ්‍රහස්පති සහ සෙනසුරු යන ග්‍රහලෝක එකවර අහසේ නිරීක්ෂණය කළ හැති අතර, චන්ද්‍රයාගේ ආලෝකයේ බලපෑම අවම වන බැවින් අද අළුයම එය වඩා පැහැදිළිව දැකගත හැකි බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තරමක් අහස මුදුනට වන්නට පිහිටා ඇති සෙනසුරු ග්‍රහලෝකය හඳුනාගැනීම තරමක් අපහසු වුවත් සිකුරු හා බ්‍රහස්පති යන ග්‍රහලෝක ඉතා දීප්තියෙන් යුතුව දැකගත හැකි නිසා එම ග්‍රහලෝක මනසින් යා කරමින් අනෙක් ග්‍රහලෝක ද හඳුනාගත හැකි බව වනිගසේකර මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාව ජූලි මස පළමු සතිය දක්වාම දැකගත හැකි බව ද හෙතෙම කීවේය.",
        "මෙලෙස ග්‍රහ ලෝක පහක් එකම රේඛාවක යළිත් දැකගත හැකි වන්නේ 2040 වසරේදීයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "උදෑසන",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට උදේ 4.40 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගීතාංජන වනිගසේකර ග්‍රහලෝකාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රසදිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පති",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wanigasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පති",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2040",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளை காலை ஒரே வரிசையில் ஐந்து கிரகங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த நாட்களில் சூரிய குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஐந்து கோள்களை ஒரே கோட்டில் பார்க்க முடியும் என்றும், அந்த நிகழ்வு நாளை (29) அதிகாலை 4.40 மணி முதல் நாளை சூரிய உதயம் வரை சிறப்பாகக் காணப்படும் என்றும் கோளரங்கத்தின் விரிவுரையாளர் கீதாஞ்சன வணிகசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "புதன், வெள்ளி, செவ்வாய், வியாழன் மற்றும் சனி ஆகிய கிரகங்கள் ஒரே நேரத்தில் வானில் காணப்பட்டதாகவும், இன்று காலை நிலவின் ஒளியின் தாக்கம் குறைவாகவே காணப்படுவதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "வானில் இருந்து சற்று மேலே அமைந்துள்ள சனி கிரகத்தை அடையாளம் காண்பது கடினம் என்றாலும், சுக்கிரன் மற்றும் வியாழன் ஆகிய கிரகங்களை மிகவும் பிரகாசமாக பார்க்க முடியும் என்றும், அந்த கிரகங்களை மனதோடு இணைத்து மற்ற கிரகங்களையும் அடையாளம் காண முடியும் என்றும் திரு வணிகசேகரன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த வாய்ப்பை ஜூலை முதல் வாரம் வரை காணலாம் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இதனால் 2040ம் ஆண்டு மீண்டும் ஐந்து கிரகங்களும் ஒரே கோட்டில் தென்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "காலை",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை அதிகாலை 4.40",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோளரங்கம் கீதாஞ்சனா வணிகசேகர",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதரசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீனஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wanigasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீனஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2040 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}