{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84400/land-value-in-colombo-district-accelerates-in-first-half-of-2022",
  "time_ut": 1660902660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Land value in Colombo District accelerates in first half of 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Land value in Colombo District accelerates in first half of 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Land value in Colombo District increased substantially in the first half of the year 2022, the Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) says.",
        "According to the Statistics Department of the Central Bank, the Land Valuation Indicator (LVI) for Colombo District climbed to 186.9 with a year-on-year change of 17.0 percent during the first half of the year.",
        "This annual increase (17.0) and the semi-annual increase (4.6%) of the Land Valuation Indicator, showed deceleration of the increasing trend observed in the second half of 2021.",
        "All sub-indicators of the Land Valuation Indicator, namely Residential LVI, Commercial LVI and Industrial LVI contributed to the overall increase.",
        "Industrial LVI recorded the highest annual increase of 20.6% followed by Commercial LVI and Residential LVI."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "first half of 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half of the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Statistics Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Land Valuation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "186.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.0 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Land Valuation Indicator",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second half of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Land Valuation Indicator",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Residential LVI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ඉඩම් වටිනාකම 2022 පළමු භාගයේදී වේගවත් වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 වසරේ මුල් භාගයේදී කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ඉඩම් වටිනාකම සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව (CBSL) පවසයි.",
        "මහ බැංකුවේ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට අනුව, කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය සඳහා වන ඉඩම් තක්සේරු දර්ශකය (LVI) වසරේ මුල් භාගයේදී සියයට 17.0ක වාර්ෂික වෙනසක් සමඟින් 186.9 දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "මෙම වාර්ෂික වැඩිවීම (17.0) සහ ඉඩම් තක්සේරු දර්ශකයේ අර්ධ වාර්ෂික වැඩිවීම (4.6%) 2021 දෙවන භාගයේ නිරීක්ෂණය කරන ලද වැඩිවන ප්‍රවණතාවේ අඩුවීමක් පෙන්නුම් කළේය.",
        "ඉඩම් තක්සේරු දර්ශකයේ සියලුම උප දර්ශක, එනම් නේවාසික LVI, වාණිජ LVI සහ Industrial LVI සමස්ත වැඩිවීමට දායක විය.",
        "Industrial LVI 20.6% ක ඉහළම වාර්ෂික වැඩිවීම වාර්තා කළ අතර පසුව වාණිජ LVI සහ නේවාසික LVI."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 වසරේ පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංඛ්යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉඩම් තක්සේරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "186.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 17.0 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරේ පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉඩම් තක්සේරු දර්ශකය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 දෙවන භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉඩම් තක්සේරු දර්ශකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේවාසික LVI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதியில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் காணியின் பெறுமதி அதிகரிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதியில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் காணியின் பெறுமதி கணிசமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி (CBSL) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் புள்ளிவிபரத் திணைக்களத்தின் படி, கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்திற்கான காணி மதிப்பீட்டுக் குறிகாட்டியானது (LVI) வருடத்தின் முதல் அரையாண்டில் 17.0 சதவீத வருடாந்த மாற்றத்துடன் 186.9 ஆக உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு அதிகரிப்பு (17.0) மற்றும் நில மதிப்பீட்டுக் குறிகாட்டியின் அரை ஆண்டு அதிகரிப்பு (4.6%), 2021 இன் இரண்டாம் பாதியில் காணப்பட்ட அதிகரித்து வரும் போக்கின் வீழ்ச்சியைக் காட்டியது.",
        "நில மதிப்பீட்டு காட்டியின் அனைத்து துணை குறிகாட்டிகளான குடியிருப்பு எல்.வி.ஐ, வணிக எல்.வி.ஐ மற்றும் தொழில்துறை எல்.வி.ஐ ஆகியவை ஒட்டுமொத்த அதிகரிப்புக்கு பங்களித்தன.",
        "தொழில்துறை எல்.வி.ஐ 20.6% உயர்ந்த வருடாந்திர அதிகரிப்பைப் பதிவுசெய்தது, அதைத் தொடர்ந்து வணிக எல்.வி.ஐ மற்றும் குடியிருப்பு எல்.வி.ஐ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2022 இன் முதல் பாதி",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புள்ளியியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில மதிப்பீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "186.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.0 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில மதிப்பீட்டு காட்டி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 இன் இரண்டாம் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நில மதிப்பீட்டு காட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடியிருப்பு LVI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}