{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-minister-dhammika-perera-wants-pm-to-resign-as-finance-minister-97012/",
  "time_ut": 1657089840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Minister Dhammika Perera wants PM to resign as Finance Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Minister Dhammika Perera wants PM to resign as Finance Minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka Prime Minister Ranil Wikcremesinghe should resign from the post of Finance Minister for delaying dollar earning avenues and for “planning for disaster”, newly sworn in ruling party MP and business tycoon Dhammika Perera said, challenging Wickremesinghe for a debate.",
        "Speaking in Colombo Wednesday July 06 morning, Perera said Wickremesinghe has no appetite to resolve Sri Lanka’s ongoing dollar crisis.",
        "“All of Sri Lanka’s economic challenges are linked to the dollar crisis. The Finance Minister plans to borrow money from friends. He has no future cashflow planning for the country,” he said, reading from a document.",
        "“The minister delayed all matters related to dollar earning, borrowing, bridging finance, avaialble credit lines and essential goods credit line. I think for these reasons the minister of finance should resign,” he said.",
        "Speaking impromptu, he told reporters that he will “not allow such things to happen to the country”.",
        "“I too will come out in support of the aragalaya. We cannot resolve the people’s problems by staying silent,” he added.",
        "Perera challenged Wickremesinghe and some 10 economists said to be advising him to come to an open debate on the latter’s handling of Sri Lanka’s economic crisis, the worst since Independence.",
        "“I will not allow this country to be dragged to a disaster from now on. I challenge him and the media to bring him out. I am ready without a script or piece of paper to do that with him,” he said.",
        "Perera’s entry to parliament has not been uncontroversial. He replaced former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa on the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) national list, after Rajapaksa resigned following months of islandwide protests demanding his resignation along with that of his older brother President Gotabaya Rajapaksa over their role in the crisis. (Colombo/Jul06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhammika Perera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Finance",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wikcremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul06/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා අමාත්‍ය ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා පවසයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - Sri Lanka ඩොලර් ඉපැයීමේ මාර්ග ප්‍රමාද කිරීම සහ \"ආපදා සඳහා සැලසුම් කිරීම\" සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව අලුතින් දිවුරුම් දුන් ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ ව්‍යාපාරික ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට විවාදයකට අභියෝග කරමින් පැවසීය.",
        "ජුලි 06 බදාදා උදෑසන කොළඹදී අදහස් දක්වමින් පෙරේරා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ඩොලර් අර්බුදය විසඳීමට වික්‍රමසිංහට කිසිදු රුචියක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම ආර්ථික අභියෝග ඩොලර් අර්බුදයට සම්බන්ධයි. මුදල් ඇමති මිතුරන්ගෙන් ණයට ගැනීමට සැලසුම් කරයි. ඔහුට රට සඳහා අනාගත මුදල් ප්‍රවාහ සැලැස්මක් නැත, ”ඔහු ලියවිල්ලකින් කියවමින් පැවසීය.",
        "“ඇමතිවරයා ඩොලර් ඉපැයීම, ණය ගැනීම, මූල්‍ය පාලම්, ලබා ගත හැකි ණය මාර්ග සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ ණය රේඛාව සම්බන්ධ සියලු කාරණා ප්‍රමාද කළේය. මම හිතන්නේ මේ හේතු නිසා මුදල් ඇමැතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි.”",
        "හදිසියේ කතා කරමින් ඔහු මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ “රටට මෙවැනි දේ සිදු වීමට ඉඩ නොදෙන” බවයි.",
        "“මමත් අරගලයට සහායට එන්නම්. අපිට නිහඬව ඉඳලා ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳන්න බැහැ.",
        "පෙරේරා වික්‍රමසිංහට අභියෝග කළ අතර නිදහසින් පසු ඇති වූ දරුණුතම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විවෘත විවාදයකට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් 10 දෙනකු පමණ ඔහුට උපදෙස් දෙන බව කීහ.",
        "“මින් ඉදිරියට මේ රට විපතකට ඇදගෙන යන්න මම ඉඩ තියන්නේ නැහැ. මම එතුමාට සහ මාධ්‍යයට අභියෝග කරනවා ඔහුව එළියට ගේන්න කියලා. ඔහු සමඟ එය කිරීමට පිටපතක් හෝ කඩදාසි කැබැල්ලක් නොමැතිව මම සූදානම්, ”ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පෙරේරාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රවේශය මතභේදාත්මක නැත. අර්බුදයේ ඔවුන්ගේ භූමිකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහුගේ වැඩිමහල් සොහොයුරු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සමඟ ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කරමින් මාස ගණනාවක් දිවයින පුරා පැවති විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ඔහු හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ වෙනුවට පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවට ඇතුළත් කළේය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මූල්ය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 06/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் நிதியமைச்சர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என இலங்கை அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, டாலர் சம்பாதிக்கும் வழிகளை தாமதப்படுத்தியதற்காகவும், \"பேரழிவைத் திட்டமிடுவதற்காகவும்\" நிதியமைச்சர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலக வேண்டும் என்று புதிதாக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்துள்ள ஆளும் கட்சி எம்.பி.யும் வர்த்தக அதிபருமான தம்மிக பெரேரா கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 06 புதன்கிழமை காலை கொழும்பில் பேசிய பெரேரா, இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய டாலர் நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு விருப்பமில்லை என்றார்.",
        "“இலங்கையின் அனைத்து பொருளாதார சவால்களும் டாலர் நெருக்கடியுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. நிதி அமைச்சர் நண்பர்களிடம் கடன் வாங்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளார். நாட்டிற்கான எதிர்கால பணப்புழக்கத் திட்டமிடல் அவரிடம் இல்லை, ”என்று அவர் ஒரு ஆவணத்திலிருந்து படித்தார்.",
        "“டலர் சம்பாதித்தல், கடன் வாங்குதல், நிதியளித்தல், கிடைக்கக்கூடிய கடன் வரிகள் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் கடன் வரி தொடர்பான அனைத்து விஷயங்களையும் அமைச்சர் தாமதப்படுத்தினார். இந்த காரணங்களுக்காக நிதியமைச்சர் ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று நான் நினைக்கிறேன், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவசரமாக பேசிய அவர், \"நாட்டில் இதுபோன்ற சம்பவங்கள் நடக்க அனுமதிக்க மாட்டோம்\" என்று செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "“நானும் அரகலயாவுக்கு ஆதரவாக வருவேன். மௌனமாக இருப்பதன் மூலம் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க முடியாது” என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பெரேரா விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு சவால் விடுத்தார், மேலும் 10 பொருளாதார வல்லுநர்கள், சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின் ஏற்பட்ட மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைக் கையாள்வது குறித்து வெளிப்படையான விவாதத்திற்கு வருமாறு அவருக்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்குவதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "“இனிமேல் இந்த நாட்டை ஒரு பேரழிவிற்கு இழுக்க நான் அனுமதிக்க மாட்டேன். அவரை வெளியே கொண்டு வருமாறு அவருக்கும் ஊடகங்களுக்கும் சவால் விடுகிறேன். அவருடன் அதைச் செய்ய ஸ்கிரிப்ட் அல்லது துண்டு காகிதம் இல்லாமல் நான் தயாராக இருக்கிறேன், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பெரேராவின் பாராளுமன்ற பிரவேசம் சர்ச்சைக்குரியதாக இல்லை. முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்சவை ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனா (SLPP) தேசிய பட்டியலில் அவர் மாற்றினார், நெருக்கடியில் அவர்களின் பங்கிற்காக அவரது மூத்த சகோதரர் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுடன் ராஜினாமா செய்யக் கோரி பல மாதங்களாக நாடு தழுவிய போராட்டங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன் ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை06/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}