{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/kanchana-says-tus-thrive-on-inefficient-members/",
  "time_ut": 1661591460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kanchana says TUs thrive on inefficient members",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kanchana says TUs thrive on inefficient members",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara slammed trade unions on Saturday (27), tweeting that they thrive on inefficient members and emphasized the importance of restructuring State owned enterprises.",
        "In a tweet, the Minister said that all SOEs need restructuring, and what led to the current downfall of the SOEs is political decisions, political appointments, misadministration and incompetence.",
        "He further pointed out that majority of the public workforce will survive in the private sector or be recruited at all, and that performance based salaries must be implemented.",
        "The Minister also called out on the inefficiency and incompetence of workers at CEB, CPC and CPSTL, and also mentioned the downsizing of the workforce.",
        "\"A good 500 workforce instead of the 4200 could do the job efficiently at CPC- CPSTL & half of the 26000 workforce at CEB,\" he tweeted.",
        "A week ago, the Minister alleged that trade unions of the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation linked to political parties are carrying out protests opposing the proposed reforms to the CPC.",
        "The Minister recently appointed a seven-member committee to restructure the Ceylon Electricity Board as well.",
        "1) All SOEs need restructuring. Political decisions, political appointments, misadministration & incompetence has led to the downfall. I don’t think majority of the public workforce will survive in the private sector or be recruited at all. Performance based salaries is a must.",
        "2) While there are capable & efficient workers at CEB, CPC & CPSTL, the majority are inefficient & incompetence. A good 500 workforce instead of the 4200 could do the job efficiently at CPC- CPSTL & half of the 26000 workforce at CEB. Trade Unions thrive on inefficient members."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPSTL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4200",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A week ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC & CPSTL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "inefficient &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4200",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාංචනා පවසන්නේ TU අකාර්යක්ෂම සාමාජිකයින් මත වර්ධනය වන බවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර සෙනසුරාදා (27) වෘත්තීය සමිතිවලට දැඩි ලෙස දෝෂාරෝපණය කරමින් ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ඔවුන් අකාර්යක්ෂම සාමාජිකයින් මත වර්ධනය වන අතර රජය සතු ව්‍යවසායන් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කරමිනි.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ සියලුම රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායයන් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමක් අවශ්‍ය බවත්, වත්මන් රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යූහයන්ගේ කඩා වැටීමට හේතු වී ඇත්තේ දේශපාලන තීරණ, දේශපාලන පත්වීම්, වැරදි පරිපාලනය සහ නොහැකියාව බවත්ය.",
        "රාජ්‍ය ශ්‍රම බලකායෙන් බහුතරයක් පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ නොනැසී පවතිනු ඇති බව හෝ කිසිසේත්ම බඳවා ගනු ඇති බවත්, කාර්ය සාධනය පදනම් කරගත් වැටුප් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතු බවත් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "CEB, CPC සහ CPSTL යන ආයතනවල කම්කරුවන්ගේ අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව සහ අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව පිළිබඳව ද අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, ශ්‍රම බලකාය අඩු කිරීම ගැන ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"4200 වෙනුවට හොඳ 500 ශ්‍රම බලකායකට CPC-CPSTL සහ ලංවිමේ 26000 ශ්‍රම බලකායෙන් අඩකට කාර්යක්‍ෂමව කාර්යය ඉටු කළ හැකිය\" යනුවෙන් ඔහු ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ යෝජිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලට එරෙහිව දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට සම්බන්ධ ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ වෘත්තීය සමිති විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරවල නිරත වන බවට අමාත්‍යවරයා සතියකට පෙර චෝදනා කළා.",
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය ද ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් සත් පුද්ගල කමිටුවක් පසුගියදා පත් කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "1) සියලුම SOEs ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම අවශ්‍ය වේ. දේශපාලන තීරණ, දේශපාලන පත්වීම්, වැරදි පරිපාලනය සහ නොහැකියාව පහත වැටීමට හේතු වී ඇත. රාජ්‍ය ශ්‍රම බලකායෙන් බහුතරයක් පුද්ගලික අංශයේ නොනැසී පවතිනු ඇතැයි හෝ කිසිසේත්ම බඳවා ගනු ඇතැයි මම නොසිතමි. කාර්ය සාධනය පදනම් කරගත් වැටුප් අනිවාර්ය වේ.",
        "2) CEB, CPC සහ CPSTL හි දක්ෂ හා කාර්යක්ෂම සේවකයින් සිටින අතර, බහුතරය අකාර්යක්ෂම සහ අකාර්යක්ෂම වේ. 4200 වෙනුවට හොඳ ශ්‍රම බලකාය 500කට CPC- CPSTL සහ ලංවිමේ 26000 ශ්‍රම බලකායෙන් අඩකට කාර්යක්‍ෂමව කාර්යය කළ හැකිය. වෘත්තීය සමිති වර්ධනය වන්නේ අකාර්යක්ෂම සාමාජිකයින් මත ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPSTL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4200",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතියකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC සහ CPSTL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අකාර්යක්ෂම සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4200",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திறமையற்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் TUக்கள் வளர்கின்றன என்கிறார் காஞ்சனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர, சனிக்கிழமை (27) தொழிற்சங்கங்களை கடுமையாக சாடினார், அவை திறமையற்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் செழித்து வளர்கின்றன என்றும் அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களை மறுசீரமைப்பதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் ஒரு ட்வீட்டில், அனைத்து SOE களுக்கும் மறுசீரமைப்பு தேவை என்றும், SOE களின் தற்போதைய வீழ்ச்சிக்கு வழிவகுத்தது அரசியல் முடிவுகள், அரசியல் நியமனங்கள், தவறான நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் திறமையின்மை.",
        "பெரும்பான்மையான அரச பணியாளர்கள் தனியார் துறையில் வாழ்வார்கள் அல்லது ஆட்சேர்ப்பு செய்யப்படுவார்கள் என்றும், செயல்திறன் அடிப்படையிலான சம்பளம் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் மேலும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "CEB, CPC மற்றும் CPSTL ஆகியவற்றில் உள்ள தொழிலாளர்களின் திறமையின்மை மற்றும் திறமையின்மை குறித்தும் அமைச்சர் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார், மேலும் பணியாளர்களின் குறைப்பு குறித்தும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"4200 க்கு பதிலாக ஒரு நல்ல 500 பணியாளர்கள் CPC- CPSTL மற்றும் CEB இல் உள்ள 26000 பணியாளர்களில் பாதி பேர் திறமையாக வேலை செய்ய முடியும்\" என்று அவர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடன் தொடர்புடையவர்கள், இ.பீ.சி.யில் முன்வைக்கப்படவுள்ள சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து போராட்டங்களை முன்னெடுத்து வருவதாக அமைச்சர் ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு முன்னர் குற்றஞ்சாட்டினார்.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையையும் மறுசீரமைப்பதற்காக அமைச்சர் அண்மையில் ஏழு பேர் கொண்ட குழுவொன்றை நியமித்தார்.",
        "1) அனைத்து SOE களுக்கும் மறுசீரமைப்பு தேவை. அரசியல் முடிவுகள், அரசியல் நியமனங்கள், தவறான நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் திறமையின்மை ஆகியவை வீழ்ச்சிக்கு வழிவகுத்தன. பெரும்பான்மையான பொதுப் பணியாளர்கள் தனியார் துறையில் உயிர்வாழ்வார்கள் அல்லது பணியமர்த்தப்படுவார்கள் என்று நான் நினைக்கவில்லை. செயல்திறன் அடிப்படையிலான சம்பளம் அவசியம்.",
        "2) CEB, CPC & CPSTL ஆகியவற்றில் திறமையான மற்றும் திறமையான தொழிலாளர்கள் இருந்தாலும், பெரும்பான்மையானவர்கள் திறமையற்ற மற்றும் திறமையற்றவர்கள். 4200க்கு பதிலாக ஒரு நல்ல 500 பணியாளர்கள் CPC- CPSTL & CEB இல் உள்ள 26000 பணியாளர்களில் பாதி பேர் திறமையாக வேலையைச் செய்ய முடியும். திறமையற்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் வளர்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPSTL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4200",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC & CPSTL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திறமையற்ற &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4200",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}