{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78467",
  "time_ut": 1657305000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Religious and Civil Society Leaders including Omalpe Sobhitha Thero and Cardinal Malcolm Ranjith Sign  “senkadagala Statement” at Queens Hotel Kandy;6 Key Demands Include Resignation of President Rajapaksa, Setting up of all Party Interim Govt and Time Frame for Fresh Parliament and President Elections",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Religious and Civil Society Leaders including Omalpe Sobhitha Thero and Cardinal Malcolm Ranjith Sign  “senkadagala Statement” at Queens Hotel Kandy;6 Key Demands Include Resignation of President Rajapaksa, Setting up of all Party Interim Govt and Time Frame for Fresh Parliament and President Elections",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "A host of multi-religious and civil society leaders yesterday signed a six-point resolution calling on the President Gotabaya Rajapaksa-led Government to step down immediately.",
        "Titled ‘Senkadagala Statement’, multi-religious and civil society leaders pledged their support to establish an all-party Government and to help Sri Lanka to seek international aid and provide relief to people suffering from the worst economic crisis in its history.",
        "The statement includes six key demands including; the President should resign unconditionally, establish an interim Government comprising all parties, and present a definite timeframe for parliamentary and presidential elections by an all-party consensus Government.",
        "The ‘Senkadagala Statement’ which was signed at the Queens Hotel, Kandy by a host of participants was then presented to the Chief Prelates of Asgiri and Malwathu Chapters collectively.",
        "Religious leaders pointed out that a clear and transparent change of Government is important to gain the trust of the international community and to seek and get aid in order to end the suffering of the people.",
        "“President Rajapaksa and his Prime Minister who was appointed via a ‘palatial conspiracy’ should resign immediately. The thousands of crowds that are coming into the street today will only scream at the President Rajapaksa-led Government to resign immediately heeding the public opinion,” Ven. Dr. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero told journalists near the memorable statue of Weera Kappetipola in Kandy, yesterday.",
        "He also said that everyone taking to the streets today is to kick out the corrupt Government. “The country needs freedom and liberation. We can no longer live divided, enslaved, and go to the streets for justice,” Ven. Sobhitha added.",
        "Archbishop of Colombo Cardinal Malcolm Ranjith also said Cardinal also said the corrupt political culture should come to an end, whilst bringing in new change to the country.",
        "“We need a new direction for this country and a future without political corruption. This Government was only concerned about securing power without any plan, by dividing people with their ethnicities and religion,” he claimed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Malcolm Ranjith Sign",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "senkadagala Statement",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "Queens Hotel Kandy;6 Key Demands",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The ‘Senkadagala Statement’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Queens Hotel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asgiri",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weera Kappetipola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malcolm Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cardinal",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි සහ කාදිනල් මැල්කම් රංජිත් හිමිපාණන් ඇතුළු ආගමික සහ සිවිල් සමාජ නායකයින් මහනුවර ක්වීන්ස් හෝටලයේදී “සෙන්කඩගල ප්‍රකාශය” අත්සන් කිරීම; 6 ප්‍රධාන ඉල්ලීම් වන්නේ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම, සියලු පක්ෂ අන්තර්වාර රජයක් සහ නැවුම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සහ ජනාධිපතිවරණ සඳහා කාල රාමුවක් සැකසීම.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ රජය වහා ඉවත් විය යුතු බවට කරුණු හයකින් යුත් යෝජනාවකට බහු ආගමික සහ සිවිල් සමාජ නායකයින් රැසක් ඊයේ අත්සන් තැබීය.",
        "‘සෙංකඩගල ප්‍රකාශය’ යන මාතෘකාව යටතේ සර්වපාක්ෂික රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර ආධාර ලබා ගැනීමට සහ ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් පෙළෙන ජනතාවට සහන සැලසීමට සහය දැක්වීමට බහු ආගමික සහ සිවිල් සමාජ නායකයින් ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්හ.",
        "ප්‍රකාශය ඇතුළු ප්‍රධාන ඉල්ලීම් හයක් ඇතුළත් වේ; ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොන්දේසි විරහිතව ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු අතර, සියලු පක්‍ෂවලින් සමන්විත අන්තර්වාර රජයක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු අතර, සර්වපාක්ෂික සම්මුතිවාදී රජයක් මගින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සහ ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා නිශ්චිත කාල රාමුවක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතුය.",
        "මහනුවර ක්වීන්ස් හෝටලයේ දී ඊට සහභාගි වූ විශාල පිරිසක් අත්සන් කළ ‘සෙංකඩගල ප්‍රකාශය’ ඉන් අනතුරුව සාමූහිකව අස්ගිරි සහ මල්වතු පාර්ශවයේ මහනාහිමිවරුන් වෙත පිළිගැන්විණි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවගේ විශ්වාසය දිනා ගැනීමටත්, ජනතාවගේ දුක්ඛිත තත්ත්වයන් නිමා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ආධාර ලබා ගැනීමටත් පැහැදිලි විනිවිදභාවයෙන් යුත් ආණ්ඩු වෙනසක් වැදගත් බව ආගමික නායකයෝ පෙන්වා දුන්හ.",
        "“රාජ්‍ය කුමන්ත්‍රණයකින්” පත්කළ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ අගමැති වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි. අද පාරට එන දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත ජනකාය මහජන මතයට අවනත වී වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ ප්‍රමුඛ රජයට කෑගසනවා පමණයි.” ආචාර්ය ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ ඊයේ මහනුවර වීර කැප්පෙටිපොළ අනුස්මරණීය පිළිරුව අසල මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් පැවසූහ.",
        "අද සියලු දෙනා පාරට බසින්නේ දූෂිත ආණ්ඩුවට පයින් ගැසීම සඳහා බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියේය. “රටට නිදහස සහ විමුක්තිය අවශ්‍යයි. අපිට තවදුරටත් බෙදිලා, වහල්ලු වෙලා, යුක්තිය වෙනුවෙන් පාරට බහින්න බැහැ.” සෝභිත වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "කොළඹ අගරදගුරු කාදිනල් මැල්කම් රංජිත් හිමිපාණන් ද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රටට නව වෙනසක් ඇති කරමින් දූෂිත දේශපාලන සංස්කෘතිය අවසන් කළ යුතු බව කාදිනල් හිමිපාණෝ ද පැවසූහ.",
        "“අපිට මේ රටට නව දිශානතියක් සහ දේශපාලන දූෂණයෙන් තොර අනාගතයක් අවශ්‍යයි. මේ ආණ්ඩුව උනන්දු වුණේ කිසිම සැලැස්මකින් තොරව, ජාතීන් හා ආගම් වශයෙන් මිනිසුන් බෙදා වෙන්කර බලය තහවුරු කර ගැනීම ගැන පමණයි.” ඔහු කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැල්කම් රංජිත් ලකුණ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සෙංකඩගල ප්‍රකාශය",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "Queens Hotel Kandy;ප්‍රධාන ඉල්ලීම් 6",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "‘සෙංකඩගල ප්‍රකාශය’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Queens හෝටලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අස්ගිරිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීර කැප්පෙටිපොල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැල්කම් රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාදිනල්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கண்டி குயின்ஸ் ஹோட்டலில் ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் மற்றும் கர்தினால் மல்கம் ரஞ்சித் உட்பட மத மற்றும் சிவில் சமூகத் தலைவர்கள் செங்கடகல அறிக்கையில் கையெழுத்திட்டனர்; 6 முக்கிய கோரிக்கைகளில் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ ராஜினாமா செய்தல், அனைத்துக் கட்சி இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தை அமைத்தல் மற்றும் புதிய பாராளுமன்றம் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலுக்கான காலக்கெடுவும் அடங்கும்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என பல மத மற்றும் சிவில் சமூக தலைவர்கள் நேற்று ஆறு அம்ச தீர்மானத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "'செங்கடகல அறிக்கை' என்ற தலைப்பில், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கும், இலங்கை வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மக்களுக்கு சர்வதேச உதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கும், நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்கும் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதற்கும் பல மதங்கள் மற்றும் சிவில் சமூகத் தலைவர்கள் உறுதியளித்தனர்.",
        "அந்த அறிக்கையில் ஆறு முக்கிய கோரிக்கைகள் அடங்கியுள்ளன; ஜனாதிபதி நிபந்தனையின்றி ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும், அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளையும் உள்ளடக்கிய ஒரு இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தை நிறுவ வேண்டும், மேலும் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளின் ஒருமித்த அரசாங்கத்தின் மூலம் பாராளுமன்ற மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்களுக்கான திட்டவட்டமான காலவரையறையை முன்வைக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "கண்டி குயின்ஸ் ஹோட்டலில் பங்குபற்றியவர்களால் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்ட ‘செங்கடகல அறிக்கை’ பின்னர் அஸ்கிரி மற்றும் மல்வத்து பீடாதிபதிகளுக்கு கூட்டாக கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் நம்பிக்கையைப் பெறுவதற்கும், மக்களின் துன்பங்களுக்கு முடிவு கட்டுவதற்கும் உதவிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கும் தெளிவான மற்றும் வெளிப்படையான ஆட்சி மாற்றம் முக்கியமானது என மதத் தலைவர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டினர்.",
        "“அரண்மனை சதி” மூலம் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சேவும் அவரது பிரதமரும் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும். இன்று வீதிக்கு வரும் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள், ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ச தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தை உடனடியாக ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று கூக்குரலிடுவார்கள். கண்டியில் அமைந்துள்ள வீர கப்பெட்டிபொலவின் சிலைக்கு அருகில் நேற்று ஊடகவியலாளர்களிடம் கலாநிதி ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று அனைவரும் வீதிக்கு வருவது ஊழலற்ற அரசை உதைப்பதற்காகவே என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். “நாட்டிற்கு சுதந்திரமும் விடுதலையும் தேவை. நாம் இனியும் பிரிந்து, அடிமைப்பட்டு, நீதிக்காக வீதியில் இறங்கி வாழ முடியாது” என்று வண. சோபித மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் புதிய மாற்றத்தை கொண்டு வரும் அதே வேளையில் ஊழல் நிறைந்த அரசியல் கலாசாரம் முடிவுக்கு வர வேண்டும் என்றும் கர்தினால் கூறியதாக கொழும்பு பேராயர் கர்தினால் மல்கம் ரஞ்சித் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“இந்த நாட்டிற்கு புதிய திசையும், அரசியல் ஊழலற்ற எதிர்காலமும் தேவை. எந்தவொரு திட்டமும் இல்லாமல், மக்களை இனம் மற்றும் மதத்தின் அடிப்படையில் பிரித்து அதிகாரத்தை பாதுகாப்பதில் மட்டுமே இந்த அரசாங்கம் அக்கறை கொண்டுள்ளது,” என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மால்கம் ரஞ்சித் அடையாளம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "செங்கடகல அறிக்கை",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "குயின்ஸ் ஹோட்டல் கண்டி;6 முக்கிய கோரிக்கைகள்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "‘செங்கடகல அறிக்கை’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "குயின்ஸ் ஹோட்டல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஸ்கிரி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீர கப்பெட்டிபொல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மால்கம் ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்டினல்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}