{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/BASL-urges-all-parties-to-respect-party-leaders-decision/155-241224",
  "time_ut": 1657977046,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "BASL urges all parties to respect party leaders’ decision",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "BASL urges all parties to respect party leaders’ decision",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) yesterday requested all parties to respect the decisions taken at the Party Leaders meeting on 9th July 2022 and to act in an expeditious manner in order to restore public confidence in the legal and Constitutional mechanisms of Sri Lanka.",
        "In a statement, the BASL stated that it is up to the Parliament to elect successor to the post of Presidency without delay in terms of the Constitution and the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981.",
        "The BASL maintained that the date fixed for this election, namely 20th July 2022, can remain unchanged, despite delays in the formal resignation of President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa,since Parliament is now convened today (16).",
        "The BASL noted the uncertainty which has prevailed in the country since the 9th of July 2022, over the resignation of the President and the appointment of the acting President under Article 37(1) of the Constitution which should have been avoided at a time when the country has been affected by social, political",
        "In electing the new President, the Members of Parliament now represent the entire electorate of Sri Lanka and must perform this onerous duty respecting the sovereignty of the People and their wishes and uphold democratic values, BASL statement added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th of July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 37(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ තීරණයට ගරු කරන ලෙස BASL සියලු පාර්ශවයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ජුලි 9 වැනි දින පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ගනු ලැබූ තීරණවලට ගරු කරන ලෙසත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නෛතික හා ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත යාන්ත්‍රණයන් පිළිබඳ මහජන විශ්වාසය යළි ඇති කිරීම සඳහා කඩිනමින් ක්‍රියා කරන ලෙසත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) සියලු පාර්ශ්වවලින් ඊයේ ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් BASL ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සහ 1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත ප්‍රකාරව ප්‍රමාදයකින් තොරව ජනාධිපති ධූරයට අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සතු බවයි.",
        "අද (16) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවා ඇති බැවින්, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිල ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රමාද වුවද, මෙම මැතිවරණය සඳහා නියම කර ඇති දිනය, එනම් 2022 ජූලි 20 වැනි දින නොවෙනස්ව පැවතිය හැකි බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා BASL පවසයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 37(1) ව්‍යවස්ථාව යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත්කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් 2022 ජූලි 9 වැනිදා සිට රට තුළ පවතින අවිනිශ්චිතභාවය BASL විසින් සටහන් කර ඇති අතර එය වළක්වා ගත යුතුව තිබුණේ රට සමාජ, දේශපාලනික වශයෙන් බලපා ඇත",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේදී, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමස්ත ඡන්ද කොට්ඨාසය නියෝජනය කරන අතර, ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යයට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන්ට ගරු කරමින් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වටිනාකම් ආරක්ෂා කරමින් මෙම භාරදූර යුතුකම ඉටු කළ යුතු බව BASL නිවේදනය වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථානුකූලයි",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 37(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் முடிவை மதிக்குமாறு அனைத்து தரப்பினரையும் BASL கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானங்களுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து, இலங்கையின் சட்ட மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு பொறிமுறைகள் மீதான பொதுமக்களின் நம்பிக்கையை மீட்டெடுக்க துரிதமான முறையில் செயற்படுமாறு இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) நேற்று அனைத்து தரப்பினரையும் கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு மற்றும் 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் அடிப்படையில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு வாரிசை தாமதமின்றி தெரிவு செய்வது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பொறுப்பாகும் என்று BASL ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இராஜினாமாவில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்ட போதிலும், நாடாளுமன்றம் இன்று (16) கூட்டப்பட்டதால், இந்தத் தேர்தலுக்கு நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட தேதி, அதாவது 2022 ஜூலை 20, மாறாமல் இருக்க முடியும் என்று BASL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 37(1) பிரிவின் கீழ் ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமா மற்றும் செயற்பாட்டு ஜனாதிபதியின் நியமனம் தொடர்பாக 2022 ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி முதல் நாட்டில் நிலவும் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மையை BASL குறிப்பிட்டது. நாடு சமூக, அரசியல் ரீதியாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதில், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தற்போது இலங்கையின் முழு வாக்காளர்களையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகின்றனர் மற்றும் மக்களின் இறையாண்மை மற்றும் அவர்களின் விருப்பங்களுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து ஜனநாயக விழுமியங்களை நிலைநிறுத்தி இந்த பாரிய கடமையை செய்ய வேண்டும் என BASL அறிக்கை மேலும் கூறியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 37(1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}