{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/28/chinese-ambassador-violated-diplomatic-etiquette-indian-hc/",
  "time_ut": 1661692020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese Ambassador violated diplomatic etiquette: Indian HC",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese Ambassador violated diplomatic etiquette: Indian HC",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); High Commission of India in Sri Lanka Tweeted that Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Qi Zenghong has \"violated  basic diplomatic etiquette, which may be a personal trait or reflecting a larger national attitude\".",
        "The Indian High Commission stated that the Chinese ambassador's view of Sri Lanka's northern neighbour may be coloured by how his own country behaves.",
        "The High Commission tweeted, \"His imputing a geopolitical context to the visit of a purported scientific research vessel is a giveaway.\"",
        "Pointing out that opaqueness and debt driven agendas are now a major challenge, especially for smaller nations, the High Commission stated that the recent developments are a caution.",
        "The Commission added, \"Sri Lanka needs support, not unwanted pressure or unnecessary controversies to serve another country’s agenda.\"",
        "India’s response came a day after Chinese Ambassador Qi Zhenhong wrote an article titled: “From One-China Principle to Yuan Wang 5: Let’s Join Hands and Resolutely Safeguard Our Sovereignty, Independence and Territorial Integrity”.",
        "In it, he referred to countries “far or near bullying Sri Lanka”.",
        "The Ambassador also said that Sri Lanka overcame “aggression from its northern neighbour 17 times”.",
        "The Ambassador also referred that the “successful” docking of Chinese satellite-tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 in the Hambantota port, and argued for China and Sri Lanka “jointly safeguarding each other’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity”."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "High Commission of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tweeted",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zenghong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන තානාපති රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආචාර විධි කඩ කළා: ඉන්දීය මහාධිකරණය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ට්වීට් කර ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zenghong \"මූලික රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආචාර විධි උල්ලංඝනය කර ඇති අතර එය පුද්ගලික ලක්ෂණයක් විය හැකි හෝ විශාල ජාතික ආකල්පයක් පිළිබිඹු කරන\" බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උතුරු අසල්වැසියා පිළිබඳ චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ අදහස ඔහුගේම රට හැසිරෙන ආකාරය අනුව වර්ණවත් විය හැකි බව ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, \"ඔහු විසින් කියනු ලබන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක සංචාරයට භූ දේශපාලනික සන්දර්භයක් ආරෝපණය කිරීම දීමනාවකි.\"",
        "පාරාන්ධභාවය සහ ණය මත පදනම් වූ න්‍යාය පත්‍ර දැන් ප්‍රධාන අභියෝගයක් බව පෙන්වා දෙන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, විශේෂයෙන් කුඩා ජාතීන්ට ප්‍රධාන අභියෝගයක් වී ඇති බව පෙන්වා දෙන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේ මෑත කාලීන වර්ධනයන් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් බවයි.",
        "\"වෙනත් රටක න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට සේවය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය අවශ්‍ය මිස අනවශ්‍ය බලපෑම් හෝ අනවශ්‍ය මතභේද නොවේ\" යනුවෙන් කොමිසම වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ප්‍රතිචාරය පැමිණියේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong විසින් ලිපියක් ලිවීමෙන් දිනකට පසුව ය: “එක්-චීන මූලධර්මයේ සිට යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 දක්වා: අත්වැල් බැඳගනිමු සහ අපගේ ස්වෛරීභාවය, ස්වාධීනත්වය සහ භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාව අධිෂ්ඨානශීලීව සුරකිමු”.",
        "එහි ඔහු \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හිරිහැර කරන දුර හෝ ආසන්න\" රටවල් ගැන සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව \"උතුරේ අසල්වැසියාගේ ආක්‍රමණ 17 වතාවක්\" ජයගත් බව ද තානාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "චීන චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 හම්බන්තොට වරායේ “සාර්ථක” නැව්ගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව ද සඳහන් කළ තානාපතිවරයා, චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “එකිනෙකාගේ ස්වෛරීභාවය, ස්වාධීනත්වය සහ භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාව ඒකාබද්ධව ආරක්ෂා කිරීම” සඳහා තර්ක කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාවේ මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ට්වීට් කළේය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zenghong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன தூதர் ராஜதந்திர நெறிமுறைகளை மீறியதாக இந்திய உயர்நீதிமன்றம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zenghong \"அடிப்படை இராஜதந்திர நெறிமுறைகளை மீறியுள்ளார், இது தனிப்பட்ட பண்பாக இருக்கலாம் அல்லது ஒரு பெரிய தேசிய அணுகுமுறையை பிரதிபலிக்கும்\" என்று இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் வடக்கு அண்டை நாடு குறித்த சீனத் தூதுவரின் பார்வை அவரது சொந்த நாடு எவ்வாறு நடந்து கொள்கிறது என்பதன் வண்ணமாக இருக்கலாம் என இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ட்வீட் செய்தது, \"அவர் கூறப்படும் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலின் வருகைக்கு ஒரு புவிசார் அரசியல் சூழலைக் குறிப்பிடுவது ஒரு பரிசு.\"",
        "ஒளிவுமறைவு மற்றும் கடன் உந்துதல் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரல்களும், குறிப்பாக சிறிய நாடுகளுக்கு இப்போது பெரும் சவாலாக இருப்பதைச் சுட்டிக்காட்டிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்கள் எச்சரிக்கையாக இருப்பதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டது.",
        "மற்றொரு நாட்டின் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலுக்கு சேவை செய்ய இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவு தேவை, தேவையற்ற அழுத்தங்கள் அல்லது தேவையற்ற சர்ச்சைகள் அல்ல” என ஆணைக்குழு மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சீனத் தூதர் குய் ஜென்ஹாங் எழுதிய ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு இந்தியாவின் பதில் வந்தது: \"ஒரு-சீனா கொள்கையிலிருந்து யுவான் வாங் 5 வரை: கைகோர்ப்போம், நமது இறையாண்மை, சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் பிராந்திய ஒருமைப்பாட்டை உறுதியாகப் பாதுகாப்போம்\".",
        "அதில், \"இலங்கையை மிரட்டும் தூரத்தில் அல்லது அருகில் உள்ள நாடுகளை\" குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை தனது வடக்கு அண்டை நாடுகளின் ஆக்கிரமிப்பை 17 தடவைகள் முறியடித்துள்ளதாகவும் தூதுவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் சீன செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 \"வெற்றிகரமாக\" இணைக்கப்பட்டதையும் தூதுவர் குறிப்பிட்டார், மேலும் சீனாவும் இலங்கையும் \"ஒருவருக்கொருவரின் இறையாண்மை, சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் பிராந்திய ஒருமைப்பாட்டைக் கூட்டாகப் பாதுகாத்தல்\" என்று வாதிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளது",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zenghong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}