{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/30/urea-fertilizer-for-all-rice-farmers/",
  "time_ut": 1656562800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Urea fertilizer for all rice farmers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Urea fertilizer for all rice farmers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Agriculture has decided to provide Urea fertilizer to all the farmers who cultivated paddy this year.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture Mahinda Amaraweera has instructed the officials to take steps to provide the Urea fertilizer given by the Indian Government to all the farmers who cultivated paddy.",
        "The Minister has also highlighted that if the farmers who cultivated paddy on the advice of the Department of Agriculture are facing any difficulties, it is the Government’s responsibility to help the relevant farmers.",
        "Therefore, the Minister has instructed the officials to look into the possibility of providing fertilizer to the farmers if they need it, although the harvest has already been reaped.",
        "The Minister has further instructed to take steps to distribute urea fertilizer provided by the Government of India at the rate of 100kg per hectare.",
        "Quick Passports for Foreign Employment: Dhammika makes first move as Minister"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Urea",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Urea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Quick Passports for Foreign Employment: Dhammika",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සියලුම වී ගොවීන්ට යූරියා පොහොර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මෙවර වී වගා කළ සියලුම ගොවීන්ට යූරියා පොහොර ලබාදීමට කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "වී වගා කළ සියලුම ගොවීන් වෙත ඉන්දීය රජය ලබාදෙන යූරියා පොහොර ලබාදීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් ලබාදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ උපදෙස් මත වී වගා කළ ගොවීන් යම් දුෂ්කරතාවකට පත්වුවහොත් අදාළ ගොවීන්ට උපකාර කිරීම රජයේ වගකීමක් බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා අවධාරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "එබැවින් ගොවීන්ට අවශ්‍ය නම් පොහොර ලබාදීමේ හැකියාව සොයා බලන ලෙස අමාත්‍යවරයා නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් ලබාදී ඇති අතර, මේ වන විටත් අස්වැන්න නෙළා අවසන්ය.",
        "ඉන්දීය රජය මඟින් ලබාදෙන යූරියා පොහොර හෙක්ටයාරයකට කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 100 බැගින් බෙදා හැරීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ද අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් උපදෙස් දී ඇත.",
        "විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා ඉක්මන් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර: ධම්මික ඇමතිවරයා ලෙස පළමු පියවර ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යූරියා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යූරියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා ඉක්මන් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර: ධම්මික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்து நெல் விவசாயிகளுக்கும் யூரியா உரம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இந்த வருடம் நெற்செய்கை செய்த அனைத்து விவசாயிகளுக்கும் யூரியா உரத்தை வழங்க விவசாய அமைச்சு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தினால் வழங்கப்படும் யூரியா உரத்தை நெல் பயிரிட்ட அனைத்து விவசாயிகளுக்கும் வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "விவசாயத் திணைக்களத்தின் ஆலோசனையின் பேரில் நெல் பயிரிட்ட விவசாயிகள் ஏதேனும் சிரமங்களை எதிர்கொண்டால், உரிய விவசாயிகளுக்கு உதவுவது அரசாங்கத்தின் பொறுப்பாகும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "எனவே, ஏற்கனவே அறுவடை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும், விவசாயிகளுக்கு உரம் தேவைப்படின் அவற்றை வழங்குவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராயுமாறு அமைச்சர் அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தினால் வழங்கப்படும் யூரியா உரத்தை ஹெக்டேருக்கு 100 கிலோ வீதம் விநியோகிக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு அமைச்சர் மேலும் பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்புக்கான விரைவான கடவுச்சீட்டுகள்: அமைச்சராக தம்மிக்க முதல் நகர்வை மேற்கொண்டார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யூரியா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்புக்கான விரைவான கடவுச்சீட்டுகள்: தம்மிக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}