{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පොහොර-යෙදීම-ගැන-බතලගොඩ-පර්යේෂණ-සාර්ථකයි/1-618669",
  "time_ut": 1661322970,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොර යෙදීම ගැන බතලගොඩ පර්යේෂණ සාර්ථකයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Batalagoda research on fertilizer application is successful",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dr. Ajantha de Silva, Director General of the Department of Agriculture, said that the research conducted by the Batalagoda Paddy Research Institute of applying 70 percent and 30 percent chemical fertilizers and organic fertilizers for paddy cultivation was successful.",
        "The Batalagoda Paddy Research Institute conducted this research regarding the application of 70 percent chemical fertilizers and 30 percent organic fertilizers to paddy cultivation in the upcoming season.",
        "According to the Ministry of Agriculture, the entire cultivation process collapsed due to the use of 100% organic fertilizers and liquid fertilizers and the paddy yield fell by 40 percent in the high season of that year."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajantha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Batalagoda Paddy Research Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Batalagoda Paddy Research Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the upcoming season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the high season of that year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොර යෙදීම ගැන බතලගොඩ පර්යේෂණ සාර්ථකයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වී වගාව සඳහා සියයට 70 සහ සියයට 30 ප්‍රතිශතයට රසායනික පොහොර හා කාබනික පොහොර යෙදීමේ බතලගොඩ වී පර්යේෂණායතනය මගින් සිදු කළ පර්යේෂණ  සාර්ථක බව කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ආචාර්ය අජන්ත ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එළඹෙන මහ කන්නයේ දී  වී වගාවට සියයට 70ක් රසායනික පොහොර හා සියයට 30ක් කාබනික  පොහොර යෙදීම සම්බන්ධව බතලගොඩ වී පර්යේෂණායතනය මෙම පර්යේෂණ කළේය.",
        "100% කාබනික පොහොර හා දියර පොහොර යොදාගනිමින් වගා කිරීමට යාම නිසා සමස්ත වගා ක්‍රියාවලිය කඩා වැටුණු බවත් එම වසරේ මහ කන්නයේ  වී අස්වැන්න සියයට 40කින් පහත වැටුණු බවත් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අජන්තා ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බතලගොඩ වී පර්යේෂණ ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 30 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බතලගොඩ වී පර්යේෂණ ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 30 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 40 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම වසරේ ඉහළ සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உரமிடுதல் குறித்த பட்டலகொட ஆராய்ச்சி வெற்றியடைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெற்செய்கைக்கு 70 வீதம் மற்றும் 30 வீதம் இரசாயன உரங்கள் மற்றும் கரிம உரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி படலகொட நெல் ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம் நடத்திய ஆராய்ச்சி வெற்றியடைந்துள்ளதாக விவசாய திணைக்கள பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் கலாநிதி அஜந்த டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் பருவத்தில் நெற்செய்கைக்கு 70 வீத இரசாயன உரங்களையும் 30 வீத இயற்கை உரங்களையும் இடுவது தொடர்பில் படலகொட நெல் ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம் இந்த ஆய்வை மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "விவசாய அமைச்சின் கூற்றுப்படி, 100% கரிம உரங்கள் மற்றும் திரவ உரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தியதால் முழு சாகுபடி செயல்முறையும் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தது மற்றும் அந்த ஆண்டின் உயர் பருவத்தில் நெல் விளைச்சல் 40 சதவீதம் குறைந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜந்த டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "படலகொட நெல் ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "படலகொட நெல் ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரவிருக்கும் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த ஆண்டின் உயர் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}