{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Avoid-violence-and-act-with-restraint-Religious-leaders/342-240992",
  "time_ut": 1657702679,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Avoid violence and act with restraint: Religious leaders",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Avoid violence and act with restraint: Religious leaders",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The religious leaders appealed to the nation today not to resort to violence and act with restraint.",
        "Respected Buddhist Priest Ven. Omalpe Sobitha Thera appealed to the people to remain calm and said President Gotabaya Rajapaksa should announce his resignation as promised.",
        "The Archbishop of Colombo, His Eminence Cardinal Malcolm Ranjith also appealed for calm, saying Sri Lanka is staring at the danger of foreign intervention,\" Foreign intervention should be avoided at any cost. There is no need for the people to come to Colombo. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobitha Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malcolm Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයෙන් වැළකී සංයමයෙන් ක්‍රියා කරන්න: ආගමික නායකයින්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවලින් වළකින ලෙසත් සංයමයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙසත් ආගමික නායකයෝ අද ජාතියෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියහ.",
        "ගෞරවණීය බෞද්ධ පුජ්‍ය හිමි සන්සුන්ව සිටින ලෙස ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කළ යුතු බව ද ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "කොළඹ අගරදගුරු අතිඋතුම් මැල්කම් රංජිත් කාදිනල් හිමිපාණන් ද සන්සුන්ව සිටින ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විදේශ මැදිහත්වීමේ අනතුර දෙස බලා සිටින බව පවසමින්, විදේශ මැදිහත්වීම් කුමන ආකාරයකින් හෝ වළක්වා ගත යුතුය. ජනතාවට කොළඹට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය නැත. ( යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැල්කම් රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வன்முறையைத் தவிர்த்து, நிதானத்துடன் செயல்படுங்கள்: மதத் தலைவர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட வேண்டாம் மற்றும் நிதானத்துடன் செயற்படுமாறு மதத் தலைவர்கள் இன்று நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மதிப்பிற்குரிய பௌத்த மதகுரு வண. அமைதி காக்குமாறு மக்களிடம் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்த ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ வாக்குறுதியளித்தபடி தனது பதவி விலகலை அறிவிக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு பேராயர் மேதகு கர்தினால் மல்கம் ரஞ்சித் அவர்கள், இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டுத் தலையீட்டின் ஆபத்தை உற்று நோக்குவதாகக் கூறி, \"வெளிநாட்டுத் தலையீடுகள் எவ்வகையிலும் தவிர்க்கப்பட வேண்டும். மக்கள் கொழும்புக்கு வரத் தேவையில்லை. யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மால்கம் ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}