{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රට-පනින්න-ගිය-47ක්-අල්ලයි/101-617367",
  "time_ut": 1659333523,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රට පනින්න ගිය 47ක් අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The country catches 47 who went to jump",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Navy says that 47 people suspected of trying to illegally migrate to a foreign country by sea were arrested.",
        "Based on information received from the Sri Lanka Navy, the Wennappuwa police conducted a special search operation in Hawennappuwa city, and these suspects were arrested while observing and inspecting 03 suspicious vans.",
        "Among these people, 47 people including 37 men over 18 years of age, 06 women and 04 under 18 years of age have been arrested.",
        "These people were identified as residents of Jaffna, Vavuniya, Trincomalee, Kalmune, Batticaloa, Puttalam, Halawatha, Marawila, Mahawewa, Mundalama and Wellawatta, and the group was handed over to Wennappuwa Police for further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 under 18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna, Vavuniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalmune, Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahawewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mundalama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රට පනින්න ගිය 47ක් අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයන් 47 දෙනකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව නාවික හමුදාව කියයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවට ලද තොරතුරක් මත  වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය හාවෙන්නප්පුව නගරයේ සිදුකළ මෙම විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමේදි සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථ 03 ක් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කර පරීක්‍ෂාවට ලක් කිරීමේදී මෙම සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම පුද්ගලයන් අතර වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි පිරිමි පුද්ගලයන් 37 ක්, කාත්තාවන් 06 ක් සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු 04 ක් ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයන් 47 දෙනකු  අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම  පිරිස යාපනය, වව්නියාව, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, කල්මුනේ, මඩකලපුව, පුත්තලම, හලාවත, මාරවිල, මහවැව, මුන්දලම සහ වැල්ලවත්ත යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හී පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනා ගන්නා ලද අතර, එම පිරිස ඉදිරි විමර්ශන කටයුතු සඳහා වෙන්නප්පුව පොලීසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු 04 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය, වවුනියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ, මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහවැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුන්දලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குதிக்க சென்ற 47 பேரை நாடு பிடிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு செல்ல முயற்சித்த 47 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸார் ஹவென்னப்புவ நகரில் விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டதுடன், சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான 03 வான்களை அவதானித்து சோதனையிட்ட போதே இவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இவர்களில் 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட ஆண்கள் 37 பேர், பெண்கள் 06 பேர் மற்றும் 18 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட 04 பேர் உட்பட 47 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் யாழ்ப்பாணம், வவுனியா, திருகோணமலை, கல்முனை, மட்டக்களப்பு, புத்தளம், ஹலவத்தை, மாரவில, மஹவெவ, முந்தலம மற்றும் வெள்ளவத்தை ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டு, மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயதுக்கு உட்பட்ட 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம், வவுனியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை, மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாவெவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முண்டலமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}