{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-boi-targets-one-billion-dollars-in-fdi-for-2022-99210/",
  "time_ut": 1661918460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s BOI targets one billion dollars in FDI for 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s BOI targets one billion dollars in FDI for 2022",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Despite an ongoing economic crisis Sri Lanka Investments Promotion agency, Board of Investments said one billion US dollars in realized investments are expected in the year, with first six months running slightly ahead of target, an official said.",
        "“During the first half the target for the first six months was around 400 million US dollars however, we were able to attract investments around 520 million US dollars,” Director General of the Board of Invetment of Sri Lanka Renuka Weerakone told EconomyNext.",
        "BOI also expects to have 2.2 billion US dollars’ worth of approved projects for 2022 and so far around one billion projects have been approved by the BOI, Weerakone said.",
        "“I believe we are in track to achieve those targets that will in return create the environment for other investments to come in.”",
        "The BOI is taking measures to streamline the process and facilities of the country for the convenience of the investors also expects to acquire 225 acres of land with proceedings done, for the investors to set up their projects, she said.",
        "“…[The] overall target of the BOI is contributing towards the Economic growth of the country, attracting FDI and creating employment opportunities as increasing the exports revenue and developing readymade land plots for the investors to be able to invest in their projects,” Weerakone said at the launch of the Sri Lanka SDG map for Inventors in Colombo.",
        "“The BOI has 14 export processing zones, and on top of that we are planning this because of the demand and in order to make it easier for the investors.”",
        "Exports oriented manufacturing, import substitution, high-tech modernize agriculture and integrated waste management are few of the sectors BOI is targeting to get investments and hopes to take the investments outside the Western province creating more employment opportunities for rural areas as well.",
        "“We also targeting increase our export revenue to 9.2 billion rupees from 8 billion last years. We have seen a growth in exports,” (Colombo/Aug 1/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "BOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "one billion dollars",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "FDI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Investments Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Board of Investments",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 400 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 520 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Invetment of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225 acres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9.2 billion rupees",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "last years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය 2022 සඳහා ඩොලර් බිලියනයක එෆ්ඩීඅයි ඉලක්ක කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන නියෝජිතායතනය, ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය පැවසුවේ, පළමු මාස ​​හය ඉලක්කයට වඩා මඳක් ඉදිරියෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන අතර, වසර තුළ ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියනයක සාක්ෂාත් කර ගත් ආයෝජන අපේක්ෂා කරන බව, නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "\"පළමු මාස ​​හය තුළ ඉලක්කය ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 ක් පමණ වූ නමුත් ඩොලර් මිලියන 520 ක පමණ ආයෝජන ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට අපට හැකි වුණා\" යැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් රේණුකා වීරකෝන් EconomyNext වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "2022 සඳහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.2 ක අනුමත ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර මේ වන විට ව්‍යාපෘති බිලියනයක් පමණ ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇති බව වීරකෝන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"මම විශ්වාස කරනවා අපි එම ඉලක්ක සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර එමඟින් වෙනත් ආයෝජන පැමිණීම සඳහා පරිසරය නිර්මාණය වනු ඇත.\"",
        "ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය ආයෝජකයින්ගේ පහසුව සඳහා රටේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සහ පහසුකම් විධිමත් කිරීමට පියවර ගනිමින් සිටින අතර, ආයෝජකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ව්‍යාපෘති පිහිටුවීම සඳහා අක්කර 225 ක භූමි ප්‍රමාණයක් අත්පත් කර ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"... ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලයේ සමස්ත ඉලක්කය වන්නේ රටේ ආර්ථික වර්ධනයට දායක වීම, විදේශ සෘජු ආයෝජන ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීම සහ අපනයන ආදායම වැඩි කිරීම සහ ආයෝජකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජනය කිරීමට හැකි වන පරිදි සූදානම් කළ ඉඩම් කට්ටි සංවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා රැකියා අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය කිරීම,\" වීරකෝන් කොළඹදී නව නිපැයුම්කරුවන් සඳහා වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා SDG සිතියම එළිදැක්වීමේ උත්සවයේදී පැවසීය.",
        "\"BOI සතුව අපනයන සැකසුම් කලාප 14 ක් ඇති අතර, ඊට ඉහළින් අපි මෙය සැලසුම් කරන්නේ ඉල්ලුම නිසා සහ ආයෝජකයින්ට පහසු කිරීම සඳහා ය.\"",
        "අපනයනය ඉලක්ක කරගත් නිෂ්පාදනය, ආනයන ආදේශනය, අධි තාක්‍ෂණික නවීකරණය කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය සහ ඒකාබද්ධ අපද්‍රව්‍ය කළමනාකරණය යන අංශවලින් කිහිපයක් ආයෝජන ලබා ගැනීමට ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය ඉලක්ක කරන අතර ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රදේශවලට වැඩි රැකියා අවස්ථා උදාකරමින් ආයෝජන බස්නාහිර පළාතෙන් බැහැරට ගෙන යාමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "“අපගේ අපනයන ආදායම පසුගිය වසරවල බිලියන 8 සිට රුපියල් බිලියන 9.2 දක්වා වැඩි කර ගැනීමටත් අපි ඉලක්ක කරනවා. අපි අපනයනවල වර්ධනයක් දැක තිබෙනවා” (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 1/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "BOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියනයක්",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "එෆ්ඩීඅයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියනයක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු මාස ​​හය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 520 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කර 225 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ඩීඅයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 9.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் BOI 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான அந்நிய நேரடி முதலீட்டில் ஒரு பில்லியன் டாலர்களை இலக்காகக் கொண்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு நிறுவனம், பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள போதிலும், முதலீட்டுச் சபையானது, இந்த வருடத்தில் ஒரு பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் முதலீடுகள் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும், முதல் ஆறு மாதங்கள் இலக்கை விட சற்று முன்னதாகவே இயங்கும் என்றும், அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“முதல் பாதியில் முதல் ஆறு மாதங்களுக்கான இலக்கு சுமார் 400 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களாக இருந்த போதிலும், சுமார் 520 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை முதலீடுகளை ஈர்க்க முடிந்தது” என இலங்கை முதலீட்டுச் சபையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் ரேணுகா வீரகோன் EconomyNext இடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "BOI 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான 2.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மதிப்பிலான திட்டங்களுக்கு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது என்றும் இதுவரை சுமார் ஒரு பில்லியன் திட்டங்கள் BOI ஆல் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன என்றும் வீரகோன் கூறினார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் அந்த இலக்குகளை அடைவதற்கான பாதையில் இருக்கிறோம் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன், அது மற்ற முதலீடுகள் வருவதற்கான சூழலை உருவாக்கும்.\"",
        "முதலீட்டாளர்களின் வசதிக்காக நாட்டின் செயல்முறை மற்றும் வசதிகளை சீரமைக்க BOI நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருகிறது, மேலும் முதலீட்டாளர்கள் தங்கள் திட்டங்களை அமைப்பதற்காக 225 ஏக்கர் நிலத்தை கையகப்படுத்த எதிர்பார்க்கிறது.",
        "முதலீட்டாளர்கள் தங்கள் திட்டங்களில் முதலீடு செய்யக்கூடிய வகையில், ஏற்றுமதி வருவாயை அதிகரிப்பது மற்றும் ஆயத்த நிலங்களை உருவாக்குவது போன்றவற்றின் மூலம், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்களிப்பது, அந்நிய நேரடி முதலீட்டை ஈர்ப்பது மற்றும் வேலை வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்குவது ஆகியவை BOI யின் ஒட்டுமொத்த இலக்கு ஆகும்,\" வீரகோன் கொழும்பில் கண்டுபிடிப்பாளர்களுக்கான இலங்கை SDG வரைபடத்தின் வெளியீட்டு விழாவில் கூறினார்.",
        "\"BOI க்கு 14 ஏற்றுமதி செயலாக்க மண்டலங்கள் உள்ளன, மேலும் தேவை மற்றும் முதலீட்டாளர்களுக்கு எளிதாக்கும் வகையில் நாங்கள் இதைத் திட்டமிடுகிறோம்.\"",
        "ஏற்றுமதி சார்ந்த உற்பத்தி, இறக்குமதி மாற்றீடு, உயர் தொழில்நுட்ப நவீனமயமாக்கல் விவசாயம் மற்றும் ஒருங்கிணைந்த கழிவு மேலாண்மை ஆகியவை முதலீடுகளைப் பெறுவதற்கு BOI இலக்காகக் கொண்ட சில துறைகளாகும், மேலும் கிராமப்புறங்களுக்கும் அதிக வேலை வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்கும் வகையில் முதலீடுகளை மேற்கு மாகாணத்திற்கு வெளியே கொண்டு செல்ல நம்புகிறது.",
        "“எங்கள் ஏற்றுமதி வருவாயை கடந்த வருடங்களில் 8 பில்லியனில் இருந்து 9.2 பில்லியன் ரூபாவாக அதிகரிக்க இலக்கு வைத்துள்ளோம். ஏற்றுமதியில் வளர்ச்சியை நாங்கள் கண்டுள்ளோம்” (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட் 1/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "BOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "FDI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 400 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 520 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை முதலீட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225 ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9.2 பில்லியன் ரூபாய்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}