{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Opposition-Leader-Sajith-Premadasa-withdraws-from-Presidential-nomination/342-241365",
  "time_ut": 1658205414,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa withdraws from Presidential nomination",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa withdraws from Presidential nomination",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa has decided to withdraw his presidential nomination and the SJB will support SLPP MP Dullas Allahapperuma in the Presidential election in Parliament tomorrow.",
        "\"For the greater good of my country that I love and the people I cherish I hereby withdraw my candidacy for the position of President. SJB Sri Lanka and our alliance and our opposition partners will work hard towards making Dullas Allahapperuma victorious,\" Premadasa said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Allahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Allahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වයෙන් ඉවත් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සිය ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කර ඇති අතර SJB හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහය පළ කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "\"මම ආදරය කරන මගේ රටේ සහ මා ආදරය කරන ජනතාවගේ යහපත වෙනුවෙන් මම මගේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය මෙයින් ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගනිමි. SJB ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහ අපගේ සන්ධානය සහ අපගේ විපක්ෂයේ හවුල්කරුවන් ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට දැඩි උත්සාහයක් දරනු ඇත,\" ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஜனாதிபதி வேட்புமனுவிலிருந்து விலகியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது ஜனாதிபதி வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெறத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதுடன், ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அலகப்பெருமவுக்கு SJB ஆதரவளிக்கும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"நான் நேசிக்கும் எனது நாட்டிற்கும், நான் நேசிக்கும் மக்களின் நலனுக்காகவும் நான் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான எனது வேட்புமனுவை இதிலிருந்து விலக்கிக் கொள்கிறேன். எஸ்.ஜே.பி ஸ்ரீலங்காவும் எங்கள் கூட்டணியும் எங்கள் எதிர்க்கட்சி பங்காளிகளும் டலஸ் அலகப்பெருமாவை வெற்றிபெறச் செய்ய கடுமையாக உழைக்கும்\" என்று பிரேமதாச கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அலகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அலகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}