{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/12/three-fuel-shipments-due-soon/",
  "time_ut": 1657599900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three fuel shipments due soon",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three fuel shipments due soon",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Three fuel shipments are to reach Sri Lankan shores soon.",
        "Sri Lanka’s Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekra updated the delivery of fuel to Sri Lanka on Twitter.",
        "He said on Friday, full payments were made with the assistance of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, Ministry of Finance to Lanka IOC for a Diesel Cargo to arrive between the 15th & 17th of July, and for Petrol Cargo for 22nd to 24th July.",
        "The Minister said that advance payments were made last week for a Diesel cargo to arrive 15th to 17th July & Petrol Cargo for 17th to 19th July. The Minister said that the balance payment is to be made today (11) for the Diesel.",
        "He said that the the balance payment for the petrol to arrive between 17th to 19th July will have to be paid on Tuesday the 12th.",
        "The Minister said that three further cargo will arrive in Colombo on the following dates:",
        "He said the payments for the above three cargo will be made upon arrival.",
        "The Minister said that the cargo scheduled to arrive on the 9th was delayed due to weather conditions & could not be loaded on time & the supplier has communicated the departure from India this morning.",
        "The new Laycan has been given as 12th-15th July, said the Minister adding that all dates are given by the suppliers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between the 15th & 17th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol Cargo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd to 24th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th to 17th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol Cargo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th to 19th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 17th to 19th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Laycan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12th-15th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන තොග තුනක් ළඟදීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් තුනක් ළඟදීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළට ළඟා වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර ට්විටර් ඔස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම යාවත්කාලීන කළේය.",
        "ජූලි 15 සහ 17 අතර ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩයක් පැමිණීමට සහ ජූලි 22 සිට 24 දක්වා පෙට්‍රල් භාණ්ඩ සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලංකා IOC වෙත සම්පූර්ණ ගෙවීම් සිදු කළ බව ඔහු සිකුරාදා පැවසීය.",
        "ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩයක් ජූලි 15 සිට 17 දක්වා පැමිණීමට සහ පෙට්‍රල් භාණ්ඩ ජූලි 17 සිට 19 දක්වා පැමිණීම සඳහා පසුගිය සතියේ අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවා ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. ඩීසල් සඳහා ඉතිරි මුදල් ගෙවීම අද (11) සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ජුලි 17 සිට 19 දක්වා කාලය තුළ පෙට්‍රල් පැමිණීමට ඇති ඉතිරි මුදල 12 අඟහරුවාදා ගෙවිය යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පහත සඳහන් දිනවලදී තවත් භාණ්ඩ තුනක් කොළඹට පැමිණෙන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉහත භාණ්ඩ තුන සඳහා ගෙවීම් පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ගෙවන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "9 වැනිදා පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ භාණ්ඩ කාලගුණික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රමාද වූ බවත් නියමිත වේලාවට පැටවීමට නොහැකි වූ බවත් සැපයුම්කරු අද උදෑසන ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත්ව යන බව දන්වා ඇති බවත් ඇමැතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "නව ලේකන් රථය ජූලි 12 සිට 15 දක්වා ලබා දී ඇති බවත්, සියලු දිනයන් සැපයුම්කරුවන් විසින් ලබා දෙන බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචනා විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15 සහ 17 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල් බඩු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22 සිට 24 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15 සිට 17 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල් බඩු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 17 සිට 19 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 17 සිට 19 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மூன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி விரைவில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மூன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி விரைவில் இலங்கைக் கரையை வந்தடைய உள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர ட்விட்டரில் இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை புதுப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 15 மற்றும் 17 க்கு இடையில் டீசல் சரக்கு வருவதற்கும், ஜூலை 22 முதல் 24 வரையிலான பெட்ரோல் சரக்குகளுக்கு இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி, நிதி அமைச்சகம், லங்கா ஐஓசி ஆகியவற்றின் உதவியுடன் முழுப் பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது என்றும் அவர் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "டீசல் சரக்கு ஜூலை 15 முதல் 17 வரை வருவதற்கும், பெட்ரோல் சரக்கு ஜூலை 17 முதல் 19 வரை வருவதற்கும் கடந்த வாரம் முன்பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார். டீசலுக்கான மீதிப்பணம் இன்று (11) செலுத்தப்பட உள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 17 முதல் 19ம் தேதி வரை பெட்ரோல் வருவதற்கான நிலுவைத் தொகையை 12ம் தேதி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை செலுத்த வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "மேலும் மூன்று சரக்குகள் பின்வரும் தேதிகளில் கொழும்பை வந்தடையும் என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட மூன்று சரக்குகளுக்கான கட்டணம் வந்தவுடன் வழங்கப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "9 ஆம் திகதி வரவிருந்த சரக்கு காலநிலை காரணமாக தாமதமானதாகவும், சரியான நேரத்தில் ஏற்ற முடியவில்லை என்றும், சப்ளையர் இன்று காலை இந்தியாவிலிருந்து புறப்பட்டதைத் தெரிவித்ததாகவும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய லேகான் ஜூலை 12 முதல் 15 வரை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, அனைத்து தேதிகளும் சப்ளையர்களால் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15 மற்றும் 17 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் சரக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22 முதல் 24 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15 முதல் 17 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் சரக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 17 முதல் 19 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 17 முதல் 19 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லேகான்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}