{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඩලස්ගේ-අය-වෙන්-වෙන්න-තීරණයක්/101-616904",
  "time_ut": 1658548248,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩලස්ගේ අය වෙන් වෙන්න තීරණයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The people of Dallas decided to separate",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that the group of members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna who supported Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma in the selection of the President will work as a separate group in the Parliament in the future.",
        "It is also said that the group includes about sixteen members of the Podujana Peramuna.",
        "It is said that the group headed by Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma will include Prof. GL Peiris, Prof. Charita Herath, Prof. Channa Jayasumana, Dr. Nalaka Godaheva, as well as the group of MPs who agree with the conscience of the Public Front.",
        "It is known that this group is also focused on building a new political movement in the future."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about sixteen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channa Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godaheva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්ගේ අය වෙන් වෙන්න තීරණයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරාගැනීමේ දී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කණ්ඩායම ඉදිරියේ දී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වෙනම කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස කටයුතු කරනු ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "එම කණ්ඩායමට පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දහසය දෙනෙකු පමණ ඇතුළත් වන බව ද පැවසේ.",
        "ඩලස්අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් එම කණ්ඩායමට මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස්, මහාචාර්ය චරිත හේරත්, මහාචාර්ය චන්න ජයසුමන,ආචාර්ය නාලක ගොඩහේවා යන මහත්වරුන්ට අමතරව,පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ\" හෘද සාක්ෂියට එකග මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායමද ඇතළත් වනු ඇති බව පැවසේ.",
        "මෙම කණ්ඩායම ඉදිරියේ දී නව දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් ගොඩනැගීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද අවධානයෙන් සිටින බව දැනගන්නට ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහසයක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්න ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸ் மக்கள் பிரிந்து செல்ல முடிவு செய்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவில் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளித்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்கள் குழு எதிர்காலத்தில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தனியான குழுவாக செயற்படவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவில் பொதுஜன பெரமுனவைச் சேர்ந்த சுமார் பதினாறு பேர் உள்ளடங்குவதாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தலைமையிலான குழுவில் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ், பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத், பேராசிரியர் சன்ன ஜயசுமண, கலாநிதி நாலக கொடஹேவா, பொது முன்னணியின் மனசாட்சிக்கு உடன்படும் எம்.பி.க்கள் குழுவும் உள்ளடங்குவதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. .",
        "இந்த குழு எதிர்காலத்தில் புதிய அரசியல் இயக்கத்தை கட்டியெழுப்புவதில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதாகவும் அறியமுடிகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் பதினாறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ன ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}