{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/IMF-නියෝජිතයෝ-ජනපති-හමු-වෙති/11-396585",
  "time_ut": 1661348774,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "IMF නියෝජිතයෝ ජනපති හමු වෙති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF representatives meet the President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A preliminary round of discussions with the International Monetary Fund to provide solutions to the financial crisis facing Sri Lanka was held today (24) afternoon at the President's Office under the chairmanship of President Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "The current situation of the financial crisis that Sri Lanka is facing was discussed here. It was further decided to hold another discussion in this round of discussions on Friday 26th and to discuss technical level issues with the Central Bank officials in the future.",
        "Peter Bruber, Head of the International Monetary Fund's Negotiation Panel, Deputy Head Osairo Kosaiko, Mr. Tubagans, Permanent Representative of the International Monetary Fund in Sri Lanka, and Chief of Staff to the President and Senior Advisor to the President on National Security Sagala Ratnayake, President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake, Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe. Gentlemen and others were present on this occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday 26th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Bruber",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's Negotiation Panel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osairo Kosaiko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tubagans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Security Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF නියෝජිතයෝ ජනපති හමු වෙති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් ලබාදීම වෙනුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග සිදු කෙරෙන මූලික වටයේ සාකච්ඡාවක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී අද (24) පස්වරුවේ පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡාවට ලක් කෙරිණ.මෙම සාකච්ඡා වටයේ තවත් සාකච්ඡාවක් ලබන 26 වන සිකුරාදා පැවැත්වීමටත්,  තාක්ෂණික මට්ටමේ කරුණු සම්බන්ධව මහ බැංකු නිලධාරීන් සමග ඉදිරියේ දී සාකච්ඡා කිරීමටත් මෙහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් තීරණය විය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානි පීටර් බෘබර්, නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධානි ඔසයිරෝ කොසයිකෝ, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මෙරට නිත්‍ය නියෝජිත ටුබැගන්ස් යන මහත්වරු සහ ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානි හා ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක, මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ යන මහත්වරු ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲබර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osairo Kosaiko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටුබාගන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை எதிர்நோக்கும் நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வுகளை வழங்குவதற்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான ஆரம்ப கட்ட கலந்துரையாடல் இன்று (24) பிற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையில் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இலங்கை எதிர்நோக்கும் நிதி நெருக்கடியின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து இங்கு கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது.மேலும் 26 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இக்கலந்துரையாடலில் மற்றுமொரு கலந்துரையாடலை நடாத்துவது எனவும், தொழில்நுட்ப விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் எதிர்காலத்தில் மத்திய வங்கி அதிகாரிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடுவது எனவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைக் குழுவின் தலைவர் பீட்டர் புரூபர், பிரதித் தலைவர் ஒசைரோ கொசைகோ, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதி திரு. டுபாகன்ஸ் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமை அதிகாரியும், தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகருமான சாகல ரத்நாயக்க. , ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க, மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, கௌரவர்கள் மற்றும் பலர் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osairo Kosaiko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tubagans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}