{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ධනුෂ්කට-හා-ශානුකට-ජනපති-මාධ්‍ය-අංශයේ-ඉහළ-පුටු/11-395734",
  "time_ut": 1658766015,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ධනුෂ්කට හා ශානුකට ජනපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ ඉහළ පුටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhanushka and Shanukata are the top chairs of the President's media department",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Senior journalist Dhanushka Ramanayake has been appointed as Director General of the President's Media Division. Also Mr. Shanuka Karunaratne has been appointed as the President's Media Director."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhanushka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shanukata",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhanushka Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanuka Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධනුෂ්කට හා ශානුකට ජනපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ ඉහළ පුටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මාධ්‍යවේදී ධනුෂ්ක රාමනායක මහතා ජනපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් තනතුරට පත්කර තිබේ. එසේම ශානුක කරුණාරත්න මහතා ජනපති මාධ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා ලෙස පත්කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධනුෂ්ක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශානුකට",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්ක රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශානුක කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனுஷ்க மற்றும் ஷனுகதா ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவின் உயர்மட்டத் தலைவர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகமாக சிரேஷ்ட ஊடகவியலாளர் தனுஷ்க ராமநாயக்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். மேலும் ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பணிப்பாளராக திரு.ஷானுக கருணாரத்ன நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனுஷ்கா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஷனுகதா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்க ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷனுகா கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}