{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/வேட்பாளர்களை-கை-விட்டது-கை/175-300529",
  "time_ut": 1657963187,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "வேட்பாளர்களை கை விட்டது ’கை’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'Gai' has given up on the candidates.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Freedom Party has decided that it will not support any presidential candidate contesting the upcoming 20th presidential election in Parliament, the party's leader Maithripala Sirisena has announced."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "'ගයි' අපේක්ෂකයන් අත හැර ඇත.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය එළඹෙන 20 වනදා පැවැත්වෙන ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වන කිසිදු ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සහය නොදෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය තීරණය කර ඇති බව එම පක්ෂයේ නායක මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන ප්‍රකාශ කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வேட்பாளர்களை கை விட்டது ’கை’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியானது, எதிர்வரும் 20ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெறவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடும் எந்த ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளருக்கும் ஆதரவளிக்கப் போவதில்லை என்று தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக கட்சியின் தலைவர் மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}