{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/One-day-passport-issuance-service-starts-in-3-regional-offices-today/56-737013",
  "time_ut": 1656880234,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "One-day passport issuance service starts in 3 regional offices today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One-day passport issuance service starts in 3 regional offices today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Decentralised one-day passport service comes into effect in Kandy, Matara, and Vavuniya offices",
        "Initially service is extended to 100 applicants who have already got an online appointment",
        "Foreign employment seekers who have registered for one-day service at HQ can get priority via regional offices",
        "The Department of Immigration and Emigration announced that the issuance of passports under the one-day service will commence from today (4) in Matara, Vavuniya, and Kandy regional offices.",
        "“At the beginning, this service will be given for only 100 applicants who have already reserved a date and time at the specific regional offices,” the Department noted, issuing a media notice.",
        "Previously, the issuance of passports under one-day service was only possible at its head office in Battaramulla. The move to decentralise the one-day passport issuance service is a result of Investment Promotion Minister Dhammika Perera’s directive to the Department during his visit last week.",
        "The Department in its notice reiterates that this service is for those who already registered with regional offices for the normal service through the website www.immigration.gov.lk and requests new applicants not to be present.",
        "It also requests foreign employment seekers who have already registered for the one-day service at the head office to send a WhatsApp message to 0706311711 with documentary evidence to get priority.",
        "The majority of the people who visit the Department’s head office daily was to obtain one-day service countrywide. Given the high transportation cost following the steep fuel hike, people had been waiting at the Department premises. Disgruntled people claimed they had to wait for over a month to get their passports."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්දින ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීමේ සේවාව ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාල 3 කදී අද ආරම්භ වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විමධ්‍යගත එක්දින ගමන් බලපත්‍ර සේවාව මහනුවර, මාතර සහ වවුනියාව කාර්යාලවල ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ",
        "දැනටමත් මාර්ගගත හමුවීමක් ලබාගෙන ඇති අයදුම්කරුවන් 100 දෙනෙකු සඳහා මුලික වශයෙන් සේවාව දීර්ඝ කෙරේ",
        "මූලස්ථානයේ එක්දින සේවය සඳහා ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති විදේශ රැකියා අපේක්ෂකයින්ට ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාල හරහා ප්‍රමුඛත්වය ලබා ගත හැකිය",
        "එක්දින සේවාව යටතේ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීම අද (4) සිට මාතර, වවුනියාව සහ මහනුවර ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාලවලින් ආරම්භ කරන බව ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "\"ආරම්භයේදී, නිශ්චිත ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාලවල දැනටමත් දිනයක් සහ වේලාවක් වෙන් කර ඇති අයදුම්කරුවන් 100 දෙනෙකු සඳහා පමණක් මෙම සේවාව ලබා දෙනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මීට පෙර, එක්දින සේවාව යටතේ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීම කළ හැකි වූයේ එහි බත්තරමුල්ලේ පිහිටි ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේදී පමණි. එක්දින විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීමේ සේවාව විමධ්‍යගත කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇත්තේ ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා පසුගිය සතියේ කළ සංචාරයේදී දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට කළ නියෝගයක ප්‍රතිඵලයකි.",
        "මෙම සේවාව www.immigration.gov.lk වෙබ් අඩවිය හරහා සාමාන්‍ය සේවය සඳහා ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාලවල දැනටමත් ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති අය සඳහා වන බවත් නව අයදුම්කරුවන්ට නොපැමිණෙන ලෙසත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සිය නිවේදනයෙන් යළිත් අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේ එක්දින සේවාව සඳහා දැනටමත් ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති විදේශ රැකියා අපේක්ෂකයින්ට ප්‍රමුඛතාවය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ලේඛනගත සාක්ෂි සහිතව 0706311711 අංකයට WhatsApp පණිවිඩයක් එවන ලෙස ද එය ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයට දිනපතා පැමිණෙන බහුතර ජනතාවක් වූයේ රටපුරා එක්දින සේවාවක් ලබාගැනීමටයි. අධික ඉන්ධන මිල වැඩිවීමත් සමඟ අධික ප්‍රවාහන වියදම හේතුවෙන් ජනතාව දෙපාර්තමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයේ රැඳී සිටියහ. අතෘප්තිමත් පුද්ගලයින් කියා සිටියේ තම විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර ලබා ගැනීමට මාසයකට වැඩි කාලයක් රැඳී සිටීමට සිදු වූ බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක දවසක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්රවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு நாள் பாஸ்போர்ட் வழங்கும் சேவை 3 மண்டல அலுவலகங்களில் இன்று தொடங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கண்டி, மாத்தறை மற்றும் வவுனியா அலுவலகங்களில் பரவலாக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு நாள் கடவுச்சீட்டு சேவை அமுலுக்கு வருகிறது",
        "ஏற்கனவே ஆன்லைன் அப்பாயிண்ட்மெண்ட் பெற்ற 100 விண்ணப்பதாரர்களுக்கு ஆரம்பத்தில் சேவை நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "தலைமையகத்தில் ஒரு நாள் சேவைக்காக பதிவு செய்துள்ள வெளிநாட்டு வேலை தேடுபவர்கள் பிராந்திய அலுவலகங்கள் மூலம் முன்னுரிமை பெறலாம்",
        "மாத்தறை, வவுனியா மற்றும் கண்டி பிராந்திய அலுவலகங்களில் ஒரு நாள் சேவையின் கீழ் கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கும் பணி இன்று (4) முதல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் என குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"தொடக்கத்தில், குறிப்பிட்ட பிராந்திய அலுவலகங்களில் ஏற்கனவே தேதி மற்றும் நேரத்தை முன்பதிவு செய்துள்ள 100 விண்ணப்பதாரர்களுக்கு மட்டுமே இந்த சேவை வழங்கப்படும்\" என்று திணைக்களம் ஊடக அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்டது.",
        "முன்னதாக, ஒரு நாள் சேவையின் கீழ் கடவுச்சீட்டுகளை வழங்குவது பத்தரமுல்லையில் உள்ள அதன் தலைமை அலுவலகத்தில் மட்டுமே சாத்தியமாகும். முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா கடந்த வாரம் தனது விஜயத்தின் போது திணைக்களத்திற்கு வழங்கிய அறிவுறுத்தலின் விளைவாக ஒரு நாள் கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கும் சேவையை பரவலாக்குவதற்கான நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "www.immigration.gov.lk என்ற இணையத்தளத்தின் ஊடாக ஏற்கனவே பிராந்திய அலுவலகங்களில் சாதாரண சேவைக்காக பதிவு செய்தவர்களுக்கு இந்த சேவை வழங்கப்படுவதாக திணைக்களம் அதன் அறிவிப்பில் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "ஏற்கனவே தலைமை அலுவலகத்தில் ஒரு நாள் சேவைக்காக பதிவு செய்துள்ள வெளிநாட்டு வேலை தேடுபவர்கள் முன்னுரிமை பெற ஆவண ஆதாரங்களுடன் 0706311711 என்ற எண்ணுக்கு WhatsApp செய்தியை அனுப்புமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது.",
        "திணைக்களத்தின் பிரதான காரியாலயத்திற்கு தினமும் வருகை தரும் பெரும்பான்மையான மக்கள் நாடு தழுவிய ஒரு நாள் சேவையைப் பெறுவதற்காகவே இருந்தனர். செங்குத்தான எரிபொருள் உயர்வைத் தொடர்ந்து போக்குவரத்து செலவு அதிகமாக இருப்பதால், மக்கள் திணைக்கள வளாகத்தில் காத்திருந்தனர். அதிருப்தியடைந்த மக்கள் தங்கள் பாஸ்போர்ட்டுகளைப் பெற ஒரு மாதத்திற்கும் மேலாக காத்திருக்க வேண்டியிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பகிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}