{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කුට්ටිආරච්චිට-ආණ්ඩු-පක්ෂයේ-තනතුරක්/11-395814",
  "time_ut": 1658988156,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කුට්ටිආරච්චිට ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ තනතුරක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A position in the ruling party for Kuttiarachi",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Deputy Organizers and Assistant Organizers of the ruling party in the Parliament were presented with appointment letters by Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena yesterday (27) at the Prime Minister's Office in Parliament.",
        "Accordingly, MPs Sagara Kariyawasam and Jayantha Katagoda were appointed as Deputy Organizers and MPs Kokila Gunawardena, Madhura Vithanage, and Tissa Kuttiarachchi as Assistant Organizers, received the relevant appointment letters from Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena.",
        "Minister Susil Premajayantha, Leader of the Parliament, Minister Prasanna Ranatunga, the Chief Organizer of the ruling party, as well as Mr. Chaminda Kularatne, Additional Secretary to the President and Secretary to the Chief Organizer of the Government Party, Harsha Wijewardene, Additional Secretary to the Prime Minister and Secretary to the Leader of the House joined the occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kuttiarachi",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Katagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kokila Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madhura Vithanage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Kuttiarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Assistant Organizers",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Kularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුට්ටිආරච්චිට ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ තනතුරක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ නියෝජ්‍ය සංවිධායකවරුන් සහ සහකාර සංවිධායකවරුන්ට ඊට අදාළ පත්වීම් ලිපි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අතින් ඊයේ (27) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී පිරිනැමිණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් සහ ජයන්ත කැටගොඩ යන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නියෝජ්‍ය සංවිධායකවරු ලෙසද කෝකිලා ගුණවර්ධන, මධුර විතානගේ, තිස්ස කුට්ටිආරච්චි යන මන්ත්‍රීවරයන් සහකාර සංවිධායකවරු ලෙසද, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අතින් අදාළ පත්වීම් ලිපි ලබා ගත්හ.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායක අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මෙන්ම ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් හා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලේකම් නීතීඥ චමින්ද කුලරත්න, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය අතිරේක ලේකම් හා සභානායක ලේකම් හර්ෂ විජේවර්ධන යන මහත්තුරුද එක්වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කුට්ටිආරච්චි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත කැටගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝකිලා ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධුර විතානගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස කුට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහකාර සංවිධායකවරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குட்டியாராச்சிக்கு ஆளுங்கட்சியில் ஒரு பதவி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதி அமைப்பாளர்கள் மற்றும் உதவி அமைப்பாளர்களுக்கு பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவினால் நியமனக் கடிதங்கள் நேற்று (27) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் வைத்து வழங்கி வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான சாகர காரியவசம் மற்றும் ஜயந்த கடகொட பிரதி அமைப்பாளர்களாகவும், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான கோகிலா குணவர்தன, மதுர விதானகே மற்றும் திஸ்ஸ குட்டியாராச்சி ஆகியோர் உதவி அமைப்பாளர்களாகவும் பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவிடமிருந்து உரிய நியமனக் கடிதங்களை பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, நாடாளுமன்ற அவைத்தலைவர், அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க, ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளர், ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் சமிந்த குலரத்ன, அரசாங்கக் கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளரின் செயலாளர் ஹர்ஷ விஜேவர்தன, மேலதிக செயலாளர் ஹர்ஷ விஜேவர்தன. பிரதமர் மற்றும் சபைத் தலைவரின் செயலாளரும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "குட்டியாராச்சி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த கடகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகிலா குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுர விதானகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ குட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துணை அமைப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த குலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}