{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Fleeing-Gotabaya-faces-protests-in-Maldives/56-737457",
  "time_ut": 1657756089,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fleeing Gotabaya faces protests in Maldives",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fleeing Gotabaya faces protests in Maldives",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankans living in the Maldives stage a demonstration in Male on 13 July 2022, to protest the arrival of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who is fleeing his own country after thousands of protesters overran his official residence accusing him of responsibility for Sri Lanka’s worst economic crisis – AFP",
        "AFP: Escaping Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa faced protests in the Maldives on Wednesday, with dozens of compatriots urging Male not to provide him safe heaven.",
        "Sri Lankan expatriates carrying flags and placards denounced Rajapaksa, who fled his country early Wednesday after protesters overran his Colombo residence at the weekend over the worsening economic crisis in the South Asian nation.",
        "“Dear Maldivian friends, please urge your Government not to safeguard criminals,” said a black and white banner held by Sri Lankans working in the islands’ tiny capital.",
        "Local media carried unverified videos of residents shouting insults at Rajapaksa as he walked out of the Velana International airport following his arrival on a military aircraft.",
        "As Sri Lankans protested at an artificial beach area in Male on Wednesday, Special Operations Police confiscated placards and dispersed the demonstrators, witnesses said.",
        "Local reports suggested that Rajapaksa was staying at an exclusive resort and would leave for either the United Arab Emirates or Singapore later Wednesday.",
        "“He is going into exile in either of the two locations,” a Sri Lankan security source in Colombo said. “Ensuring security would be a challenge because there are Sri Lankan communities in both.” The main opposition, Progressive Party of Maldives opposed the granting of free passage to Rajapaksa, who faces several court cases, including allegations of war crimes.",
        "“We are betraying our friends in Sri Lanka by accepting Rajapaksa, a hated figure in that country,” a PPM leader told AFP.",
        "The two countries have close ties and a considerable Maldivian community lives in the bigger island nation, while a significant number of Sri Lankans work in education, health and hospitality in the Maldives."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Fleeing Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Escaping Sri Lankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "dozens",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early Wednesday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dear Maldivian",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velana International",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Male",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Special Operations Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Arab Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Progressive Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය පලායාම මාලදිවයිනේ විරෝධතාවලට මුහුණ දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිව යුතු බවට චෝදනා කරමින් දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඔහුගේ නිල නිවස පෙරළීමෙන් පසු ඔහුගේම රටින් පලා යන හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ පැමිණීමට විරෝධය දැක්වීම සඳහා මාලදිවයිනේ වෙසෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් 2022 ජූලි 13 වන දින මාලේ නගරයේ විරෝධතාවක් පවත්වයි. AFP",
        "AFP: පලා යන ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බදාදා මාලදිවයිනේ විරෝධතාවලට මුහුණ දුන් අතර, දුසිම් ගනනක් රටවැසියන් ඔහුට ආරක්ෂිත ස්වර්ගය ලබා නොදෙන ලෙස මාලේගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියහ.",
        "දකුණු ආසියානු ජාතියේ නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සති අන්තයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඔහුගේ කොළඹ නිවසට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු බදාදා අලුයම ඔහුගේ රටින් පලා ගිය රාජපක්ෂට කොඩි සහ පුවරු රැගත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික විදේශිකයන් හෙලා දුටුවේය.",
        "\"ආදරණීය මාලදිවයින් මිත්‍රවරුනි, අපරාධකරුවන් ආරක්ෂා නොකරන ලෙස කරුණාකර ඔබගේ රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමු\" යනුවෙන් දිවයිනේ කුඩා අගනුවර සේවය කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් විසින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටි කළු සුදු බැනරයක සඳහන් විය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් පැමිණීමෙන් පසු වේලන ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටව යද්දී ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් ඔහුට බැන වදින ආකාරය පිළිබඳ තහවුරු නොකළ වීඩියෝ පට ප්‍රාදේශීය මාධ්‍ය විසින් ප්‍රචාරය කරන ලදී.",
        "බදාදා ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මාලේ කෘතිම වෙරළ තීරයක විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වීමත් සමඟ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුම් පොලිසිය විරෝධතා පුවරු රාජසන්තක කර පෙළපාලිකරුවන් විසුරුවා හැර ඇති බව දුටුවෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "ප්‍රාදේශීය වාර්තා යෝජනා කළේ රාජපක්ෂ විශේෂ නිවාඩු නිකේතනයක නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටින අතර බදාදා පසුව එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය හෝ සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව යනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "කොළඹ සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක මූලාශ්‍රයක් පැවසුවේ “ඔහු එම ස්ථාන දෙකෙන් එකකට පිටුවහල් කිරීමට යයි. \"දෙකම ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ප්‍රජාවන් සිටින නිසා ආරක්ෂාව සහතික කිරීම අභියෝගයක් වනු ඇත.\" ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන මාලදිවයිනේ ප්‍රගතිශීලී පක්ෂය යුද අපරාධ චෝදනා ඇතුළු අධිකරණ නඩු කිහිපයකට මුහුණ දෙන රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට නිදහසේ ගමන් කිරීමට අවසර දීමට විරුද්ධ විය.",
        "\"අපි එම රටේ වෛරයට පාත්‍ර වූ චරිතයක් වන රාජපක්ෂ පිළිගැනීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින අපගේ මිතුරන් පාවා දෙන්නෙමු\" යනුවෙන් PPM නායකයෙක් AFP වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "දෙරට අතර සමීප සබඳතා ඇති අතර සැලකිය යුතු මාලදිවයින් ප්‍රජාවක් විශාල දූපත් රාජ්‍යයේ ජීවත් වන අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සැලකිය යුතු සංඛ්‍යාවක් මාලදිවයිනේ අධ්‍යාපනය, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ආගන්තුක සත්කාරය යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සේවය කරති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය පලා යනවා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පැන යාම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුසිම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා මුල",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිතවත් මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේලන ජාත්යන්තර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ මෙහෙයුම් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රගතිශීලී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய தப்பியோடியது மாலைதீவில் போராட்டங்களை எதிர்கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு அவர் பொறுப்பு என்று குற்றம் சாட்டி ஆயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து, அவரது சொந்த நாட்டிலிருந்து தப்பிச் செல்லும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் வருகைக்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில், மாலத்தீவில் வசிக்கும் இலங்கையர்கள் 13 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று மாலேயில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் நடத்தினர். AFP",
        "AFP: தப்பியோடிய இலங்கை அதிபர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச புதன்கிழமை மாலைதீவில் எதிர்ப்புகளை எதிர்கொண்டார், அவருக்கு பாதுகாப்பான சொர்க்கத்தை வழங்க வேண்டாம் என்று டஜன் கணக்கான தோழர்கள் மாலேவை வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "தெற்காசிய தேசத்தில் மோசமடைந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக வார இறுதியில் அவரது கொழும்பு இல்லத்தை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலையில் ராஜபக்சே நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டினர் கொடிகள் மற்றும் பலகைகளை ஏந்தியவாறு கண்டனம் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "\"அன்புள்ள மாலத்தீவு நண்பர்களே, குற்றவாளிகளைப் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டாம் என்று உங்கள் அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்துங்கள்\" என்று தீவுகளின் சிறிய தலைநகரில் பணிபுரியும் இலங்கையர்களால் ஒரு கருப்பு மற்றும் வெள்ளை பதாகை இருந்தது.",
        "அவர் இராணுவ விமானத்தில் வந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து வேலனா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து ராஜபக்சே வெளியேறும்போது, ​​குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் அவரை அவமதிக்கும் வகையில் கூச்சலிடும் வீடியோவை உள்ளூர் ஊடகங்கள் சரிபார்க்கவில்லை.",
        "புதன் கிழமை மாலேயில் உள்ள செயற்கைக் கடற்கரைப் பகுதியில் இலங்கையர்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டபோது, ​​விசேட அதிரடிப் பொலிஸார் பதாகைகளை பறிமுதல் செய்து ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை கலைத்ததாக நேரில் பார்த்தவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச ஒரு பிரத்யேக ரிசார்ட்டில் தங்கியிருப்பதாகவும், புதன்கிழமைக்குப் பிறகு ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ் அல்லது சிங்கப்பூர் செல்வார் என்றும் உள்ளூர் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள இலங்கை பாதுகாப்பு வட்டாரம் கூறுகையில், \"அவர் இரண்டு இடங்களில் ஏதாவது ஒரு இடத்திற்கு நாடுகடத்தப்படுகிறார். \"இரண்டிலும் இலங்கை சமூகங்கள் இருப்பதால் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வது ஒரு சவாலாக இருக்கும்.\" போர்க் குற்றச் சாட்டுகள் உட்பட பல நீதிமன்ற வழக்குகளை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு இலவச வழியை வழங்குவதை பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான மாலத்தீவின் முற்போக்குக் கட்சி எதிர்த்தது.",
        "\"இலங்கையில் வெறுக்கப்படும் நபரான ராஜபக்சேவை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதன் மூலம் நாங்கள் இலங்கையில் உள்ள எங்கள் நண்பர்களுக்கு துரோகம் செய்கிறோம்\" என்று ஒரு PPM தலைவர் AFPயிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இரு நாடுகளும் நெருங்கிய உறவுகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளன மற்றும் கணிசமான மாலத்தீவு சமூகம் பெரிய தீவு நாட்டில் வாழ்கிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் கணிசமான எண்ணிக்கையிலான இலங்கையர்கள் மாலைதீவில் கல்வி, சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் விருந்தோம்பல் ஆகியவற்றில் பணிபுரிகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய தப்பி ஓடுகிறார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தப்பிச் செல்லும் இலங்கையர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டஜன் கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன் ஆரம்பத்தில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அன்புள்ள மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலனா இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு நடவடிக்கை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முற்போக்கு கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}