{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/වගා-හානි-සත්ව-ලැයිස්තුවෙන්-වන-අලියා-ඉවතට/1-618691",
  "time_ut": 1661340415,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වගා හානි සත්ව ලැයිස්තුවෙන් වන අලියා ඉවතට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Elephant removed from crop damage list",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation, Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera instructed the Secretary of the Ministry of Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation, Mrs. Chandra Herath to take steps to remove the wild elephant from the list of wild animals that cause crop damage in Sri Lanka.",
        "Among the animals that cause crop damage, the crop damage caused by the wild elephant is the least amount of 20 percent of the total crop damage and about 46 percent of the crop damage is caused by the wild boar, monkey, peacock, wild boar and deer, said the Ministry of Agriculture."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Wildlife",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 46 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වගා හානි සත්ව ලැයිස්තුවෙන් වන අලියා ඉවතට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වගා හානි සිදු කරන වනසත්ව ලැයිස්තුවෙන් වන අලියා ඉවත් කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස කෘෂිකර්ම වනජීවී හා වනසම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා වනජීවි හා වනසම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් චන්ද්‍රා හේරත් මහත්මියට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "වගා හානි සිදු කරන සතුන්  අතරින් වන අලියාගෙන් සිදුවන වගා හානිය සමස්ත වගා හානියෙන් සියයට 20ක් පමණ අවම ප්‍රමාණයක් බවත්    සියයට 46ක පමණ වගා හානියක් රිළවා, වඳුරා, මොණරා,වල් ඌරා හා දඩුලේනාගෙන් සිදුවන බව තහවුරු වී ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 46 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயிர் சேத பட்டியலில் இருந்து யானை நீக்கம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "விவசாயம், வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீர, பயிர் சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் வனவிலங்கு பட்டியலில் இருந்து காட்டு யானையை நீக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் திருமதி சந்திரா ஹேரத்துக்கு பணிப்புரை வழங்கினார். இலங்கையில்",
        "பயிர் சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் விலங்குகளில், காட்டு யானையால் ஏற்படும் பயிர் சேதம் மொத்த பயிர் சேதத்தில் 20 சதவீதம் மற்றும் சுமார் 46 சதவீதம் பயிர் சேதம் காட்டுப்பன்றி, குரங்கு, மயில், காட்டுப்பன்றி மற்றும் மான் என்று விவசாய அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திர ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 46 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}