{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/aragalaya-activist-anthony-weranga-pushpika-remanded-to-9th-august/",
  "time_ut": 1659012480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Aragalaya activist Anthony Weranga Pushpika, remanded to 9th August",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Aragalaya activist Anthony Weranga Pushpika, remanded to 9th August",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Anthony Weranga Pushpika, an Aragalaya protest activist who was arrested on multiple charges, was remanded until the 9th of August 2022.",
        "Police Spokesperson SSP Attorney-at-Law Nihal Thalduwa told News 1st that the suspect was produced to the Kaduwela Magistrate's Court, and was remanded in order to be produced in an Identification Parade.",
        "The charges against him are engaging in protest in Battaramulla on the 10th of June in violation of a court order, unlawful assembly, criminal engagement against police officers, and causing damage to state property, said police in a statement on Thursday (28).",
        "Japan hands over donation of USD 1.5Mn to curb medicine crisis"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Aragalaya",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Anthony Weranga Pushpika",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anthony Weranga Pushpika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th of August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson SSP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 10th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ඇන්තනි වේරංග පුෂ්පික අගෝස්තු 9 දක්වා රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විවිධ චෝදනා මත අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අරගලය විරෝධතා ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ඇන්තනි වේරංග පුෂ්පික 2022 අගෝස්තු 9 දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කෙරුණා.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නීතීඥ නිහාල් තල්දූව News 1st වෙත කියා සිටියේ සැකකරු කඩුවෙල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව හඳුනාගැනීමේ පෙරට්ටුවකට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඔහුට එරෙහිව ජූනි 10 වැනිදා බත්තරමුල්ලේදී අධිකරණ නියෝගයක් කඩකරමින් විරෝධතාවයේ නිරතවීම, නීතිවිරෝධී රැස්වීම්, පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට සාපරාධී ලෙස සම්බන්ධවීම, රාජ්‍ය දේපළවලට අලාභ හානි සිදුකිරීම යන චෝදනා බව පොලිසිය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (28දා) නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ජපානය ඖෂධ අර්බුදය මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.5 ක පරිත්‍යාගයක් ලබා දෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අරගලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඇන්තනි වේරංග පුෂ්පිකා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි වේරංග පුෂ්පිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரகலயா செயற்பாட்டாளர் அந்தோனி வெரங்க புஷ்பிகா ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பல குற்றச்சாட்டுக்களில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட அரகலய போராட்ட செயற்பாட்டாளர் அந்தோனி வெரங்க புஷ்பிகா 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர் கடுவெல நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டு, அடையாள அணிவகுப்பில் ஆஜர்படுத்துவதற்காக விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் சட்டத்தரணி நிஹால் தல்துவ News 1st க்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறி ஜூன் 10ஆம் திகதி பத்தரமுல்லையில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டமை, சட்டவிரோதமாக ஒன்றுகூடல், பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களுக்கு எதிராக குற்றச் செயல்களில் ஈடுபட்டமை, அரச சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தல் ஆகிய குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் அவர் மீது சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் வியாழக்கிழமை (28) அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மருத்துவ நெருக்கடியைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த ஜப்பான் 1.5 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரகலயா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அந்தோணி வெரங்க புஷ்பிகா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தோணி வெரங்க புஷ்பிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}