{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/ஏறாவூர்-வன்முறை-சந்தேக-நபர்-சரணடைந்தார்/175-303055",
  "time_ut": 1661546561,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஏறாவூர் வன்முறை: சந்தேக நபர் சரணடைந்தார்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ebravoor violence: Suspect surrenders",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main suspect, who was wanted in connection with the violent incident that took place on the night of May 9th in Ebravoor, Batticaloa, surrendered yesterday (26) at the Ebravoor Tourism Magistrate's Court.",
        "After the surrender of the suspect through lawyer Habib Muhammad Riban, the judge Anwar Sadat of the Tourism Magistrate's Court of Ebravur has ordered that he be remanded till September 9.",
        "The prime suspect surrendered yesterday while 38 people had already been arrested and interrogated by the District Crime Investigation Department in connection with the burning and looting of the rented office of the Member of Parliament and Environment Minister Naseer Ahmed, his relative's house and hostels, as well as the destruction of 3 garment factories. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ebravoor",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ebravoor Tourism Magistrate's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Habib Muhammad Riban",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anwar Sadat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tourism Magistrate's Court of Ebravur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the District Crime Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Ebravoor හිංසනය: සැකකරු යටත් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මඩකලපුව, එබ්‍රවුර් ප්‍රදේශයේ මැයි 9 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍යව සිටි ප්‍රධාන සැකකරු ඊයේ (26) එබ්‍රවුර් සංචාරක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට භාර විය.",
        "නීතීඥ හබීබ් මුහම්මද් රිබාන් මහතා මාර්ගයෙන් සැකකරු භාරවීමෙන් පසු එබ්‍රාවුර් සංචාරක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේ විනිසුරු අන්වර් සදාත් මහතා සැප්තැම්බර් 9 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කිරීමට නියෝග කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ්ගේ කුලියට ගත් කාර්යාලය, ඔහුගේ ඥාති නිවස සහ නේවාසිකාගාර ගිනි තබා කොල්ලකෑම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැනටමත් 38 දෙනෙකු දිස්ත්‍රික් අපරාධ විමර්ශන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ප්‍රශ්න කරමින් සිටියදී ප්‍රධාන සැකකරු ඊයේ භාර විය. ඇඟලුම් කම්හල් 3ක් විනාශ කිරීම. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එබ්‍රවුර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එබ්‍රවූර් සංචාරක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හබීබ් මුහම්මද් රිබන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්වර් සදාත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එබ්‍රාවුර් සංචාරක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්‍රික් අපරාධ විමර්ශන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஏறாவூர் வன்முறை: சந்தேக நபர் சரணடைந்தார்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மட்டக்களப்பு ஏறாவூரில் கடந்த மே 9 ஆம் திகதி இரவு இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் தேடப்பட்டு வந்த நிலையில் தலைமறைவாகியிருந்த பிரதான சந்தேக நபர் நேற்று (26) ஏறாவூர் சுற்றுலா நீதிவான் நீமன்றத்தில் சரணடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "சட்டத்தரணி ஹபீப் முஹம்மது றிபான் ஊடாக சந்தேக நபர்  சரணடைந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து  செப்ரெம்பெர் 9 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு ஏறாவூர் சுற்றுலா நீதிவான் நீதிமன்ற நீதிவான் அன்வர் சதாத் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சருமான  நஸீர் அஹமட்டின் வாடகைக் காரியாலயம், அவரது உறவினரின் வீடு, விடுதிகளும்  தீயிட்டுக் கொளுத்தியமை கொள்ளையயடித்தமை அத்துடன்,  3 ஆடைத்தொழிற்சாலைளை சேதப்படுத்தியமை தொடர்பாக,  மாவட்ட குற்ற விசாரணைப் பிரிவினரால் ஏற்கெனவே 38 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு விசாரணைக்குட்படுத்தப்பட்டு வந்த நிலையில் பிரதான சந்தேக நபர் நேற்று சரணடைந்துள்ளார். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எப்ராவூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எப்ராவூர் சுற்றுலா மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹபீப் முஹம்மது ரிபான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்வர் சதாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எப்ராவூர் சுற்றுலா மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}