{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ජනපති-ගෝඨාභය-සිංගප්පූරු-ඊයේ-නොයයි/101-616390",
  "time_ut": 1657765439,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය සිංගප්පූරු ඊයේ නොයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Gotabaya will not go to Singapore yesterday",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Foreign media reported that President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa did not take off from Singapore flight SK 437 which was supposed to go from Male to Singapore.",
        "The media stated that due to security reasons, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Mrs. Loma Rajapaksa and the two bodyguards did not leave the plane.",
        "Maldivian media reported that they are negotiating to get a private plane for President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to leave for Singapore.",
        "As President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa was scheduled to leave for Singapore yesterday (13) at 11.25 PM Maldives time, the foreign media further stated that strict security was provided at Velena International Airport in Maldives and that after going to Singapore, he may send his resignation to the Speaker of the Parliament of Sri Lanka, Mr. Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena. said"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "yesterday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Loma Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.25 PM Maldives time",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velena International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය සිංගප්පූරු ඊයේ නොයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා යාමට නියමිතව තිබූ එස්.කිව් 437 සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් යානයෙන් පිටත් නොවූ බව විිදෙස් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ආරක්ෂක හේතුන් මත ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා,ලෝමා රාජපක්ෂ මහත්මිය සහ ආරක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනා  එම ගුවන් යානයෙන් පිටත් නොවූ බව එම මාධ්‍ය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව යාම සඳහා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පෞද්ගලික ගුවන් යානයක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බව මාලදිවයින් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ(13) මාලදිවයින් වේලාවෙන් පස්වරු 11.25 ට සිංගප්පූරුවට පිටත් වීමට නියමිත තිබූ බැවින් මාලදිවයිනේ වෙලේනා ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපොළට දැඩි ආරක්ෂාවක් ලබා දී තිබූ බවත් සිංගප්පූරුවට යෑමෙන් පසු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත යැවිය හැකි බවත් විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය තවදුරටත් පැවසුවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඊයේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝමා රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයිනේ වේලාවෙන් ප.ව.11.25",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velena ජාත්යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய நேற்று சிங்கப்பூர் செல்ல மாட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மாலேயில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லவிருந்த SK 437 என்ற சிங்கப்பூர் விமானத்தில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ புறப்படவில்லை என வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, திருமதி லோமா ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் இரு மெய்ப்பாதுகாவலர்கள் விமானத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறவில்லை என ஊடகங்கள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சிங்கப்பூர் செல்வதற்கு தனி விமானம் ஒன்றை பெற்றுக் கொடுப்பதற்கு பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருவதாக மாலைதீவு ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மாலைதீவு நேரப்படி நேற்று (13) இரவு 11.25 மணிக்கு சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லவிருந்த நிலையில், மாலைதீவின் வெலேனா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் பலத்த பாதுகாப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், சிங்கப்பூர் சென்ற பின்னர் அவர் தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை அனுப்பலாம் எனவும் வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் சபாநாயகர் திரு மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நேற்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோமா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலைதீவு நேரம் 11.25 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலினா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}