{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83863/82038203foreign-minister-ali-sabry-assumes-duties",
  "time_ut": 1658748900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "​​Foreign Minister Ali Sabry assumes duties",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "​​Foreign Minister Ali Sabry assumes duties",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry officially assumed duties at the Ministry today (25) at a simple ceremony.",
        "Foreign Secretary Aruni Wijewardane and the senior officials were present, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said.",
        "Addressing the officials, Minister Ali Sabry stated that he looked forward to delivering on the mandate of the Ministry to steer forward Sri Lanka’s foreign relations, taking the domestic compulsions too into consideration.",
        "He commended the outgoing Minister Prof G. L. Peiris for his leadership provided to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.",
        "Minister Sabry was appointed a Member of Parliament in 2020. Minister Ali Sabry served as the Minister of Justice since 12 August 2020, until he was appointed the Finance Minister on 4 April, 2022.",
        "As the Minister of Justice, he launched many new initiatives including the wide-ranging reforms into the Sri Lankan justice sector with the justice sector reform programme to amend over hundred laws, some of which have not been changed in over a century.",
        "Minister Ali Sabry also initiated the digitization drive of the justice sector, the expansion of courthouses across the country and the introduction of specialized courthouses to address the issue of delays.",
        "As the Finance Minister, he led the Sri Lankan delegation for the recent negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank in Washington D.C.",
        "Prior to his entry into politics, Minister Ali Sabry was a practicing lawyer with many of the cases he handled appearing in law reports and publications.",
        "He was appointed a President’s Counsel in 2012 and was awarded the Outstanding Young Person of The Year for Achievement in Law in 2009. He has also served as Sri Lanka’s Consul General in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia in 1997."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ali Sabry",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prof G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 August 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 April, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "over hundred",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over a century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.C.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Year for Achievement in Law",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeddah",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1997",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි වැඩ භාර ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මහතා අද (25) එම අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී චාම් උත්සවයකදී නිල වශයෙන් වැඩ භාර ගත්තේය.",
        "විදේශ ලේකම් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් එක්ව සිටි බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "නිලධාරීන් අමතමින් අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි ප්‍රකාශ කළේ දේශීය බලකිරීම් ද සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ සබඳතා ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ වරම ලබා දීමට තමන් අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයට ලබාදුන් නායකත්වය පිළිබඳව ඔහු අමාත්‍යවරයාගෙන් නික්ම යන මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.පීරිස් මහතාට ප්‍රශංසා කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය සබ්රි 2020 දී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස පත් කරන ලදී. අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි 2020 අගෝස්තු 12 සිට 2022 අප්‍රේල් 4 වන දින මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කරන තෙක් අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ඔහු ශතවර්ෂයකට වැඩි කාලයක් තිස්සේ වෙනස් කර නොමැති නීති සියයකට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් සංශෝධනය කිරීම සඳහා අධිකරණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ වැඩසටහන සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධිකරණ ක්ෂේත්‍රය තුළ පුළුල් පරාසයක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ඇතුළු නව මුල පිරීම් රාශියක් දියත් කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මහතා අධිකරණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ඩිජිටල්කරණ ව්‍යාපාරය, රට පුරා උසාවි පුළුල් කිරීම සහ ප්‍රමාදයන් පිළිබඳ ගැටළුව විසඳීම සඳහා විශේෂිත උසාවි හඳුන්වාදීම ද ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ඔහු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සහ ලෝක බැංකුව සමඟ වොෂින්ටන් ඩී.සී. හි මෑතකාලීන සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත පිරිසට නායකත්වය දුන්නේය.",
        "ඔහු දේශපාලනයට පිවිසීමට පෙර, අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි නීති වාර්තා සහ ප්‍රකාශනවල පෙනී සිටිමින් ඔහු විසින් හසුරුවන ලද බොහෝ නඩු සමඟ ප්‍රායෝගික නීතිඥයෙකු විය.",
        "ඔහු 2012 දී ජනාධිපති නීතීඥයෙකු ලෙස පත් කරන ලද අතර 2009 වසරේ නීතියේ ජයග්‍රහණ වෙනුවෙන් වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම තරුණ පුද්ගලයා ලෙසින් සම්මානයට පාත්‍ර විය. ඔහු 1997 දී සෞදි අරාබියේ ජෙඩා හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොන්සල් ජනරාල්වරයා ලෙස ද සේවය කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 අගෝස්තු 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 අප්රේල්, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියවසකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.සී.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතියේ ජයග්රහණය සඳහා වසර",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙඩා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1997",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி இன்று (25) அமைச்சில் எளிமையான வைபவத்தில் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக கடமைகளை பொறுப்பேற்றார்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார செயலாளர் அருணி விஜேவர்தன மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் கலந்துகொண்டதாக வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதிகாரிகளிடம் உரையாற்றிய அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி, உள்நாட்டு நிர்ப்பந்தங்களையும் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகளை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கான அமைச்சின் ஆணையை வழங்க எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சுக்கு வழங்கிய தலைமைத்துவத்திற்காக பதவி விலகும் அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸை அவர் பாராட்டினார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் சப்ரி 2020 இல் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி 12 ஆகஸ்ட் 2020 முதல், 4 ஏப்ரல் 2022 அன்று நிதி அமைச்சராக நியமிக்கப்படும் வரை நீதி அமைச்சராக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "நீதி அமைச்சராக, அவர் இலங்கை நீதித்துறையில் பரந்த அளவிலான சீர்திருத்தங்கள் உட்பட நூற்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட சட்டங்களை திருத்துவதற்கான நீதித்துறை சீர்திருத்த வேலைத்திட்டத்துடன் பல புதிய முயற்சிகளை ஆரம்பித்தார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி, நீதித்துறையின் டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கல், நாடு முழுவதும் நீதிமன்றங்களை விரிவுபடுத்துதல் மற்றும் காலதாமத பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண சிறப்பு நீதிமன்றங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவற்றையும் தொடங்கி வைத்தார்.",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் என்ற முறையில், வாஷிங்டன் டி.சி.யில் நடந்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (ஐ.எம்.எஃப்) மற்றும் உலக வங்கி உடனான சமீபத்திய பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளுக்கு இலங்கை தூதுக்குழுவை வழிநடத்தினார்.",
        "அவர் அரசியலுக்கு வருவதற்கு முன்னர், அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி சட்ட அறிக்கைகள் மற்றும் வெளியீடுகளில் தோன்றிய பல வழக்குகளுடன் ஒரு வழக்கறிஞராக இருந்தார்.",
        "அவர் 2012 இல் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார் மற்றும் 2009 இல் சட்டத்தில் சாதனை படைத்ததற்காக ஆண்டின் சிறந்த இளம் நபருக்கான விருதைப் பெற்றார். அவர் 1997 இல் சவூதி அரேபியாவின் ஜெட்டாவில் இலங்கையின் துணைத் தூதராகவும் பணியாற்றியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஆகஸ்ட் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 ஏப்ரல், 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நூற்றாண்டுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.சி.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தில் சாதனை படைத்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜித்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1997",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}