{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Conman-bought-house-for-Jacqueline-Fernandez-in-Sri-Lanka/108-244114",
  "time_ut": 1662004874,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Conman bought house for Jacqueline Fernandez in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Conman bought house for Jacqueline Fernandez in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Conman Sukesh Chandrashekhar had bought a house in Sri Lanka for Jacqueline Fernandez and made an advance for a bungalow in Mumbai’s upscale Juhu locality for her, the Enforcement Directorate’s chargesheet read.",
        "According to the probe agency, the conman had told his associate Pinky Irani about his plans to buy the houses. Pinky Irani was tasked by Sukesh to introduce Jacqueline Fernandez to him and was allegedly paid in crores of rupees for the job, the India Today reported.",
        "“Sukesh Chandrasekhar also conveyed to Pinky Irani that he had given some token money to buy a house for Jacqueline in Mumbai’s Juhu beach area and that he had already gifted a house to the actor’s parents in Bahrain. Further, he was negotiating to buy a house in Sri Lanka for the actor,” the chargesheet revealed.",
        "The ED is investigating whether Sukesh actually bought any of these properties. When officials questioned Jacqueline about them, she admitted that Sukesh had told her about a house for her in Sri Lanka but she had never been there.",
        "“When asked about her WhatsApp chat with accused Pinky Irani about Sukesh having bought a new house for her in Sri Lanka, the actor admitted that Sukesh had bought a property at Weligama in Sri Lanka for her. However, she never visited the said property,” the chargesheet said.",
        "Weligama is a popular tourist destination in Sri Lanka and is known for its beaches.",
        "The financial probe agency is yet to ascertain if the property was indeed bought by the conman or he was lying to her.",
        "“Jacqueline also mentioned Sukesh’s plans to buy a few more properties for her or her relatives. It is yet to be ascertained whether Sukesh used the proceeds of crime on any other properties for Jacqueline Fernandez or her relatives,” the chargesheet added.",
        "The actor was allegedly gifted jewellery worth over Rs 7 crore by Sukesh Chandrashekhar. He had also allegedly gifted several high end cars, expensive bags, clothes, shoes and costly watches to the actor and her family members."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Conman",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pinky Irani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pinky Irani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the India Today",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pinky Irani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Juhu beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahrain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pinky Irani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weligama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekhar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොන්මන් ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිවසක් මිලදී ගත්තේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොන්මන් සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේඛර් ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිවසක් මිල දී ගෙන ඇති අතර ඇය වෙනුවෙන් මුම්බායි හි ඉහළ මට්ටමේ ජුහු ප්‍රදේශයේ බංගලාවක් සඳහා අත්තිකාරමක් ලබා දී ඇති බව බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "විමර්ශන ඒජන්සියට අනුව, මෙම නිවාස මිලදී ගැනීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව ව්‍යාපාරිකයා ඔහුගේ සහකාරිය වන පිංකි ඉරානිට පවසා ඇත. ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්ව ඔහුට හඳුන්වා දීම සඳහා සුකේෂ් විසින් පිංකි ඉරානිට පැවරූ අතර එම කාර්යය සඳහා රුපියල් කෝටි ගණනින් ගෙවා ඇති බව ඉන්දියා ටුඩේ වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "“සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් ද පිංකි ඉරානිට දන්වා සිටියේ ජැකලින්ට මුම්බායි හි ජුහු වෙරළ ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක් මිලදී ගැනීමට ටෝකන් මුදල් ලබා දුන් බවත්, ඔහු ඒ වන විටත් බහරේනයේ නළුවාගේ දෙමාපියන්ට නිවසක් තෑගි කර ඇති බවත්ය. තවද, ඔහු එම නළුවාට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිවසක් මිලදී ගැනීමට සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටියේය.",
        "සුකේෂ් ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම මෙම දේපල කිසිවක් මිලදී ගත්තේද යන්න ED විමර්ශනය කරයි. ඔවුන් ගැන නිලධාරීන් ජැකලින්ගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදී ඇය පිළිගත්තේ ඇයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිවසක් ගැන සුකේෂ් පැවසූ නමුත් ඇය කිසි විටෙකත් එහි නොසිටි බවයි.",
        "“සුකේෂ් ඇයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව නිවසක් මිලදී ගැනීම ගැන චූදිත පිංකි ඉරානි සමඟ කළ WhatsApp සංවාදය ගැන විමසූ විට, නළුවා පිළිගත්තේ සුකේෂ් ඇය වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වැලිගම ප්‍රදේශයෙන් දේපළක් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඇය කිසි දිනෙක එම දේපළට නොපැමිණි බව” චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "වැලිගම යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනප්‍රිය සංචාරක ගමනාන්තයක් වන අතර එහි වෙරළ තීරයන් සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය.",
        "මෙම දේපල ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම ව්‍යාපාරිකයා විසින් මිලදී ගත්තාද නැතහොත් ඔහු ඇයට බොරු කීවාද යන්න මූල්‍ය විමර්ශන ඒජන්සිය තවමත් තහවුරු කර නොමැත.",
        "“ඇයට හෝ ඇයගේ ඥාතීන්ට තවත් දේපල කිහිපයක් මිලදී ගැනීමට සුකේෂ්ගේ සැලසුම් ගැනද ජැකලින් සඳහන් කළාය. සුකේෂ් අපරාධයෙන් උපයාගත් මුදල් ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් හෝ ඇයගේ ඥාතීන් වෙනුවෙන් වෙනත් දේපළකට යොදවා තිබේද යන්න තවම තහවුරු වී නැත.",
        "මෙම නළුවාට සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් විසින් රුපියල් කෝටි 7කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් ස්වර්ණාභරණ තෑගි කර ඇති බව පැවසේ. ඔහු නළුවාට සහ ඇගේ පවුලේ සාමාජිකයින්ට උසස් තත්ත්වයේ මෝටර් රථ, මිල අධික බෑග්, ඇඳුම් පැළඳුම්, සපත්තු සහ මිල අධික ඔරලෝසු කිහිපයක් තෑගි කර ඇති බව පැවසේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොන් මෑන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිංකි ඉරානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිංකි ඉරානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India Today",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිංකි ඉරානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුහු වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහරේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිංකි ඉරානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கான்மேன் ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு இலங்கையில் வீடு வாங்கினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கான்மேன் சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர், ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு இலங்கையில் வீடு வாங்கி, அவருக்காக மும்பையின் உயர்மட்ட ஜூஹூ பகுதியில் உள்ள பங்களாவுக்கு முன்பணம் கொடுத்ததாக அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகத்தின் குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "விசாரணை முகமையின் படி, அந்த கடத்தல்காரன் தனது கூட்டாளியான பிங்கி இரானியிடம் வீடுகளை வாங்கும் திட்டத்தைப் பற்றி கூறியதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. பிங்கி இரானிக்கு ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸை அறிமுகப்படுத்த சுகேஷ் பணித்தார், மேலும் அந்த வேலைக்காக பல கோடி ரூபாய் சம்பளம் பெற்றதாக இந்தியா டுடே செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“மும்பையின் ஜூஹு கடற்கரை பகுதியில் ஜாக்குலினுக்கு வீடு வாங்க சில டோக்கன் பணம் கொடுத்ததாகவும், பஹ்ரைனில் உள்ள நடிகரின் பெற்றோருக்கு ஏற்கனவே ஒரு வீட்டை பரிசாக கொடுத்ததாகவும் சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் பிங்கி இரானியிடம் தெரிவித்தார். மேலும், நடிகருக்கு இலங்கையில் வீடு வாங்க பேரம் பேசியதாக குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த சொத்துக்களை சுகேஷ் உண்மையில் வாங்கியாரா என ED விசாரித்து வருகிறது. அதிகாரிகள் ஜாக்குலினிடம் அவர்களைப் பற்றி விசாரித்தபோது, ​​​​சுகேஷ் தனக்கு இலங்கையில் ஒரு வீட்டைப் பற்றி சொன்னதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டார், ஆனால் அவர் அங்கு செல்லவில்லை.",
        "“சுகேஷ் இலங்கையில் தனக்காக ஒரு புதிய வீட்டை வாங்கியது குறித்து குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட பிங்கி இரானியுடன் வாட்ஸ்அப் உரையாடலைப் பற்றி கேட்டபோது, ​​நடிகர் சுகேஷ் தனக்காக இலங்கையில் உள்ள வெலிகமவில் ஒரு சொத்தை வாங்கியதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டார். இருப்பினும், அவர் அந்த சொத்தை பார்க்கவே இல்லை” என்று குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வெலிகம இலங்கையின் ஒரு பிரபலமான சுற்றுலாத் தலமாகும், மேலும் அதன் கடற்கரைகளுக்கு பெயர் பெற்றது.",
        "இந்த சொத்து உண்மையில் கடத்தல்காரரால் வாங்கப்பட்டதா அல்லது அவர் அவளிடம் பொய் சொன்னாரா என்பதை நிதி விசாரணை நிறுவனம் இன்னும் கண்டறியவில்லை.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் மேலும் சில சொத்துக்களை தன் உறவினர்களுக்காக வாங்க சுகேஷின் திட்டத்தையும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் அல்லது அவரது உறவினர்களுக்காக சுகேஷ் வேறு ஏதேனும் சொத்துகளில் குற்றச் செயல்களில் ஈடுபட்டாரா என்பது இன்னும் கண்டறியப்படவில்லை.",
        "நடிகர் சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் ரூ.7 கோடிக்கு மேல் நகைகளை பரிசாக அளித்ததாக கூறப்படுகிறது. அவர் பல உயர் ரக கார்கள், விலையுயர்ந்த பைகள், உடைகள், காலணிகள் மற்றும் விலையுயர்ந்த கடிகாரங்களை நடிகர் மற்றும் அவரது குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு பரிசாக அளித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கான்மேன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிங்கி இரானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிங்கி இரானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா டுடே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிங்கி இரானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூஹு கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹ்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பகிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிங்கி இரானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}