{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83726/transport-minister-directs-ntc-to-reduce-bus-fares",
  "time_ut": 1658148840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Transport Minister directs NTC to reduce bus fares",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Transport Minister directs NTC to reduce bus fares",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Transport Bandula Gunawardena has instructed the National Transport Commission (NTC) to reduce bus fares in proportion to the reduction in fuel prices.",
        "Accordingly, the minister has directed the NTC to reduce the bus fares with effect from midnight tomorrow (July 19) while the revised fares will be announced tomorrow.",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CEYPETCO) and Lanka Indian Oil Company (LIOC) had reduced fuel prices with effect from 10 pm yesterday (17).",
        "CEYPETCO and LIOC announced that a liter of petrol (octane 92) has been reduced by Rs. 20 rupees and a liter of petrol (octane 95) has been reduced by Rs. 10.",
        "The price of a liter of diesel was slashed by Rs. 20 and a liter of super diesel by Rs. 10.",
        "Meanwhile the two major associations representing private bus operators in the country, the All Ceylon Bus Owners’ Association and Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association, have also expressed willingness to reduce bus fares by 4% in line with the revision of fuel prices."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Transport Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight tomorrow",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Indian Oil Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LIOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the All Ceylon Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බස් ගාස්තු අඩු කරන ලෙස ප්‍රවාහන ඇමති NTC වෙත උපදෙස් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන මිල අඩුවීමට සමානුපාතිකව බස් ගාස්තු අඩු කරන ලෙස ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාවට උපදෙස් ලබාදී තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව හෙට (ජුලි 19) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි බස් ගාස්තු අඩු කරන ලෙස අමාත්‍යවරයා NTC වෙත නියෝග කර ඇති අතර සංශෝධිත ගාස්තු හෙට ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CEYPETCO) සහ ලංකා ඉන්දියන් ඔයිල් සමාගම (LIOC) ඊයේ (17) රාත්‍රී 10 සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි ඉන්ධන මිල අඩු කර තිබුණි.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක් ​​(ඔක්ටේන් 92) රුපියල් 10 කින් අඩු කර ඇති බව CEYPETCO සහ LIOC නිවේදනය කරයි. රුපියල් 20 කින් සහ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක් ​​(ඔක්ටේන් 95) රු. 10.",
        "ඩීසල් ලීටරයක මිල රු. 20 කින් සහ සුපර් ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රු. 10.",
        "මේ අතර මෙරට පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ හිමියන් නියෝජනය කරන ප්‍රධාන සංගම් දෙක වන සමස්ත ලංකා බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය සහ ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය ද ඉන්ධන මිල සංශෝධනයට අනුව සියයට 4කින් බස් ගාස්තු අඩු කිරීමට කැමැත්ත පළ කර තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඉන්දියන් ඔයිල් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව. 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්.අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேருந்து கட்டணத்தை குறைக்குமாறு NTC-க்கு போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் உத்தரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள் விலை குறைப்புக்கு விகிதத்தில் பஸ் கட்டணத்தை குறைக்குமாறு போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி, திருத்தப்பட்ட கட்டணங்கள் நாளை அறிவிக்கப்படும் அதேவேளை, நாளை (ஜூலை 19) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் பேருந்து கட்டணத்தை குறைக்குமாறு அமைச்சர் NTCக்கு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CEYPETCO) மற்றும் லங்கா இந்தியன் எண்ணெய் நிறுவனம் (LIOC) ஆகியவை எரிபொருள் விலைகளை நேற்று (17) இரவு 10 மணி முதல் குறைத்துள்ளன.",
        "CEYPETCO மற்றும் LIOC ஆகியவை ஒரு லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் (ஒக்டேன் 92) ரூபாவால் குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அறிவித்துள்ளன. 20 ரூபாவும், ஒரு லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் (ஒக்டேன் 95) ரூபாவும் குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 10.",
        "ஒரு லிட்டர் டீசல் விலை ரூ.5 குறைக்கப்பட்டது. 20 ஆகவும், ஒரு லிட்டர் சூப்பர் டீசல் ரூ. 10.",
        "இதேவேளை, நாட்டிலுள்ள தனியார் பஸ் சேவையாளர்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் இரண்டு பிரதான சங்கங்களான அகில இலங்கை பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் மற்றும் லங்கா தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கமும் எரிபொருள் விலை திருத்தத்திற்கு ஏற்ப பஸ் கட்டணத்தை 4% குறைக்க விருப்பம் தெரிவித்துள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "என்.டி.சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா இந்திய எண்ணெய் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}