{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ඉන්දියානා-සාප්පු-සංකීර්ණ-වෙඩි-තැබීමකින්-4ක්-මරුට/3-395499",
  "time_ut": 1658124108,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දියානා සාප්පු සංකීර්ණ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් 4ක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "4 dead in Indiana mall shooting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At least four people, including the shooter, have died in a shooting that took place at the Greenwood Park mall in Indianapolis, Indiana, United States of America.",
        "According to the police, two other Poodles were injured in the incident.",
        "Indiana State Police told reporters that the mass shooter who opened fire inside a restaurant at the Greenwood Park Mall was also killed.",
        "The shooter's motive is not yet known, but the shooter was armed with a rifle and several magazines.",
        "People who were inside the mall at the time of the shooting told the media that they heard 20 gunshots inside the restaurant."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indiana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "At least four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indianapolis",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indiana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poodles",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indiana State Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Greenwood Park Mall",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියානා සාප්පු සංකීර්ණ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් 4ක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ, ඉන්දියානා ප්‍රාන්තයේ ඉන්ඩියානාපොලිස් හි ග්‍රීන්වුඩ් පාර්ක් සාප්පු සංකීර්ණයේ සිදු වූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් වෙඩික්කරු ඇතුළු අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් සිව් දෙනෙකු මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "පොලීසියට අනුව මෙම සිද්ධියෙන් තවත් පුද්ලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දියානා ප්‍රාන්ත පොලිසිය වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසුවේ, ග්‍රීන්වුඩ් පාර්ක් සාප්පු සංකීර්ණයේ අවන්හලක් තුළ වෙඩි තැබූ සමූහ වෙඩික්කරුද ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "වෙඩි තැබූ පුද්ගලයාගේ චේතනාව දැනට අනාවරණය වී නොමැති අතර, වෙඩි තැබූ පුද්ගලයා සතුව රයිෆලයක් සහ මැගසින් කිහිපයක් තිබී ඇත.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීම සිදුවන අවස්ථාවේ වෙළෙඳ සංකීර්ණය තුළ සිටි පුද්ගලයින් මාධ්‍ය වෙත කියා සිටියේ අවන්හල තුළ වෙඩි හඬ 20ක් ඇසුණු බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියානා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් හතරක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ඩියානාපොලිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූඩ්ල්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානා ප්‍රාන්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්‍රීන්වුඩ් පාර්ක් වෙළඳ සංකීර්ණය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியானா மால் துப்பாக்கி சூட்டில் 4 பேர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவின் இண்டியானாபோலிஸில் உள்ள கிரீன்வுட் பார்க் மாலில் நடந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் உட்பட குறைந்தது நான்கு பேர் உயிரிழந்தனர்.",
        "இச்சம்பவத்தில் மேலும் இரண்டு பூடில்கள் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாக காவல்துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கிரீன்வுட் பார்க் மாலில் உள்ள உணவகத்திற்குள் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்திய மாஸ் ஷூட்டரும் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக இந்தியானா மாநில காவல்துறை செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவரின் நோக்கம் இன்னும் அறியப்படவில்லை, ஆனால் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் பல பத்திரிகைகளுடன் ஆயுதம் ஏந்தியிருந்தார்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடந்தபோது மாலுக்குள் இருந்தவர்கள், உணவகத்திற்குள் 20 துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சத்தம் கேட்டதாக ஊடகங்களுக்குத் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியானா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இண்டியானாபோலிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூடில்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியானா மாநில போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரீன்வுட் பார்க் மால்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}