{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/August-tourist-arrivals-dip-20-from-July/108-244249",
  "time_ut": 1662142143,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "August tourist arrivals dip 20% from July",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "August tourist arrivals dip 20% from July",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Destination SL inches away from reaching half a million arrivals mark for 2022",
        "UK, India and Germany rank as top three source markets for August",
        "SriLankan Airlines, Qatar Airways and Emirates rank as top three carriers that have helped generate tourist traffic to SL",
        "The tourist arrivals for the month of August witnessed a 20 percent dip when compared with the previous month, with the numbers totalling to 37,760.",
        "With the August number, the arrivals for the first eight months of the year totalled to 496,420, making Sri Lanka inches away from the half a million mark.",
        "The August arrival figure is a dip when compared with the marginal increase in the number of international visitors entering the country seen in the month of June and July. After the impressive arrivals seen in March (106,500), the highest since Sri Lanka opened for tourism after the pandemic, the numbers crumbled to 62,980 in April and then further contracted to 30,207 in May, due to the worsening of the political and economic crisis in the country.",
        "The month of June and July saw the arrivals improve to 32,856 and 47,293. However, the reimposition of travel advisories against the island nation resulted in dampened arrival numbers for August.",
        "The provisional data from the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority show that the first week of August had the highest weekly arrivals (11,046), after which the number of international visitors entering the country continued to decline for the next two weeks and picked up once again in the final week (8,847).  The improvement in August week three from week two (8,317) can be attributed to the increase in confidence amongst tourists around the world to visit destination Sri Lanka, as the country’s situation began to improve.",
        "The top source markets for Sri Lanka tourism for August are the United Kingdom, India and Germany, whereas the top three airlines that contributed to the arrivals are SriLankan Airlines, Qatar Airways and Emirates Airlines.  The cumulative analysis shows that for the January 01 to August 31 period, the top three tourist traffic generators are India, the United Kingdom and Russian Federation.",
        "With the political and economic environment showing some improvement and less volatility than what was witnessed in the months of April and May, tourist source markets began relaxing travel advisories to the country last week.",
        "Majority of the nations relaxed the travel advisories from Level 3 (orange) - ‘Reconsider need to travel, to Level 2 (yellow) - ‘Exercise a high degree of caution. A further relaxation will place Sri Lanka among the ‘green’ nations where tourists are advised to ‘Exercise normal safety precaution’, which is the lowest advisory. A higher advisory means higher risk.",
        "Some of the countries that relaxed the travel advisory to Sri Lanka include the UK, Sweden, Denmark, the Netherlands and Norway."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "August",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "half a million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Airways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the month of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37,760",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first eight months of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "496,420",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the half a million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of June and July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62,980",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,207",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The month of June and July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,293",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11,046",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the final week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,847",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August week three from week two",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,317",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Airways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the January 01 to August 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian Federation",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the months of April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sweden",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Denmark",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norway",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගෝස්තු මාසයේ සංචාරක පැමිණීම ජූලි මාසයේ සිට 20% කින් පහත වැටේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගමනාන්තය 2022 සඳහා මිලියන භාගයක පැමිණීමේ ලකුණට ළඟා වීමට අඟල් දුරින්",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය, ඉන්දියාව සහ ජර්මනිය අගෝස්තු සඳහා හොඳම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙලඳපොලවල් තුන ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස්, කටාර් එයාර්වේස් සහ එමිරේට්ස් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරක ගමනාගමනය උත්පාදනය කිරීමට උපකාරී වූ ප්‍රමුඛතම ගුවන් සමාගම් තුන ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය මාසය හා සසඳන විට අගෝස්තු මාසය සඳහා සංචාරක පැමිණීම් සියයට 20 කින් අඩු වී ඇති අතර, එම සංඛ්‍යාව 37,760 ක් විය.",
        "අගෝස්තු සංඛ්‍යාව සමඟ, වසරේ මුල් මාස අට සඳහා පැමිණි මුළු සංඛ්‍යාව 496,420 ක් වූ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මිලියන භාගයේ සීමාවෙන් අඟල් දුරස් විය.",
        "ජූනි සහ ජූලි මාසවලදී රටට ඇතුළු වන ජාත්‍යන්තර අමුත්තන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාවේ ආන්තික වැඩිවීම හා සසඳන විට අගෝස්තු පැමිණීමේ අගය පහත වැටීමකි. වසංගතයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය සඳහා විවෘත කිරීමෙන් පසු ඉහළම මාර්තු මාසයේදී (106,500) දක්නට ලැබුණු ආකර්ෂණීය පැමිණීමෙන් පසුව, අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එම සංඛ්‍යාව 62,980 දක්වා කඩා වැටී පසුව මැයි මාසයේදී 30,207 දක්වා හැකිලී ගියේය. රට.",
        "ජූනි සහ ජූලි මාසවල පැමිණීම් 32,856 සහ 47,293 දක්වා වර්ධනය විය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දිවයිනට එරෙහිව සංචාරක උපදේශන නැවත ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අගෝස්තු සඳහා පැමිණීමේ සංඛ්‍යාව අඩු කිරීමට හේතු විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ තාවකාලික දත්තවලට අනුව අගෝස්තු මස මුල් සතියේ වැඩිම සතිපතා පැමිණීම් (11,046) සිදු වූ අතර ඉන් පසුව රට තුළට පැමිණෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර අමුත්තන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව ඉදිරි සති දෙක තුළ අඛණ්ඩව පහත වැටී නැවත වරක් ඉහළ ගියේය. අවසාන සතිය (8,847). දෙවන සතියේ සිට (8,317) අගෝස්තු මාසයේ තුන්වන සතියේ ඇති වූ දියුණුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගමනාන්තය වෙත පැමිණීමට ලොව පුරා සංචාරකයින් අතර ඇති විශ්වාසය වැඩිවීමට හේතු විය හැකි අතර, රටේ තත්ත්වය වැඩිදියුණු වීමට පටන් ගත්තේය.",
        "අගෝස්තු මාසය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයේ ප්‍රමුඛතම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළෙඳපොළ වන්නේ එක්සත් රාජධානිය, ඉන්දියාව සහ ජර්මනිය වන අතර, පැමිණීමට දායක වූ ප්‍රමුඛතම ගුවන් සමාගම් තුන වන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස්, කටාර් එයාර්වේස් සහ එමිරේට්ස් එයාර්ලයින්ස් වේ. සමුච්චිත විශ්ලේෂණයෙන් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ ජනවාරි 01 සිට අගෝස්තු 31 දක්වා කාලය සඳහා සංචාරක රථවාහන උත්පාදකයින් තුන වන්නේ ඉන්දියාව, එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව බවයි.",
        "දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික පරිසරය අප්‍රේල් සහ මැයි මාසවල දක්නට ලැබුණු ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා යම් දියුණුවක් සහ අඩු අස්ථාවරත්වයක් පෙන්නුම් කිරීමත් සමඟ, සංචාරක මූලාශ්‍ර වෙලඳපොලවල් පසුගිය සතියේ රට වෙත සංචාරක උපදේශන ලිහිල් කිරීමට පටන් ගත්හ.",
        "බොහෝ ජාතීන් සංචාරක උපදේශන 3 මට්ටමේ (තැඹිලි) සිට ලිහිල් කර ඇත - 'ගමන් කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය නැවත සලකා බලන්න, 2 මට්ටමට (කහ) - 'ඉහළ ප්‍රවේශමෙන් ක්‍රියා කරන්න. තවදුරටත් ලිහිල් කිරීම මගින් සංචාරකයින්ට අවම උපදේශනය වන ‘සාමාන්‍ය ආරක්ෂක පූර්වෝපායන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලෙස’ උපදෙස් දෙන ‘හරිත’ ජාතීන් අතරට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පත් කරනු ඇත. ඉහළ උපදේශනයක් යනු ඉහළ අවදානමක්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරක උපදේශනය ලිහිල් කළ සමහර රටවල් අතරට එක්සත් රාජධානිය, ස්වීඩනය, ඩෙන්මාර්කය, නෙදර්ලන්තය සහ නෝර්වේ ඇතුළත් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජුලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන භාගයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් එයාර්වේස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37,760 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරේ මුල් මාස අට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "496,420 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන භාගයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි සහ ජූලි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62,980 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,207 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි සහ ජූලි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,293 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11,046 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,847 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකේ සිට අගෝස්තු තුන්වන සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,317 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් එයාර්වේස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 01 සිට අගෝස්තු 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෙන්මාර්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாத சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை ஜூலையில் இருந்து 20% குறைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலக்கு SL அங்குலங்கள் தொலைவில் 2022 இல் அரை மில்லியன் வருகையை எட்டுகிறது",
        "இங்கிலாந்து, இந்தியா மற்றும் ஜெர்மனி ஆகியவை ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கான முதல் மூன்று மூல சந்தைகளாக தரவரிசையில் உள்ளன",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ், கத்தார் ஏர்வேஸ் மற்றும் எமிரேட்ஸ் ஆகியவை இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை உருவாக்க உதவிய முதல் மூன்று கேரியர்களாக தரவரிசையில் உள்ளன.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை முந்தைய மாதத்துடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது 20 சதவீதம் சரிவைக் கண்டுள்ளது, மொத்தம் 37,760 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தின் எண்ணிக்கையுடன், ஆண்டின் முதல் எட்டு மாதங்களில் மொத்தமாக 496,420 பேர் வருகை தந்தனர்.",
        "ஜூன் மற்றும் ஜூலை மாதங்களில் நாட்டிற்குள் நுழையும் சர்வதேச பார்வையாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையில் காணப்படும் சிறிதளவு அதிகரிப்புடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது ஆகஸ்ட் வருகையின் எண்ணிக்கை ஒரு சரிவு. மார்ச் மாதத்தில் (106,500) காணப்பட்ட ஈர்க்கக்கூடிய வருகையின் பின்னர், தொற்றுநோய்க்குப் பின்னர் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாவிற்கு திறக்கப்பட்டதிலிருந்து மிக உயர்ந்த எண்ணிக்கையாக இருந்தது, ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் எண்ணிக்கை 62,980 ஆக சரிந்தது, பின்னர் அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மோசமடைந்ததன் காரணமாக மே மாதத்தில் 30,207 ஆக சுருங்கியது. நாடு.",
        "ஜூன் மற்றும் ஜூலை மாதங்களில் வருகை 32,856 மற்றும் 47,293 ஆக அதிகரித்துள்ளது. எவ்வாறாயினும், தீவு நாட்டிற்கு எதிரான பயண ஆலோசனைகளை மீண்டும் அமல்படுத்தியதன் விளைவாக ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கான வருகை எண்ணிக்கை குறைந்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் தற்காலிக தரவுகள், ஆகஸ்டு முதல் வாரத்தில் அதிக வாராந்த வருகையை (11,046) பெற்றதாகக் காட்டுகின்றன, அதன் பின்னர் நாட்டிற்குள் நுழையும் சர்வதேச பார்வையாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து குறைந்து, மீண்டும் ஒருமுறை அதிகரித்தது. இறுதி வாரம் (8,847). ஆகஸ்ட் வாரத்தில் மூன்றாம் வாரத்தில் இருந்து இரண்டு வாரத்தில் (8,317) ஏற்பட்ட முன்னேற்றம், நாட்டின் நிலைமை மேம்படத் தொடங்கியதால், உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தருவதற்கான நம்பிக்கையை அதிகரித்ததன் காரணமாகக் கூறலாம்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கான இலங்கை சுற்றுலாவுக்கான சிறந்த ஆதார சந்தைகள் ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம், இந்தியா மற்றும் ஜேர்மனி ஆகும், அதேசமயம் வருகைக்கு பங்களித்த முதல் மூன்று விமான நிறுவனங்கள் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ், கத்தார் ஏர்வேஸ் மற்றும் எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் ஆகும். ஜனவரி 01 முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 31 வரையிலான காலக்கட்டத்தில், இந்தியா, யுனைடெட் கிங்டம் மற்றும் ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு ஆகியவை முதல் மூன்று சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்து உருவாக்குநர்கள் என்று ஒட்டுமொத்த பகுப்பாய்வு காட்டுகிறது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் மற்றும் மே மாதங்களில் காணப்பட்டதை விட அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார சூழல் சில முன்னேற்றம் மற்றும் குறைந்த ஏற்ற இறக்கத்தை காட்டுவதால், சுற்றுலா மூல சந்தைகள் கடந்த வாரம் நாட்டிற்கான பயண ஆலோசனைகளை தளர்த்தத் தொடங்கின.",
        "பெரும்பான்மையான நாடுகள் லெவல் 3 (ஆரஞ்சு) இலிருந்து பயண ஆலோசனைகளை தளர்த்தியுள்ளன - ‘பயணத்தின் தேவையை நிலை 2 (மஞ்சள்) க்கு மறுபரிசீலனை செய்யுங்கள் - ‘அதிக அளவு எச்சரிக்கையுடன் செயல்படுங்கள். மேலும் தளர்வு இலங்கையை ‘பசுமை’ நாடுகளின் பட்டியலில் சேர்க்கும், அங்கு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் ‘சாதாரண பாதுகாப்பு முன்னெச்சரிக்கையை கடைப்பிடிக்க’ அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகிறார்கள், இது மிகக் குறைந்த ஆலோசனையாகும். அதிக ஆலோசனை என்றால் அதிக ஆபத்து.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம், சுவீடன், டென்மார்க், நெதர்லாந்து மற்றும் நார்வே ஆகிய நாடுகள் இலங்கைக்கான பயண ஆலோசனையை தளர்த்திய நாடுகளில் சில."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அரை மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஏர்வேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37,760",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் முதல் எட்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "496,420",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரை மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மற்றும் ஜூலை மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62,980",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,207",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மற்றும் ஜூலை மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,293",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11,046",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இறுதி வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,847",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் வாரம் மூன்று முதல் வாரம் இரண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,317",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஏர்வேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 01 முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டென்மார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}