{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/UN-Special-Rapporteur-raises-concerns-on-arrests-of-IUSF-activists-under-PTA/56-738957",
  "time_ut": 1661115225,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UN Special Rapporteur raises concerns on arrests of IUSF activists under PTA",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UN Special Rapporteur raises concerns on arrests of IUSF activists under PTA",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "UN Special Rapporteur calls on President to not sign detention orders",
        "UN Special Rapporteur on Human Rights Defenders Mary Lawlor has expressed her concern about the arrests of Inter-University Students Federation (IUSF) activists Wasantha Mudalige, Hashan Jeevantha and Galwewa Siridamma Thera under Sri Lanka’s draconian Prevention of Terrorism Act.",
        "The trio were arrested last Thursday by the Sri Lanka Police following a protest by the IUSF against the ‘Ranil Wickremesinghe - Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna’ Government in Colombo. Mudalige already had a pending arrest warrant against him at the time.",
        "Following their arrests, a 72-hour detention order was obtained from a Superintendent of Police to detain and interrogate the three arrestees the Police said.",
        "According to Police Spokesman SSP Nihla Talduwa, they were detained in order to be questioned about the violent incidents that took place across the country following the 31 March protest near the private residence of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa in Mirihana.",
        "“More incidents of violence took place on 9 May, 9 July and 13 July,” he said, adding that Mudalige’s statements to the media thereafter made it seem he had a link to these incidents.",
        "“The IGP had ordered Senior Officers to look into this possibility and they had reported back that a conspiracy against the state was in play and that it should be investigated,” he said.",
        "Talduwa also confirmed that investigators have requested the approval of the Minister of Defence, President Ranil Wickremesinghe to extend the detention of the activists for further questioning.",
        "But Lawlor has called on President Wickremesinghe not to sign their detention order. “Doing so would be a dark day for Sri Lanka,” she said.",
        "Meanwhile, the interrogation of Mudalige and two others were handed over to the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) yesterday on the instructions of IGP C.D. Wickramaratne."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UN Special Rapporteur",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UN Special Rapporteur",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN Special Rapporteur on",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mary Lawlor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inter-University Students Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashan Jeevantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galwewa Siridamma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna’ Government",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "72-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nihla Talduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 31 March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July and 13 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lawlor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP C.D. Wickramaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ අවිශිබම ක්‍රියාකාරීන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු කනස්සල්ල මතු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රැඳවුම් නියෝග අත්සන් නොකරන ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ (අවිශිබම) ක්‍රියාකාරීන් වන වසන්ත මුදලිගේ, හෂාන් ජීවන්ත සහ ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමියන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුරිරු ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්ෂකයින් පිළිබඳ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු මේරි ලෝලර් සිය කනස්සල්ල පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "‘රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ’ රජයට එරෙහිව අවිශිබම විසින් කොළඹදී පැවැත්වූ විරෝධතාවයකින් පසු මෙම තිදෙනා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් පසුගිය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී. මුදලිගේ ඒ වන විටත් ඔහුට එරෙහිව අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුවක් තිබුණි.",
        "ඔවුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් පසු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තිදෙනා රඳවාගෙන ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම සඳහා පැය 72ක රැඳවුම් නියෝගයක් පොලිස් අධිකාරිවරයකුගෙන් ලබා ගත් බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහ්ල තල්දූව මහතා සඳහන් කළේ, පසුගිය මාර්තු 31 වැනිදා මිරිහානේ පිහිටි හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස අසල පැවති විරෝධතාවයෙන් අනතුරුව රට පුරා ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී සිදුවීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන් රඳවා තබා ගත් බවයි.",
        "“තවත් ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා මැයි 9, ජුලි 9 සහ ජූලි 13 යන දිනවල සිදු විය,” මුදලිගේ ඉන් පසුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත කළ ප්‍රකාශවලින් පෙනී ගියේ මෙම සිදුවීම්වලට තමාට සම්බන්ධයක් ඇති බව පෙනෙන්නට ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"මෙම හැකියාව පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන ලෙස පොලිස්පතිවරයා ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්ට නියෝග කර තිබූ අතර, රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත්, එය විමර්ශනය කළ යුතු බවටත් ඔවුන් නැවත වාර්තා කර තිබුණා,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ක්‍රියාකාරීන් තවදුරටත් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම සඳහා රඳවා තබා ගැනීම දීර්ඝ කිරීමට ආරක්ෂක රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ අනුමැතිය සඳහා විමර්ශකයින් ඉල්ලා ඇති බවද තල්දූව තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "එහෙත් ඔවුන්ගේ රැඳවුම් නියෝගයට අත්සන් නොකරන ලෙස ලෝලර් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත. “එසේ කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඳුරු දවසක් වනු ඇත,” ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "මේ අතර මුදලිගේ ඇතුළු දෙදෙනකුගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී.ගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි ඊයේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (සී.අයි.ඩී.) භාරදී තිබිණි. වික්‍රමරත්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවිශිබම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු මත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේරි ලෝලර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෂාන් ජීවන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "72-පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් අධිකාරිවරයෙකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිහ්ලා තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9 සහ ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝලර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී. වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IUSF செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் கைது செய்யப்படுவது குறித்து UN சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர் கவலைகளை எழுப்பினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தடுப்புக்காவல் உத்தரவுகளில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம் என ஐ.நா.வின் சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்",
        "இலங்கையின் கொடூரமான பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் (IUSF) செயற்பாட்டாளர்களான வசந்த முதலிகே, ஹஷான் ஜீவந்த மற்றும் கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர் ஆகியோர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளமை குறித்து ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைப் பாதுகாவலர்கள் தொடர்பான விசேட அறிக்கையாளர் மேரி லோலர் கவலை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் ‘ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க – ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன’ அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக IUSF நடத்திய ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, கடந்த வியாழன் அன்று இலங்கை பொலிஸாரால் மூவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர். முதலிகே ஏற்கனவே அவருக்கு எதிராக கைது வாரண்ட் நிலுவையில் இருந்தது.",
        "அவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, கைது செய்யப்பட்ட மூவரையும் தடுத்து வைத்து விசாரணை நடத்துவதற்காக 72 மணி நேர காவலில் வைக்க காவல்துறை கண்காணிப்பாளரிடம் உத்தரவு பெறப்பட்டது.",
        "மிரிஹானவில் உள்ள முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு அருகில் கடந்த மார்ச் 31ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை அடுத்து நாடு முழுவதும் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்காகவே இவர்கள் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிஹ்ல தல்துவா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"மே 9, ஜூலை 9 மற்றும் ஜூலை 13 ஆகிய தேதிகளில் அதிக வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்கள் நடந்தன,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், அதன்பின் ஊடகங்களுக்கு முதலிகேவின் அறிக்கைகள் இந்த சம்பவங்களுடன் அவருக்கு தொடர்பு இருப்பதாகத் தெரிகிறது.",
        "\"இந்த சாத்தியத்தை ஆராய மூத்த அதிகாரிகளுக்கு ஐஜிபி உத்தரவிட்டார், மேலும் அவர்கள் அரசுக்கு எதிரான சதி நாடகத்தில் இருப்பதாகவும், அது விசாரிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர்கள் மீண்டும் அறிக்கை அளித்தனர்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக காவலில் வைக்க பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் விசாரணையாளர்கள் அனுமதி கோரியுள்ளதாகவும் தல்துவா உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "ஆனால் அவர்களை தடுத்து வைக்கும் உத்தரவில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம் என லோலர் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார். அவ்வாறு செய்வது இலங்கைக்கு இருண்ட நாளாக அமையும் என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, முதலிகே மற்றும் இருவரது விசாரணைகள் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சி.டி.யின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் நேற்று குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்திடம் (சிஐடி) ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டது. விக்கிரமரத்ன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐநா சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐநா சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேரி லாலர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷன் ஜீவந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "72-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு போலீஸ் சூப்பிரண்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஹ்லா தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை மற்றும் 13 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஜிபி சி.டி. விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}