{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83921/opaque-loans-from-china-hurt-sri-lanka-usaid-administrator",
  "time_ut": 1658977560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Opaque’ loans from China hurt Sri Lanka - USAID Administrator",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Opaque’ loans from China hurt Sri Lanka - USAID Administrator",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "“Opaque” loans for “headline-grabbing” infrastructure projects, were among the factors behind the current crisis that has engulfed Sri Lanka, said Samantha Power, Administrator, United States Agency for International Development (USAID), on Wednesday.",
        "Delivering a speech at the IIT-Delhi, Ms. Power praised India’s “swift” action in response to the emergency in Sri Lanka and argued that India’s strength especially in the field of tackling food security threats, was nurtured over the past seven decades in partnership with the United States.",
        "Ms. Power cited the Upanishads and urged India to play a greater role in the world in tackling hunger and poverty, which have intensified in the backdrop of the Ukraine crisis. She made a strong pitch in favour of “pluralism and tolerance” saying there are “forces in the United States and India who seek to sow divisions, who seek to pitch ethnicities and religions against each other”.",
        "“Indeed, over the past two decades, China became one of Sri Lanka’s biggest creditors, offering often opaque loan deals at higher interest rates than other lenders, and financing a raft of headline-grabbing infrastructure projects with often questionable practical use for Sri Lankans,” said Ms. Power.",
        "China, she pointed out, has not answered calls for greater relief to Sri Lanka, and said the “biggest question of all is whether Beijing will restructure debt to the same extent as other bilateral creditors”.",
        "She said the United States extended $180 million to Sri Lanka in emergency financing in 2022 and praised India for coming to Colombo’s help, saying, “The Government of India has already supplied $16 million in humanitarian aid to Sri Lanka, it has exported 100,000 tons of organic fertilizer to try to help farmers stave off future food shortages, and it has supplied $3.5 billion in Lines of Credits to the Government of Sri Lanka as it attempts to steer its economy out of default and further collapse.”",
        "Ms. Power painted a broad canvas of possible partnership between India and the United States based upon Cold War era instances of American support to Delhi, leading up to the launch of the Green Revolution. Ms. Power said India had proved itself capable of helping the “Global South” soon after attaining independence.",
        "The American official met with External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar and Foreign Secretary Vinay Mohan Kwatra, on Tuesday. She announced that the U.S. will invest $ 25 million in a new partnership with India for promoting agroforestry. “Across these past 75 years, India has always shown itself to be a friend to the world’s poor. Now, when the stakes have rarely been higher, India stands able to be an incredibly impactful development leader. ,” said Ms. Power.",
        "Ms. Power sounded a note of caution about the cascading political effect that global food insecurity can have in the coming months. “Sri Lanka’s government was the first to fall. 17 countries are facing (similar) protests,” said Ms. Power.",
        "During a brief press conference following the speech, Ms. Power said that she recognised that despite global expectations from India to help reduce food insecurity elsewhere, New Delhi will have to rise to its “sovereign responsibility” to look after food security at home first. She however, said, export restrictions are not the best way to address food security issues at home, and argued agriculture surplus countries can continue food supplies despite import restrictions for addressing “grave humanitarian emergencies” in different parts of the world.",
        "In her speech, Ms. Power mentioned the role that private capital can play in ensuring food security. When asked about the farmers’ protest against private investment in agriculture, she argued that there is “not enough public sector financing” in countering critical collective challenges like climate change (and its fallouts like food insecurity) and said therefore “private sector has become absolutely indispensable.”",
        "“Public-private partnership has become more catalytic. Food security resilience will come from that kind of investment, different from grand financing,” said Ms. Power."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Administrator",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United States Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past seven decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upanishads",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past two decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$180 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Government of India",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "$16 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lines of Credits",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Green Revolution",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the “Global South”",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vinay Mohan Kwatra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 25 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "these past 75 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනයෙන් ලැබෙන ‘Opaque’ ණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හානියක් - USAID පරිපාලක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගිලගෙන ඇති වත්මන් අර්බුදය පිටුපස ඇති සාධක අතර “ශීර්ෂ පාඨය අල්ලාගැනීමේ” යටිතල පහසුකම් ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා “පාරා නොපෙනී” ණය ලබා දීම බව ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ එක්සත් ජනපද ඒජන්සියේ (USAID) පරිපාලක සමන්තා පවර් බදාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "IIT-Delhi හි දේශනයක් පවත්වමින්, පවර් මහත්මිය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හදිසි අවස්ථාවට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ “කඩිනම්” ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය පැසසුමට ලක් කළ අතර, විශේෂයෙන් ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා තර්ජනවලට මුහුණ දීමේ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ඉන්දියාවේ ශක්තිය පසුගිය දශක හත තුළ හවුල්කාරිත්වයෙන් පෝෂණය වූ බව තර්ක කළාය. එක්සත් ජනපදය සමඟ.",
        "පවර් මහත්මිය උපනිෂද් උපුටා දක්වමින් යුක්රේන අර්බුදයේ පසුබිම තුළ තීව්‍ර වී ඇති කුසගින්න සහ දරිද්‍රතාවයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ලෝකය තුළ විශාල කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරන ලෙස ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියාය. \"බහුවිධත්වය සහ ඉවසීම\" වෙනුවෙන් ඇය ප්‍රබල තාරතාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර, \"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සහ ඉන්දියාවේ බෙදීම් වැපිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන, ජාතීන් සහ ආගම් එකිනෙකාට එරෙහිව නැගී සිටීමට උත්සාහ කරන බලවේග සිටින\" බව පවසමින්.",
        "“ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, පසුගිය දශක දෙක තුළ චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාලතම ණය දෙන්නා බවට පත් වූ අතර, අනෙකුත් ණය දෙන්නන්ට වඩා වැඩි පොලී අනුපාත යටතේ බොහෝ විට විනිවිද නොපෙනෙන ණය ගනුදෙනු ලබා දෙමින් සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සඳහා බොහෝ විට සැක සහිත ප්‍රායෝගික භාවිතයක් සහිත ප්‍රධාන පෙළේ යටිතල පහසුකම් ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා මූල්‍ය සම්පාදනය කළේය. ” පවර් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "චීනය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැඩි සහන සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම්වලට පිළිතුරු දී නොමැති බව පෙන්වා දුන් චීනය, “සියල්ලටම ඇති ලොකුම ප්‍රශ්නය වන්නේ බීජිනය අනෙකුත් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්ට සමාන ප්‍රමාණයකට ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරන්නේද යන්නයි”.",
        "2022 දී එක්සත් ජනපදය හදිසි මූල්‍ය ආධාර ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 180 ක් ලබා දුන් බවත්, කොළඹගේ උදව්වට පැමිණීම ගැන ඉන්දියාවට ප්‍රශංසා කළ බවත් ඇය පැවසුවාය, “ඉන්දියා රජය දැනටමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 16 ක් මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබා දී ඇති අතර එය ටොන් 100,000 ක් අපනයනය කර ඇත. අනාගත ආහාර හිඟය මගහරවා ගැනීමට ගොවීන්ට උපකාර කිරීමට කාබනික පොහොර උත්සාහ කරන අතර, එහි ආර්ථිකය පෙරනිමියෙන් හා තවදුරටත් කඩා වැටීමෙන් ඉවතට ගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කරන බැවින් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ක් ණය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "හරිත විප්ලවය දියත් කිරීම දක්වාම දිල්ලියට ඇමරිකානු සහාය ලබා දුන් සීතල යුද යුගයේ අවස්ථා මත පදනම්ව පවර් මහත්මිය ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය අතර ඇති විය හැකි හවුල්කාරිත්වයේ පුළුල් කැන්වසයක් පින්තාරු කළාය. නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු \"ගෝලීය දකුණට\" උදව් කිරීමට ඉන්දියාවට හැකියාව ඇති බව පවර් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඇමරිකානු නිලධාරියා අඟහරුවාදා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය S. Jaishankar සහ විදේශ ලේකම් Vinay Mohan Kwatra හමුවිය. කෘෂි වන වගාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව සමඟ නව හවුල්කාරිත්වයක් සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 ක් ආයෝජනය කරන බව ඇය නිවේදනය කළාය. “පසුගිය වසර 75 පුරාවටම ඉන්දියාව සෑම විටම ලෝකයේ දුප්පතුන්ගේ මිතුරෙකු බව පෙන්නුම් කර ඇත. දැන්, කොටස් කලාතුරකින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති විට, ඉන්දියාව ඇදහිය නොහැකි තරම් බලපෑම් සහගත සංවර්ධන නායකයෙකු වීමට හැකි වේ. ,” පවර් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඉදිරි මාසවලදී ගෝලීය ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට ඇති විය හැකි කඩාවැටෙන දේශපාලන බලපෑම පිළිබඳව පවර් මහත්මිය අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ සටහනක් තැබුවාය. “පළමුවෙන්ම වැටුනේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයයි. රටවල් 17ක් (සමාන) විරෝධතාවලට මුහුණ දී සිටිනවා,” පවර් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "කතාවෙන් අනතුරුව පැවති කෙටි මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී, පවර් මහත්මිය පැවසුවේ, වෙනත් රටවල ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත භාවය අවම කිරීමට ඉන්දියාවෙන් ගෝලීය අපේක්ෂාවන් තිබියදීත්, නව දිල්ලියට ප්‍රථමයෙන් නිවසේ ආහාර සුරක්‍ෂිතතාව ගැන සොයා බැලීමේ “ස්වෛරී වගකීම” වෙත නැඟී සිටිය යුතු බව තමන් හඳුනාගත් බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අපනයන සීමා කිරීම් නිවසේදී ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා ගැටළු විසඳීමට හොඳම ක්‍රමය නොවන බවත්, ලෝකයේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල “බරපතල මානුෂීය හදිසි අවස්ථා” ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම සඳහා ආනයන සීමා කිරීම් නොතකා කෘෂිකාර්මික අතිරික්ත රටවලට ආහාර සැපයුම් දිගටම කරගෙන යා හැකි බවත් ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ආහාර සුරක්‍ෂිතතාව තහවුරු කිරීමේදී පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රාග්ධනයට කළ හැකි කාර්යභාරය ගැන පවර් මහත්මිය සිය කතාවේදී සඳහන් කළාය. කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ පෞද්ගලික ආයෝජනයට එරෙහිව ගොවීන්ගේ විරෝධතාව ගැන විමසූ විට, දේශගුණික විපර්යාස (සහ ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත භාවය වැනි එහි බිඳවැටීම්) වැනි තීරණාත්මක සාමූහික අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීමේදී “ප්‍රමාණවත් රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ මූල්‍යකරණයක් නොමැති” බව ඇය තර්ක කළාය. අත්‍යවශ්‍ය.”",
        "“රාජ්‍ය පෞද්ගලික හවුල්කාරිත්වය වඩාත් උත්ප්‍රේරක වී ඇත. මහා මූල්‍යකරණයට වඩා වෙනස් වූ එවැනි ආයෝජනයකින් ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවයට ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව ලැබෙනු ඇත,” පවර් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිපාලක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද නියෝජිතායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර සංවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශක හත",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපනිෂද්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශක දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 180 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 16 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 100,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය රේඛා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත විප්ලවය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"ගෝලීය දකුණ\"",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනේ මෝහන් ක්වාත්‍රා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ පසුගිය අවුරුදු 75",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனாவின் ‘ஒப்பக்’ கடன்கள் இலங்கையை பாதித்துள்ளது - USAID நிர்வாகி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியின் பின்னணியில் உள்ள காரணிகளில் ஒன்றாக, \"தலைப்புரையை இழுக்கும்\" உள்கட்டமைப்பு திட்டங்களுக்கான \"ஒளிபுகா\" கடன்கள் உள்ளன என்று, சர்வதேச அபிவிருத்திக்கான ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்காவின் ஏஜென்சியின் (USAID) நிர்வாகி சமந்தா பவர் புதன்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஐஐடி-டெல்லியில் உரை நிகழ்த்திய திருமதி. பவர், இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்ட அவசரநிலைக்கு பதிலடி கொடுக்கும் வகையில் இந்தியாவின் \"விரைவான\" நடவடிக்கையை பாராட்டியதுடன், குறிப்பாக உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு அச்சுறுத்தல்களை எதிர்கொள்ளும் துறையில் இந்தியாவின் பலம் கடந்த ஏழு தசாப்தங்களாக கூட்டாண்மை மூலம் வளர்க்கப்பட்டது என்றும் வாதிட்டார். அமெரிக்காவுடன்.",
        "திருமதி. பவர் உபநிடதங்களை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, உக்ரைன் நெருக்கடியின் பின்னணியில் தீவிரமடைந்துள்ள பசி மற்றும் வறுமையைச் சமாளிப்பதில் உலகில் இந்தியா அதிகப் பங்கு வகிக்க வேண்டும் என்று வலியுறுத்தினார். \"பன்மைத்துவம் மற்றும் சகிப்புத்தன்மைக்கு\" ஆதரவாக அவர் ஒரு வலுவான சுருதியை உருவாக்கினார், \"அமெரிக்காவிலும் இந்தியாவிலும் பிளவுகளை விதைக்க முற்படும் சக்திகள் உள்ளன, அவை இனங்கள் மற்றும் மதங்களை ஒருவருக்கொருவர் எதிர்த்து நிற்க முயல்கின்றன\".",
        "\"உண்மையில், கடந்த இரண்டு தசாப்தங்களாக, சீனா இலங்கையின் மிகப்பெரிய கடன் வழங்குநர்களில் ஒருவராக மாறியது, மற்ற கடன் வழங்குபவர்களை விட அதிக வட்டி விகிதத்தில் ஒளிபுகா கடன் ஒப்பந்தங்களை வழங்குகிறது, மேலும் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு அடிக்கடி சந்தேகத்திற்குரிய நடைமுறைப் பயன்பாட்டுடன் தலையாய உள்கட்டமைப்பு திட்டங்களுக்கு நிதியளித்தது. ” என்றாள் சக்தி செல்வி.",
        "சீனா, இலங்கைக்கு அதிக நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்கான அழைப்புகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கவில்லை என்று அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார், மேலும் \"பெய்ஜிங் மற்ற இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களைப் போலவே கடனை மறுசீரமைக்குமா என்பதே அனைவரின் மிகப்பெரிய கேள்வி\" என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் அவசரகால நிதியுதவியாக இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா 180 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை வழங்கியது என்றும், கொழும்பின் உதவிக்கு இந்தியா வந்ததற்குப் பாராட்டு தெரிவித்ததாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். கரிம உரங்கள் விவசாயிகளுக்கு எதிர்கால உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறையைத் தடுக்க உதவுகின்றன, மேலும் அது இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு 3.5 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடன்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது, ஏனெனில் அது அதன் பொருளாதாரத்தை இயல்புநிலை மற்றும் மேலும் சரிவிலிருந்து வெளியேற்ற முயற்சிக்கிறது.",
        "பசுமைப் புரட்சியின் தொடக்கத்திற்கு வழிவகுத்த அமெரிக்க ஆதரவின் பனிப்போர் கால நிகழ்வுகளின் அடிப்படையில் இந்தியாவிற்கும் அமெரிக்காவிற்கும் இடையிலான சாத்தியமான கூட்டாண்மையின் பரந்த கேன்வாஸை திருமதி பவர் வரைந்தார். சுதந்திரம் அடைந்த உடனேயே \"உலகளாவிய தெற்கு\" பகுதிக்கு உதவ இந்தியா தன்னை நிரூபித்துள்ளதாக திருமதி பவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அமெரிக்க அதிகாரி செவ்வாயன்று வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர் மற்றும் வெளியுறவு செயலாளர் வினய் மோகன் குவாத்ராவை சந்தித்தார். வேளாண் காடுகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக இந்தியாவுடன் ஒரு புதிய கூட்டாண்மையில் அமெரிக்கா $ 25 மில்லியன் முதலீடு செய்யும் என்று அவர் அறிவித்தார். \"கடந்த 75 ஆண்டுகளில், இந்தியா எப்போதும் உலகின் ஏழைகளுக்கு நண்பனாகத் தன்னைக் காட்டி வருகிறது. இப்போது, ​​பங்குகள் அரிதாகவே அதிகமாக இருக்கும் போது, ​​இந்தியா நம்பமுடியாத தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் வளர்ச்சித் தலைவராக நிற்கிறது. ,” என்றார் செல்வி.",
        "வரவிருக்கும் மாதங்களில் உலகளாவிய உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை ஏற்படக்கூடிய அரசியல் விளைவுகளைப் பற்றி திருமதி. “இலங்கையின் அரசாங்கம் முதலில் வீழ்ந்தது. 17 நாடுகள் (ஒத்த) எதிர்ப்புகளை எதிர்கொள்கின்றன,” என்று திருமதி பவர் கூறினார்.",
        "உரையைத் தொடர்ந்து ஒரு சுருக்கமான செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​திருமதி. பவர், மற்ற இடங்களில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையைக் குறைக்க உதவும் உலகளாவிய எதிர்பார்ப்புகளை இந்தியா ஏற்றுக்கொண்டாலும், முதலில் வீட்டில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பைக் கவனிக்கும் \"இறையாண்மைப் பொறுப்பிற்கு\" புது தில்லி உயர வேண்டும். எவ்வாறாயினும், வீட்டில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்புப் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு ஏற்றுமதி கட்டுப்பாடுகள் சிறந்த வழி அல்ல என்றும், உலகின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள \"கடுமையான மனிதாபிமான அவசரநிலைகளுக்கு\" இறக்குமதி கட்டுப்பாடுகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், விவசாய உபரி நாடுகள் உணவுப் பொருட்களைத் தொடரலாம் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "திருமதி பவர் தனது உரையில், உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதில் தனியார் மூலதனம் ஆற்றக்கூடிய பங்கைக் குறிப்பிட்டார். விவசாயத்தில் தனியார் முதலீட்டுக்கு எதிரான விவசாயிகள் எதிர்ப்பு பற்றி கேட்டபோது, ​​காலநிலை மாற்றம் (மற்றும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை போன்ற அதன் வீழ்ச்சி) போன்ற முக்கியமான கூட்டு சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் \"போதுமான பொதுத்துறை நிதி இல்லை\" என்று வாதிட்டார், எனவே \"தனியார் துறை முற்றிலும் மாறிவிட்டது. தவிர்க்க முடியாத.\"",
        "“பொது-தனியார் கூட்டாண்மை மிகவும் ஊக்கமளிக்கிறது. பெரும் நிதியளிப்பில் இருந்து வேறுபட்ட, அந்த வகையான முதலீட்டில் இருந்து உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு பின்னடைவு வரும்,” என்று திருமதி பவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனைடெட் ஸ்டேட்ஸ் ஏஜென்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வளர்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஏழு தசாப்தங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபநிடதங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு தசாப்தங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$180 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "$16 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் வரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசுமைப் புரட்சி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"உலகளாவிய தெற்கு\"",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு விவகாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வினய் மோகன் குவாத்ரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 75 வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}