{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රට-කජු-ඕසෙට-කන්න-ලැබෙන-ළකුණු/1-618605",
  "time_ut": 1661237504,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රට කජු ඕසෙට කන්න ලැබෙන ළකුණු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Signs that the cashew nut can eat",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said that Sri Lanka has become self-sufficient in groundnuts and there is no need to import even the variety of cashew required for processing \"jumbo peanuts\".",
        "The Agriculture Minister said that the alternative groundnut variety \"Sri Lanka Jumbo\" cultivated in Sri Lanka is higher in quality than the imported groundnuts.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture stated this while attending the Sri Lanka Jumbo Groundnut Harvesting Program at the Middeniya Thorakolaya Government Seed Farm.",
        "According to the Department of Agriculture, 29 percent of the daily protein requirement for humans can be provided by eating these peanuts.",
        "Due to the increase in meat and fish prices, there is difficulty in getting the required amount of animal protein for the people, but the deficiency can be met due to the protein content of peanuts, says the Department of Agriculture.",
        "The annual requirement of peanuts in Sri Lanka is 30,000 metric tons and the Ministry of Agriculture says that 64,000 metric tons have been harvested from peanut cultivation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Jumbo",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Groundnut Harvesting Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middeniya Thorakolaya Government Seed Farm",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "64,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රට කජු ඕසෙට කන්න ලැබෙන ළකුණු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටකජු වලින් ලංකාව ස්වයංපෝෂිත වී ඇති අතර \"ජම්බෝ පීනට්ස්\"සැකසීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය වන කජු ප්‍රභේදයවත්  මින්පසු ආනයනය කරන්නට අවශ්‍යතාවයක් නැතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙරට වගා කරන ලද \"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජම්බෝ\" නම්  විකල්ප රටකජු ප්‍රභේදය ආනයනය කරන රටකජු වලට වඩා ගුණාත්මකභාවයෙන් ඉහළ බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය .",
        "මිද්දෙනිය  තෝරකොළයාය රජයේ බීජ ගොවිපොළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජම්බෝ රටකජු අස්වැන්න නෙලීමේ වැඩ සටහනට එක්වෙමින් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මිනිසුන්ට අවශ්‍ය දෛනික ප්‍රෝටීන ප්‍රමාණයෙන් සියයට 29ක් මෙම රටකජු ආහාරයට ගැනීම නිසා සපයා ගත හැකි බව කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "මස් හා මාළු මිල ගණන් ඉහළ යාම නිසා ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය සත්ව ප්‍රෝටීන් ප්‍රමාණය ලබා ගැනීමේ අපහසුතාවයක් පවතින නමුත් රටකජුවල අවශ්‍ය තරම් ප්‍රෝටීන් අන්තර්ගත නිසා එම අඩුව සපුරා ගත හැකි බව කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ලංකාවෙි වාර්ෂික රටකජු අවශ්‍යතාවය  මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000ක් වන අතර මේ වනවිට රටකජු වගාවෙන් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 64,000ක අස්වැන්නක් ලැබී ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජම්බෝ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රටකජු අස්වනු නෙලීමේ වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිද්දෙණිය තොරකොළය රජයේ බීජ ගොවිපල",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 29 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 64,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முந்திரி பருப்பு சாப்பிடலாம் என்பதற்கான அறிகுறிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிலக்கடலையில் இலங்கை தன்னிறைவு அடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், \"ஜம்போ வேர்கடலை\" பதப்படுத்துவதற்கு தேவையான முந்திரி வகைகளை கூட இறக்குமதி செய்ய வேண்டிய அவசியமில்லை எனவும் விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் பயிரிடப்படும் \"ஸ்ரீலங்கா ஜம்போ\" என்ற மாற்று நிலக்கடலை இறக்குமதி செய்யப்படும் நிலக்கடலையை விட தரத்தில் உயர்ந்தது என விவசாய அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மித்தெனிய தோரகொலயா அரச விதைப்பண்ணையில் நடைபெற்ற இலங்கை ஜம்போ நிலக்கடலை அறுவடை வேலைத்திட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்ட போதே விவசாய அமைச்சர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த வேர்க்கடலையை உண்பதன் மூலம் மனிதர்களுக்கு தினசரி தேவைப்படும் புரதத்தில் 29 சதவீதத்தை வழங்க முடியும் என வேளாண் துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இறைச்சி, மீன் விலை உயர்வால் மக்களுக்கு தேவையான அளவு விலங்கு புரதம் கிடைப்பதில் சிரமம் ஏற்பட்டாலும், வேர்க்கடலையில் உள்ள புரதச்சத்து காரணமாக பற்றாக்குறையை சமாளிக்க முடியும் என வேளாண் துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் வருடாந்த கடலையின் தேவை 30,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் எனவும், கடலைச் செய்கையில் 64,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் அறுவடை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜம்போ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலக்கடலை அறுவடை திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மித்தெனிய தோரகொலயா அரசாங்க விதைப்பண்ணை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "64,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}