{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83292/cabinet-approval-to-gazette-22nd-amendment-and-table-in-parliament",
  "time_ut": 1656350880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cabinet approval to gazette 22nd Amendment and table in Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cabinet approval to gazette 22nd Amendment and table in Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Cabinet of Ministers have approved the proposal to gazette the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution and to present it to the Parliament, Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe said.",
        "The amendment, which had been referred to as the 21st Amendment so far, will in fact be the 22nd Amendment, as another draft 21st Amendment has already been gazetted.",
        "Last week, the draft constitutional amendment was tabled and passed during the Cabinet meeting following extensive discussions.",
        "The 22nd Amendment was initially tabled in the Cabinet on June 06 by Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe and the discussion on it had been adjourned on multiple occasions due to failure to reach a consensus.",
        "The Constitutional Amendment is expected to empower Parliament over the executive president and annul the 20A to the Constitution, which had given unfetted unfettered powers to President after abolishing the 19th Amendment.",
        "Under the 22A, the President, the Cabinet of Ministers and the National Council will be held accountable to the Parliament. Fifteen Committees and Oversight Committees are also accountable to Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22nd Amendment",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 21st Amendment",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Constitutional Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers and the National Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fifteen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ගැසට් කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභාගත කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ගැසට් කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමේ යෝජනාව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇති බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මේ වන විට 21 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ලෙසින් හැඳින්වූ එම සංශෝධනය සත්‍ය වශයෙන්ම 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය වනු ඇත්තේ තවත් කෙටුම්පතක් 21 වැනි සංශෝධනයක් දැනටමත් ගැසට් කර ඇති බැවිනි.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ, පුළුල් සාකච්ඡාවලින් පසු කැබිනට් රැස්වීමේදී ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන කෙටුම්පත සභාගත කර සම්මත කරන ලදී.",
        "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ජූනි 06 වැනි දින අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කළේ ඇමැති විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ විසින් වන අතර ඒ පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාව අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදීම කල් දමා තිබුණේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීමට අපොහොසත් වීම හේතුවෙනි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය මඟින් විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා කෙරෙහි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට බලය පැවරීමටත්, 19 වැනි සංශෝධනය අහෝසි කිරීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අසීමිත අසීමිත බලතල ලබා දී තිබූ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 20A අවලංගු කිරීමටත් අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "22A යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා, අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ජාතික සභාව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට වග කිව යුතුයි. කාරක සභා පහළොවක් සහ අධීක්ෂණ කාරක සභා ද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට වගකිව යුතු ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ජාතික සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහළොව",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22வது திருத்தத்தை வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிட்டு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்பிக்க அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தத்தை வர்த்தமானியில் பிரகடனம் செய்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்பிப்பதற்கான யோசனைக்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "21ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் மற்றுமொரு வரைவு ஏற்கனவே வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளதால், இதுவரை 21ஆவது திருத்தம் என்று குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட திருத்தம் உண்மையில் 22ஆவது திருத்தமாகவே இருக்கும்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம், விரிவான விவாதங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தின் போது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்த வரைவு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டு நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டம் முதலில் ஜூன் 06ஆம் திகதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவினால் அமைச்சரவையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டதுடன் அது தொடர்பான விவாதம் பல தடவைகள் இணக்கப்பாட்டுக்கு வராத காரணத்தினால் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தமானது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியின் மீது பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அதிகாரம் அளிக்கும் என்றும், 19 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை இரத்து செய்ததன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தடையற்ற அதிகாரங்களை வழங்கிய அரசியலமைப்பின் 20A ஐ இரத்துச் செய்வதற்கும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "22A இன் கீழ், ஜனாதிபதி, அமைச்சரவை மற்றும் தேசிய கவுன்சில் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு பொறுப்புக் கூற வேண்டும். பதினைந்து குழுக்கள் மற்றும் மேற்பார்வைக் குழுக்களும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு பொறுப்புக் கூற வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை மற்றும் தேசிய கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதினைந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}