{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/24/hirunika-s-defender-abduction-case-postponed-for-13th-time/",
  "time_ut": 1661327220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hirunika’s Defender Abduction case postponed for 13th time",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika’s Defender Abduction case postponed for 13th time",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Hirunika Premachandra says one cannot condone causing damage to the property of public representatives under the guise of the people's struggle.",
        "Speaking outside the Colombo High Court on Wednesday (24), she said rather than arresting those who caused damage to property, authorities are chasing after the youth who engaged in protests.",
        "She said that the introduction of the QR-based fuel distribution and reduced power cuts are the results of the Aragalaya protests, including the appointment of the current President, who does not have a mandate from the people.",
        "She also condemned the use of the Prevention of Terrorism Act to crackdown the youth protesters.",
        "The Former MP said Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is always welcome to return to Sri Lanka, and slammed the Ex-President for One person injured in a shooting carried out by motorcycle gunmen in Makawita, Gampaha – PoliceOne person injured in a shooting carried out by motorcycle gunmen in Makawita, Gampaha – Police",
        "Hirunika Premachandra warned that the Aragalaya will have to be revived again by end of September.",
        "Hirunika Premachandra was at the Colombo High Court on Wednesday (24) to appear for a case where she is charged with the abduction of a youth, forced detention, and assault, back in 2015.",
        "Counsel appearing for Hirunika Premachandra requested the court for a new date for the case to be taken up, as her Senior Counsel had taken ill, and accordingly, the case was postponed to the 16th of November.",
        "The High Court Judge noted that since 2017 when the trial resumed, the matter has been postponed 13 times."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hirunika’s Defender Abduction",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "13th",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makawita",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makawita",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th of November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිරුණිකාගේ ඩිෆෙන්ඩර් පැහැරගැනීමේ නඩුව 13 වැනි වරටත් කල් යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනතා අරගලයට මුවා වී මහජන නියෝජිතයන්ගේ දේපළවලට හානි කිරීම කිසිසේත් අනුමත කළ නොහැකි බව හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය පවසයි.",
        "බදාදා (24) කොළඹ මහාධිකරණයෙන් පිටතදී අදහස් දක්වමින් ඇය කියා සිටියේ දේපළවලට හානි කළ පුද්ගලයන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නවාට වඩා බලධාරීන් විරෝධතාවල නිරත වූ තරුණයන් පසුපස හඹා යමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "QR පදනම් කරගත් ඉන්ධන බෙදාහැරීම හඳුන්වාදීම සහ විදුලි කප්පාදුව අඩු කිරීම ජනතා වරමක් නැති වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත් කිරීම ඇතුළු අරගල විරෝධතාවල ප්‍රතිඵල බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "තරුණ විරෝධතාකරුවන් මර්දනය කිරීමට ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යොදා ගැනීම ද ඇය හෙළා දකිනවා.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට සැමවිටම සාදරයෙන් පිළිගන්නා බව පැවසූ හිටපු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා, ගම්පහ, මාකාවිටදී යතුරුපැදි තුවක්කු කරුවන් විසින් සිදුකළ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් තුවාල ලැබූ එක් අයෙකු සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට බැණ වැදුණු බව සඳහන්. ගම්පහ මාකවිට තුවක්කුකරුවන් – පොලිසිය",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් මාසය අවසන් වන විට අරගල යළි පණ ගැන්වීමට සිදුවන බව හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර 2015 වසරේ තරුණයෙකු පැහැරගෙන යාම, බලහත්කාරයෙන් රඳවා තබා ගැනීම සහ පහරදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇති නඩුවක් සඳහා පෙනී සිටීමට බදාදා (24) කොළඹ මහාධිකරණයට පැමිණ සිටියා.",
        "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මියගේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥවරිය අසනීප වී ඇති බැවින් නඩුව කැඳවීමට නව දිනයක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඇය වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතිඥවරිය අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර ඒ අනුව නඩුව නොවැම්බර් 16 වැනිදාට කල් තැබිණි.",
        "මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරයා සඳහන් කළේ 2017 වසරේ සිට නඩු විභාගය යළි ආරම්භ වූ අවස්ථාවේ සිට මෙම නඩුව 13 වතාවක් කල් දැමූ බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හිරුණිකාගේ ඩිෆෙන්ඩර් පැහැර ගැනීම",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "13 වැනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකාවිට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකාවිට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 16 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஹிருணிகாவின் பாதுகாவலர் கடத்தல் வழக்கு 13வது முறையாக ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மக்கள் போராட்டம் என்ற போர்வையில் மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளின் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவிப்பதை மன்னிக்க முடியாது என ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு வெளியே புதன்கிழமை (24) உரையாற்றிய அவர், சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தவர்களைக் கைது செய்வதற்குப் பதிலாக, போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட இளைஞர்களை அதிகாரிகள் துரத்துகிறார்கள்.",
        "QR அடிப்படையிலான எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் மற்றும் குறைக்கப்பட்ட மின்வெட்டு ஆகியவை மக்கள் ஆணையைப் பெறாத தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியின் நியமனம் உட்பட அரகலயா போராட்டங்களின் விளைவுகளாகும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இளைஞர் போராட்டக்காரர்களை ஒடுக்க பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதையும் அவர் கண்டித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதை எப்போதும் வரவேற்கிறேன் என தெரிவித்த முன்னாள் எம்.பி., கம்பஹா மக்காவிட்டவில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் துப்பாக்கிதாரிகள் நடத்திய துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் காயமடைந்தமைக்காக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை கடுமையாக சாடியுள்ளார். கம்பஹா, மக்காவிட்டவில் ஆயுததாரிகள் – பொலிஸ்",
        "செப்டெம்பர் மாத இறுதிக்குள் மீண்டும் அரகலய புனரமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என ஹிருணிகா பிரேமசந்திர எச்சரித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர, 2015ஆம் ஆண்டு இளைஞரைக் கடத்தியமை, வலுக்கட்டாயமாகத் தடுத்துவைத்தல் மற்றும் தாக்கப்பட்டமை ஆகிய குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கு ஒன்றில் ஆஜராகுவதற்காக புதன்கிழமை (24) கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராகியிருந்தார்.",
        "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திரவின் சிரேஷ்ட சட்டத்தரணி சுகயீனமடைந்துள்ளதால் வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு புதிய திகதியை வழங்குமாறு ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி நீதிமன்றில் கோரியதையடுத்து வழக்கு எதிர்வரும் நவம்பர் மாதம் 16ஆம் திகதிக்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2017ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் வழக்கு விசாரணை மீண்டும் தொடங்கியதில் இருந்து 13 முறை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக உயர் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி குறிப்பிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஹிருணிகாவின் பாதுகாவலர் கடத்தல்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "13வது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாவிட்ட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாவிட்ட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 16 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}