{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/30/us-ambassador-meets-president/",
  "time_ut": 1656601380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US Ambassador meets President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US Ambassador meets President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); President Gotabaya Rajapaksa met with the USA Ambassador in Sri Lanka Julie J. Ching today (30) and thanked the US for the valuable support shown during these difficult times.",
        "Further, the Ambassador assured the Government of the USA’s continuous support in stabilizing the economy with the recent developments with the International Monetary Fund (IMF).",
        "US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung told President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that the US will support Sri Lanka in finding a solution to the economic crisis.",
        "A high-level diplomatic delegation from the United States stated that the US supports the strengthening of the relationship with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "US President Joe Biden has also taken steps to provide humanitarian assistance on several occasions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie J. Ching",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of the USA’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපතිවරයා ජනපති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද (30) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනී Julie J. Ching මහත්මිය හමුවී මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී දැක්වූ වටිනා සහයෝගය වෙනුවෙන් එක්සත් ජනපදයට ස්තූතිය පළ කළේය.",
        "තවද, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ මෑතකාලීන වර්ධනයන් සමඟ ආර්ථිකය ස්ථාවර කිරීම සඳහා ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද රජය අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දෙන බවට තානාපතිවරයා සහතික විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා අමෙරිකාවේ සහය ලබාදෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනී ජුලී චුන්ග් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග පවතින සබඳතාව ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට අමෙරිකාව සහාය දක්වන බව අමෙරිකාවේ ඉහළ පෙළේ රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "අමෙරිකානු ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් ද අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබාදීමට පියවර ගෙන තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලී ජේ. චිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்க தூதர் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று (30) இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் Julie J. Ching ஐ சந்தித்ததுடன், இந்த கடினமான காலங்களில் அமெரிக்கா வழங்கிய பெறுமதியான ஆதரவிற்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்களுடன் பொருளாதாரத்தை ஸ்திரப்படுத்துவதில் அமெரிக்க அரசாங்கத்தின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஆதரவை தூதுவர் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா ஆதரவளிக்கும் என இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான உறவை வலுப்படுத்த அமெரிக்கா ஆதரவளிப்பதாக அமெரிக்காவின் உயர்மட்ட இராஜதந்திரக் குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனும் பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி ஜே. சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்காவின் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}