{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/China-says-Ball-is-in-Sri-Lankas-court/108-243846",
  "time_ut": 1661566854,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China says Ball is in Sri Lanka’s court",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China says Ball is in Sri Lanka’s court",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Responding to Sri Lanka’s request for China to change its tune on debt relief, a spokesman for the Chinese embassy said the ball is in Sri Lanka’s court, not China’s.",
        "The spokesman told Daily Mirror China communicated to the Sri Lankan Finance Ministry three months ago about its readiness to discuss how to address the debt issue with the Chinese banks.",
        "He said China encouraged its banks to discuss it. The Chinese position was also communicated during the telephone conversation between Chinese Premier Li Keqiang and then Sri Lankan Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa.",
        "“We sent proposals to the Finance Ministry. But, there was no response from them. Also, Sri Lanka insisted that it should complete the agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) first. The ball is in Sri Lanka’s court,” the spokesman said.",
        "Sri Lanka’s total bilateral debt was estimated at $6.2 billion at the end of 2020 by the IMF.",
        "Japan and China hold the largest shares. India has provided around $4 billion to help keep Sri Lanka’s economy afloat, mainly through credit lines and swaps this year. Sri Lanka also has $14 billion of international sovereign bond debt. (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ball",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around $4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$14 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනය පවසන්නේ පන්දුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිටියේ තිබෙන බවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ණය සහන සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනය වෙනස් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කළ ඉල්ලීමට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු පැවසුවේ පන්දුව ඇත්තේ චීනයේ නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිටියේ බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රකාශකයා ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසුවේ, චීන බැංකු සමඟ ඇති ණය ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳා ගන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ඇති සූදානම පිළිබඳව චීනය මාස තුනකට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයට සන්නිවේදනය කළ බවයි.",
        "ඒ ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට චීනය තම බැංකු දිරිමත් කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය. චීන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය Li Keqiang සහ එවකට ශ්‍රී ලංකා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අතර පැවති දුරකථන සංවාදයේ දී ද චීන ස්ථාවරය සන්නිවේදනය කර ඇත.",
        "“අපි මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයට යෝජනා යැව්වා. නමුත්, ඔවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබුණේ නැහැ. එසේම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රථමයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ ඇතිකරගත් ගිවිසුම සම්පූර්ණ කළ යුතු බව අවධාරණය කළේය. පන්දුව තිබෙන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිටියේ,” ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසීය.",
        "IMF විසින් 2020 අවසානයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සම්පූර්ණ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇත.",
        "ජපානය සහ චීනය විශාලතම කොටස් හිමිකර ගනී. මේ වසරේ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ණය මාර්ග සහ හුවමාරු හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය නැඟී සිටීමට ඉන්දියාව ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 ක් පමණ ලබා දී ඇත. ඩොලර් බිලියන 14 ක ජාත්‍යන්තර ස්වෛරීත්ව බැඳුම්කර ණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද තිබේ. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පන්දුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 14 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பந்து இலங்கையின் நீதிமன்றத்தில் இருப்பதாக சீனா கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடன் நிவாரணம் தொடர்பாக சீனா தனது போக்கை மாற்ற வேண்டும் என்ற இலங்கையின் கோரிக்கைக்கு பதிலளித்த சீன தூதரகத்தின் பேச்சாளர், பந்து இலங்கையின் நீதிமன்றத்தில் உள்ளது, சீனாவின் அல்ல என்றார்.",
        "சீன வங்கிகளுடனான கடன் பிரச்சினையை எவ்வாறு கையாள்வது என்பது குறித்து ஆலோசிக்க தயார் என மூன்று மாதங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இலங்கை நிதியமைச்சகத்திடம் சீனா தொடர்பு கொண்டதாக டெய்லி மிரர் சீனாவிடம் பேச்சாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "இது குறித்து விவாதிக்க சீனா தனது வங்கிகளை ஊக்குவித்ததாக அவர் கூறினார். சீனப் பிரதமர் லீ கெகியாங் மற்றும் அப்போதைய இலங்கைப் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கும் இடையில் இடம்பெற்ற தொலைபேசி உரையாடலின் போது சீன நிலைப்பாடும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "“நாங்கள் நிதி அமைச்சகத்திற்கு பரிந்துரைகளை அனுப்பினோம். ஆனால், அவர்களிடமிருந்து எந்த பதிலும் வரவில்லை. அத்துடன், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான (IMF) உடன்படிக்கையை முதலில் பூர்த்தி செய்ய வேண்டும் எனவும் இலங்கை வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது. பந்து இலங்கையின் நீதிமன்றத்தில் உள்ளது” என்று பேச்சாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் மொத்த இருதரப்புக் கடன் 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் 6.2 பில்லியன் டொலர்களாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தால் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜப்பான் மற்றும் சீனா அதிக பங்குகளை வைத்துள்ளன. இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கு இந்தியா சுமார் 4 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது, முக்கியமாக இந்த ஆண்டு கடன் மற்றும் பரிமாற்றங்கள் மூலம். இலங்கையில் 14 பில்லியன் டாலர் சர்வதேச இறையாண்மை பத்திரக் கடனும் உள்ளது. (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பந்து",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$14 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}