{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83367/japanese-embassy-denies-media-reports-on-japan-refusing-to-support-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1656677040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japanese Embassy denies media reports on Japan refusing to support Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japanese Embassy denies media reports on Japan refusing to support Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Embassy of Japan in Colombo today (July 01) categorically denied a media report which stated that Japan would not support Sri Lanka at the moment due to mismanagement of funds.",
        "According to an article published by a local newspaper, the Ambassador of Japan to Sri Lanka reportedly mentioned this during a meeting with the TNA yesterday. The Japanese ambassador engaged in a visit to Jaffna from June 27 to 30.",
        "Issuing a clarification on Japan’s position on the economic situation in Sri Lanka, the embassy dismissed the contents of the article as “incorrect and misleading information”.",
        "“Japan is closely paying attention to the current difficult economic situation in Sri Lanka and severe humanitarian situation accompanied,” the statement noted.",
        "The embassy also said: “Considering such situation, the Government of Japan has decided to provide Emergency Grant Aid of USD 3 million through UNICEF and WFP in order to provide medicine and food in a manner that would directly benefit the Sri Lankan people. Japan sincerely hopes that this assistance will be of help to overcoming the hardship faced by the people of Sri Lanka, Japan’s long-standing friends.",
        "“The Government of Japan would like to consider its further contribution to Sri Lanka in consultation with the Government of Sri Lanka and other developing partners, while giving attention to the situation of Sri Lanka and the negotiation progress between Sri Lanka and IMF.",
        "Japan, time-tested partner in Sri Lanka’s socio-economic development, has been supporting Sri Lanka and will continue to do its part in combining its efforts with the people and Government of Sri Lanka.”",
        "Meanwhile, Deputy Ambassador of the Japanese Embassy, Katsuki Kotaro has written to the Prime Minister’s Office regarding the matter.",
        "The PM’s office also stated that this would have a detrimental impact on the country’s economic recovery and the cordial bilateral relationship with Japan."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japanese Embassy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Embassy of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 27 to 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNICEF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Government of Japan",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katsuki Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බවට පළ වූ මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුදල් අවභාවිතය හේතුවෙන් ජපානය මේ මොහොතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය නොදක්වන බවට පළ වූ මාධ්‍ය වාර්තාවක් කොළඹ පිහිටි ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලය අද (ජූලි 01) තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා ඊයේ දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මේ බව සඳහන් කළ බව එරට පුවත්පතක් පළ කළ ලිපියක සඳහන් වේ. ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා ජුනි 27 සිට 30 දක්වා යාපනයේ සංචාරයක නිරත විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ ජපානයේ ස්ථාවරය පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලි කිරීමක් නිකුත් කරමින් තානාපති කාර්යාලය ලිපියේ අන්තර්ගතය “වැරදි සහ නොමඟ යවන සුළු තොරතුරු” ලෙස ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් දුෂ්කර ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සහ දැඩි මානුෂීය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ජපානය සමීපව අවධානයෙන් සිටින බව\" එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "තානාපති කාර්යාලය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසුවේ, “මෙවැනි තත්ත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට සෘජුවම ප්‍රතිලාභ සැලසෙන පරිදි ඖෂධ සහ ආහාර ලබාදීම සඳහා යුනිසෙෆ් සහ ඩබ්ලිව්එෆ්පී හරහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 3 ක හදිසි ආධාර ආධාර ලබාදීමට ජපාන රජය තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා. ජපානයේ දිගුකාලීන මිතුරන් වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීමට මෙම ආධාර උපකාර වනු ඇතැයි ජපානය අවංකවම බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල අතර සාකච්ඡා ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරන අතරම ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ අනෙකුත් සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එහි තවදුරටත් දායකත්වය සලකා බැලීමට ජපාන රජය කැමති වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමාජ-ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනයේ කාලානුරූපී හවුල්කරුවා වන ජපානය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය වෙමින් සිටින අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සහ රජය සමඟ එහි ප්‍රයත්නයන් ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීමෙහිලා සිය කාර්යභාරය දිගටම කරගෙන යනු ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ නියෝජ්‍ය තානාපති Katsuki Kotaro මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයට ලිපියක් යොමු කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙය රටේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතියට සහ ජපානය සමඟ පවතින සුහද ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතාවට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපානු ඇති බව ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය ප්‍රකාශ කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානයේ තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 27 සිට 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනිසෙෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katsuki Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க மறுப்பதாக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான செய்திகளை ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் மறுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிதியை தவறாக நிர்வகிப்பதன் காரணமாக ஜப்பான் இலங்கைக்கு தற்போதைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்காது என ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான செய்தியை கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜப்பான் தூதரகம் இன்று (ஜூலை 01) திட்டவட்டமாக மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் நேற்று தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்புடனான சந்திப்பின் போது இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டதாக உள்ளூர் பத்திரிகையொன்று வெளியிட்டுள்ள கட்டுரையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் ஜூன் 27 முதல் 30 வரை யாழ்ப்பாணத்திற்கான விஜயத்தில் ஈடுபட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நிலை குறித்து ஜப்பானின் நிலைப்பாடு குறித்து தெளிவுபடுத்திய தூதரகம், கட்டுரையின் உள்ளடக்கங்களை \"தவறான மற்றும் தவறான தகவல்\" என்று நிராகரித்தது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய கடினமான பொருளாதார நிலைமை மற்றும் கடுமையான மனிதாபிமான நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பில் ஜப்பான் உன்னிப்பாக அவதானம் செலுத்தி வருவதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தூதரகம் மேலும் கூறியது: “இவ்வாறான சூழ்நிலையைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு நேரடியாகப் பயன்தரும் வகையில் மருந்து மற்றும் உணவை வழங்குவதற்காக UNICEF மற்றும் WFP மூலம் 3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை அவசர உதவியாக வழங்க ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. ஜப்பானின் நீண்டகால நண்பர்களான இலங்கை மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் இன்னல்களை போக்குவதற்கு இந்த உதவி உதவியாக இருக்கும் என ஜப்பான் உண்மையிலேயே நம்புகிறது.",
        "“இலங்கையின் நிலைமை மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துக்கும் இடையிலான பேச்சுவார்த்தை முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தும் அதே வேளையில், இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் பிற வளரும் பங்காளிகளுடன் கலந்தாலோசித்து இலங்கைக்கான தனது மேலதிக பங்களிப்பை ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம் பரிசீலிக்க விரும்புகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் சமூக-பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தியில் காலத்தால் சோதிக்கப்பட்ட பங்காளியான ஜப்பான், இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளித்து வருவதுடன், இலங்கை மக்களுடனும் அரசாங்கத்துடனும் தனது முயற்சிகளை இணைப்பதில் தனது பங்களிப்பை தொடர்ந்து செய்யும்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஜப்பான் தூதரகத்தின் துணைத் தூதர் கட்சுகி கோட்டாரோ இந்த விவகாரம் தொடர்பாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளார்.",
        "இது நாட்டின் பொருளாதார மீட்சி மற்றும் ஜப்பானுடனான சுமுகமான இருதரப்பு உறவில் மோசமான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் என்றும் பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27 முதல் 30 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனிசெஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் அரசு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katsuki Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}