{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Govt-to-offer-Rs-7-500-allowance-to-worst-hit-citizens-from-WB-ADB-fund/108-240210",
  "time_ut": 1656707520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Govt. to offer Rs.7,500 allowance to worst-hit citizens from WB, ADB fund",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Govt. to offer Rs.7,500 allowance to worst-hit citizens from WB, ADB fund",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In a bid to support the people from the worsening economic crisis that has made it challenging to access food, fuel and gas, the government yesterday said it is gearing up to provide a fresh round of assistance to those severely impacted.",
        "From this month onwards (July), the government plans to roll out an allowance of Rs.7500 to those hit by the crisis, said Plantations Minister Ramesh Pathirana.",
        "The allowance will be extended from the funds received from the international donor agencies. Part of the allowance will be offered from the US $ 200 million from the World Bank (WB), while part will be from the US $ 200 million from the Asian Development Bank (ADB).",
        "Samurdhi beneficiaries, senior citizens and medical-related persons are those among who are eligible for the allowance.",
        "However, the minister did not share how the handout will be offered."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "WB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ADB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය WB, ADB අරමුදලින් දරුණුතම පීඩාවට පත් පුරවැසියන්ට රුපියල් 7,500 දීමනාවක් පිරිනැමීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආහාර, ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් වෙත ප්‍රවේශ වීම අභියෝගයක් වී ඇති නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ජනතාවට සහය දැක්වීම සඳහා රජය ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූවන් සඳහා නැවුම් වටයක් සහන සැලසීමට සූදානම් වන බවයි.",
        "මෙම මාසයේ සිට (ජූලි) අර්බුදයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් වූවන්ට රුපියල් 7500 ක දීමනාවක් ලබාදීමට රජය සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව වැවිලි අමාත්‍ය රමේෂ් පතිරණ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර පරිත්‍යාගශීලී ආයතනවලින් ලැබෙන අරමුදල්වලින් මෙම දීමනාව දීර්ඝ කෙරේ. දීමනාවෙන් කොටසක් ලෝක බැංකුවේ (WB) ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 න් පිරිනමන අතර කොටසක් ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුවේ (ADB) ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 න් ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "සමෘද්ධි ප්‍රතිලාභීන්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පුරවැසියන් සහ වෛද්‍ය සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයින් දීමනාව සඳහා සුදුසුකම් ලබන අය අතර වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එම අත් පත්‍රිකාව ලබාදෙන ආකාරය පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ නැහැ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ADB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு WB, ADB நிதியில் இருந்து மோசமாக பாதிக்கப்பட்ட குடிமக்களுக்கு ரூ.7,500 உதவித்தொகை வழங்க",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உணவு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயுவை அணுகுவதை சவாலாக மாற்றியுள்ள மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மக்களை ஆதரிக்கும் முயற்சியில், கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு புதிய சுற்று உதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்கு தயாராகி வருவதாக அரசாங்கம் நேற்று கூறியது.",
        "இம்மாதம் (ஜூலை) முதல் நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு 7500 ரூபா கொடுப்பனவை வழங்க அரசாங்கம் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக பெருந்தோட்ட அமைச்சர் ரமேஷ் பத்திரன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நன்கொடை நிறுவனங்களிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட நிதியிலிருந்து கொடுப்பனவு நீட்டிக்கப்படும். உதவித்தொகையின் ஒரு பகுதி உலக வங்கியின் (WB) 200 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களில் இருந்து வழங்கப்படும், அதே சமயம் ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கியின் (ADB) ஒரு பகுதி US $ 200 மில்லியனிலிருந்து வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "சமுர்த்தி பயனாளிகள், மூத்த குடிமக்கள் மற்றும் மருத்துவம் தொடர்பான நபர்கள் இந்த கொடுப்பனவுக்கு தகுதியுடையவர்கள்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இந்த கையூட்டு எவ்வாறு வழங்கப்படும் என்பதை அமைச்சர் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ளவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "WB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏடிபி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 200 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 200 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}