{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Sajith-Premadasa-admitted-to-hospital-with-a-viral-flu/108-240706",
  "time_ut": 1657353261,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith Premadasa admitted to hospital with a viral flu",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith Premadasa admitted to hospital with a viral flu",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa has been admitted to a private hospital in Colombo with the viral flu, SJB General Secretary Ranjith Madduma Bandara confirmed to Daily Mirror a short while ago.",
        "Premadasa who was supposed to lead the SJB at the protest today, calling for the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, was admitted to the hospital with the flu. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස වෛරස් උණ රෝගයකින් රෝහල් ගත කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා වෛරස් උණ රෝගයකින් කොළඹ පෞද්ගලික රෝහලකට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති බව SJB ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර මහතා මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව පවසමින් අද පැවති විරෝධතාවයේ SJB නායකත්වය දැරීමට නියමිතව සිටි ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා උණ වැළදීම හේතුවෙන් රෝහල් ගත කර ඇත. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB ජෙනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச வைரஸ் காய்ச்சல் காரணமாக வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச வைரஸ் காய்ச்சலால் கொழும்பில் உள்ள தனியார் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக SJB பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார சற்று முன்னர் டெய்லி மிரருக்கு உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி இன்று நடைபெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் எஸ்ஜேபியை வழிநடத்தவிருந்த பிரேமதாச காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}