{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Sri-Lankas-ousted-president-expected-to-go-to-Thailand-sources/342-242793",
  "time_ut": 1660115273,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s ousted president expected to go to Thailand - sources",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s ousted president expected to go to Thailand - sources",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka's ousted president, Gotabaya Rajapaksa, is expected to arrive in Thailand on Thursday, seeking temporary shelter in a second Southeast Asian country after fleeing his island nation last month amid mass protests, two sources said.",
        "Rajapaksa fled to Singapore on July 14, via the Maldives, following unprecedented unrest triggered by Sri Lanka's worst economic crisis in seven decades and days after thousands of protesters stormed the president's official residence and office",
        "The retired military officer then resigned from the presidency, becoming the first Sri Lankan president to quit mid-term.",
        "The former president is expected to leave Singapore and go to Thailand's capital Bangkok on Thursday, two sources said, asking not to be named.",
        "Sri Lanka's foreign ministry did not immediately respond to requests for comment. Thai government spokeswoman Ratchada Thanadirek told Reuters “no comment”.",
        "Rajapaksa has not made any public appearances or comments since leaving Sri Lanka, and Singapore's government said this month that the city-state had not accorded him any privileges or immunity.",
        "A member of the influential Rajapaksa family, the 73-year-old served in the Sri Lankan military and later as defence secretary.",
        "During his time as defence secretary government forces finally defeated Tamil Tiger rebels in 2009 to end the Sri Lankan civil war. Some rights groups now want accusations thatRajapaksa committed war crimes to be investigated. Rajapaksa has previously strenuously denied the allegations.",
        "Some critics and protesters also accuse Rajapaksa and his family of mishandling the economy during his term as president, leading to the country's worst financial crisis since independence from Britain in 1948.",
        "His elder brother, Mahinda Rajapaksa, is a former president and prime minister. Their younger sibling, Basil Rajapaksa, served as finance minister till earlier this year.",
        "Rajapaksa's successor, Ranil Wickremesinghe, has previously indicated that the former president should refrain from returning to Sri Lanka in the near future.",
        "\"I don't believe it's the time for him to return,\" Wickremesinghe told the Wall Street Journal in an interview on July 31. \"I have no indication of him returning soon.\"",
        "If Rajapaksa returned to Sri Lanka, he might not be protected under law if any charges were filed against him, legal experts have said. (Reuters)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thailand",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven decades and days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratchada Thanadirek",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe told the Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලයෙන් පහකළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තායිලන්තයට යාමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලයෙන් පහකළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, මහජන විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ පසුගිය මාසයේ සිය දිවයිනෙන් පලා යාමෙන් පසු දෙවන අග්නිදිග ආසියාතික රටක තාවකාලික නවාතැන් පතා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා තායිලන්තයට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ආරංචි මාර්ග දෙකක් පවසයි.",
        "දශක හතකට පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් පෙර නොවූ විරූ නොසන්සුන්තාවකින් පසුව සහ දහස් ගණන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති නිල නිවසට සහ කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදී දින කිහිපයකට පසු රාජපක්ෂ ජූලි 14 දා මාලදිවයින හරහා සිංගප්පූරුවට පලා ගියේය.",
        "ඉන්පසුව විශ්‍රාමික හමුදා නිලධාරියා ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූ අතර, මැද කාලීනව ඉල්ලා අස් වූ පළමු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත් විය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් පිටත්ව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා තායිලන්තයේ බැංකොක් අගනුවරට යාමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ආරංචි මාර්ග දෙකක් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ නම් නොකිරීමට ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය වහාම ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ නැත. තායි රජයේ ප්‍රකාශිකා රචඩා තනාදිරෙක් රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පැවසුවේ “කිසිදු අදහසක් නැත” යනුවෙනි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හැර යාමෙන් පසු කිසිදු ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ පෙනී සිටීමක් හෝ අදහස් දැක්වීමක් කර නොමැති අතර සිංගප්පූරු රජය මේ මාසයේ කියා සිටියේ නගර රාජ්‍යය ඔහුට කිසිදු වරප්‍රසාදයක් හෝ මුක්තියක් ලබා දී නොමැති බවයි.",
        "බලගතු රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන 73 හැවිරිදි ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදාවේ සේවය කළ අතර පසුව ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙසද කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "ඔහු ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන කාලය තුළ 2009 වසරේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා සිවිල් යුද්ධය අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා රජයේ හමුදා දෙමළ කොටි කැරලිකරුවන් පරාජය කරන ලදී. සමහර මානව හිමිකම් සංවිධානවලට දැන් අවශ්‍ය වී ඇත්තේ රාජපක්ෂ යුද අපරාධ කළ බවට එල්ල වන චෝදනා විමර්ශනය කළ යුතු බවයි. රාජපක්ෂ මීට පෙර එම චෝදනා තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "1948 බි‍්‍රතාන්‍යයෙන් නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු රටේ දරුණුතම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට තුඩු දුන් ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය තුළ රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ පවුලේ අය ආර්ථිකය වැරදි ලෙස හසුරුවා ගත් බවට ඇතැම් විවේචකයින් සහ විරෝධතාකරුවන් ද චෝදනා කරති.",
        "ඔහුගේ වැඩිමහල් සොහොයුරා වන මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සහ අගමැතිවරයෙකි. ඔවුන්ගේ බාල සොහොයුරා වන බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මේ වසර මුල වනතුරුම මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා වන රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් වැළකිය යුතු බව මීට පෙර පෙන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "ජූලි 31දා වෝල් ස්ට්‍රීට් ජර්නල් වෙත සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසුවේ, \"ඔහු නැවත පැමිණීමට කාලය මෙය බව මම විශ්වාස නොකරමි.\"",
        "රාජපක්ෂ යළි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියහොත් ඔහුට එරෙහිව චෝදනා ගොනු කළහොත් ඔහුට නීතිය යටතේ ආරක්ෂාවක් නොලැබෙනු ඇතැයි නීති විශාරදයෝ පවසති. (රොයිටර්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තායිලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතක් සහ දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රච්චද තනාදිරෙක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ Wall Street Journal වෙත පැවසීය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி தாய்லாந்து செல்வார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது - ஆதாரங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு மத்தியில் கடந்த மாதம் தனது தீவு தேசத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பின்னர் இரண்டாவது தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய நாட்டில் தற்காலிக தங்குமிடம் தேடி வியாழக்கிழமை தாய்லாந்திற்கு வருவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, இரண்டு வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ஏழு தசாப்தங்களில் இலங்கையின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் மற்றும் அலுவலகத்தை ஆயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் தாக்கிய சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத அமைதியின்மையைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜூலை 14 அன்று மாலைத்தீவு வழியாக சிங்கப்பூருக்கு ராஜபக்சே தப்பிச் சென்றார்.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற இராணுவ அதிகாரி பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார், இடைக்காலத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முதல் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ஆனார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிங்கப்பூரை விட்டு வெளியேறி தாய்லாந்தின் தலைநகர் பாங்காக்கிற்கு வியாழக்கிழமை செல்வார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, இரண்டு வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன, பெயரை வெளியிட வேண்டாம் என்று கேட்டுக் கொண்டனர்.",
        "கருத்துக்கான கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு இலங்கையின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் உடனடியாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை. தாய்லாந்து அரசாங்கத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ரட்சடா தனடிரெக் ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம் \"கருத்து இல்லை\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறியதில் இருந்து ராஜபக்சே பொதுத் தோற்றங்களோ கருத்துக்களோ எதனையும் வெளியிடவில்லை, மேலும் சிங்கப்பூர் அரசாங்கம் இந்த மாதம் அவருக்கு நகர-அரசு எந்த சலுகைகளையும் விலக்குகளையும் வழங்கவில்லை என்று கூறியது.",
        "செல்வாக்கு மிக்க ராஜபக்சே குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 73 வயதான அவர், இலங்கை ராணுவத்திலும், பின்னர் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளராகவும் பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "அவர் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளராக இருந்த காலத்தில், இலங்கை உள்நாட்டுப் போரை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டு வர, 2009 ஆம் ஆண்டு தமிழ்ப் புலி கிளர்ச்சியாளர்களை அரசுப் படைகள் தோற்கடித்தன. சில உரிமைக் குழுக்கள் இப்போது ராஜபக்ஷ போர்க்குற்றம் இழைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டை விசாரிக்க வேண்டும் என்று விரும்புகின்றன. இந்த குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை ராஜபக்சே கடுமையாக மறுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "சில விமர்சகர்கள் மற்றும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் ராஜபக்சே மற்றும் அவரது குடும்பத்தினர் ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த காலத்தில் பொருளாதாரத்தை தவறாக கையாண்டதாக குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றனர், இது 1948 இல் பிரிட்டனில் இருந்து சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "இவரது மூத்த சகோதரர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமரும் ஆவார். இவர்களது இளைய சகோதரரான பசில் ராஜபக்ச, இந்த ஆண்டு தொடக்கம் வரை நிதி அமைச்சராக பதவி வகித்தார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சேவின் வாரிசான ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே, முன்னாள் அதிபர், எதிர்காலத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதைத் தவிர்க்க வேண்டும் என்று முன்பு குறிப்பிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 31 அன்று வோல் ஸ்ட்ரீட் ஜேர்னலுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியில், \"அவர் திரும்பி வருவதற்கான நேரம் இது என்று நான் நம்பவில்லை,\" என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார். \"அவர் விரைவில் திரும்பி வருவதற்கான எந்த அறிகுறியும் என்னிடம் இல்லை.\"",
        "ராஜபக்சே இலங்கை திரும்பினால், அவருக்கு எதிராக ஏதேனும் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டால், அவருக்கு சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பாதுகாப்பு கிடைக்காது என, சட்ட நிபுணர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். (ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு தசாப்தங்கள் மற்றும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரட்சட தனடிரெக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க வோல் ஸ்ட்ரீட் ஜேர்னலுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}