{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83697/sri-lankas-economy-to-contract-by-more-than-6-in-2022-cbsl-governor",
  "time_ut": 1658034360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s economy to contract by more than 6% in 2022 - CBSL governor",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s economy to contract by more than 6% in 2022 - CBSL governor",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s economy is likely to contract by more than 6 percent in 2022 as political instability and social unrest affect discussions on financial relief with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the country’s central bank governor, Nandalal Weerasinghe, told The Wall Street Journal in an interview.",
        "“This year the contraction will be much higher, maybe higher than 6 percent contraction,” he told the Journal, referring to the pandemic-affected 2020, when the economy shrank 3.5 percent.",
        "He said that a stable political administration is urgently needed to progress discussions with the IMF on key structural reforms, as well as to secure short-term bridge financing from other countries and multilateral agencies to help pay for key imports like fuel, pharmaceuticals and fertilizers.",
        "According to Bloomberg, IMF Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva said debt-restructuring talks with Sri Lanka will proceed quite quickly, as soon as a new government is in place."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "more than 6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bloomberg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kristalina Georgieva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2022 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය 6%කට වඩා හැකිලෙනු ඇතැයි මහ බැංකු අධිපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය සහ සමාජ අසහනය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ මූල්‍ය සහන පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවලට බලපාන බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය 2022 දී සියයට 6 කට වඩා හැකිලීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව රටේ මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ වෝල් ස්ට්‍රීට් ජර්නලයට පැවසීය. සම්මුඛ පරීක්ෂණය.",
        "“මේ වසරේ හැකිලීම බෙහෙවින් වැඩි වනු ඇත, සමහර විට සියයට 6 ක හැකිලීමට වඩා වැඩි වනු ඇත,” ඔහු ජර්නලයට පැවසුවේ, වසංගතයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් 2020, ආර්ථිකය සියයට 3.5 කින් හැකිලුණු විට ය.",
        "ප්‍රධාන ව්‍යුහාත්මක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට මෙන්ම ඉන්ධන, ඖෂධ සහ පොහොර වැනි ප්‍රධාන ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා වෙනත් රටවලින් සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික ආයතනවලින් කෙටිකාලීන පාලම් මූල්‍යකරණය ලබා ගැනීමට ස්ථාවර දේශපාලන පරිපාලනයක් අවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "Bloomberg ට අනුව, IMF කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ Kristalina Georgieva පැවසුවේ නව රජයක් ස්ථාපිත වූ වහාම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා ඉතා ඉක්මනින් ඉදිරියට යන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6% ට වඩා",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6 කට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඟරාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 3.5 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්ලූම්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර්ජිවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 இல் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் 6%க்கும் அதிகமாக சுருங்கும் - CBSL ஆளுநர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை மற்றும் சமூக அமைதியின்மை ஆகியவை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) நிதி நிவாரணம் தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடல்களை பாதிக்கும் என்பதால், 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் 6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக சுருங்கக்கூடும் என்று நாட்டின் மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார். நேர்காணல்.",
        "\"இந்த ஆண்டு சுருக்கம் மிக அதிகமாக இருக்கும், ஒருவேளை 6 சதவீத சுருக்கத்தை விட அதிகமாக இருக்கும்,\" என்று அவர் ஜர்னலிடம் கூறினார், தொற்றுநோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட 2020, பொருளாதாரம் 3.5 சதவீதம் சுருங்கியது.",
        "IMF உடனான முக்கிய கட்டமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்கள் குறித்த விவாதங்களை முன்னெடுப்பதற்கும், மற்ற நாடுகள் மற்றும் பலதரப்பு முகவர்களிடமிருந்தும் குறுகிய கால நிதியுதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கும், எரிபொருள், மருந்துகள் மற்றும் உரங்கள் போன்ற முக்கிய இறக்குமதிகளுக்கு பணம் செலுத்துவதற்கு உதவுவதற்கு ஒரு நிலையான அரசியல் நிர்வாகம் அவசரமாக தேவை என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "புளூம்பேர்க் கருத்துப்படி, இலங்கையுடனான கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் விரைவில் புதிய அரசாங்கம் அமைந்தவுடன் மிக விரைவாக தொடரும் என சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் முகாமைத்துவ பணிப்பாளர் கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜோர்ஜீவா தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6%க்கு மேல்",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி வால் ஸ்ட்ரீட் ஜர்னல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ப்ளூம்பெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜார்ஜீவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}