{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/01/sjbs-hesha-credits-cbsl-governor-for-imf-agreement-slams-govt-for-trying-to-take-credit/",
  "time_ut": 1662037080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJBs Hesha credits CBSL Governor for IMF agreement; Slams Govt for trying to take credit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJBs Hesha credits CBSL Governor for IMF agreement; Slams Govt for trying to take credit",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka managed to secure a Staff-Level Agreement with the International Monetary Fund due to the efforts undertaken by Central Bank Governor Nandalal Weerasinghe, said SJB MP Hesha Withanage.",
        "He told the Parliament on Thursday (1) that the discussion between the visiting IMF Delegation to Sri Lanka, and the local authorities were successful mainly because of the progressive steps taken by Dr. Weerasinghe, as the Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka.",
        "He slammed the members of the government for attempting to take credit for the efforts of someone else.",
        "He said the government is attempting to portray the Staff-Level Agreement with the IMF as an achievement of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "\"If one has done something for the country, it is okay to take the credit for that,\" he remarked reminding the house that it is because of Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe, the CBSL Governor, that Sri Lanka achieved the Staff Level Agreement.",
        "The MP said the government has not been able to show any form of stability, and warned the government not to disrupt the efforts taken by the Central Bank Governor.",
        "Hesha Vithanage said that when the opposition called on the government to approach the IMF, they were ridiculed by the ruling faction noting that Sri Lanka does not need the IMF, and only needs investments.",
        "SJBs Hesha credits CBSL Governor for IMF agreement; Slams Govt for trying to take credit",
        "Sri Lanka needs government with mandate to carry out reforms – IMF Mission Chief"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Slams Govt",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hesha Withanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF Delegation to Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hesha Vithanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Slams Govt",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJBs Hesha IMF ගිවිසුම සඳහා CBSL ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයාට බැර කරයි; ණය ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම ගැන රජයට මඩ ගසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතාගේ උත්සාහය හේතුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් ඇති කර ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමත් වූ බව SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හේෂා විතානගේ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිස සහ පළාත් පාලන ආයතන අතර සාකච්ඡාව සාර්ථක වූයේ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා ගත් ප්‍රගතිශීලී පියවර නිසා බව ඔහු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (1) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "වෙනත් කෙනෙකුගේ උත්සාහයේ ගෞරවය ලබා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම ගැන ඔහු ආණ්ඩුවේ සාමාජිකයින්ට බැණ වැදුණි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ඇති කර ගත් කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලෙස හුවා දැක්වීමට රජය උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“කෙනෙක් රට වෙනුවෙන් යමක් කළා නම් ඒකෙ ගෞරවය ගත්තට කමක් නෑ,” ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් ඇති කර ගත්තේ මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ නිසා බව ඔහු සභාවට සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "කිසිදු ආකාරයක ස්ථාවරත්වයක් පෙන්වීමට රජයට නොහැකි වී ඇති බව පැවසූ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා, මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා ගන්නා උත්සාහයන් කඩාකප්පල් නොකරන ලෙස රජයට අවවාද කළේය.",
        "හේෂා විතානගේ කියා සිටියේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට ළං වන ලෙස විපක්ෂය රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල අවශ්‍ය නොවන බවත් ආයෝජන පමණක් අවශ්‍ය බවත් සඳහන් කරමින් පාලක පාර්ශවය ඔවුන්ව සමච්චලයට ලක් කළ බවයි.",
        "SJBs Hesha IMF ගිවිසුම සඳහා CBSL ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයාට බැර කරයි; ණය ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම ගැන රජයට මඩ ගසයි",
        "ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජනවරමක් සහිත රජයක් අවශ්‍යයි - IMF දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානියා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Slams Govt",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේෂා විතානගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හේෂා විතානගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Slams Govt",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF உடன்படிக்கைக்காக CBSL ஆளுநருக்கு SJBs ஹேஷா பெருமை சேர்த்துள்ளார்; கடன் வாங்க முயற்சிக்கும் அரசாங்கத்தை அவதூறு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுனர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவின் முயற்சியினால் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை இலங்கை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடிந்தது என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹேஷா விதானகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநராக கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க மேற்கொண்ட முற்போக்கான நடவடிக்கைகளின் காரணமாக இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் உள்ளூர் அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் இடையிலான கலந்துரையாடல் வெற்றியடைந்ததாக அவர் வியாழன் (1) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வேறொருவரின் முயற்சிக்கு கடன் வாங்க முயற்சிப்பதற்காக அரசாங்கத்தின் உறுப்பினர்களை அவர் கடுமையாக சாடினார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் சாதனையாக காட்ட அரசாங்கம் முயற்சிப்பதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"ஒருவர் நாட்டுக்காக ஏதாவது செய்திருந்தால், அதற்கான கிரெடிட்டைப் பெறுவது சரியே\" என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார், சிபிஎஸ்எல் ஆளுநரான கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவால்தான் இலங்கை பணியாளர்கள் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியது என்பதை நினைவூட்டினார்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தால் எந்த விதமான ஸ்திரத்தன்மையையும் காட்ட முடியவில்லை என தெரிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநரின் முயற்சிகளை சீர்குலைக்க வேண்டாம் என அரசாங்கத்தை எச்சரித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தை அணுகுமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தபோது, ​​இலங்கைக்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தேவையில்லை, முதலீடுகள் மட்டுமே தேவை என ஆளும் தரப்பினால் கேலி செய்யப்பட்டதாக ஹேஷா விதானகே தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "IMF உடன்படிக்கைக்காக CBSL ஆளுநருக்கு SJBs ஹேஷா பெருமை சேர்த்துள்ளார்; கடன் வாங்க முயற்சிக்கும் அரசாங்கத்தை அவதூறு",
        "சீர்திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கு ஆணை கொண்ட அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு தேவை - IMF மிஷன் தலைவர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரசாங்கத்தை திட்டுகிறது",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேஷா விதானகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைக்கான IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹேஷா விதானகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கத்தை திட்டுகிறது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}