{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Trains-SLTB-buses-run-as-usual-limited-private-buses/342-240777",
  "time_ut": 1657508848,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Trains, SLTB buses run as usual, limited private buses",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Trains, SLTB buses run as usual, limited private buses",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Even though trains are in operation as usual, buses only take a limited turn owing to unavailability of fuel.",
        "The Railways General Manager (GMR) Dhammika Jayasundara said that all trains, including office trains are on tracks today.",
        "Meanwhile, the private bus owners said they would operate buses as per availability of fuel. However, the Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) said they would operate buses as usual. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "GMR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය, ලංගම බස් රථ සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ධාවනය වේ, පුද්ගලික බස් රථ සීමිතයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ක්‍රියාත්මක වුවද ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් බස් රථ ගමන් කරන්නේ සීමිත වාරයක් පමණි.",
        "අද දිනයේ කාර්යාල දුම්රිය ඇතුළු සියලුම දුම්රියන් පීලිගත කරන බව දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී (GMR) ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්ධන ඇති ප්‍රමාණය අනුව බස් රථ ධාවනය කරන බව පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන් ප්‍රකාශ කළා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) පැවසුවේ සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි බස් රථ ධාවනය කරන බවයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "GMR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில்கள், SLTB பேருந்துகள் வழக்கம் போல் இயங்கும், மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட தனியார் பேருந்துகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரயில்கள் வழக்கம் போல் இயக்கப்பட்டாலும், எரிபொருள் கிடைக்காததால் பேருந்துகள் குறைந்த அளவில் மட்டுமே இயக்கப்படுகின்றன.",
        "அலுவலக ரயில்கள் உட்பட அனைத்து ரயில்களும் இன்று தண்டவாளத்தில் இயங்குவதாக ரயில்வே பொது முகாமையாளர் (ஜிஎம்ஆர்) தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, எரிபொருள் இருப்புக்கு ஏற்ப பஸ்களை இயக்குவதாக தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். எவ்வாறாயினும், வழமை போன்று பஸ்களை இயக்குவதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எம்.ஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}