{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Tyeab-Akbarally-joins-Sunshine-Holdings-Board/34-738997",
  "time_ut": 1661201756,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tyeab Akbarally joins Sunshine Holdings Board",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tyeab Akbarally joins Sunshine Holdings Board",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tyeab Akbarally has been appointed as a Non-Independent Non-Executive Director on the Board of Sunshine Holdings PLC.",
        "Akbarally has been a Director of Akbar Brothers Group of Companies since 1979, and presently holds the position of the Managing Director and is actively engaged in the Tea and Commodity Export Trade. He was a former Chairman of The Colombo Tea Traders Association, and Spices and Allied Products Producers’ and Traders’ Association. He was also a Director of Amana Bank and the Chairman of Amana Takaful PLC and is on the Boards of several other companies",
        "Akbar Brothers holds 49.2 million shares or 10% stake in Sunshine Holdings.",
        "With the latest appointment, the Board of Directors of Sunshine Holdings comprises Chairman Amal Cabraal, Group Managing Director V. Govindasamy, S. Ratwatte, H.D. Abeywickrama, A.D.B. Talwatte, S. Shishoo, G. Sathasivam, S.G. Sathasivam, S. Jain, W.Y.R. Fernando, S. Renganathan and T. Akbarally."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sunshine Holdings Board",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Board of Sunshine Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Akbar Brothers Group of Companies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Tea Traders Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spices",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Allied Products Producers’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amana Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amana Takaful PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Akbar Brothers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "49.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amal Cabraal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Govindasamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Ratwatte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.D. Abeywickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.D.B. Talwatte",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Shishoo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. Sathasivam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.G. Sathasivam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.Y.R. Fernando",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Renganathan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Tyeab Akbarally සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් මණ්ඩලයට එක්වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tyeab Akbarally සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී මණ්ඩලයේ ස්වාධීන නොවන විධායක නොවන අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයෙකු ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "අක්බාරාලි 1979 සිට අක්බාර් බ්‍රදර්ස් සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයෙකු ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇති අතර, වර්තමානයේ කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ තනතුර දරණ අතර තේ සහ භාණ්ඩ අපනයන වෙළඳාමේ සක්‍රීයව නිරත වේ. ඔහු කොළඹ තේ වෙළඳුන්ගේ සංගමයේ සහ කුළුබඩු සහ ඒ ආශ්‍රිත නිෂ්පාදන නිෂ්පාදකයින්ගේ සහ වෙළඳ සංගමයේ හිටපු සභාපතිවරයා විය. ඔහු අමානා බැංකුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයකු සහ අමානා තකාෆුල් පීඑල්සී හි සභාපතිවරයා ද වූ අතර තවත් සමාගම් කිහිපයක අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලවල ද සිටී.",
        "අක්බාර් බ්‍රදර්ස් සතුව සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි කොටස් මිලියන 49.2 ක් හෝ 10% ක කොටස් තිබේ.",
        "නවතම පත්වීමත් සමඟ සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයට සභාපති අමල් කබ්රාල්, සමූහ කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ වී.ගෝවින්දසාමි, එස්.රත්වත්ත, එච්.ඩී. අබේවික්‍රම, ඒ.ඩී.බී. තල්වත්ත, එස්.ෂිෂූ, ජී.සතාසිවම්, එස්.ජී.සතාසිවම්, එස්.ජේන්, ඩබ්ලිව්.වයි.ආර්. ප්‍රනාන්දු, එස්.රෙන්ගනාදන් සහ ටී.අක්බරලි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස් මණ්ඩලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අක්බාර් සහෝදර සමාගම් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ තේ වෙළෙඳ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුළුබඩු",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුබද්ධ නිෂ්පාදන නිෂ්පාදකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමානා බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමානා තකාෆුල් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අක්බර් සහෝදරයෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 49.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමල් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී ගෝවින්දසාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් රත්වත්තේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.ඩී. අබේවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.බී. තල්වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Shishoo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී සතාසිවම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජී.සතාසිවම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් ජේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.වයි.ආර්. ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.රෙන්ගනාදන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தியாப் அக்பரலி சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் போர்டில் இணைந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தியாப் அக்பரலி சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி வாரியத்தில் சுயாதீனமற்ற நிர்வாக இயக்குனராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அக்பரலி 1979 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் அக்பர் பிரதர்ஸ் குழும நிறுவனங்களின் இயக்குநராக இருந்து வருகிறார், மேலும் தற்போது நிர்வாக இயக்குநராக பதவி வகித்து தேயிலை மற்றும் பொருட்கள் ஏற்றுமதி வர்த்தகத்தில் தீவிரமாக ஈடுபட்டுள்ளார். அவர் கொழும்பு தேயிலை வர்த்தகர்கள் சங்கம் மற்றும் மசாலா மற்றும் அதனுடன் தொடர்புடைய பொருட்கள் உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் மற்றும் வர்த்தகர்கள் சங்கத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவராக இருந்தார். அவர் அமானா வங்கியின் இயக்குநராகவும், அமானா தக்காஃபுல் பிஎல்சியின் தலைவராகவும் இருந்தார் மேலும் பல நிறுவனங்களின் வாரியங்களில் உள்ளார்.",
        "அக்பர் பிரதர்ஸ் சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸில் 49.2 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் அல்லது 10% பங்குகளை வைத்திருக்கிறார்.",
        "சமீபத்திய நியமனத்துடன், சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸின் பணிப்பாளர் சபையின் தலைவர் அமல் கப்ரால், குழும முகாமைத்துவ பணிப்பாளர் வி. கோவிந்தசாமி, எஸ். ரத்வத்தே, எச்.டி. அபேவிக்ரம, ஏ.டி.பி. தல்வத்தே, எஸ்.ஷிஷூ, ஜி.சதாசிவம், எஸ்.ஜி.சதாசிவம், எஸ்.ஜெயின், டபிள்யூ.ஒய்.ஆர். பெர்னாண்டோ, எஸ். ரெங்கநாதன் மற்றும் டி. அக்பரலி."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் போர்டு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்பர் பிரதர்ஸ் குழும நிறுவனங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மசாலா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்புடைய தயாரிப்புகள் தயாரிப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமானா வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமானா தக்காஃபுல் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்பர் சகோதரர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "49.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமல் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.கோவிந்தசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ரத்வத்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்.டி. அபேவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.டி.பி. தல்வத்தே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Shishoo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.சதாசிவம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜி.சதாசிவம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெயின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வ.ஒய்.ஆர். பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ரெங்கநாதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}