{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83312/sri-lankas-economy-contracts-by-16-in-first-quarter-of-2022",
  "time_ut": 1656472560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s economy contracts by 1.6% in first quarter of 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s economy contracts by 1.6% in first quarter of 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The economy of Sri Lanka contracted by 1.6 percent in the first quarter of the year 2022, the Department of Census and Statistics (DCS) says.",
        "In a press release, the DCS said “the year-on-year Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth rate for the first quarter of the year 2022 is estimated as negative 1.6 percent which indicated a considerable contraction of the economy compared to the first quarter of 2021.”",
        "At the beginning of 2022, the Sri Lankan economy began to improve slowly, following a difficult period of time due to the Covid-19 pandemic in the 2020 and 2021, with new expectations of economic recovery, the statement read further.",
        "However, unfortunately, within the first quarter of 2022, the economic growth rate was reported to slow down compared to the first quarters of 2021, as a result of the adverse effects of some factors such as inflation, foreign exchange devaluation and dollar deficit, the DCS explained."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "first quarter",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter of the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Census and Statistics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter of the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "negative 1.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the beginning of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first quarter of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarters of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2022 පළමු කාර්තුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය 1.6% කින් හැකිලී යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය සියයට 1.6 කින් හැකිලී ගොස් ඇති බව ජනලේඛන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (DCS) පවසයි.",
        "මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් DCS පැවසුවේ “2022 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුව සඳහා වසරින් වසර දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයේ (GDP) වර්ධන වේගය සෘණ සියයට 1.6ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති අතර එය පළමු කාර්තුවට සාපේක්ෂව ආර්ථිකයේ සැලකිය යුතු හැකිලීමක් පෙන්නුම් කරයි. 2021 දී.\"",
        "2022 ආරම්භයේදී, 2020 සහ 2021 වසරවල කොවිඩ්-19 වසංගතය හේතුවෙන් දුෂ්කර කාල පරිච්ඡේදයකින් පසු, ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිමත් වීමේ නව අපේක්ෂාවන් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය සෙමින් දියුණු වීමට පටන් ගත් බව එම ප්‍රකාශයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අවාසනාවකට මෙන්, උද්ධමනය, විදේශ විනිමය අවප්‍රමාණය වීම සහ ඩොලර් හිඟය වැනි සමහර සාධකවල අහිතකර බලපෑම් හේතුවෙන් 2022 පළමු කාර්තුව තුළ ආර්ථික වර්ධන වේගය 2021 පළමු කාර්තුවලට සාපේක්ෂව මන්දගාමී වන බව වාර්තා විය. DCS පැහැදිලි කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "පළමු කාර්තුව",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනලේඛන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෘණ සියයට 1.6",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ආරම්භය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 முதல் காலாண்டில் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் 1.6% சுருங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டில் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் 1.6 வீதத்தால் சுருங்கியுள்ளது என மக்கள் தொகைக் கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றும் புள்ளிவிபரத் திணைக்களம் (DCS) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு செய்திக்குறிப்பில், DCS கூறியது, \"2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டில் ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியின் (ஜிடிபி) வளர்ச்சி விகிதம் எதிர்மறையான 1.6 சதவீதமாக மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது முதல் காலாண்டுடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது பொருளாதாரத்தின் கணிசமான சுருக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கிறது. 2021 இன்.\"",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில், இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் மெதுவாக முன்னேறத் தொடங்கியது, 2020 மற்றும் 2021 இல் கொவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் காரணமாக ஒரு கடினமான காலகட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கான புதிய எதிர்பார்ப்புகளுடன், அறிக்கை மேலும் வாசிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இருப்பினும், துரதிருஷ்டவசமாக, 2022 இன் முதல் காலாண்டில், பணவீக்கம், அந்நியச் செலாவணி மதிப்பிழப்பு மற்றும் டாலர் பற்றாக்குறை போன்ற சில காரணிகளின் பாதகமான விளைவுகளின் விளைவாக, 2021 முதல் காலாண்டுகளுடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி விகிதம் குறைவதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. DCS விளக்கினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதல் காலாண்டு",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் தொகை கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றும் புள்ளியியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்மறை 1.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 தொடக்கம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 முதல் காலாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}