{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/public-questions-police-leading-to-overnight-queue-being-dispersed/",
  "time_ut": 1656415320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Public questions Police, leading to overnight queue being dispersed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Public questions Police, leading to overnight queue being dispersed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Police took steps to respond in a violent and an angry manner in Matale when the people who were staying in queue proceeded to question the Police personnel on refueling personal vehicles under the essential services order.",
        "Police were seen acting in a violent manner when the people, some who were queued up since 7 PM last night, were demanded to leave.",
        "The Police dispersed the crowd which was in queues overnight, some having to push their vehicles as they had no fuel to travel back home.",
        "US President Biden announces $20 M in additional assistance to SL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Matale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7 PM last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "overnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 M",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහජන ප්‍රශ්න පොලිසිය, රාත්‍රියේ පෝලිම් විසුරුවා හැරීමට හේතු වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා නියෝගය යටතේ පුද්ගලික වාහනවලට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පෝලිමේ රැඳී සිටි ජනතාව පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමට යාමේදී මාතලේ නගරයේදී ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී සහ කෝපයෙන් ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට පොලිසිය පියවර ගත්තේය.",
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රී 7.00 සිට පෝලිම්වල සිටි පිරිසට පිටව යන ලෙස බල කරන විට පොලිසිය ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරන අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "රාත්‍රිය පුරාවට පෝලිම්වල සිටි පිරිස විසුරුවා හැරීමට පොලිසිය කටයුතු කළ අතර ඇතැමුන්ට නිවෙස් බලා යාමට ඉන්ධන නොමැති වීම නිසා වාහන තල්ලු කිරීමට සිදු විය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති බයිඩන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අතිරේක ආධාර වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 20ක් ප්‍රකාශ කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ රෑ 7 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක රැයකින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுமக்கள் போலீசாரிடம் கேள்வி எழுப்பியதால், இரவோடு இரவாக வரிசை கலைக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அத்தியவசிய சேவைகள் கட்டளையின் கீழ் தனிப்பட்ட வாகனங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவது தொடர்பில் காவற்துறையினரிடம் வரிசையில் தங்கியிருந்த மக்கள் விசாரணைகளை முன்னெடுத்த போது மாத்தளையில் வன்முறையாகவும் கோபமாகவும் பதிலளிக்க பொலிஸார் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நேற்றிரவு 7 மணி முதல் வரிசையில் நின்ற சிலரை அங்கிருந்து வெளியேறுமாறு கூறியபோது, ​​காவல்துறையினர் வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட்டதைக் காணமுடிந்தது.",
        "இரவோடு இரவாக வரிசையில் நின்ற கூட்டத்தை போலீசார் கலைத்தனர், சிலர் வீடு திரும்புவதற்கு எரிபொருள் இல்லாததால் வாகனங்களை தள்ள வேண்டியிருந்தது.",
        "அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி பிடன் SL க்கு கூடுதல் உதவியாக $20 M ஐ அறிவித்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு 7 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரே இரவில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 M",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}