{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/CPC-to-low-fuel-prices-from-tonight/342-241237",
  "time_ut": 1658064876,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CPC to low fuel prices from tonight",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CPC to low fuel prices from tonight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) has decided to reduce the retail price of their fuel from 10.00 pm today.",
        "Accordingly, the price of a litre of Octane 92 petrol will be reduced by Rs.20, and the new retail price will be Rs.450.",
        "The price of a litre of Octane 95 (Euro 4) petrol will be reduced by Rs.10, and the new price will be Rs.540.",
        "The price of a litre of Lanka white diesel will be reduced by Rs.20, and thus the new price will be Rs.440.",
        "A litre of Super Diesel (four star Euro 4) will be reduced by Rs.10, and the new price will be Rs.510.",
        "The CPC also said a special plan in place to ensure continual distribution of Octane 95 and Lanka White Diesel for consumers from July 21. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tonight",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Euro 4",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "White Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CPC අද රාත්‍රියේ සිට ඉන්ධන මිල පහළට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) අද රාත්‍රී 10.00 සිට සිය ඉන්ධනවල සිල්ලර මිල අඩු කිරීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඔක්ටේන් 92 පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක මිල රුපියල් 20 කින් අඩු වන අතර නව සිල්ලර මිල රුපියල් 450 කි.",
        "ඔක්ටේන් 95 (යුරෝ 4) පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක මිල රුපියල් 10කින් අඩු වන අතර, නව මිල රුපියල් 540කි.",
        "ලංකා වයිට් ඩීසල් ලීටරයක මිල රුපියල් 20 කින් අඩු වන අතර, ඒ අනුව නව මිල රුපියල් 440 කි.",
        "සුපර් ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​(තරු හතරේ යුරෝ 4) රුපියල් 10 කින් අඩු කෙරෙන අතර, නව මිල රුපියල් 510 කි.",
        "ඔක්ටේන් 95 සහ ලංකා වයිට් ඩීසල් ජුලි 21 සිට පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව බෙදා හැරීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා විශේෂ සැලැස්මක් ද ක්‍රියාත්මක බව CPC පවසයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද රෑ",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුපිරි ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝ 4",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදු ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று இரவு முதல் குறைந்த எரிபொருள் விலைக்கு CPC",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) இன்று இரவு 10.00 மணி முதல் தமது எரிபொருளின் சில்லறை விலையை குறைக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, ஒக்டேன் 92 லீற்றர் பெற்றோலின் விலை 20 ரூபாவினால் குறைக்கப்படவுள்ளதுடன், புதிய சில்லறை விலை 450 ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "ஒக்டேன் 95 (யூரோ 4) லீற்றர் பெற்றோலின் விலை 10 ரூபாவினால் குறைக்கப்படவுள்ளதுடன், புதிய விலை 540 ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "லங்கா ஒயிட் டீசல் ஒரு லீற்றரின் விலை 20 ரூபாவினால் குறைக்கப்படவுள்ளதுடன், புதிய விலை 440 ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "ஒரு லிட்டர் சுப்பர் டீசல் (நான்கு நட்சத்திர யூரோ 4) ரூ.10 குறைக்கப்பட்டு, புதிய விலை ரூ.510 ஆக இருக்கும்.",
        "ஜூலை 21 முதல் நுகர்வோருக்கு ஒக்டேன் 95 மற்றும் லங்கா ஒயிட் டீசல் தொடர்ந்து விநியோகிக்கப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்கான சிறப்புத் திட்டம் நடைமுறையில் இருப்பதாகவும் CPC தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்றிரவு",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரோ 4",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}