{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/dialog-axiata-extends-its-support-to-the-sri-dalada-perahera-for-the-16th-consecutive-year/",
  "time_ut": 1660672440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dialog Axiata extends its support to the Sri Dalada Perahera for the 16th consecutive year",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dialog Axiata extends its support to the Sri Dalada Perahera for the 16th consecutive year",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "As a key contributor and advocator of the major cultural and religious festivals in the country, Dialog Axiata PLC, Sri Lanka’s premier connectivity provider, once again extended its support to the Kandy Esala Perahera (also known as the Sri Dalada Perahera or the Festival of the Tooth) which was held from August 2 – 12.",
        "One of the oldest and most venerated religious festivals in Sri Lanka, the Sri Dalada Perahera is held in the month of Esala (July or August) to commemorate the first sermon of Lord Buddha after he attained enlightenment. A 10-day event, the Kandy Esala Perahera pays homage to the Sacred Tooth Relic and its four guardian deities, Gods Natha, Vishnu, Kataragama and Goddess Pattini. The procession appeals to the Gods, seeking their blessings for rains that will aid the cultivation of crops and the prosperity of the country.",
        "While large crowds of spectators travelled from near and far to witness the procession, Dialog enabled its customers with the facility to watch the festival from the comfort of their homes by broadcasting it on Dialog Television.",
        "In its efforts of preserving and promoting Sri Lanka’s heritage and culture, Dialog has been a long-term patron of a multitude of events across the country, contributing to the upliftment of Sri Lanka’s rich cultural history. This year will be the 16th consecutive year Dialog Axiata has extended its support to the historical Kandy Esala Festival and the procession of the Temple of the Sacred Tooth Relic of Kandy.",
        "SME businesses in Puttalam enriched by Seylan Bank and CCC workshop",
        "Profit-takings in blue chip counters put an end to bourse’s bullish run",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Sri Dalada Perahera",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the 16th consecutive year",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Esala Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Dalada Perahera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tooth",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Dalada Perahera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Esala Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sacred Tooth Relic",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vishnu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Television",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Esala Festival",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Dialog Axiata අඛණ්ඩව 16 වන වරටත් ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැරට සිය සහය",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ ප්‍රධාන සංස්කෘතික හා ආගමික උත්සවවල ප්‍රධාන දායකයෙකු සහ උපදේශකයෙකු ලෙස, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම සම්බන්ධතා සපයන්නා වන Dialog Axiata PLC නැවත වරක් මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැරට (ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැර හෝ මහා මංගල්‍යය ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ. දත්) අගෝස්තු 2 සිට 12 දක්වා පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පැරණිතම සහ ගෞරවාදරයට පාත්‍ර වූ ආගමික උත්සවයක් වන ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැර ඇසළ මාසයේ (ජූලි හෝ අගෝස්තු) බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ බුද්ධත්වයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු සිදු කළ ප්‍රථම දේශනාව සිහිපත් කිරීම සඳහා පවත්වනු ලැබේ. දින 10 ක උත්සවයක් වන මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර ශ්‍රී දළදා වහන්සේ සහ එහි සතර මුර දේවතාවුන් වන නාථ, විෂ්ණු, කතරගම සහ පත්තිනි දෙවිඳුන්ට වන්දනාමාන කරයි. භෝග වගාවට සහ රටේ සෞභාග්‍යයට උපකාර වන වර්ෂාපතනය සඳහා දෙවියන්ගේ ආශිර්වාදය පතා පෙරහැර දෙවියන්ට ආයාචනා කරයි.",
        "පෙරහැර නැරඹීමට අවට සහ දුර බැහැර ප්‍රදේශවලින් විශාල ප්‍රේක්ෂක පිරිසක් පැමිණි අතර, ඩයලොග් විසින් එය Dialog රූපවාහිනිය ඔස්සේ විකාශය කරමින් තම පාරිභෝගිකයන්ට තම නිවෙස්වල සිටම උත්සවය නැරඹීමේ පහසුකම සලසා දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උරුමය සහ සංස්කෘතිය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමේ සහ ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ එහි ප්‍රයත්නයන්හිදී, Dialog ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොහොසත් සංස්කෘතික ඉතිහාසය නඟා සිටුවීමට දායක වෙමින් රට පුරා සිදුවීම් රාශියකට දිගුකාලීන අනුග්‍රාහකයෙකු වී ඇත. මෙවර පැවැත්වෙන්නේ අඛණ්ඩව 16 වැනි වරටත් පැවැත්වෙන මහනුවර ඓතිහාසික ඇසළ මංගල්‍යය සහ මහනුවර ශ්‍රී දළදා මාලිගාවේ පෙරහැර සඳහා Dialog Axiata සිය සහයෝගය ලබාදී ඇත.",
        "පුත්තලමේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර සෙලාන් බැංකුව සහ CCC වැඩමුළුව මගින් පොහොසත් කර ඇත",
        "බ්ලූ චිප් කවුන්ටරවල ලාභ ලැබීම්, කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ ඉහළ යාමේ ධාවනයට තිත තැබීය",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අඛණ්ඩව 16 වන වසර",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇසල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී දළදා වහන්සේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විෂ්ණු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩයලොග් රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව 16 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර ඇසළ උත්සවය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Dialog Axiata தொடர்ந்து 16வது ஆண்டாக ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெராவிற்கு தனது ஆதரவை வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் முக்கிய கலாச்சார மற்றும் மத விழாக்களில் முக்கிய பங்களிப்பாளராகவும், வக்கீலாகவும், இலங்கையின் முதன்மை இணைப்பு வழங்குனரான Dialog Axiata PLC மீண்டும் கண்டி எசல பெரஹெராவிற்கு (ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெரா அல்லது திருவிழா என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. பல்) ஆகஸ்ட் 2 முதல் 12 வரை நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இலங்கையின் பழமையான மற்றும் மிகவும் போற்றப்படும் சமய விழாக்களில் ஒன்றான ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெரா எசல மாதத்தில் (ஜூலை அல்லது ஆகஸ்ட்) புத்த பகவான் ஞானம் பெற்ற பிறகு அவர் செய்த முதல் பிரசங்கத்தை நினைவுகூரும் வகையில் நடத்தப்படுகிறது. 10 நாள் நிகழ்வு, கண்டி எசல பெரஹெரா புனித பல்லக்கு மற்றும் அதன் நான்கு காவல் தெய்வங்களான நாதா, விஷ்ணு, கதிர்காமம் மற்றும் பத்தினி தெய்வங்களுக்கு மரியாதை செலுத்துகிறது. இந்த ஊர்வலம், பயிர்கள் பயிரிடுவதற்கும், நாட்டின் செழிப்புக்கும் உதவும் மழைக்காக கடவுள்களின் ஆசீர்வாதத்தை வேண்டி, முறையிடுகிறது.",
        "ஊர்வலத்தைக் காண அருகிலிருந்தும் வெகுதொலைவில் இருந்தும் பெருந்திரளான பார்வையாளர்கள் பயணித்த போது, ​​டயலொக் தொலைக்காட்சியில் ஒளிபரப்புவதன் மூலம், டயலொக் தனது வாடிக்கையாளர்களை தங்கள் வீடுகளில் இருந்து விழாவைக் காணும் வசதியை வழங்கியது.",
        "இலங்கையின் பாரம்பரியம் மற்றும் கலாசாரத்தை பாதுகாத்து மேம்படுத்தும் முயற்சிகளில், இலங்கையின் வளமான கலாச்சார வரலாற்றை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு பங்களித்து, நாடு முழுவதும் பல நிகழ்வுகளுக்கு டயலொக் நீண்டகால ஆதரவாளராக இருந்து வருகிறது. இந்த வருடம் தொடர்ச்சியாக 16வது வருடமாக Dialog Axiata ஆனது வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க கண்டி எசல திருவிழாவிற்கும் கண்டி புனித பல்லக்கு ஆலய ஊர்வலத்திற்கும் தனது ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "புத்தளத்தில் உள்ள SME வணிகங்கள் செலான் வங்கி மற்றும் CCC பட்டறை மூலம் வளப்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன",
        "ப்ளூ சிப் கவுண்டர்களில் லாபம் ஈட்டுவது, பங்குச்சந்தையின் ஏற்றமான ஓட்டத்திற்கு முற்றுப்புள்ளி வைத்தது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெரா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தொடர்ந்து 16வது ஆண்டு",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி எசல பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எசல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி எசல பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித பல்லின் நினைவுச்சின்னம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஷ்ணு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டயலொக் தொலைக்காட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 16வது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி எசல திருவிழா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}