{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132469",
  "time_ut": 1659079147,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களை ஒன்றிணைத்து மஹிந்த தலைமையில் விசேட பேச்சுவார்த்தை - சாகர காரியவசம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A special discussion led by Mahinda bringing together the members of Podujana Peramuna - Sagara Kariyavasam",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Podujana Peramuna will give its full support to the President Ranil Wickremesinghe-led government.",
        "Sagara Kariyawasam, Secretary General of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna said that we have decided to bring together the members of Podujana Peramuna and carry out special talks under the leadership of former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa.",
        "In the situation where the economic crisis has intensified in the country, we have supported the formation of the government under the leadership of President Ranil Wickremesinghe so that political factors should not be given priority.",
        "A few members of Podujana Peramuna have refrained from supporting President Ranil Wickremesinghe based on their personal animosity.",
        "We have supported President Ranil Wickremesinghe so that political factors should not be prioritized when the economic crisis has intensified.",
        "It cannot be assumed that everyone's views are unanimous in all cases.",
        "Therefore, we have decided to bring together all the members and carry out a special discussion under the leadership of former Prime Minister Party leader Mahinda Rajapaksa.",
        "The narrow political agenda of the 10 political parties that claim to be independent in Parliament has undermined the entire political structure.",
        "He said that we will soon make it public with evidence that the protests have taken place due to political manipulation and are taking place."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahinda",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Podujana Peramuna - Sagara Kariyavasam",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහින්දගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කැඳවා විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාවක් - සාගර කාරියවසම්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ රජයට පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබා දෙනවා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසුවේ, හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සාමාජිකයන් එක් කර විශේෂ සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "රටතුළ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වී ඇති තත්ත්වය තුළ දේශපාලන සාධකවලට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය නොදිය යුතු පරිදි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් රජය පිහිටුවීමට අපි සහයෝගය ලබාදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "පෞද්ගලික තරහක් මත පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දීමෙන් වැලකී සිටිනවා.",
        "අපි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමාට සහයෝගය දීලා තියෙන්නේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වී ඇති අවස්ථාවක දේශපාලන සාධකවලට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය නොදිය යුතු නිසයි.",
        "සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම සෑම කෙනෙකුගේම අදහස් ඒකමතික යැයි සිතිය නොහැක.",
        "ඒ නිසා අපි තීරණය කළා හිටපු අගමැති පක්‍ෂ නායක මහින්ද රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් එකතු කරගෙන විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාවක් කරන්න.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන යැයි කියන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ 10 ගේ පටු දේශපාලන න්‍යාය පත්‍රය සමස්ත දේශපාලන ව්‍යුහයම හෑල්ලූවට ලක් කර ඇත.",
        "එම විරෝධතා දේශපාලන හසුරුවීම් මත සිදුවී ඇති බවත් ඒවා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත් සාක්ෂි සහිතව අපි ළඟදීම ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහින්ද",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ - සාගර කාරියවසම්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களை ஒன்றிணைத்து மஹிந்த தலைமையில் விசேட பேச்சுவார்த்தை - சாகர காரியவசம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பொதுஜன பெரமுன முழுமையான ஆதரவை வழங்கும்.",
        "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களை ஒன்றிணைத்து முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையில் விசேட பேச்சுவார்த்தையை முன்னெடுக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளோம் என  ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச்செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தீவிரமடைந்துள்ள சூழ்நிலையில் அரசியல் காரணிகளுக்கு முன்னுரிமை வழங்க கூடாது என்பதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையில் அரசாங்கத்தை தோற்றுவித்து ஆதரவு வழங்கியுள்ளோம்.",
        "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஒருசில உறுப்பினர்கள் தங்களின் தனிப்பட்ட பகைமை அடிப்படையாக கொண்டு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்குவதை தவிர்த்துள்ளார்கள்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தீவிரமடைந்துள்ள நிலையில் அரசியல் காரணிகளுக்கு முன்னுரிமை வழங்க கூடாது என்பதற்காகவே ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்கியுள்ளோம்.",
        "சகலரது கருத்துக்களும் அனைத்து சந்தர்ப்பங்களிலும் ஒருமித்த வகையில் காணப்படும் என கருத முடியாது.",
        "ஆகவே அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களையும் ஒன்றிணைத்து முன்னாள் பிரதமர் கட்சியின் தலைவர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையில் விசேட பேச்சுவார்த்தையினை முன்னெடுக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளோம்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படுவதாக குறிப்பிட்டுக்கொள்ளும் 10 அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் குறுகிய அரசியல் நோக்கம் முழு அரசியல் கட்டமைப்பையும் பாதிப்பிற்குள்ளாக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "அரசியல் சூழ்ச்சியினால் போராட்டகங்கள் இடம் பெற்றது, இடம் பெறுகிறது என்பதை வெகுவிரைவில் ஆதாரபூர்வமாக பகிரங்கப்படுத்துவோம் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஹிந்த",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன - சாகர காரியவசம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}