{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/අරගලකරුවන්-දෙපිරිසක්-අගමැති-මැදුරෙදී-ගුටි-ඇනගෙන/101-616278",
  "time_ut": 1657591222,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අරගලකරුවන් දෙපිරිසක් අගමැති මැදුරෙදී ගුටි ඇනගෙන",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two groups of activists beat each other at the Prime Minister's office",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A senior spokesman said that ten people who were injured in a clash between two groups of protesters inside the Kollupitiya temple complex have been admitted to the Colombo National Hospital.",
        "He said that nine men and one woman are among them",
        "An officer of the Kollupitiya police said that a conflict had arisen during the inquiries made to the Kollupitiya police and that officers would be dispatched to the place shortly for investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලකරුවන් දෙපිරිසක් අගමැති මැදුරෙදී ගුටි ඇනගෙන",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොල්ලුපිටිය අරලියගහ මන්දිරය තුළදී  අරගල කරුවන් දෙපිරිසක්   අතර ඇති වූ ගැටුමකින් තුවාල ලැබූ පුද්ගලයන් දස දෙනකු කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇතැයි එහි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය",
        "පිරිමි පුද්ගලයන් නම දෙනකු සහ කාන්තාවක ද ඒ අතර වන බව ඔහු පැවසීය",
        "මේ පිළිබඳ කොල්ලූපිටිය පොලිසියෙන් කළ  විමසීමේ දී ගැටුමක් ඇති වෙලා තිබෙන බවත් විමර්ශන කටයුතු සඳහා තව නොබෝ වේලාවකින් එම ස්ථානයට නිලධාරීන් පිටත් කර හරින බවත් එහි නිලධාරයෙක් කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதம மந்திரி அலுவலகத்தில் இரண்டு குழுக்களின் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் ஒருவரையொருவர் அடித்துக் கொண்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி ஆலய வளாகத்தினுள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட இரு குழுக்களுக்கிடையில் இடம்பெற்ற மோதலில் காயமடைந்த பத்து பேர் கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சிரேஷ்ட பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அவர்களில் ஒன்பது ஆண்களும் ஒரு பெண்ணும் அடங்குவதாக அவர் கூறினார்",
        "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸாரிடம் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசாரணைகளின் போது முரண்பாடு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், விசாரணைக்காக அதிகாரிகள் விரைவில் அந்த இடத்திற்கு அனுப்பப்படவுள்ளதாக கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}