{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Vatican-paying-close-attention-to-Sri-Lanka/342-240223",
  "time_ut": 1656733630,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Vatican paying close attention to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vatican paying close attention to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Vatican is closely following the current situation in Sri Lanka and on the developments pertaining to investigations on the Easter Sunday attacks, it is learnt.",
        "Under Secretary for the Holy See Mgr Miroslaw Wachowski in a letter addressed to Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP Dr. Kavinda Jayawardana has stated that the Vatican including Pope Francis with the means, and in the matter proper to it, has followed and studied the situation in Sri Lanka with attention and interest.",
        "“With your letter of March 27, you brought to the attention of Holy Father, among other issues, the recent issues in Sri Lanka, particularly those related to the Easter Sunday attacks in 2019 and necessity to address them urgently with transparency, for the sake of justice, and the common good. While I thank you for sharing your concerns in relation to those important subjects, I wish to assure you that the Holy See with the means, and in the matter proper to it, has followed and studied the situation in Sri Lanka with attention and interest,” the Under Secretary said in his letter to Dr. Jayawardana.(YOHAN PERERA)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vatican",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vatican",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Holy See Mgr Miroslaw Wachowski",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kavinda Jayawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vatican",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pope Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "March 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PERERA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වතිකානුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කෙරෙහි දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වතිකානුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සහ පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය පිළිබඳ විමර්ශනවලට අදාළ වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටින බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෛද්‍ය කාවින්ද ජයවර්ධන වෙත ලිපියක් යවමින් ශුද්ධාසනයේ උප ලේකම් Mgr Miroslaw Wachowski ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ ඇතුළු වතිකානුව ඊට සුදුසු ක්‍රමවේදයන් අනුගමනය කර අධ්‍යයනය කර ඇති බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය අවධානයෙන් හා උනන්දුවෙන්.",
        "\"මාර්තු 27 වැනි දින ඔබගේ ලිපිය සමඟ, ඔබ ශුද්ධෝත්තම පියතුමාගේ අවධානයට යොමු කළ අතර, අනෙකුත් කරුණු අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෑත කාලීන ගැටළු, විශේෂයෙන් 2019 පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයට සම්බන්ධ ගැටළු සහ විනිවිදභාවයෙන් යුතුව ඒවාට කඩිනමින් විසඳුම් ලබා දීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය. යුක්තිය සහ පොදු යහපත. එම වැදගත් විෂයයන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔබගේ උත්සුකයන් බෙදාගැනීම ගැන මම ඔබට ස්තූතිවන්ත වන අතරම, ශුද්ධාසනය ඒ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය විධික්‍රම සමඟින් සහ ඊට සුදුසු කාරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානයෙන් හා උනන්දුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය අනුගමනය කර අධ්‍යයනය කර ඇති බව ඔබට සහතික වීමට කැමැත්තෙමි. ” උප ලේකම්වරයා වෛද්‍ය ජයවර්ධන වෙත සිය ලිපියේ සඳහන් කළේය.(යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වතිකානුව",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වතිකානුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශුද්ධාසනය Mgr Miroslaw Wachowski",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවින්ද ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වතිකානුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வத்திக்கான் இலங்கையை உன்னிப்பாக கவனிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை மற்றும் ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள் தொடர்பான முன்னேற்றங்கள் குறித்து வத்திக்கான் உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருவதாக தெரியவருகிறது.",
        "புனித திருச்சபையின் துணைச் செயலாளர் Mgr Miroslaw Wachowski, சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டாக்டர். காவிந்த ஜெயவர்தனவுக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில், பாப்பரசர் பிரான்சிஸ் உட்பட வத்திக்கான், அதற்கான வழிமுறைகளையும், அதற்கான வழிமுறைகளையும் பின்பற்றி ஆய்வு செய்ததாகக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். கவனத்துடனும் ஆர்வத்துடனும் இலங்கையின் நிலைமை.",
        "“மார்ச் 27ஆம் திகதிய உங்கள் கடிதத்தின் மூலம், இலங்கையின் அண்மைக்காலப் பிரச்சினைகள், குறிப்பாக 2019 இல் ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகள் மற்றும் அவற்றை வெளிப்படைத் தன்மையுடன் அவசரமாக நிவர்த்தி செய்ய வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை நீங்கள் புனிதத் தந்தையின் கவனத்திற்குக் கொண்டு வந்தீர்கள். நீதி மற்றும் பொது நன்மை. முக்கியமான விடயங்கள் தொடர்பான உங்கள் கவலைகளைப் பகிர்ந்தமைக்காக நான் உங்களுக்கு நன்றி கூறுகின்ற அதேவேளை, பரிசுத்த ஆசனம், அதற்கான வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் அதற்கேற்ற விடயத்தில், இலங்கையின் நிலைமையை கவனத்துடனும் ஆர்வத்துடனும் பின்பற்றி ஆய்வு செய்துள்ளதாக நான் உங்களுக்கு உறுதியளிக்க விரும்புகின்றேன். ” என்று துணைச் செயலாளர் டாக்டர் ஜெயவர்தனவுக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில் கூறியுள்ளார்.(யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வாடிகன்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வாடிகன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி ஹோலி சீ எம்ஜிஆர் மிரோஸ்லா வச்சோவ்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிந்த ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாடிகன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "போப் பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}