{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘ජනතාව-සතුටුවන-ස්ථීර-විසැඳුමකට-යන්න‘‘/101-616162",
  "time_ut": 1657436916,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘ජනතාව සතුටුවන ස්ථීර විසැඳුමකට යන්න‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Go to a permanent solution that pleases the people.\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United States of America called on political parties in Sri Lanka to work quickly to achieve long-term economic and political solutions that would satisfy the Sri Lankan people.",
        "A spokesperson of the United States of America State Department said that the Parliament of Sri Lanka is requested to work for the betterment of Sri Lanka at this time and not for the betterment of one political party.",
        "The statement states that the United States of America calls on this government or the constitutionally elected new government to quickly identify and implement solutions that will achieve long-term economic stability that will satisfy the Sri Lankan people.",
        "The United States expressed dismay at the attacks on protesters and journalists and criticized the violence that erupted during Saturday's protest."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘ජනතාව සතුටුවන ස්ථීර විසැඳුමකට යන්න‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට සෑහීමකට පත් විය හැකි දිගු කාලීන ආර්ථික සහ දේශපාලනික විසඳුම් ළඟා කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඉක්මණින් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "එක් දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා මේ අවස්ථාවේ කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසුවේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට සෑහීමකට පත්විය හැකි දිගු කාලීන ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ළඟා කර ගත හැකි විසඳුම් ඉක්මණින් හඳුනා ගනිමින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලෙස මෙම රජයෙන් හෝ ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව පත්වන නව රජයෙන් ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය ඉල්ලා සිටින බව එම ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ඇමෙරිකා එකසත් ජනපදය විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට සහ මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහර දීම පිළිබඳ අප්‍රසාදය පළ කළ අතර සෙනසුරාදා විරෝධතාවයේදී ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය විවේචනය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மக்களை மகிழ்விக்கும் நிரந்தர தீர்வுக்கு செல்லுங்கள்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மக்களை திருப்திப்படுத்தும் நீண்ட கால பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் தீர்வுகளை அடைவதற்கு விரைவாக செயற்படுமாறு இலங்கையிலுள்ள அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கு அமெரிக்கா அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நேரத்தில் ஒரு அரசியல் கட்சியின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக அல்லாமல் இலங்கையின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம் பாடுபட வேண்டும் என அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களை திருப்திப்படுத்தும் நீண்ட கால பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை அடையக்கூடிய தீர்வுகளை விரைவாக இனங்கண்டு அமுல்படுத்துமாறு இந்த அரசாங்கம் அல்லது அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட புதிய அரசாங்கத்திடம் அமெரிக்கா அழைப்பு விடுப்பதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மற்றும் பத்திரிகையாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்கள் குறித்து அமெரிக்கா வருத்தம் தெரிவித்ததோடு, சனிக்கிழமையன்று நடந்த போராட்டத்தின் போது வெடித்த வன்முறையையும் விமர்சித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}