{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/implement-ag-recommendations-on-chinese-fertilizer-ship-sajith/",
  "time_ut": 1662132780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Implement AG recommendations on Chinese Fertilizer ship: Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Implement AG recommendations on Chinese Fertilizer ship: Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa emphasizes that the recommendations presented by the Auditor General in his report concerning the Chinese Fertilizer shipment should be implemented as soon as possible.",
        "The Opposition Leader, pointing out that a report has been compiled by the Auditor General, said that legal action should be instituted against those responsible for causing a loss to the government by releasing funds for the Chinese Fertilizer shipment with zero supervision.",
        "Moreover, Premadasa said that recommendations have also been made to recover compensation from the supplier, which has been blacklisted in Sri Lanka.",
        "\"Therefore, I appeal the Government to actively take steps to reover the loss without waiting for the Auditor General's recommendations\" he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese Fertilizer",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Fertilizer",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන පොහොර නැව සම්බන්ධයෙන් නීතිපති නිර්දේශ ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන්න: සජිත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); චීන පොහොර තොගය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විගණකාධිපතිවරයා සිය වාර්තාවෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති නිර්දේශ කඩිනමින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතු බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "විගණකාධිපතිවරයා විසින් වාර්තාවක් සම්පාදනය කර ඇති බව පෙන්වා දුන් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා, චීන පොහොර තොගය සඳහා කිසිදු අධීක්‍ෂණයකින් තොරව මුදල් නිකුත් කර රජයට පාඩුවක් සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වගකිව යුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගත යුතු බව පැවසීය.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අසාදු ලේඛනගත කර ඇති සැපයුම්කරුගෙන් වන්දි අයකර ගැනීමට ද නිර්දේශ ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"එබැවින් විගණකාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිර්දේශ එනතෙක් බලා නොසිට අලාභය අයකර ගැනීමට ක්‍රියාකාරීව පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස මම රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමි,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන පොහොර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන පොහොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශුන්ය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපතිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன உரக் கப்பலில் AG பரிந்துரைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துங்கள்: சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சீன உர ஏற்றுமதி தொடர்பில் கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம் தனது அறிக்கையில் முன்வைத்துள்ள பரிந்துரைகளை விரைவில் அமுல்படுத்த வேண்டும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகத்தினால் அறிக்கை தொகுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டிய எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், சீன உரக் கப்பலுக்கு பூஜ்ய கண்காணிப்புடன் நிதியை விடுவித்து அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நஷ்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியவர்கள் மீது சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "மேலும், இலங்கையில் கறுப்புப் பட்டியலில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ள சப்ளையரிடமிருந்து இழப்பீட்டுத் தொகையை வசூலிக்கவும் பரிந்துரைகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "\"எனவே, கணக்காய்வாளர் ஜெனரலின் பரிந்துரைகளுக்குக் காத்திருக்காமல், இழப்பை ஈடுகட்ட அரசு தீவிரமாக நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஏஜி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன உரம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன உரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}