{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හි﻿ඟා-කාලා-හරි-පාසල්-ළමුන්ට-කෑම-වේල-දෙනවා/11-396807",
  "time_ut": 1662011319,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හි﻿ඟා කාලා හරි පාසල් ළමුන්ට කෑම වේල දෙනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Meals are given to begging or school children",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"Giving food to children in times of need. What's wrong with that?\" Education Minister Susil Premjayantha asked in Parliament.",
        "He said this while clarifying the issue raised in the Parliament yesterday regarding receiving a stock of food from America as aid.",
        "He also mentioned that he has been wearing black suits since before 1985. That some persons were in the dock when they represented the defendants in court.",
        "He further said that when he became the minister, he first thought about the process of providing lunch for school children."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premjayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හි﻿ඟා කාලා හරි පාසල් ළමුන්ට කෑම වේල දෙනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"හිඟාකාල හරි ළමයින්ට කෑම වේලක් දෙනවා. ඒ්කේ වැරැද්ද මොකක්ද?\" යැයි අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේම්ජයන්ත මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුමේදී ‌විමසා සිටියේය.",
        "ඇමෙරිකාවෙන් ආහාර තොගයක් ආධාරයක් ලෙස ලබාගැනිම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී මතුවූ කරුණ පිළිබඳව පැහැදිලි කිරීමක් කරමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවැසීය.",
        "තමා කළු සූට් ඇන්දේ 1985ට පෙර සිට බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. තමන් උසාවියේදී විත්තිකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටින විට ඇතැම් පුද්ගලයන් විත්ති කූඩුවේ සිටි බවයි.",
        "තමා අමාත්‍යධුරයට පත්වූ විට තමන් මුලින්ම කල්පනා කළේ පාසල් ළමුන් වෙනුවෙන් දිවා ආහාරය ලබාදීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේම්ජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிச்சை எடுக்கும் அல்லது பள்ளிக் குழந்தைகளுக்கு உணவு வழங்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"குழந்தைகளுக்கு தேவையான நேரத்தில் உணவு கொடுப்பது. அதில் என்ன தவறு?\" என கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேம்ஜயந்த பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "அமெரிக்காவிடமிருந்து உணவுப் பொருட்களை உதவியாகப் பெறுவது தொடர்பில் நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எழுப்பப்பட்ட பிரச்சினை தொடர்பில் தெளிவுபடுத்தும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "1985ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கு முன்னரே கறுப்பு உடை அணிந்து வருவதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். நீதிமன்றத்தில் பிரதிவாதிகள் சார்பில் வாதாடிய போது சிலர் படகுத்துறையில் இருந்தனர்.",
        "அவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில், தான் அமைச்சரானவுடன் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு மதிய உணவு வழங்கும் செயற்பாடுகளை முதலில் சிந்தித்தேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேம்ஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}