{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/sec-cse-and-ca-sri-lanka-to-capitalize-on-synergies-to-encourage-and-advance-non-financial-reporting/",
  "time_ut": 1662145020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SEC, CSE and CA Sri Lanka to capitalize on synergies to encourage and advance non-financial reporting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SEC, CSE and CA Sri Lanka to capitalize on synergies to encourage and advance non-financial reporting",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Securities and Exchange Commission of Sri Lanka (SEC), the Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) and the Institute of Chartered Accountants of Sri Lanka (CA Sri Lanka) recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to encourage and advance non-financial reporting in Sri Lanka.",
        "Through the MoU, the three institutions aim to capitalize on mutual interests and synergies to jointly deliver awareness on Integrated Reporting, Corporate Governance, Sustainability and other ESG focus areas. Furthermore, the MoU also paves the way for broader cooperation on ESG, including dialogue and consultations on driving progressive ESG policies & frameworks and the introduction of ESG focused new products in the capital market and joint stakeholder engagement on advancing ESG.",
        "Chairman of the SEC Viraj Dayaratne PC commenting on the development stated “The MoU with CA Sri Lanka brings together three like-minded institutions, with the common goal of establishing more elaborate and transparent reporting of non-financial information in Sri Lanka. The MoU lays a long-term foundation for the SEC and CSE to work with CA Sri Lanka to introduce policies to ensure that Sri Lankan corporates report more progressively and in-line with international standards, especially in relation to the meaningful disclosure of non-financial information.”",
        "Chairman of CSE Dilshan Wirasekara commenting on the MoU said “Through this MoU, the CSE aims to work with the SEC and CA Sri Lanka to encourage more Sri Lankan corporates to use non-financial reporting as a means to deliver trust and confidence to the market on long term value creation. Our joint efforts also will focus on aligning the interests of institutions that report on non-financial performance with those who use such information such as investors, analysts and others, which will result in further enhancing the quality of non-financial information and encourage informed decision making.”",
        "President of CA Sri Lanka Mr. Sanjaya Bandara said “Along with financial information, non-financial information is essential for presenting a more comprehensive picture of corporate performance, and CA Sri Lanka is dedicated to promoting both financial and non-financial reporting in our position as the national body of accountants and as the sole standard-setter. Therefore, we are happy to partner with SEC and CSE in this landmark endeavor in our joint efforts to encourage and advance non-financial reporting in Sri Lanka.”",
        "Chairman Viraj Dayaratne PC and Director General Chinthaka Mendis were signatories to the MoU from the SEC while Chairman Dilshan Wirasekara and CEO Rajeeva Bandaranaike signed on-behalf of the CSE. President Sanjaya Bandara was the signatory from CA Sri Lanka. SEC Commission Member and Immediate Past President of CA Sri Lanka Manil Jayesinghe, CA Sri Lanka CEO Ms. Dulani Fernando and other senior officials from the SEC and CSE were also present at the event.",
        "A toast to partnership – amanté hosts inaugural Frontline Partners’ Night",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SEC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Securities and Exchange Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Institute of Chartered Accountants of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Integrated Reporting",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sustainability",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MoU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ESG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ESG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the SEC Viraj Dayaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The MoU with CA Sri Lanka",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilshan Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjaya Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Viraj Dayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilshan Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajeeva Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjaya Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manil Jayesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulani Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Frontline Partners’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SEC, CSE සහ CA ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මූල්‍ය නොවන වාර්තාකරණය දිරිගැන්වීම සහ දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන ගැනීමට",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාව (SEC), කොළඹ කොටස් හුවමාරුව (CSE) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරලත් ගණකාධිකාරී ආයතනය (CA Sri Lanka) විසින් මූල්‍ය නොවන වාර්තාකරණය දිරිමත් කිරීම සහ දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමක් (MoU) පසුගියදා අත්සන් කරන ලදී. ලංකාවේ.",
        "අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම හරහා, ආයතන තුන ඒකාබද්ධ වාර්තාකරණය, ආයතනික පාලනය, තිරසාරභාවය සහ අනෙකුත් ESG අවධානය යොමු කරන ක්ෂේත්‍ර පිළිබඳව ඒකාබද්ධව දැනුවත් කිරීම සඳහා අන්‍යෝන්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සහ සහයෝගීතාවයන් ප්‍රයෝජනයට ගැනීම අරමුණු කරයි. තවද, ප්‍රගතිශීලී ESG ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ රාමු මෙහෙයවීම පිළිබඳ සංවාද සහ උපදේශන සහ ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළඳපොළ තුළ ESG අවධානය යොමු කරන ලද නව නිෂ්පාදන හඳුන්වාදීම සහ ESG ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා හවුල් පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය ඇතුළුව ESG පිළිබඳ පුළුල් සහයෝගීතාව සඳහා ද අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම මග පාදයි.",
        "සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ විරාජ් දයාරත්න මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ “ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ මූල්‍ය නොවන තොරතුරු වඩාත් සවිස්තරාත්මක සහ විනිවිදභාවයෙන් වාර්තා කිරීමේ පොදු අරමුණ ඇතිව, CA ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමඟ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම සමාන අදහස් ඇති ආයතන තුනක් එකට ගෙන එයි. විශේෂයෙන්ම මූල්‍ය නොවන අර්ථවත් ලෙස හෙළිදරව් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආයතනික වාර්තා වඩාත් ප්‍රගතිශීලීව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුකූලව වාර්තා කිරීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්ති හඳුන්වාදීම සඳහා CA ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ වැඩ කිරීමට SEC සහ CSE සඳහා මෙම අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම දිගුකාලීන පදනමක් දරයි. විස්තර.\"",
        "අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් CSE හි සභාපති ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර මහතා පැවසුවේ, “මෙම අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම හරහා, වෙළඳපලට විශ්වාසය සහ විශ්වාසය ලබා දීමේ මාධ්‍යයක් ලෙස මූල්‍ය නොවන වාර්තාකරණය භාවිතා කිරීමට වැඩි ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ආයතනික ආයතන දිරිමත් කිරීම සඳහා SEC සහ CA Sri Lanka සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කිරීමට CSE අපේක්ෂා කරයි. දිගු කාලීන වටිනාකම් නිර්මාණය මත. අපගේ ඒකාබද්ධ ප්‍රයත්නයන් ආයෝජකයින්, විශ්ලේෂකයින් සහ වෙනත් අය වැනි තොරතුරු භාවිතා කරන අය සමඟ මූල්‍ය නොවන කාර්ය සාධනය පිළිබඳ වාර්තා කරන ආයතනවල අවශ්‍යතා පෙළගැස්වීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරනු ඇත, එමඟින් මූල්‍ය නොවන තොරතුරුවල ගුණාත්මක භාවය තවදුරටත් ඉහළ නැංවීමට සහ දැනුවත් තීරණ දිරිගන්වනු ඇත. හදනවා.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා CA හි සභාපති සංජය බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසුවේ, “ආයතනික කාර්ය සාධනය පිළිබඳ වඩාත් පුළුල් චිත්‍රයක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා මූල්‍ය තොරතුරු සමඟ මූල්‍ය නොවන තොරතුරු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන අතර, CA Sri Lanka අපගේ තත්ත්වය තුළ මූල්‍ය සහ මූල්‍ය නොවන වාර්තාකරණය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට කැපවී සිටී. ජාතික ගණකාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය ලෙස සහ එකම ප්‍රමිති සකසන්නෙකු ලෙස. එබැවින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මූල්‍ය නොවන වාර්තාකරණය දිරිමත් කිරීමට සහ ප්‍රගතියට ගෙන ඒමේ අපගේ ඒකාබද්ධ ප්‍රයත්නයේ මෙම සන්ධිස්ථානයේ ප්‍රයත්නයෙහි SEC සහ CSE සමඟ හවුල් වීමට ලැබීම ගැන අපි සතුටු වෙමු.”",
        "සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ විරාජ් දයාරත්න සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් චින්තක මෙන්ඩිස් සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමට අත්සන් කළ අතර කොළඹ කොටස් හුවමාරුව වෙනුවෙන් සභාපති ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී රජීව බණ්ඩාරනායක අත්සන් කළහ. CA Sri Lanka වෙතින් අත්සන් කළේ ජනාධිපති සංජය බණ්ඩාර ය. සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සාමාජික සහ CA ශ්‍රී ලංකා හි ක්ෂණික හිටපු සභාපති මනිල් ජයසිංහ, CA ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී දුලානි ප්‍රනාන්දු මෙනවිය සහ සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සහ CSE හි අනෙකුත් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "හවුල්කාරිත්වයට සව්දිය - amanté සමාරම්භක Frontline Partners' Night",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SEC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරලත් ගණකාධිකාරී ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒකාබද්ධ වාර්තාකරණය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරසාර බව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ESG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ESG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරැකුම්පත් හා විනිමය කොමිෂන් සභාව විරාජ් දයාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA Sri Lanka සමඟ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජය බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරාජ් දයාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජීව බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජය බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනිල් ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුලානි ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරටුගාමී හවුල්කරුවන්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SEC, CSE மற்றும் CA ஸ்ரீலங்கா ஆகியவை நிதி அல்லாத அறிக்கையிடலை ஊக்குவிப்பதற்காகவும் முன்னேற்றுவதற்காகவும் சினெர்ஜிகளைப் பயன்படுத்துகின்றன.",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் பத்திரங்கள் மற்றும் பரிவர்த்தனை ஆணைக்குழு (SEC), கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை (CSE) மற்றும் இலங்கையின் பட்டயக் கணக்காளர்கள் நிறுவனம் (CA Sri Lanka) ஆகியவை நிதியல்லாத அறிக்கைகளை ஊக்குவிக்கவும் முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்லவும் அண்மையில் புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் (MoU) கையெழுத்திட்டன. இலங்கையில்",
        "புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தின் மூலம், மூன்று நிறுவனங்களும் பரஸ்பர நலன்கள் மற்றும் ஒருங்கிணைந்த அறிக்கையிடல், கார்ப்பரேட் நிர்வாகம், நிலைத்தன்மை மற்றும் பிற ESG கவனம் செலுத்தும் பகுதிகள் பற்றிய விழிப்புணர்வை கூட்டாக வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளன. மேலும், இந்த புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம் ESG இல் பரந்த ஒத்துழைப்பிற்கு வழி வகுக்கிறது, இதில் முற்போக்கான ESG கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் கட்டமைப்புகளை இயக்குவதற்கான உரையாடல் மற்றும் ஆலோசனைகள் மற்றும் ESG கவனம் செலுத்தும் புதிய தயாரிப்புகளை மூலதன சந்தையில் அறிமுகப்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் ESG ஐ முன்னேற்றுவதில் கூட்டு பங்குதாரர்களின் ஈடுபாடு ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "அபிவிருத்தி குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த SEC இன் தலைவர் விராஜ் தயாரத்ன பிசி, “சிஏ ஸ்ரீலங்காவுடனான புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம், இலங்கையில் நிதி அல்லாத தகவல்களை மிகவும் விரிவான மற்றும் வெளிப்படையான அறிக்கையிடலை நிறுவும் பொதுவான இலக்குடன், ஒத்த எண்ணம் கொண்ட மூன்று நிறுவனங்களை ஒன்றிணைக்கிறது. இந்த புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம் SEC மற்றும் CSE க்கு CA இலங்கையுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதற்கான நீண்டகால அடித்தளத்தை அமைக்கிறது. தகவல்.\"",
        "புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம் குறித்து CSE தலைவர் தில்ஷான் விரசேகர கருத்துத் தெரிவிக்கையில், “இந்த புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தின் மூலம், சந்தைக்கு நம்பிக்கை மற்றும் நம்பிக்கையை வழங்குவதற்கான வழிமுறையாக நிதியல்லாத அறிக்கைகளைப் பயன்படுத்துவதை ஊக்குவிக்கும் வகையில், SEC மற்றும் CA ஸ்ரீலங்காவுடன் இணைந்து செயல்படுவதை CSE நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. நீண்ட கால மதிப்பு உருவாக்கம். எங்கள் கூட்டு முயற்சிகள் முதலீட்டாளர்கள், ஆய்வாளர்கள் மற்றும் பிறர் போன்ற தகவல்களைப் பயன்படுத்துபவர்களுடன் நிதி அல்லாத செயல்திறனைப் பற்றி அறிக்கையிடும் நிறுவனங்களின் நலன்களை ஒருங்கிணைப்பதில் கவனம் செலுத்தும் தயாரித்தல்.\"",
        "CA ஸ்ரீலங்காவின் தலைவர் திரு.சஞ்சய பண்டார, \"நிதித் தகவல்களுடன், பெருநிறுவன செயல்திறன் பற்றிய விரிவான படத்தை வழங்குவதற்கு நிதி அல்லாத தகவல்களும் அவசியம், மேலும் CA Sri Lanka ஆனது நிதி மற்றும் நிதி அல்லாத அறிக்கைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு அர்ப்பணிப்புடன் உள்ளது. கணக்காளர்களின் தேசிய அமைப்பாகவும், ஒரே தரநிலை அமைப்பாகவும். எனவே, இலங்கையில் நிதியல்லாத அறிக்கையிடலை ஊக்குவித்து முன்னேற்றுவதற்கான எங்கள் கூட்டு முயற்சிகளில் இந்த முக்கிய முயற்சியில் SEC மற்றும் CSE உடன் பங்குதாரர்களாக இருப்பதில் நாங்கள் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம்.",
        "தலைவர் விராஜ் தயாரத்ன பிசி மற்றும் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் சிந்தக மெண்டிஸ் ஆகியோர் SEC யில் இருந்து புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டனர், மேலும் CSE சார்பாக தலைவர் டில்ஷான் விரசேகர மற்றும் CEO ரஜீவ பண்டாரநாயக்க ஆகியோர் கையெழுத்திட்டனர். சிஏ இலங்கையில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி சஞ்சய பண்டார கையெழுத்திட்டார். SEC ஆணைக்குழுவின் உறுப்பினரும் CA ஸ்ரீலங்காவின் உடனடி முன்னாள் தலைவருமான மணில் ஜெயசிங்க, CA Sri Lanka CEO திருமதி. துலானி பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் SEC மற்றும் CSE இன் மூத்த அதிகாரிகளும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "கூட்டாண்மைக்கு ஒரு சிற்றுண்டி - பிரண்ட்லைன் பார்ட்னர்ஸ் நைட் தொடக்க விழாவை அமன்டே நடத்துகிறார்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SEC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பத்திரங்கள் மற்றும் பரிவர்த்தனை ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பட்டய கணக்காளர்கள் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒருங்கிணைந்த அறிக்கையிடல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலைத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ESG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ESG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEC விராஜ் தயாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஏ இலங்கையுடன் புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டில்ஷான் விரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சய பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விராஜ் தயாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தக மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டில்ஷான் விரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஜீவ பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சய பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணில் ஜெயசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CA இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துலானி பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னணி பங்குதாரர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}