{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/EFC-appoints-new-Council-and-Board-of-Trustees-for-2022-2023/34-737064",
  "time_ut": 1656971677,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "EFC appoints new Council and Board of Trustees for 2022/2023",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "EFC appoints new Council and Board of Trustees for 2022/2023",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 93rd Annual General Meeting of the Employers’ Federation of Ceylon (EFC) was held on 29 June.",
        "The highlight of the AGM was the appointment of the Council and the Board of Trustees for the financial year 2022-2023.  Krishan Balendra was appointed as the new Chairman succeeding Vish Govindasamy while Dinesh Weerakkody was appointed as the Vice Chairman.",
        "The newly appointed Chairman Krishan Balendra who is also the Chairman of John Keells Holdings, one of the largest diversified conglomerates in the country, brings a wealth of experience. Balendra thanked the members for placing confidence in him and invited the members to closely engage with the EFC.  Joining the new Chairman is the newly appointed Vice Chairman Dinesh Weerakkody, Senior Company Director. He is also the former Chairman of the Employees’ Trust Fund Board of Sri Lanka, Commercial Bank of Ceylon and Hatton National Bank.",
        "13th Director General Vajira Ellepola to have taken the reins of the EFC with effect from 1 July, is an Attorney-at-Law and has been with the EFC since 2000. An experienced professional in the fields of employment law and industrial relations, Ellepola has held the position of the Deputy Director General of the EFC since July 2015.",
        "Established in 1929, the Employers’ Federation of Ceylon (EFC) is the national employers’ organisation in Sri Lanka. In its nearly 100-year journey, EFC had committed itself to adapt to the requirements of a dynamic membership to promote productive employment and social harmony. Apart from the wide range of services EFC provides to its member organisations which consist of individual employers representing different business interests, the organization has today evolved into a formidable body which commands the attention of the policy makers in relation to labour policy. The EFC is recognised by all Trade and Business Chambers in Sri Lanka as the ‘voice of business’ in relation to employment law and industrial relations here at home."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Council and Board of Trustees",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022/2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "93rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Annual General Meeting of the Employers’ Federation of Ceylon",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Trustees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the financial year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krishan Balendra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vish Govindasamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Krishan Balendra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Weerakkody",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Employees’ Trust Fund Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Bank of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton National Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Ellepola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ellepola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Employers’ Federation of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "all Trade and Business Chambers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "EFC විසින් 2022/2023 සඳහා නව කවුන්සිලය සහ භාරකාර මණ්ඩලය පත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා සේවා යෝජකයින්ගේ සම්මේලනයේ (EFC) 93 වැනි වාර්ෂික මහා සභා රැස්වීම ජුනි 29 දින පැවැත්විණි.",
        "AGM හි විශේෂත්වය වූයේ 2022-2023 මුදල් වර්ෂය සඳහා සභාව සහ භාරකාර මණ්ඩලය පත් කිරීමයි. විශ් ගෝවින්දසාමි මහතාගෙන් පසුව නව සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස ක්‍රිෂාන් බාලේන්ද්‍ර පත් කෙරුණු අතර උප සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස දිනේෂ් වීරක්කොඩි මහතා පත් කෙරුණා.",
        "මෙරට විශාලතම විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයක් වන ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි සභාපතිවරයා ද වන අභිනව සභාපති ක්‍රිෂාන් බාලේන්ද්‍ර මහතා අත්දැකීම් සම්භාරයක් ගෙන එයි. තමා කෙරෙහි විශ්වාසය තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බාලේන්ද්‍ර සාමාජිකයින්ට ස්තූතිය පුද කළ අතර EFC සමඟ සමීපව කටයුතු කරන ලෙස සාමාජිකයින්ට ආරාධනා කළේය. නව සභාපතිවරයා සමඟ එක්වන්නේ නව උප සභාපති දිනේෂ් වීරක්කොඩි, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ සමාගම් අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයාය. ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකා සේවක භාරකාර අරමුදල් මණ්ඩලයේ, කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුවේ සහ හැටන් නැෂනල් බැංකුවේ හිටපු සභාපතිවරයා ද වේ.",
        "13 වැනි අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් වජිර ඇල්ලේපොල මහතා ජුලි 01 දින සිට EFC හි පාලනය භාර ගන්නා අතර, නීතීඥවරයෙකු වන අතර 2000 වසරේ සිට EFC හි සේවය කර ඇත. රැකියා නීති සහ කාර්මික සම්බන්ධතා ක්ෂේත්‍රවල පළපුරුදු වෘත්තිකයෙකු වන ඇල්ලේපොල 2015 ජූලි මාසයේ සිට EFC හි නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් තනතුර දැරීය.",
        "1929 දී පිහිටුවන ලද, ලංකා සේවා යෝජකයින්ගේ සම්මේලනය (EFC) යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික සේවා යෝජකයින්ගේ සංවිධානයයි. එහි වසර 100කට ආසන්න ගමනේදී, ඵලදායී රැකියා සහ සමාජ සංහිඳියාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ගතික සාමාජිකත්වයක අවශ්‍යතාවලට අනුගත වීමට EFC කැපවී සිටියේය. විවිධ ව්‍යාපාරික අවශ්‍යතා නියෝජනය කරන තනි පුද්ගල සේවා යෝජකයින්ගෙන් සමන්විත EFC සිය සාමාජික සංවිධාන වෙත සපයන පුළුල් පරාසයක සේවාවන් හැරුණු විට, එම සංවිධානය අද කම්කරු ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්පාදකයින්ගේ අවධානයට ලක්වන බලවත් ආයතනයක් බවට පරිණාමය වී ඇත. EFC ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම වෙළඳ සහ ව්‍යාපාරික කුටි විසින් රැකියා නීති සහ කාර්මික සබඳතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් 'ව්‍යාපාරයේ හඬ' ලෙස පිළිගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සභාව සහ භාරකාර මණ්ඩලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022/2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "93 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා හාම්පුතුන්ගේ සම්මේලනයේ වාර්ෂික මහා සභා රැස්වීම",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරකාර මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂාන් බාලේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ් ගෝවින්දසාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂාන් බාලේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් වීරක්කොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේවක භාර අරමුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන් නැෂනල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර ඇල්ලේපොල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ලේපොල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා හාම්පුතුන්ගේ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 100ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියලුම වෙළඳ සහ ව්‍යාපාරික කුටි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022/2023க்கான புதிய கவுன்சில் மற்றும் அறங்காவலர் குழுவை EFC நியமிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை முதலாளிகள் சம்மேளனத்தின் (EFC) 93வது வருடாந்த பொதுக் கூட்டம் ஜூன் 29 அன்று நடைபெற்றது.",
        "2022-2023 நிதியாண்டிற்கான கவுன்சில் மற்றும் அறங்காவலர் குழு நியமனம் AGM இன் சிறப்பம்சமாகும். விஷ் கோவிந்தசாமிக்குப் பின் புதிய தலைவராக கிரிஷான் பாலேந்திராவும், உப தலைவராக தினேஷ் வீரக்கொடியும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தலைவர் கிரிஷான் பாலேந்திரா, நாட்டின் மிகப்பெரிய பல்வகைப்பட்ட கூட்டு நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸின் தலைவரும் ஆவார். தன் மீது நம்பிக்கை வைத்ததற்கு உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்த பாலேந்திரா, உறுப்பினர்களை EFC உடன் நெருக்கமாக ஈடுபட அழைத்தார். புதிய தலைவருடன் புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட உப தலைவர் தினேஷ் வீரக்கொடி, மூத்த நிறுவன பணிப்பாளர் ஆகியோர் இணைந்துள்ளனர். இவர் இலங்கையின் ஊழியர் நம்பிக்கை நிதிய சபை, கொமர்ஷல் பேங்க் ஆஃப் சிலோன் மற்றும் ஹட்டன் நேஷனல் வங்கி ஆகியவற்றின் முன்னாள் தலைவராகவும் உள்ளார்.",
        "13வது பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் வஜிர எல்லேபொல, ஜூலை 1 ஆம் தேதி முதல் EFC இன் ஆட்சியை பொறுப்பேற்றார், ஒரு சட்டத்தரணி மற்றும் EFC இல் 2000 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் பணியாற்றி வருகிறார். வேலைவாய்ப்பு சட்டம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை உறவுகள் துறைகளில் அனுபவம் வாய்ந்த நிபுணரான எல்லேபொல ஜூலை 2015 முதல் EFC இன் துணை இயக்குநர் ஜெனரலாக பதவி வகித்தார்.",
        "1929 இல் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட இலங்கை முதலாளிகளின் கூட்டமைப்பு (EFC) இலங்கையின் தேசிய முதலாளிகளின் அமைப்பாகும். ஏறக்குறைய 100 ஆண்டு கால பயணத்தில், EFC ஆனது உற்பத்தி வேலை வாய்ப்பு மற்றும் சமூக நல்லிணக்கத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு ஒரு மாறும் உறுப்பினர் தேவைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப தன்னை மாற்றிக் கொண்டது. பல்வேறு வணிக நலன்களைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் தனிப்பட்ட முதலாளிகளைக் கொண்ட அதன் உறுப்பு நிறுவனங்களுக்கு EFC வழங்கும் பரந்த அளவிலான சேவைகளைத் தவிர, தொழிலாளர் கொள்கை தொடர்பாக கொள்கை வகுப்பாளர்களின் கவனத்தை ஈர்க்கும் ஒரு வல்லமைமிக்க அமைப்பாக இன்று இந்த அமைப்பு உருவாகியுள்ளது. EFC ஆனது இலங்கையில் உள்ள அனைத்து வர்த்தக மற்றும் வர்த்தக அறைகளாலும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு சட்டம் மற்றும் உள்நாட்டில் தொழில்துறை உறவுகள் தொடர்பாக ‘வணிகத்தின் குரல்’ என அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சபை மற்றும் அறங்காவலர் குழு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022/2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "93வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை முதலாளிகள் சம்மேளனத்தின் வருடாந்த பொதுக்கூட்டம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஜிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அறங்காவலர் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருஷன் பாலேந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஷ கோவிந்தசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிருஷன் பாலேந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் வீரக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊழியர்களின் அறக்கட்டளை நிதி வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொமர்ஷல் பேங்க் ஆஃப் சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன் நேஷனல் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர எல்லேபொல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்லேபொல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் முதலாளிகள் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து வர்த்தக மற்றும் வணிக அறைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}