{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පැතුම්-කර්නර්ට-වරෙන්තු/11-396547",
  "time_ut": 1661237990,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පැතුම් කර්නර්ට වරෙන්තු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Warrants for Pathum Kerner",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Additional Magistrate Mr. Harshana Kekulawala ordered today (23rd) to arrest Dr. Pathum Kerner, who was an active member of the struggle, and bring him to court.",
        "These warrants were issued due to the fact that he did not appear in court in relation to the case regarding the incident of riotous behavior during a protest movement held at the Polduwa intersection near Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekulawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polduwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැතුම් කර්නර්ට වරෙන්තු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලයේ ක්‍රියාකාරී සාමාජිකයෙකු වූ වෛද්‍ය පැතුම් කර්නර් අත්අඩංගුව ගෙන අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන්නැයි කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුලාවල මහතා අද (23දා) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "පසුගියදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අසල ‍පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියේදී පැවති විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයක දී කලහකාරී ලෙස හැසිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන නඩුවට අදාළව ඔහු අධිකරණයේ පෙනී නොසිටීම හේතුවෙන් මෙම වරෙන්තු නිකුත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாத்தும் கெர்னருக்கான வாரண்டுகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "போராட்டத்தில் தீவிரமாக ஈடுபட்டிருந்த டொக்டர் பதும் கெர்னரை கைது செய்து நீதிமன்றில் முற்படுத்துமாறு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் திரு.ஹர்ஷன கெகுலவல இன்று (23) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகாமையில் உள்ள பொல்துவ சந்தியில் இடம்பெற்ற போராட்டத்தின் போது கலவரமாக நடந்து கொண்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலான வழக்கு தொடர்பில் அவர் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராகாத காரணத்தினால் இந்த பிடியாணை பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுலவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}