{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/ceylinco-lifes-la-serena-retirement-resort-goes-green-with-solar-energy/",
  "time_ut": 1661615160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ceylinco Life’s ‘La Serena’ retirement resort goes green with solar energy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ceylinco Life’s ‘La Serena’ retirement resort goes green with solar energy",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "La Serena, Sri Lanka’s first ever retirement resort for senior citizens, is harnessing the power of the sun — an ample resource at its beachfront location in Uswetakeiyawa — to “go green” by generating solar electricity for the national grid with an investment from its owner Ceylinco Life.",
        "The wholly-owned subsidiary of Sri Lanka’s leading life insurer has just commissioned a 100kW solar power system using its expanse of roofs to generate renewable energy that will contribute significantly to its sustainability credentials.",
        "La Serena’s solar power project, which is in line with Ceylinco Life’s own green mandate and sustainability initiatives, is funded by Ceylinco Life and will enable an offsetting of an estimated 136 tons of CO2 equivalent (tCO2e) emissions per year, and lead to shrinking its carbon footprint by 37 tons annually, the Company said.",
        "The 44-unit beach-front retirement resort has installed 4000 square feet of roof-fitted solar panels creating one of the largest solar power systems in the Wattala area.",
        "Built on almost three acres of scenic beachfront land in Uswetakeiyawa, just 14 km north of Colombo, La Serena comprises of 28 single chalets and 16 double chalets. Each living unit has its own living room, dining area, kitchenette, Wi-Fi and Cable TV facilities, and en-suite bathrooms, one for every bedroom, cleverly designed and furnished for optimal use of space – 535 square feet per single bedroom unit and 680 square feet per two bedroom unit.",
        "Ceylinco Life has already implemented a number of measures across its branch network to advance sustainability. These initiatives include constructing eco-friendly branch offices that are solar-powered and setting up rainwater harvesting, wastewater recycling, and energy-efficient lighting and air-conditioning systems in branch buildings owned by the company.",
        "Adjudged the ‘Most Valuable Life Insurance Brand in Sri Lanka’ in 2022 by Brand Finance, Sri Lanka’s Service Brand of the Year by the Sri Lanka Institute of Marketing (SLIM) in 2021 and the winner of the SLIM Kantar Peoples Award as the Most Popular Life Insurance Company in Sri Lanka for the 16th consecutive year, Ceylinco Life has been the country’s leading life insurer for more than half of the 34 years it has been in existence. Other accolades won in respect of 2021 include the ‘Most Popular Service Provider’ in Sri Lanka’s Life Insurance industry in 2021 by LMD, the ‘Most Valuable Life Insurance Brand’ in Sri Lanka by Brand Finance, one of the 10 Most Admired Companies in Sri Lanka by the International Chamber of Commerce Sri Lanka (ICCSL) in collaboration with the Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA), and one of the 10 Best Workplaces in Sri Lanka’s Banking, Financial Services and Insurance (BFSI) sector by Great Place to Work.",
        "Ceylinco Life has close to a million lives covered by active policies and provides innovative life insurance solutions which offer protection while de-risking the goals and ambitions of the Company’s policyholders.",
        "SLIC with half-year PBT of Rs. 7.7 bn, among top earning SOEs",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "La Serena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uswetakeiyawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylinco Life",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100kW",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "La Serena’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylinco Life’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylinco Life",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an estimated 136 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "per year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4000 square feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "almost three acres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uswetakeiyawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "La Serena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wi-Fi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cable TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "535 square feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "680 square feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylinco Life",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brand Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s Service Brand",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Institute of Marketing (SLIM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Most Popular Life Insurance Company in",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylinco Life",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Life Insurance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brand Finance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Chamber of Commerce Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chartered Institute of Management Accountants",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Banking, Financial Services and Insurance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Great Place to Work",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylinco Life",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "half-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT of Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ් හි ‘ලා සෙරීනා’ විශ්‍රාමික නිවාඩු නිකේතනය සූර්ය ශක්තියෙන් හරිත පැහැයට හැරේ",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පුරවැසියන් සඳහා වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම විශ්‍රාම නිකේතනය වන ලා සෙරීනා, එහි හිමිකරුගේ ආයෝජනයකින් ජාතික විදුලිබල පද්ධතියට සූර්ය විදුලිය උත්පාදනය කර “කොළ යන්න” සඳහා උස්වැටකෙයියාව වෙරළ තීරයේ ඇති ප්‍රමාණවත් සම්පතක් වන හිරුගේ බලය උපයෝගී කර ගනිමින් සිටී. සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ සමාගමට පූර්ණ හිමිකාරීත්වය දරන අනුබද්ධ සමාගම, සිය තිරසාර අක්තපත්‍ර සඳහා සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් සපයන පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය ජනනය කිරීම සඳහා එහි වහලවල්වල විශාලත්වය යොදා ගනිමින් 100kW සූර්ය බලශක්ති පද්ධතියක් දැන් ආරම්භ කර ඇත.",
        "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ් හි හරිත වරම සහ තිරසාර මුලපිරීම්වලට අනුකූල වන La Serena හි සූර්ය බලශක්ති ව්‍යාපෘතිය, සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ් විසින් අරමුදල් සපයනු ලබන අතර වසරකට ඇස්තමේන්තුගත CO2 ට සමාන (tCO2e) විමෝචනය ටොන් 136 ක් හිලව් කිරීමට සහ එය හැකිලීමට හේතු වනු ඇත. වාර්ෂිකව ටොන් 37 කින් කාබන් පියසටහන් බව සමාගම පවසයි.",
        "ඒකක 44 කින් සමන්විත වෙරළ-ඉදිරිපස විශ්‍රාමික නිවාඩු නිකේතනය වත්තල ප්‍රදේශයේ විශාලතම සූර්ය බලශක්ති පද්ධතියක් නිර්මාණය කරමින් වර්ග අඩි 4000 ක වහළ සවි කළ සූර්ය පැනල සවි කර ඇත.",
        "කොළඹට කිලෝමීටර් 14ක් උතුරින් උස්වැටකෙයියාවේ අක්කර තුනකට ආසන්න දර්ශනීය වෙරළ තීරයක ඉදිකර ඇති ලා සෙරීනා තනි කුටි 28 කින් සහ ද්විත්ව කුටි 16 කින් සමන්විත වේ. සෑම විසිත්ත ඒකකයකටම තමන්ගේම විසිත්ත කාමරයක්, කෑම කාමරයක්, මුළුතැන්ගෙයක්, Wi-Fi සහ කේබල් ටීවී පහසුකම් සහ එන්-සූට් නානකාමර, සෑම නිදන කාමරයකටම එකක්, දක්ෂ ලෙස සැලසුම් කර ඇති අතර ඉඩ ප්‍රශස්ත ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීම සඳහා සපයා ඇත - තනි නිදන කාමර ඒකකයකට වර්ග අඩි 535 කි. සහ නිදන කාමර දෙකක ඒකකයකට වර්ග අඩි 680 කි.",
        "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ් විසින් සිය ශාඛා ජාලය හරහා තිරසාරත්වය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා දැනටමත් පියවර රැසක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කර ඇත. මෙම මුල පිරීම්වලට සූර්ය බලයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිසර හිතකාමී ශාඛා කාර්යාල ඉදිකිරීම සහ සමාගම සතු ශාඛා ගොඩනැගිලිවල වැසි ජලය රැස් කිරීම, අපජල ප්‍රතිචක්‍රීකරණය සහ බලශක්ති කාර්යක්ෂම ආලෝකකරණ සහ වායු සමීකරණ පද්ධති පිහිටුවීම ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "2021 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා අලෙවිකරණ ආයතනය (SLIM) විසින් Brand Finance විසින් වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සේවා සන්නාමය වන 'ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වටිනාම ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ සන්නාමය' ලෙස 2022 දී සම්මානයට පාත්‍ර වූ අතර වඩාත් ජනප්‍රියම ලෙස SLIM Kantar ජනතා සම්මානයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබීය. අඛණ්ඩව 16 වැනි වසරටත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ සමාගම, සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ් වසර 34කට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක් මෙරට ප්‍රමුඛතම ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ සමාගම වී ඇත. 2021 වසරට අදාළව දිනාගත් අනෙකුත් සම්මාන අතරට LMD විසින් 2021 වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයේ 'වඩාත්ම ජනප්‍රිය සේවා සපයන්නා', ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ප්‍රශංසනීය සමාගම් 10න් එකක් වන Brand Finance විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 'වටිනාතම ජීවිත රක්ෂණ සන්නාමය' වේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාත්‍යන්තර වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය (ICCSL) විසින් වරලත් කළමනාකරණ ගණකාධිකාරී ආයතනය (CIMA) සමඟ සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් යුතුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බැංකු, මූල්‍ය සේවා සහ රක්‍ෂණ (BFSI) අංශයේ හොඳම සේවා ස්ථාන 10 න් එකකි. .",
        "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ් සක්‍රීය ප්‍රතිපත්ති මගින් ජීවිත මිලියනයකට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ආවරණය කර ඇති අතර සමාගමේ රක්ෂණ ඔප්පු හිමියන්ගේ ඉලක්ක සහ අභිලාෂයන් අවදානමෙන් ඉවත් කරන අතරම ආරක්ෂාව සපයන නව්‍ය ජීවිත රක්ෂණ විසඳුම් සපයයි.",
        "SLIC අර්ධ අවුරුදු PBT සමඟ රු. බිලියන 7.7, ඉහළම ඉපැයීම් ලබන SOEs අතර",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලා සෙරීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uswetakeiyawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100kW",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලා සෙරීනාගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇස්තමේන්තුගත ටොන් 136 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 37 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ග අඩි 4000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අක්කර තුනක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uswetakeiyawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 කි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලා සෙරීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wifi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රැහැන් සහිත රුපවාහිනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ග අඩි 535",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ග අඩි 680",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නාම මූල්‍ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සේවා සන්නාමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අලෙවිකරණ ආයතනය (SLIM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඩාත්ම ජනප්‍රිය ජීවිත රක්ෂණ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව 16 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩකටත් වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවිත රක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නාම මූල්‍ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ ගණකාධිකාරී වරලත් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකු, මූල්‍ය සේවා සහ රක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැඩ කිරීමට නියම ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලින්කෝ ලයිෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අර්ධ වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PBT රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்பின் ‘லா செரீனா’ ஓய்வு விடுதி சூரிய சக்தியுடன் பசுமையாக மாறுகிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூத்த குடிமக்களுக்கான இலங்கையின் முதல் ஓய்வு விடுதியான லா செரீனா, அதன் உரிமையாளரின் முதலீட்டுடன் தேசிய மின்கட்டமைப்பிற்கு சூரிய மின்சக்தியை உருவாக்குவதன் மூலம் \"பசுமை\" செய்வதற்காக, உஸ்வெட்டகேய்யாவவில் உள்ள அதன் கடற்கரையோரத்தில் ஏராளமான வளமான சூரியனின் சக்தியைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது. செலிங்கோ லைஃப்.",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னணி ஆயுள் காப்புறுதி நிறுவனத்தின் முழு உரிமையாளரான துணை நிறுவனம், 100kW சூரிய மின்சக்தி அமைப்பை அதன் விஸ்தரிப்பு கூரைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றலை உருவாக்கி அதன் நிலையான தன்மைக்கு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்களிப்பை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "லா செரீனாவின் சூரிய மின்சக்தித் திட்டம், செலிங்கோ லைஃப்பின் சொந்த பசுமை ஆணை மற்றும் நிலைத்தன்மை முயற்சிகளுக்கு இணங்க, செலிங்கோ லைஃப் மூலம் நிதியளிக்கப்பட்டு, ஆண்டுக்கு 136 டன் CO2 க்கு சமமான (tCO2e) உமிழ்வை ஈடுசெய்யும், மேலும் அதன் சுருக்கத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்கும். ஆண்டுக்கு 37 டன் கார்பன் தடம் என்று நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "44 அலகுகளைக் கொண்ட கடற்கரை-முன் ஓய்வு விடுதியில் 4000 சதுர அடியில் கூரை பொருத்தப்பட்ட சோலார் பேனல்கள் நிறுவப்பட்டு வத்தளை பகுதியில் மிகப்பெரிய சூரிய சக்தி அமைப்பு ஒன்றை உருவாக்குகிறது.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து வடக்கே 14 கிலோமீட்டர் தொலைவில் உள்ள உஸ்வெட்டகேயாவவில் கிட்டத்தட்ட மூன்று ஏக்கர் நிலப்பரப்பில் கட்டப்பட்ட லா செரீனா, 28 ஒற்றை அறைகள் மற்றும் 16 இரட்டை அறைகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. ஒவ்வொரு வாழ்க்கை அலகுக்கும் அதன் சொந்த வாழ்க்கை அறை, சாப்பாட்டுப் பகுதி, சமையலறை, Wi-Fi மற்றும் கேபிள் டிவி வசதிகள் மற்றும் என்-சூட் குளியலறைகள் உள்ளன, ஒவ்வொரு படுக்கையறைக்கும் ஒன்று, புத்திசாலித்தனமாக வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டு, உகந்த இடத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்காக வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது - ஒற்றை படுக்கையறை அலகுக்கு 535 சதுர அடி. மற்றும் இரண்டு படுக்கையறை அலகுக்கு 680 சதுர அடி.",
        "செலிங்கோ லைஃப் அதன் கிளை வலையமைப்பு முழுவதும் பேண்தகைமையை முன்னெடுப்பதற்காக ஏற்கனவே பல நடவடிக்கைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தியுள்ளது. இந்த முன்முயற்சிகளில் சூரிய சக்தியில் இயங்கும் சூழல் நட்பு கிளை அலுவலகங்களை நிர்மாணிப்பது மற்றும் மழைநீர் சேகரிப்பு, கழிவு நீர் மறுசுழற்சி மற்றும் நிறுவனத்திற்கு சொந்தமான கிளை கட்டிடங்களில் ஆற்றல்-திறனுள்ள விளக்குகள் மற்றும் ஏர் கண்டிஷனிங் அமைப்புகளை அமைத்தல் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "2021 இல் இலங்கை சந்தைப்படுத்தல் நிறுவகத்தினால் (SLIM) இலங்கையின் சிறந்த சேவை வர்த்தக நாமமான Brand Finance ஆல் 2022 இல் 'இலங்கையில் மிகவும் பெறுமதியான ஆயுள் காப்புறுதி வர்த்தக நாமம்' மற்றும் மிகவும் பிரபலமானதாக SLIM Kantar Peoples விருதை வென்றது. இலங்கையில் ஆயுள் காப்புறுதி நிறுவனம் தொடர்ச்சியாக 16 ஆவது ஆண்டாக, செலிங்கோ லைஃப் 34 வருடங்களில் அரைவாசிக்கும் மேலாக நாட்டின் முன்னணி ஆயுள் காப்புறுதி நிறுவனமாக உள்ளது. 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டைப் பொறுத்தமட்டில் பெறப்பட்ட ஏனைய பாராட்டுக்களில் 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கையின் ஆயுள் காப்புறுதித் துறையில் 'மிகவும் பிரபலமான சேவை வழங்குநர்' LMD, இலங்கையில் மிகவும் போற்றப்படும் 10 நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான Brand Finance இலங்கையின் 'மிகப் பெறுமதிமிக்க ஆயுள் காப்புறுதி பிராண்ட்' இலங்கை சர்வதேச வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தினால் (ICCSL) பட்டய முகாமைத்துவ கணக்காளர்களின் (CIMA) ஒத்துழைப்புடன், இலங்கையின் வங்கி, நிதிச் சேவைகள் மற்றும் காப்புறுதி (BFSI) துறையில் சிறந்த 10 பணியிடங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். .",
        "செலிங்கோ லைஃப் சுமார் ஒரு மில்லியன் உயிர்களை செயலில் உள்ள பாலிசிகள் மூலம் உள்ளடக்கியுள்ளது மற்றும் நிறுவனத்தின் பாலிசிதாரர்களின் இலக்குகள் மற்றும் அபிலாஷைகளை ஆபத்திலிருந்து நீக்கும் போது பாதுகாப்பை வழங்கும் புதுமையான ஆயுள் காப்பீட்டு தீர்வுகளை வழங்குகிறது.",
        "ரூ. அரையாண்டு PBT உடன் SLIC. 7.7 பில்லியன், அதிக வருமானம் ஈட்டும் SOEகளில்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லா செரீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uswetakeiyawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100கிலோவாட்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லா செரீனாவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "136 டன் என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருடத்திற்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4000 சதுர அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட மூன்று ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uswetakeiyawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லா செரீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wi-Fi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பிவட தொலைக்காட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "535 சதுர அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "680 சதுர அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராண்ட் நிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் சேவை வர்த்தக நாமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சந்தைப்படுத்தல் நிறுவனம் (SLIM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிகவும் பிரபலமான ஆயுள் காப்பீட்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 16வது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதிக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுள் காப்பீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராண்ட் நிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை கணக்காளர்கள் பட்டய நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி, நிதி சேவைகள் மற்றும் காப்பீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலை செய்ய சிறந்த இடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலிங்கோ லைஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரை வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிடி ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}