{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-foreign-ministrys-consular-affairs-division-limits-services-to-three-days-96701/",
  "time_ut": 1656578820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka foreign ministry’s consular affairs division limits services to three days",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka foreign ministry’s consular affairs division limits services to three days",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The Consular Affairs Division of Sri Lanka’s Foreign Ministry has restricted its services to three days of the week until July 10, the government information department said.",
        "Due to the current fuel crisis in the country, the Sri Lankan government has taken measures to curtail fuel consumption in the state sector by limiting the number of working days per week.",
        "The Consular Affairs Division will be open to the public  on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday with effect from June 30 until July 10, the statement from the information department said.",
        "“The same working arrangements will also apply to the Regional Consular offices in Jaffna, Matara, Kandy, Trincomalee and Kurunagela which will provide services on these days,” the statement said.",
        "The public is requested to contact the offices through the following e-mails for urgent requirements:",
        "Sri Lanka’s ongoing fuel crisis is threatening to cripple the economy. With no fuel consignments being secured, authorities have urged the public not to stay in queues until July 10. (Colombo/Jun30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "three days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days of the week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "working days per week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Consular Affairs Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday, Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Regional Consular",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunagela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "these days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ කොන්සියුලර් කටයුතු අංශය සේවා දින තුනකට සීමා කරයි",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ කොන්සියුලර් කටයුතු අංශය එහි සේවාවන් ජූලි 10 දක්වා සතියේ දින තුනකට සීමා කර ඇති බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "රට තුළ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් සතියකට වැඩ කරන දින ගණන සීමා කරමින් රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ ඉන්ධන පරිභෝජනය සීමා කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය පියවර ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ජුනි 30 සිට ජූලි 10 දක්වා බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි කොන්සියුලර් කටයුතු අංශය සඳුදා, බදාදා සහ සිකුරාදා මහජනතාව සඳහා විවෘතව පවතින බව ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "\"මෙම දිනවලදී සේවා සපයන යාපනය, මාතර, මහනුවර, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ කුරුණෑගල යන ප්‍රාදේශීය කොන්සියුලර් කාර්යාල සඳහා ද එම වැඩ විධිවිධාන අදාළ වේ\" යනුවෙන් එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "හදිසි අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා පහත විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල හරහා කාර්යාල හා සම්බන්ධ වන ලෙස මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය ආර්ථිකය අඩපණ කිරීමට තර්ජනය කරයි. ඉන්ධන තොග සුරක්ෂිත කර නොමැති බැවින්, ජූලි 10 වනදා දක්වා පෝලිම්වල නොසිටින ලෙස බලධාරීන් මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි. (කොළඹ/ජූනි 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියේ දින තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට වැඩ කරන දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොන්සියුලර් කටයුතු අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා, බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රාදේශීය කොන්සියුලර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunagela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම දිනවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் தூதரக விவகாரங்கள் பிரிவு சேவைகளை மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தியுள்ளது",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் தூதரக விவகாரங்கள் பிரிவு அதன் சேவைகளை வாரத்தின் மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு ஜூலை 10 வரை மட்டுப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக, வாரத்திற்கு வேலை நாட்களைக் குறைத்து அரச துறையில் எரிபொருள் பாவனையைக் குறைக்க அரசாங்கம் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "தூதரக விவகாரங்கள் பிரிவு ஜூன் 30 முதல் ஜூலை 10 வரை திங்கள், புதன் மற்றும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமைகளில் பொதுமக்களுக்காக திறந்திருக்கும் என்று தகவல் திணைக்களத்தின் அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"இந்த நாட்களில் சேவைகளை வழங்கும் யாழ்ப்பாணம், மாத்தறை, கண்டி, திருகோணமலை மற்றும் குருநாகல் ஆகிய பிராந்திய தூதரக அலுவலகங்களுக்கும் இதே வேலை ஏற்பாடுகள் பொருந்தும்\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொதுமக்கள் அவசரத் தேவைகளுக்கு பின்வரும் மின்னஞ்சல்கள் மூலம் அலுவலகங்களைத் தொடர்பு கொள்ளுமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "இலங்கையில் நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியானது பொருளாதாரத்தை முடக்கும் அச்சுறுத்தலாக உள்ளது. எரிபொருள் சரக்குகள் பாதுகாக்கப்படாத நிலையில், ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி வரை பொதுமக்கள் வரிசையில் நிற்க வேண்டாம் என அதிகாரிகள் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரத்தில் மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரத்திற்கு வேலை நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தூதரக விவகாரங்கள் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கள், புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிராந்திய தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunagela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}