{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83576/russian-aggression-may-have-contributed-to-sri-lanka-crisis-us-secretary-of-state",
  "time_ut": 1657518060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Russian aggression may have contributed to Sri Lanka crisis - US Secretary of State",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Russian aggression may have contributed to Sri Lanka crisis - US Secretary of State",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Sunday that Russia’s restriction on Ukrainian grain exports may have contributed to Sri Lanka’s turmoil and voiced fear it could spur other crises.",
        "“We’re seeing the impact of this Russian aggression playing out everywhere. It may have contributed to the situation in Sri Lanka; we’re concerned about the implications around the world,” Blinken told reporters in Bangkok.",
        "Renewing a demand that he has made repeatedly, Blinken called on Russia to let an estimated 20 million tonnes of grain leave Ukraine, which Moscow invaded in February.",
        "“What we are seeing around the world is growing food insecurity that has been significantly exacerbated by the Russian aggression against Ukraine,” Blinken said.",
        "He said there was also an impact in Thailand where fertiliser prices have “gone sky high” due to the blockade.",
        "“That’s significant especially in a vibrant farming country like Thailand, because in the absence of fertiliser, we know that means that next year yields will go down, prices potentially will go up,” Blinken said.",
        "Sri Lanka has been wracked by weeks of turmoil triggered by severe shortages of food and fuel.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa agreed to step down after protesters broke into his official residence on Saturday.",
        "Blinken on Sunday urged Sri Lanka’s leaders to quickly find long-term solutions to the nation’s economic and political crisis.",
        "“We would urge the Sri Lankan parliament to approach this with a commitment to the betterment of the country, not any one political party,” Blinken said of the upcoming exit of Rajapaksa, who had a rocky relationship with the United States.",
        "“It’s incumbent on the government -- whether it’s a new constitutionally selected government or existing government -- to work quickly to try to identify and implement solutions that will bring back the prospect of long-term economic stability,” Blinken told reporters during a visit to Bangkok.",
        "Such solutions must address “people’s discontent, which is so powerful and palpable over the worsening economic conditions,” he said.",
        "He warned against attacks on protesters or journalists, saying Sri Lankans have “a right to protest, to peacefully raise their voices”.",
        "“At the same time, we call for a full investigation, arrest and prosecution of anyone involved in any protest-related violence,” he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Antony Blinken",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukrainian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "an estimated 20 million tonnes",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදයට රුසියා ආක්‍රමණය බලපෑවා විය හැකියි - ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය ලේකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන් ඉරිදා කියා සිටියේ යුක්‍රේන ධාන්‍ය අපනයනය සඳහා රුසියාව සීමා කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කැලඹීමට දායක වන්නට ඇති බවත් එය වෙනත් අර්බුද ඇති කළ හැකි බවට බිය පළ කළ බවත් ය.",
        "“මෙම රුසියානු ආක්‍රමණයේ බලපෑම සෑම තැනකම ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව අපි දකිමු. එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වයට හේතු වන්නට ඇත; අපි ලොව පුරා ඇඟවුම් ගැන සැලකිලිමත් වෙමු, ”බ්ලින්කන් බැංකොක්හි වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු නැවත නැවතත් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමක් අලුත් කරමින්, පෙබරවාරි මාසයේ මොස්කව් ආක්‍රමණය කළ යුක්රේනයේ ඇස්තමේන්තුගත ධාන්‍ය ටොන් මිලියන 20කට ඉඩ දෙන ලෙස බ්ලින්කන් රුසියාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ලෝකය පුරා අප දකිමින් සිටින්නේ යුක්රේනයට එරෙහි රුසියානු ආක්‍රමණයෙන් සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස උත්සන්න වී ඇති ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත භාවයයි\" යනුවෙන් බ්ලින්කන් පැවසීය.",
        "අවහිර කිරීම හේතුවෙන් තායිලන්තයේ පොහොර මිල “අහස ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති” බලපෑමක් ද ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"එය විශේෂයෙන් තායිලන්තය වැනි උද්යෝගිමත් ගොවි රටක වැදගත් වේ, මන්ද පොහොර නොමැති විට, අපි දන්නවා එයින් අදහස් කරන්නේ ලබන වසරේ අස්වැන්න පහත වැටෙනු ඇති බවත්, මිල ඉහළ යා හැකි බවත්\" බ්ලින්කන් පැවසීය.",
        "ආහාර හා ඉන්ධනවල උග්‍ර හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ඇති වූ සති ගනනාවක කැලඹීම් වලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විනාශ වී ඇත.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් සෙනසුරාදා ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට එකඟ විය.",
        "ජාතියේ ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයට දීර්ඝ කාලීන විසඳුම් කඩිනමින් සොයා ගන්නා ලෙස බ්ලින්කන් ඉරිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නායකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“එක් දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක් නොව රටේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා කැපවීමෙන් මෙයට ප්‍රවේශ වන ලෙස අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමු,” එක්සත් ජනපදය සමඟ පාෂාණමය සබඳතාවක් පැවැත්වූ රාජපක්ෂගේ එළඹෙන පිටවීම ගැන බ්ලින්කන් පැවසීය.",
        "\"එය නව ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව තෝරාගත් රජයක් හෝ පවතින රජයක් වේවා -- දිගු කාලීන ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වයේ අපේක්ෂාව නැවත ගෙන එන විසඳුම් හඳුනාගෙන ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට කඩිනමින් ක්‍රියා කිරීම රජයට භාරයි,\" බ්ලින්කන් සංචාරයකදී වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය. බැංකොක් වෙත.",
        "එබඳු විසඳුම් මගින් “මහජනයාගේ අතෘප්තිය ආමන්ත්‍රණය කළ යුතු අතර, එය නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් එතරම් බලගතු සහ විනිවිද පෙනෙන” බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට හෝ මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට එල්ල වන ප්‍රහාරවලට එරෙහිව ඔහු අනතුරු ඇඟවූයේ, ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට \"විරෝධතා දැක්වීමට, සාමකාමීව හඬ නැගීමට අයිතියක්\" ඇති බව පවසමිනි.",
        "\"ඒ අතරම, විරෝධතා සම්බන්ධ ඕනෑම ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයකට සම්බන්ධ ඕනෑම අයෙකු සම්පූර්ණ පරීක්ෂණයක්, අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සහ නඩු පැවරීම සඳහා අපි ඉල්ලා සිටිමු,\" ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇස්තමේන්තුගත ටොන් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை நெருக்கடிக்கு ரஷ்ய ஆக்கிரமிப்பு காரணமாக இருக்கலாம் - அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உக்ரேனிய தானிய ஏற்றுமதி மீதான ரஷ்யாவின் கட்டுப்பாடு இலங்கையின் கொந்தளிப்புக்கு பங்களித்திருக்கலாம் என்றும், அது மற்ற நெருக்கடிகளை ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடும் என்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க செயலாளர் அன்டனி பிளின்கன் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இந்த ரஷ்ய ஆக்கிரமிப்பின் தாக்கம் எல்லா இடங்களிலும் விளையாடுவதை நாங்கள் காண்கிறோம். இலங்கையின் நிலைமைக்கு அது பங்களித்திருக்கலாம்; உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள தாக்கங்கள் குறித்து நாங்கள் கவலைப்படுகிறோம், ”என்று பிளிங்கன் பாங்காக்கில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "அவர் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை புதுப்பித்து, பிப்ரவரியில் மாஸ்கோ படையெடுத்த உக்ரைனில் இருந்து சுமார் 20 மில்லியன் டன் தானியங்கள் வெளியேற அனுமதிக்குமாறு பிளிங்கன் ரஷ்யாவிடம் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "\"உலகெங்கிலும் நாம் பார்ப்பது உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை அதிகரித்து வருகிறது, இது உக்ரைனுக்கு எதிரான ரஷ்ய ஆக்கிரமிப்பால் கணிசமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது\" என்று பிளிங்கன் கூறினார்.",
        "தாய்லாந்திலும் முற்றுகையின் காரணமாக உரங்களின் விலை \"வானத்தில் உயர்ந்துள்ளது\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இது குறிப்பாக தாய்லாந்து போன்ற துடிப்பான விவசாய நாட்டில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது, ஏனென்றால் உரம் இல்லாத நிலையில், அடுத்த ஆண்டு விளைச்சல் குறையும், விலைகள் உயரும் என்று எங்களுக்குத் தெரியும்,\" என்று பிளிங்கன் கூறினார்.",
        "உணவு மற்றும் எரிபொருளின் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறையால் தூண்டப்பட்ட பல வாரங்களாக கொந்தளிப்பால் இலங்கை சிதைந்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்துக்குள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் சனிக்கிழமை புகுந்ததை அடுத்து பதவி விலகுவதற்கு இணங்கினார்.",
        "நாட்டின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடிக்கு நீண்டகால தீர்வுகளை விரைவாகக் கண்டறியுமாறு இலங்கையின் தலைவர்களை பிளின்கன் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"எந்த ஒரு அரசியல் கட்சியும் அல்ல, நாட்டின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அர்ப்பணிப்புடன் இதை அணுகுமாறு இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தை நாங்கள் வலியுறுத்துவோம்\" என்று அமெரிக்காவுடன் பாறை உறவைக் கொண்டிருந்த ராஜபக்சேவின் வரவிருக்கும் வெளியேற்றம் குறித்து பிளிங்கன் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இது ஒரு புதிய அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட அரசாங்கமாக இருந்தாலும் சரி அல்லது தற்போதுள்ள அரசாங்கமாக இருந்தாலும் சரி - நீண்ட கால பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கான வாய்ப்பை மீண்டும் கொண்டு வரும் தீர்வுகளை கண்டறிந்து செயல்படுத்த விரைவாக செயல்படுவது அரசாங்கத்தின் கடமையாகும்\" என்று பிளிங்கன் ஒரு விஜயத்தின் போது செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார். பாங்காக்கிற்கு.",
        "இத்தகைய தீர்வுகள் \"மக்களின் அதிருப்தியை நிவர்த்தி செய்ய வேண்டும், இது மிகவும் சக்திவாய்ந்ததாகவும், மோசமடைந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நிலைமைகளின் மீது தெளிவாகவும் உள்ளது\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் அல்லது ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்களுக்கு எதிராக எச்சரித்த அவர், இலங்கையர்களுக்கு \"எதிர்ப்பதற்கும், அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்புவதற்கும் உரிமை உள்ளது\" என்றார்.",
        "\"அதே நேரத்தில், போராட்டம் தொடர்பான வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட்ட எவரையும் முழு விசாரணை, கைது மற்றும் வழக்குத் தொடர நாங்கள் அழைக்கிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில ஆண்டனி பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மில்லியன் டன்கள் என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}