{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79104",
  "time_ut": 1660942320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Wickremesinghe does not seem to have learnt a lesson from a basic mental aberration that the UNP suffers from: Crushing legitimate dissent by force using UNP thugs or security services has been one of the main reasons for the nemesis of the party,",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Wickremesinghe does not seem to have learnt a lesson from a basic mental aberration that the UNP suffers from: Crushing legitimate dissent by force using UNP thugs or security services has been one of the main reasons for the nemesis of the party,",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(The writer is a former editor of The Sunday Island, The Island, and consultant editor of the Sunday Leader)",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has taken on the role of an alchemist of sorts.",
        "Ancient alchemists attempted to transform various metals called, base metals, as lead and copper by subjecting them to various treatment as melting to produce pure gold, which was the most sought after metals in those times, as it is today. They failed in their attempts which were said to be impossible to achieve on scientific principles.",
        "A different kind of alchemist also attempted to produce an elixir that could make humans immortal or produce a panacea — sure cure — for all diseases. These attempts have so far not been successful although the attempts still continue, viz, ‘Vadakaha Sudiya’ and ‘Covid Paniya’ which we Lankans are familiar with.",
        "Wickremesinghe’s chosen specialty appears to be Political Alchemy: Mixing up ‘base politicians’ together with other ingredients to produce pure gold recognised worldwide in the 21st Century — the All American Mighty Dollar which could save Sri Lanka from the financial and political crisis it is sinking in.",
        "The Wickremesinghe strategy appears to be centered on the APG (All-Party Government) under his presidency.  The opposition parties, the SJB of Premadasa, the TNA of the North and East, and allied parties of the JVP have declined invitations to join the APG under Wickremesinghe, and he is left with those of the Rajapaksa government left destitute after Mahinda Rajapaksa and his ministers resigned and Gotabaya Rajapaksa took off to foreign climes with almost the whole country at his heels.",
        "The leading lights of the APG are: Wickremesinghe, Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena, the vast number of Rajapaksa members left destitute and the triad of leaders of three minor political parties: Vasudeva Nanayakkara, the Trotskyite, spewing red-hot anti-capitalist rhetoric, Wimal Weerawansa, also an incendiary speaker creating tremendous noise but with little sense and Udaya Gamanpillar, leader of the Pivithuru Hela Urumaya (Party Bearing Purest Sinhala Heritage) whose rhetoric does not cut much ice.",
        "How the APG could make these disparate elements click and work out a strategy to produce the much-needed US dollars that will take Sri Lanka out of the hell fires, perhaps, only the Alchemist Wickremesinghe knows and has them all under his hat. But what happens if he fails?",
        "Whether by accident or design when Gotabaya Rajapaksa decided to appoint Wickremesinghe as the Prime Minister and later he was elected President, he had chosen the best politician in harness for the job of negotiating with the IMF and countries Lanka is indebted to. Six times Prime minister and also having been the Finance Minister, he not only knows the complicated manoeuvres to follow but that he has also been on good terms with Western leaders whose opinions have clout with the IMF. Politicians and diplomats knowing one another over a period of time is said to be a distinct advantage in diplomacy. However, Wickremesinghe is in a severely disadvantaged position at home. The disadvantages are: His party was routed at the last parliamentary election and he is not an elected representative; his way to the presidency has been through the Rajapaksa family that has been driven out of politics. He stands firmly only on one foot — the Constitutional procedure adopted in his appointment — while his other foot is on the slippery support of the Pohottuwa members who may be asked to topple him by shadowy forces pushing the Pohottuwa around.",
        "Another looming threat is the return of Gotabaya Rajapaksa to Colombo from Bangkok. Since he fled the country to the Maldives and then to Singapore from where he sent in his resignation from the presidency and then on to Thailand, no country has given him a residence visa. Now it is reported that he will be back in Colombo and stay here until he gets back his US citizenship which he gave up to contest in the  Sri Lankan Presidential Election.",
        "This visit is fraught with the possibility of regeneration of political instability.  The intention of return to power by the Rajapaksa family is quite evident and Gotabaya’s return could be used to whip up the now moribund Rajapaksa family spirit which in turn could ignite the Aragalaya activists who Wickremesinghe has repressed with severity.",
        "All such events would have a backlash on Ranil’s Political Alchemy of turning out US dollars with IMF and international assistance.",
        "Wickremesinghe does not seem to have learnt a lesson from a basic mental aberration that the UNP suffers from: Crushing legitimate dissent by force using UNP thugs or security services has been one of the main reasons for the nemesis of the party, the notion being that if the opposing forces are given a sound thrashing, the issue at hand will disappear. It did not happen on the first occasion and the problem is still with us; it did not happen when UNP political thugs joined in the 1983 anti-Tamil riots; failed in the use of violence when the Jaffna Public Library was set on fire and on occasions like well-known UNP strongmen led by ministers pulled intellectuals such as Ediriweera Sarathchandra and subjected them to humiliation and also the use of force to crush the trade union movement for opposing the Jayewardene government.  Instead, they created massive backlashes which whipped the party to defeat at elections.",
        "Last Thursday’s use of well-armed and uniformed security forces against a peaceful protest of student leaders with tear gas and water cannon would certainly not help in his Political Alchemy or even with his Western democratic supporters."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UNP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Island",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sunday Leader",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st Century",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North and East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "APG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "APG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trotskyite",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gamanpillar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "APG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Alchemist Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one foot",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pohottuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pohottuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil’s Political Alchemy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "anti-Tamil",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna Public Library",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the trade union movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayewardene",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last Thursday’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එජාපය පෙළෙන මූලික මානසික අපගමනයකින් වික්‍රමසිංහ පාඩමක් ඉගෙන ගෙන නැති බව පෙනේ: නීත්‍යානුකූල විසම්මුතිය එජාප මැරයන් හෝ ආරක්‍ෂක අංශ යොදාගෙන බලහත්කාරයෙන් තලා දැමීම පක්‍ෂය සතුරා වීමට ප්‍රධාන හේතුවක් වී ඇත.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ලේඛකයා ද සන්ඩේ අයිලන්ඩ්, ද අයිලන්ඩ් හි හිටපු කර්තෘවරයෙක් සහ සන්ඩේ ලීඩර් හි උපදේශක කර්තෘවරයෙකි)",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා යම් ආකාරයක ඇල්කෙමිස්ට්වරයෙකුගේ භූමිකාව භාරගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පුරාණ ඇල්කෙමිස්ට්වරු මූලික ලෝහ ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන විවිධ ලෝහ ඊයම් සහ තඹ ලෙස පරිවර්තනය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ අතර ඒවා උණු කිරීම ලෙස විවිධ ප්‍රතිකාර වලට භාජනය කර පිරිසිදු රත්‍රන් නිපදවීමට උත්සාහ කළහ. විද්‍යාත්මක මූලධර්ම මත සාක්ෂාත් කරගත නොහැකි යැයි කියන ලද ඔවුන්ගේ උත්සාහයන් ඔවුන් අසාර්ථක විය.",
        "වෙනත් ආකාරයේ ඇල්කෙමිස්ට්වරයෙකු ද මිනිසුන් අමරණීය කිරීමට හෝ සියලු රෝග සඳහා කෝකටත් තෛලයක් - නිසැක සුවයක් - නිපදවීමට හැකි අමෘතයක් නිපදවීමට උත්සාහ කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් වන අපට හුරුපුරුදු ‘වඩකහ සුදිය’ සහ ‘කොවිඩ් පැණිය’ තවමත් එම උත්සාහයන් දිගටම පැවතුනද මෙම උත්සාහයන් මෙතෙක් සාර්ථක වී නොමැත.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ තෝරාගත් විශේෂත්වය දේශපාලන ඇල්කෙමිය බව පෙනේ: 21 වන සියවසේ ලොව පුරා පිළිගත් පිරිසිදු රත්‍රන් නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීම සඳහා 'මූලික දේශපාලඥයින්' වෙනත් අමුද්‍රව්‍ය සමඟ මිශ්‍ර කිරීම - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගිලෙමින් පවතින මූල්‍ය හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගලවා ගත හැකි සමස්ත ඇමරිකානු බලගතු ඩොලරය. .",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ උපායමාර්ගය ඔහුගේ සභාපතිත්වය යටතේ ඇති APG (සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආන්ඩුව) මත කේන්ද්‍රගත වී ඇති බව පෙනේ. විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ වන ප්‍රේමදාසගේ SJB, උතුරු නැගෙනහිර TNA සහ JVP හි මිත්‍ර පක්ෂ වික්‍රමසිංහ යටතේ APG සමග එක්වන ලෙස කළ ආරාධනා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති අතර, ඔහුට ඉතිරිව ඇත්තේ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ පසු අනාථ වූ රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ අයයි. අමාත්‍යවරු ඉල්ලා අස්වී ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පිටරටකට ගියේ මුළු රටම පාහේ ඔහුගේ අතේ තබාගෙනය.",
        "APG හි ප්‍රමුඛ පහන් වන්නේ: වික්‍රමසිංහ, අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන, අනාථ වූ රාජපක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන් අති විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවක් සහ සුළු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ තුනක නායක ත්‍රිත්වය: වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර, ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී, රතු-උණු ධනේශ්වර විරෝධී වාචාල කතා, විමල් වීරවංශ, මහා ඝෝෂාවක් ඇති නමුත් අඩු හැඟීමක් ඇති ගිනි අවුලුවන කථිකයෙක් සහ වැඩි අයිස් නොකැඩූ වාචාල කථිකයෙකු වන පිවිතුරු හෙළ උරුමයේ නායක උදය ගමන්පිලර් ය.",
        "APG විසින් මෙම අසමාන මූලද්‍රව්‍ය ක්ලික් කර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අපායේ ගින්නෙන් ගොඩ ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් නිපදවීමට උපාය මාර්ගයක් සකස් කරන්නේ කෙසේද, සමහර විට, ඇල්කෙමිස්ට් වික්‍රමසිංහ පමණක් දන්නා සහ ඒවා සියල්ලම ඔහුගේ තොප්පිය යට තබා ගන්න. නමුත් ඔහු අසමත් වුවහොත් කුමක් සිදුවේද?",
        "අහම්බෙන් හෝ සැලසුම් සහගතව ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගමැති කිරීමට තීරණය කර පසුව ඔහු ජනාධිපති වූ විට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සහ ලංකාව ණයගැති රටවල් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමේ කාර්යය සඳහා හොඳම දේශපාලනඥයා තෝරාගෙන තිබුණි. හය වතාවක් අගමැති වී මුදල් ඇමති වී ඇති ඔහු, අනුගමනය කළ යුතු සංකීර්ණ උපාමාරු දන්නාවා පමණක් නොව, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සම්බන්ධ අදහස් ඇති බටහිර නායකයන් සමඟ ද හොඳ සුහදතාවයකින් කටයුතු කර ඇත. දේශපාලකයින් සහ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් කාලාන්තරයක් තිස්සේ එකිනෙකා දැන හඳුනා ගැනීම රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික කටයුතුවල සුවිශේෂී වාසියක් ලෙස සැලකේ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, වික්‍රමසිංහ ගෙදර සිටින්නේ දැඩි අවාසි සහගත තත්ත්වයකය. අවාසි නම්: පසුගිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේදී ඔහුගේ පක්ෂය පරාජයට පත් වූ අතර ඔහු තේරී පත් වූ නියෝජිතයෙකු නොවේ; ඔහු ජනාධිපති ධූරය දක්වා ගමන් කර ඇත්තේ දේශපාලනයෙන් එළවා දැමූ රාජපක්ෂ පවුල හරහා ය. ඔහු ස්ථිරව සිටින්නේ එක් පාදයක පමණි - ඔහු පත් කිරීමේදී අනුගමනය කරන ලද ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය - ඔහුගේ අනෙක් පාදය පොහොට්ටුව වටා තල්ලු කරන සෙවනැලි බලවේග විසින් ඔහුව පෙරළීමට ඉල්ලා සිටිය හැකි පොහොට්ටුවේ සාමාජිකයින්ගේ ලිස්සන සුළු සහයෝගය මත ය.",
        "තවත් තර්ජනයක් එල්ල වී ඇත්තේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බැංකොක් සිට කොළඹට පැමිණීමයි. ඔහු රටින් මාලදිවයිනට පළා ගොස් එතැනින් සිංගප්පූරුවට ගොස් එතැනින් ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය යවා ඉන්පසු තායිලන්තයට ගිය නිසා කිසිම රටක් ඔහුට පදිංචි වීසා ලබා දී නැත. දැන් ඔහු නැවත කොළඹට පැමිණ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කිරීම සඳහා අත්හැර දැමූ ඇමෙරිකානු පුරවැසිභාවය නැවත ලබාගන්නා තෙක් මෙහි රැඳී සිටිනු ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෙම සංචාරය දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය යළි ඇති කිරීමේ හැකියාවෙන් පිරී තිබේ. රාජපක්ෂ පවුල විසින් නැවත බලයට ඒමේ අභිප්‍රාය මනාව පැහැදිලි වන අතර, ගෝඨාභයගේ නැවත පැමිණීම, වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් දැඩි ලෙස මර්ධනය කර ඇති අරගලයා ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ඇවිලවිය හැකි, දැන් අභාවයට යමින් පවතින රාජපක්ෂ පවුල් ආත්මය අවුලුවාලීමට යොදා ගත හැකිය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ආධාර ඇතිව ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් ආපසු හරවා යැවීමේ රනිල්ගේ දේශපාලන ඇල්කෙමිය මත එවැනි සිදුවීම් සියල්ලට පසුබෑමක් වනු ඇත.",
        "එජාපය පෙළෙන මූලික මානසික අපගමනයකින් වික්‍රමසිංහ පාඩමක් ඉගෙන ගෙන නැති බව පෙනේ: නීත්‍යානුකූල විසම්මුතිය එජාප මැරයන් හෝ ආරක්ෂක අංශ යොදාගෙන බලහත්කාරයෙන් තලා දැමීම පක්ෂයේ හතුරන් වීමට ප්‍රධාන හේතුවක් වී ඇත. ප්‍රතිවිරුද්ධ බලවේගවලට දැඩි ලෙස පහර දෙනු ලැබේ, පවතින ප්‍රශ්නය අතුරුදහන් වනු ඇත. එය පළමු අවස්ථාවේදී සිදු නොවූ අතර ගැටලුව තවමත් අප තුළ පවතී; 1983 දෙමළ විරෝධී කෝලාහලවලට එජාප දේශපාලන මැරයන් එක් වූ විට එය සිදු වූයේ නැත. යාපනය මහජන පුස්තකාලයට ගිනි තැබූ විට ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය භාවිතා කිරීමට අසමත් වූ අතර මැති ඇමතිවරුන් ප්‍රමුඛ එජාප ප්‍රබලයින් වැනි අවස්ථා වලදී එදිරිවීර සරත්චන්ද්‍ර වැනි බුද්ධිමතුන් ඇදගෙන ගොස් නින්දාවට පත් කළ අතර වෘත්තීය සමිති ව්‍යාපාරය කුඩුපට්ටම් කිරීමට බලය යෙදවූහ ජයවර්ධන ආණ්ඩුවට විරුද්ධ වීම නිසා. ඒ වෙනුවට ඔවුන් දැවැන්ත පසුබෑමක් ඇති කළ අතර එය මැතිවරණවලදී පක්ෂය පරාජයට පත් කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ශිෂ්‍ය නායකයන් කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කරන ලද සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවයකට එරෙහිව හොඳින් සන්නද්ධ හා නිල ඇඳුමින් සැරසුණු ආරක්ෂක හමුදා යොදා ගැනීම ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන ඇල්කෙමියට හෝ ඔහුගේ බටහිර ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ආධාරකරුවන්ට පවා උදව්වක් නොවනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එජාප",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එජාප",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා දිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ලීඩර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වන සියවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "APG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "APG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රොට්ස්කියි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගමන්පිලර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "APG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්කෙමිස්ට් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක් පාදයක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාපිත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්ගේ දේශපාලන ඇල්කෙමිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ විරෝධී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මහජන පුස්තකාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සමිති ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UNP குண்டர்கள் அல்லது பாதுகாப்பு சேவைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி பலவந்தமாக நியாயமான கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை நசுக்குவது, கட்சியின் விரோதிகளுக்கு முக்கிய காரணங்களில் ஒன்றாக உள்ளது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(எழுத்தாளர் தி சண்டே ஐலண்ட், தி ஐலண்டின் முன்னாள் ஆசிரியர் மற்றும் சண்டே லீடரின் ஆலோசகர் ஆசிரியர்)",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஒரு ரசவாதியின் பாத்திரத்தை ஏற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "பண்டைய ரசவாதிகள், அடிப்படை உலோகங்கள் என்று அழைக்கப்படும் பல்வேறு உலோகங்களை ஈயம் மற்றும் தாமிரமாக மாற்ற முயன்றனர், அவற்றை உருகுவதற்கு பல்வேறு சிகிச்சைக்கு உட்படுத்தி, தூய தங்கத்தை உற்பத்தி செய்தனர், இது அந்தக் காலத்தில் உலோகங்களுக்கு மிகவும் விரும்பப்பட்டது. அறிவியல் கொள்கைகளில் சாதிக்க இயலாது என்று கூறப்பட்ட முயற்சிகளில் அவர்கள் தோல்வியடைந்தனர்.",
        "ஒரு வித்தியாசமான ரசவாதி, மனிதர்களை அழியாதவர்களாக ஆக்கக்கூடிய ஒரு அமுதத்தை உற்பத்தி செய்ய முயற்சித்தார் அல்லது அனைத்து நோய்களுக்கும் ஒரு சஞ்சீவியை - உறுதியான சிகிச்சையை - தயாரிக்கிறார். இம்முயற்சிகள் இதுவரை வெற்றியடையவில்லை எனினும் முயற்சிகள் இன்னும் தொடர்கின்றன, அதாவது இலங்கையர்களாகிய நாம் நன்கு அறிந்த ‘வடகஹா சூடியா’ மற்றும் ‘கோவிட் பணியா’.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட சிறப்பு அரசியல் ரசவாதமாகத் தோன்றுகிறது: 21 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் உலகளவில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட தூய தங்கத்தை உற்பத்தி செய்ய மற்ற பொருட்களுடன் 'அடிப்படை அரசியல்வாதிகளை' கலக்குவது - இலங்கையை நிதி மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து காப்பாற்றக்கூடிய அனைத்து அமெரிக்க வல்லமைமிக்க டாலர். .",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் மூலோபாயம் அவரது ஜனாதிபதியின் கீழ் உள்ள APG (அனைத்து கட்சி அரசாங்கம்) ஐ மையமாகக் கொண்டதாகத் தெரிகிறது. எதிர்க்கட்சிகளான பிரேமதாசவின் SJB, வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கின் TNA மற்றும் JVP இன் கூட்டணிக் கட்சிகள் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கீழ் APG இல் சேருவதற்கான அழைப்புகளை நிராகரித்துள்ளன, மேலும் மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவிற்குப் பிறகு ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆதரவற்ற கட்சிகளுடன் அவர் எஞ்சியிருக்கிறார். அமைச்சர்கள் ராஜினாமா செய்தார்கள் மற்றும் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வெளிநாட்டு தட்பவெப்பநிலைக்கு ஏறக்குறைய முழு நாட்டையும் தனது குதிகால் நோக்கி அழைத்துச் சென்றார்.",
        "APG இன் முன்னணி விளக்குகள்: விக்கிரமசிங்க, பிரதம மந்திரி தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, ஆதரவற்ற நிலையில் உள்ள ராஜபக்ச உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் மூன்று சிறு அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் முக்கூட்டு தலைவர்கள்: வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, ட்ரொட்ஸ்கியவாதி, சிவப்பு-சூடான முதலாளித்துவ எதிர்ப்புச் சொல்லாடல்களை உமிழும், விமல். வீரவன்ச, பெரும் சப்தத்தை உருவாக்கும், ஆனால் சிறிதும் உணர்வு இல்லாத ஒரு தீக்குளிக்கும் பேச்சாளரும், மற்றும் அவரது சொல்லாட்சிகள் அதிக பனியை வெட்டாத பிவித்துரு ஹெல உறுமயவின் (தூய்மையான சிங்கள பாரம்பரியம்) தலைவர் உதய காமன்பில்லரும்.",
        "APG இந்த வேறுபட்ட கூறுகளை எவ்வாறு கிளிக் செய்து, இலங்கையை நரக நெருப்பில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றும் மிகவும் தேவையான அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை உற்பத்தி செய்வதற்கான ஒரு உத்தியை உருவாக்க முடியும், ஒருவேளை, ரசவாதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு மட்டுமே தெரியும் மற்றும் அவை அனைத்தையும் தனது தொப்பியின் கீழ் வைத்திருப்பார். ஆனால் அவர் தோல்வியுற்றால் என்ன ஆகும்?",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக நியமிக்க கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச முடிவுசெய்து பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டபோது தற்செயலாகவோ அல்லது வடிவமைப்பிலோ, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கு கடன்பட்டுள்ள நாடுகளுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தும் பணிக்காக சிறந்த அரசியல்வாதியை அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுத்திருந்தார். ஆறு முறை பிரதமராகவும், நிதியமைச்சராகவும் இருந்ததால், அவர் பின்பற்ற வேண்டிய சிக்கலான சூழ்ச்சிகளை அறிந்திருப்பது மட்டுமல்லாமல், IMF உடன் செல்வாக்கு பெற்ற மேற்கத்திய தலைவர்களுடன் அவர் நல்லுறவில் இருந்துள்ளார். அரசியல்வாதிகள் மற்றும் இராஜதந்திரிகள் ஒருவரையொருவர் குறிப்பிட்ட கால இடைவெளியில் அறிந்துகொள்வது இராஜதந்திரத்தில் ஒரு தனித்துவமான நன்மை என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், விக்கிரமசிங்க உள்நாட்டில் மிகவும் பின்தங்கிய நிலையில் உள்ளார். குறைபாடுகள்: கடந்த நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் அவரது கட்சி தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்டது, அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட பிரதிநிதி அல்ல; அரசியலில் இருந்து துரத்தப்பட்ட ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்தின் மூலம் அவர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு வந்துள்ளார். அவர் ஒரு காலில் மட்டுமே உறுதியாக நிற்கிறார் - அவரது நியமனத்தில் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பு நடைமுறை - அவரது மற்றொரு கால் பொஹொட்டுவ உறுப்பினர்களின் வழுக்கும் ஆதரவில் உள்ளது, அவர்கள் பொஹொட்டுவாவைச் சுற்றித் தள்ளும் நிழல் சக்திகளால் அவரை வீழ்த்துமாறு கேட்கப்படலாம்.",
        "கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச பாங்கொக்கில் இருந்து கொழும்பு திரும்புவது மற்றொரு அச்சுறுத்தலாகும். அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு மாலத்தீவுக்கும், பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் சென்று அங்கிருந்து அதிபர் பதவியிலிருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்து தாய்லாந்திற்குச் சென்றதால், எந்த நாடும் அவருக்கு குடியிருப்பு விசா வழங்கவில்லை. இலங்கை அதிபர் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதற்காக விட்டுக்கொடுத்த அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமையை திரும்ப பெறும் வரை அவர் கொழும்புக்கு திரும்புவார் என்றும், இங்கு தங்குவார் என்றும் தற்போது தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விஜயம் அரசியல் ஸ்திரமற்ற தன்மையை மீண்டும் உருவாக்குவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் நிறைந்ததாக உள்ளது. ராஜபக்ச குடும்பம் மீண்டும் ஆட்சிக்கு வரும் எண்ணம் மிகவும் தெளிவாக உள்ளது மற்றும் கோத்தபயவின் மீள்வருகையானது தற்போது நலிவடைந்துள்ள ராஜபக்ச குடும்ப உணர்வைத் தூண்டுவதற்குப் பயன்படுத்தப்படலாம், இது விக்கிரமசிங்கவால் கடுமையாக ஒடுக்கப்பட்ட அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை பற்றவைக்கும்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் மற்றும் சர்வதேச உதவியுடன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை புரட்டிப் போடும் ரணிலின் அரசியல் ரசவாதத்திற்கு இவ்வாறான அனைத்து நிகழ்வுகளும் பின்னடைவை ஏற்படுத்தும்.",
        "UNP குண்டர்கள் அல்லது பாதுகாப்பு சேவைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி சட்டப்பூர்வமான கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை வலுக்கட்டாயமாக நசுக்குவது, கட்சியின் விரோதிக்கு முக்கியக் காரணங்களில் ஒன்றாக உள்ளது. எதிர்க்கும் சக்திகளுக்கு ஒரு நல்ல அடி கொடுக்கப்பட்டால், கையில் இருக்கும் பிரச்சினை மறைந்துவிடும். முதல் சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் அது நடக்கவில்லை, பிரச்சனை இன்னும் நம்மிடம் உள்ளது; 1983 தமிழர் விரோத கலவரத்தில் UNP அரசியல் குண்டர்கள் இணைந்த போது அது நடக்கவில்லை; யாழ்.பொது நூலகம் தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்ட போது வன்முறையைப் பயன்படுத்துவதில் தோல்வியடைந்தது மற்றும் அமைச்சர்கள் தலைமையிலான ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பலமானவர்கள் எதிரிவீர சரத்சந்திர போன்ற புத்திஜீவிகளை இழுத்து இழிவுபடுத்தியதுடன் தொழிற்சங்க இயக்கத்தை நசுக்குவதற்கு பலத்தை பிரயோகித்தது ஜெயவர்த்தன அரசாங்கத்தை எதிர்த்ததற்காக. மாறாக, அவர்கள் பாரிய பின்னடைவை உருவாக்கினர், இது கட்சியை தேர்தலில் தோல்வியடையச் செய்தது.",
        "கடந்த வியாழன் அன்று நல்ல ஆயுதம் ஏந்திய மற்றும் சீருடை அணிந்த பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரை, கண்ணீர்ப்புகை மற்றும் தண்ணீர் பீரங்கியுடன் மாணவர் தலைவர்களின் அமைதியான போராட்டத்திற்கு எதிராகப் பயன்படுத்துவது நிச்சயமாக அவரது அரசியல் ரசவாதத்திற்கு அல்லது அவரது மேற்கத்திய ஜனநாயக ஆதரவாளர்களுக்கு உதவாது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு தீவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சண்டே லீடர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏ.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ரொட்ஸ்கைட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய காமன்பில்லர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏ.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரசவாதி விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணிலின் அரசியல் ரசவாதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழர் விரோதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண பொது நூலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழிற்சங்க இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்த்தன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வியாழக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}