{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මැද-පෙරදිගට-අලෙවි-කිරීමට-සුදානම්-කළ-කසල-තේ-තොගයක්-අල්ලයි/101-616779",
  "time_ut": 1658377938,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මැද පෙරදිගට අලෙවි කිරීමට සුදානම් කළ කසල තේ තොගයක් අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Catches a shipment of junk tea ready for sale in the Middle East",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Officials of the Special Task Force said that a person was arrested from a Modara Ellihouse Road warehouse with a stock of waste tea prepared to be sold in the international market under the name of Ceylon Tea.",
        "19,072.86 kilos of waste tea and 336 liters of liquid used for coloring waste tea have also been taken into police custody.",
        "It is also reported that this waste tea was prepared to be exported to the Middle East countries and it is also reported that due to this waste tea being released to the international market under the name of Ceylon Tea, the sale of tea in Sri Lanka is experiencing a big setback internationally.",
        "Under the supervision of Senior Superintendent of Police J.R. Senadheera, who is in charge of Western North, as per the instructions of Special Task Force Commanding Officer Mr. Varuna Jayasundara, Inspector HPMSK of the Special Task Force Gonahena camp. The raid was carried out by a team of officers including Veerakkodi."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Middle East",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Modara Ellihouse Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19,072.86",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "336",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "J.R. Senadheera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western North",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Varuna Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Task Force Gonahena",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veerakkodi",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැද පෙරදිගට අලෙවි කිරීමට සුදානම් කළ කසල තේ තොගයක් අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සිලෝන් ටී නමින් ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළදපලේ අලෙවි කිරිමට සුදානමි කළ කසල තේ තොගයක් සමග පුද්ගලයකු මෝදර එලිහවුස් පාර ගබඩාවකින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය නිලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "කසල තේ කිලෝ 19,072.86 ක් සහ කසල තේ වර්ණ ගැන්වීම සදහා යොදාගන්නා ලද දියර ලීටර් 336 ක් ද පොලිස් බාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම කසල තේ තොග මැදපෙරදිග රටවල්වලට අපනයනය කිරීමට සූදානම් කර තිබු බවට  අනාවරණය වූ බව ද  සීලෝන් ටී නමින් ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළෙඳපොළට නිකුත් කරන මෙම කසළ තේ හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙි තේ අලෙවිය ජාත්‍යන්තරව විශාල පසුබෑමකට ලක්වන බව ද වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය අණදෙන නිලධාරී නීතීඥ වරුණ ජයසුන්දර මහතාගේ  උපදෙස් පරිදි බස්නාහිර උතුර භාරව කටයුතු කරන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි ජේ,ආර් සේනාධීර මහතාගේ අධීක්‍ෂණය යටතේ විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය ගෝනහේන කඳවුරේ පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක එච්.පී.එම්.එස්.කේ. වීරක්කොඩි ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් මෙම වැටලීම සිදු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝදර එලිහවුස් පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19,072.86 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "336",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජේ.ආර්. සේනාධීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර උතුර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරුණ ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය ගෝනහේන",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරක්කොඩි",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மத்திய கிழக்கில் விற்பனைக்குத் தயாராக இருக்கும் குப்பைத் தேயிலை ஏற்றுமதியைப் பிடிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிலோன் டீ என்ற பெயரில் சர்வதேச சந்தையில் விற்பனை செய்வதற்கு தயார் செய்யப்பட்ட கழிவு தேயிலையுடன் மோதர எலிஹவுஸ் வீதி களஞ்சியசாலையிலிருந்து ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "19,072.86 கிலோ கழிவு தேநீர் மற்றும் 336 லீற்றர் கழிவு தேயிலைக்கு வர்ணம் பூசுவதற்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட திரவமும் பொலிஸாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும் இந்த கழிவு தேயிலை மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளுக்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்ய தயார் செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும், சிலோன் டீ என்ற பெயரில் சர்வதேச சந்தையில் வெளியிடப்படும் கழிவு தேயிலை காரணமாக இலங்கையில் தேயிலை விற்பனையானது சர்வதேச அளவில் பெரும் பின்னடைவை சந்திக்கிறது.",
        "விசேட அதிரடிப்படை கட்டளை அதிகாரி திரு.வருண ஜயசுந்தர அவர்களின் பணிப்புரைக்கமைய மேற்கு வடக்கிற்கு பொறுப்பான சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் ஜே.ஆர்.சேனாதீர அவர்களின் மேற்பார்வையில் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் கொனஹேன முகாமின் பரிசோதகர் எச்.பி.எம்.எஸ்.கே. வீரக்கொடி உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினர் இந்த சோதனையை மேற்கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோதர எலிஹவுஸ் வீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் டீ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19,072.86",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "336",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் டீ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர் சேனாதீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருண ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிரடிப்படை கொனஹேனா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரக்கொடி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}