{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/no-proper-fuel-distribution-for-buses-allege-bus-owners/",
  "time_ut": 1658380980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NO proper fuel distribution for buses, allege Bus Owners",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NO proper fuel distribution for buses, allege Bus Owners",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Lanka Private Bus Owners Association alleges that there is NO proper program to provide fuel for private passenger transport buses.",
        "The Chairman of the Lanka Private Bus Owners; Association Gemunu Wijeratne said that the absence of a proper system for fuel distribution for buses has caused serious issues in operating private buses to transport passengers.",
        "However, the Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) said that steps have been taken to operate the SLTB buses today (21).",
        "Also, the General Manager of Sri Lanka Railways Dammika Jayasundara noted that the trains are scheduled to operate as usual today (21).",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe sworn in as 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka",
        "‘I am a friend of the people, but forced occupation of offices is illegal’ – President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bus Owners",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka Private Bus Owners",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways Dammika Jayasundara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බස් රථ සඳහා නිසි පරිදි ඉන්ධන බෙදාහැරීමක් සිදු නොවන බව බස් හිමියන් චෝදනා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පෞද්ගලික මගී ප්‍රවාහන බස් රථ සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට නිසි වැඩපිළිවෙළක් නොමැති බවට ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය චෝදනා කරනවා.",
        "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සභාපතිවරයා; බස් රථ සඳහා ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා නිසි ක්‍රමවේදයක් නොමැතිවීම හේතුවෙන් මගීන් ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ ධාවනය කිරීමේදී දැඩි ගැටළු මතුව ඇති බව ගැමුණු විජේරත්න සංගමය ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංගම බස් රථ අද (21) දිනයේ ධාවනය කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බව ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "එමෙන්ම, ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී දම්මික ජයසුන්දර සඳහන් කළේ අද (21) දිනයේ ද දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට නියමිත බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය",
        "‘මම ජනතාවගේ මිතුරෙක්, නමුත් බලහත්කාරයෙන් කාර්යාල අත්පත් කර ගැනීම නීති විරෝධීයි’ – ජනපති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බස් හිමියන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය දම්මික ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேருந்துகளுக்கு முறையாக எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்யப்படவில்லை என பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தனியார் பயணிகள் போக்குவரத்து பஸ்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குவதற்கு முறையான வேலைத்திட்டம் இல்லை என இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்களின் தலைவர்; பேரூந்துகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் விநியோகிப்பதற்கான முறையான முறைமை இன்மையால் பயணிகளை ஏற்றிச் செல்வதற்காக தனியார் பேருந்துகளை இயக்குவதில் பாரிய பிரச்சினை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக சங்கம் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இன்று (21) இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை பஸ்களை இயக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், இன்று (21) புகையிரத சேவைகள் வழமை போன்று இடம்பெறும் என இலங்கை ரயில்வே பொது முகாமையாளர் தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்",
        "‘நான் மக்களின் நண்பன், ஆனால் பலவந்தமாக அலுவலகங்களை ஆக்கிரமிப்பது சட்டவிரோதமானது’ – ஜனாதிபதி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே தம்மிக்க ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}