{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/47-people-detained-for-illegal-migration-attempt/",
  "time_ut": 1656394740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "47 people detained for Illegal Migration attempt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "47 people detained for Illegal Migration attempt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A search operation carried out by the Navy in western seas off Negombo in the dark hours of 27th June 2022 led to the seizure of a local multiday fishing trawler with 47 persons, suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to Australia via sea.",
        "In the search operation mounted in seas off Negombo on 27th June, SLNS Nandimithra managed to intercept a suspicious local multiday fishing trawler carrying this group of people who were suspected to be attempting to illegally migrate from the island to Australia. Among the apprehended individuals were 34 males including 05 persons involved in this racket, 06 females, and 07 children. Along with the suspects, the fishing vessel used for this illegal act was also held by the Navy.",
        "The suspects held in this operation are residents of Jaffna, Kilinochchi, Mannar, Wennappuwa, Nattandiya, Chilaw and Batticaloa, from 01 to 50 years of age. They will be handed over to the Colombo Harbour Police for onward legal proceedings.",
        "The Navy urges the public to avoid being convicted before the law by being caught in the trap of smugglers who organize this nature of perilous voyages to earn a fast buck. Since the Australia’s borders are closed to illegal maritime migration, such individuals will be detained and deported immediately, thus depriving them of the opportunity to legally immigrate to Australia in the future.",
        "Cabinet green light to open Sri Lanka’s Fuel Import & Retail sales market to Companies from Oil producing Nations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Illegal Migration",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the dark hours of 27th June 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27th June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Nandimithra",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa, Nattandiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chilaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 to 50 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Harbour Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fuel Import & Retail",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණයට උත්සාහ කළ පුද්ගලයින් 47 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 ජුනි 27 වැනි දින අඳුරු හෝරාවේ මීගමුව බටහිර මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී පුද්ගලයන් 47 දෙනෙකු සමඟ මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ජූනි 27 වැනි දින මීගමුවට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමේදී, දිවයිනේ සිට ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන මෙම පිරිස රැගෙන යමින් තිබූ සැක කටයුතු දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා නන්දිමිත්‍ර නෞකාව සමත් විය. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයින් අතර මෙම ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයින් 05 දෙනෙකු, කාන්තාවන් 06 දෙනෙකු සහ ළමුන් 07 දෙනෙකු ඇතුළුව පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 34 දෙනෙකු ද වනවා. සැකකරුවන් සමඟ මෙම නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියාව සඳහා යොදාගත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව සතුව තිබී ඇත.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ යාපනය, කිලිනොච්චිය, මන්නාරම, වෙන්නප්පුව, නාත්තන්ඩිය, හලාවත සහ මඩකලපුව යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු 01 සිට 50 දක්වා වූ සැකකරුවන්ය. ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඔවුන් කොළඹ වරාය පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "කඩිනමින් මුදල් උපයා ගැනීම සඳහා මෙවැනි භයානක මුහුදු ගමන් සංවිධානය කරන ජාවාරම්කරුවන්ගේ උගුලට හසුවී නීතිය ඉදිරියේ වරදකරුවන් වීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස නාවික හමුදාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී. නීතිවිරෝධී සමුද්‍ර සංක්‍රමණ සඳහා ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ දේශසීමා වසා ඇති බැවින්, එවැනි පුද්ගලයින් රඳවා තබාගෙන වහාම පිටුවහල් කරනු ලබන අතර, එමඟින් අනාගතයේදී ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට නීත්‍යානුකූලව සංක්‍රමණය වීමේ අවස්ථාව අහිමි වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන ආනයනය සහ සිල්ලර වෙළෙඳ පොළ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදනය කරන රටවල සමාගම්වලට විවෘත කිරීමට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ හරිත එළියක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නීති විරෝධී සංක්රමණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජුනි 27 අඳුරු පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා නන්දිමිත්‍ර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa, Nattandiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භලාවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 01 සිට 50 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය සහ සිල්ලර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்ட 47 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூன் 27 ஆம் திகதி இருண்ட நேரத்தில் நீர்கொழும்புக்கு அப்பால் மேற்கு கடற்பகுதியில் கடற்படையினரால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது கடல் வழியாக அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 47 பேருடன் உள்ளூர் பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவைப்படகு கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜூன் 27 ஆம் திகதி நீர்கொழும்பு கடற்பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில், இலங்கை கடற்படை நந்திமித்ரா தீவில் இருந்து அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக இடம்பெயர முயற்சிப்பதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான உள்ளூர் பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவைப்படகு ஒன்றை இடைமறித்துள்ளது. கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் இந்த மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 05 பேர் உட்பட 34 ஆண்கள், 06 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 07 குழந்தைகள் உள்ளனர். சந்தேகநபர்களுடன், இந்த சட்டவிரோத செயலுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட மீன்பிடி கப்பலும் கடற்படையினரின் வசம் இருந்தது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் யாழ்ப்பாணம், கிளிநொச்சி, மன்னார், வென்னப்புவ, நாத்தாண்டி, சிலாபம் மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு ஆகிய பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 01 வயது முதல் 50 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்கள். அவர்கள் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக கொழும்பு துறைமுக பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர்.",
        "துரித கதியில் பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக இவ்வாறான ஆபத்தான கடற்பயணங்களை ஏற்பாடு செய்யும் கடத்தல்காரர்களின் வலையில் சிக்கி சட்டத்தின் முன் தண்டிக்கப்படுவதை தவிர்க்குமாறு கடற்படை பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக் கொள்கிறது. ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் எல்லைகள் சட்டவிரோத கடல் குடியேற்றத்திற்கு மூடப்பட்டிருப்பதால், அத்தகைய நபர்கள் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டு உடனடியாக நாடு கடத்தப்படுவார்கள், இதனால் எதிர்காலத்தில் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு சட்டப்பூர்வமாக குடியேறுவதற்கான வாய்ப்பை இழக்க நேரிடும்.",
        "எண்ணெய் உற்பத்தி செய்யும் நாடுகளின் நிறுவனங்களுக்கு இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் சில்லறை விற்பனை சந்தையை திறக்க அமைச்சரவை பச்சை விளக்கு."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சட்டவிரோத இடம்பெயர்வு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27, 2022 இருண்ட நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS நந்திமித்ரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa, Nattandiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 முதல் 50 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுக காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி & சில்லறை விற்பனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}