{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132323",
  "time_ut": 1658896480,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சேதமடைந்த  பொருட்கள் எவை - தரவுகளை பதிவு செய்ய இன்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு செல்லும் தொல்பொருள் குழு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The archaeological team will go to the Presidential Palace today to record the damaged items - data",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "A special team of the Department of Archeology will go to this place today (27) to record the cultural and antiquities that have been completely destroyed and damaged in the Presidential Palace.",
        "Assistant Director of Archeology (Western Province) Shyamali Rajapaksa of the Department of Archeology said that they will start these procedures as per the request made by the police.",
        "It is said that the protesters have taken over the Presidential Palace, Alary Palace and the Presidential Secretariat on the 9th of July and have damaged the antiquities in them.",
        "However, the department says that there are no records with the Department of Archeology regarding the antiquities in the Presidential Palace.",
        "It is worth noting that a special committee will go there today for records."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Presidential Palace",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Archeology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shyamali",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Archeology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Archeology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හානියට පත් භාණ්ඩ - දත්ත සටහන් කිරීම සඳහා පුරාවිද්‍යා කණ්ඩායම අද ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට යයි",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම විනාශ වී විනාශ වී ඇති සංස්කෘතික හා පුරාවස්තු සටහන් කිරීමට පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ විශේෂ කණ්ඩායමක් අද (27) මෙම ස්ථානයට යනවා.",
        "පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සහකාර පුරාවිද්‍යා අධ්‍යක්ෂ (බස්නාහිර පළාත) ශ්‍යාමලී රාජපක්ෂ මහත්මිය පැවසුවේ, පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීමට අනුව මෙම ක්‍රියා පටිපාටි ආරම්භ කරන බවයි.",
        "පසුගිය ජුලි මස 09 වනදා විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, ඇලරි මැදුර සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අත්පත් කරගෙන ඇති අතර ඒවායේ ඇති පුරාවස්තු වලටද හානි සිදුකර ඇති බව සඳහන්.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසන්නේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ ඇති පුරාවස්තු සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කිසිදු වාර්තාවක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "වාර්තා සඳහා විශේෂ කමිටුවක් අද එහි යන බව සඳහන් කිරීම වටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ් යාමලී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சேதமடைந்த  பொருட்கள் எவை - தரவுகளை பதிவு செய்ய இன்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு செல்லும் தொல்பொருள் குழு",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி  மாளிகையில் சம்பூர்ணமாக  அழிவடைந்துள்ள, சேதமாக்கப்பட்டுள்ள  கலாசார, தொல்பொருட்கள் எவை என  தரவுகளை பதிவு செய்துகொள்வதற்காக  தொல்பொருள் திணைக்களத்தின் சிறப்புக் கூழுவொன்று இன்று (27) அம்மாளிகைக்கு செல்லவுள்ளது.",
        "பொலிஸார் முன் வைத்துள்ள கோரிக்கை பிரகாரம், இந்நடவடிக்கைகளை ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளதாக தொல்பொருள் திணைக்களத்தின்  உதவி தொல்பொருள் பணிப்பாளர் (மேல் மாகாணம்) ஷியமளி ராஜபக்ஷ  குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி போராட்டக்காரர்கள், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, அலரி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தைக் கைப்பற்றிய நிலையில், அவற்றிலிருந்த தொல்பொருட்கள் சேதமாக்கப்ப்ட்டுள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்த தொல்பொருட்கள் தொடர்பில், தொல்பொருள் திணைக்களத்திடம் பதிவுகள் இல்லை என அத்திணைக்களம் கூறுகின்றது.",
        "இந்நிலையிலேயே அது குறித்த பதிவுகளுக்காக இன்று சிறப்புக் குழு அங்கு செல்லவுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷியாமலி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}