{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ත්‍රස්තපනත-නිසා-එතෙර-සහාය-නැති-වේවි/101-618699",
  "time_ut": 1661348665,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ත්‍රස්තපනත නිසා එතෙර සහාය නැති වේවි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Foreign support will be lost due to terrorism",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka has promised the international community that it will not implement the existing Terrorism Prevention Act until a new Act is brought in place of the Prevention of Terrorism, and the breach of that promise may hinder the process of obtaining international support for Sri Lanka. Mr. Peiris said today (24).",
        "He mentioned that he made that promise when he was the Minister of Foreign Affairs, and former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa also approved it and gave necessary instructions to the relevant departments to act accordingly.",
        "The implementation of this Act and the detention of people involved in demonstrations and struggles for 90 days is completely contrary to the pledge given to the international community, and the fact that the human rights situation in Sri Lanka is being criticized at a time when a delegation of the International Monetary Fund is coming to Sri Lanka to hold talks is an obstacle to the effort to get the international support that the country needs, including the support of that fund. The MP said.",
        "The MP said this while addressing a press conference held in Colombo.",
        "Mr. GL Peiris said that it is clear from the statement made by the Cabinet Media Spokesperson, Dr. Bandula Gunawardena that a new Act will be brought in place of the Act that it is wrong to take certain measures under the Prevention of Terrorism Act."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Terrorism Prevention Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet Media Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තපනත නිසා එතෙර සහාය නැති වේවි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ වෙනුවට නව පනතක් ගෙනඑන තුරු දැනට පවතින ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවට පොරොන්දු වී ඇති බවත්, එම පොරොන්දුව කඩකිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර සහය ලබාගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියට බාධාවක් විය හැකි බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කණ්ඩායම නියෝජනය කරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා අද (24) පැවසීය.",
        "තමන් විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටි සමයේ එම පොරොන්දුව දුන් බවත්, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා ද එය අනුමත කර එසේ ක්‍රියා කරන ලෙසට අදාළ අංශවලට අවශ්‍ය උපදෙස් දී තිබූ බවත් හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම පනත ක්‍රියාත්මක කර පෙලපාලි, අරගලවලට සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයන් දින 90ක් රඳවා ගැනීම ජාත්‍යන්තරයට දී ඇති ප්‍රතිඥාවට සම්පූර්ණ පටහැනි බවත්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් මෙරටට පැමිණ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වන අවස්ථාවක මෙරට මානව හිමිකම් තත්වය විවේචනයට ලක්වෙමින් තිබීම එම අරමුදලේ සහය ඇතුළු රටට අවශ්‍ය ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගය ලබාගැනීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයට බාධාවක් බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ කොළඹ දී පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් අමතමිනි.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ යම් යම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීම වැරදි සහගත බව, එම පනත වෙනුවට නව පනතක් ගෙන එන බවට කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා කර ඇති ප්‍රකාශයෙන්ම පැහැදිලි වන බව ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயங்கரவாதத்தால் வெளிநாட்டு ஆதரவு இழக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்திற்குப் பதிலாக புதிய சட்டம் கொண்டு வரப்படும் வரையில் தற்போதுள்ள பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தப் போவதில்லை என்றும், அந்த வாக்குறுதியை மீறுவது இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச ஆதரவைப் பெறுவதற்கு இடையூறாக அமையும் என்றும் இலங்கை சர்வதேச சமூகத்திற்கு உறுதியளித்துள்ளது. பீரிஸ் இன்று (24) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தாம் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சராக இருந்த போது தான் அந்த வாக்குறுதியை வழங்கியதாகவும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவும் அதனை அங்கீகரித்து உரிய திணைக்களங்களுக்கு உரிய பணிப்புரைகளை வழங்கியதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்தச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவதும், ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களிலும் போராட்டங்களிலும் ஈடுபட்டவர்களை 90 நாட்களாக தடுத்து வைப்பதும் சர்வதேச சமூகத்திற்கு வழங்கிய உறுதிமொழிக்கு முற்றிலும் முரணானது எனவும், இலங்கையின் மனித உரிமைகள் நிலை குறித்து தூதுக்குழுவினர் விமர்சனம் செய்து வருகின்றனர். சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் இலங்கைக்கு வந்து பேச்சு வார்த்தை நடத்துவது, அந்த நிதியின் ஆதரவு உட்பட நாட்டிற்கு தேவையான சர்வதேச ஆதரவை பெறுவதற்கான முயற்சிக்கு தடையாக உள்ளது என எம்.பி.",
        "கொழும்பில் இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் சில நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்வது தவறு என்பது அந்தச் சட்டத்திற்குப் பதிலாக புதிய சட்டம் கொண்டு வரப்படும் என அமைச்சரவை ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்திருப்பதன் மூலம் தெரியவருவதாக ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாத தடுப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}