{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/14/three-elephant-carcasses-discovered-in-paddy-field/",
  "time_ut": 1660475160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three elephant carcasses discovered in Paddy Field",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three elephant carcasses discovered in Paddy Field",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo (News 1st): The carcasses of three wild elephants including a tusker were discovered in a paddy field in Mihinthalaya on Sunday (14).",
        "Director General of Wildlife Chandana Sooriyabandara said a preliminary examination revealed that the pachyderms had died of electrocution after coming into contact with a electricity cable set up in the vicinity.",
        "Will support from Opposition until Tamil people are satisfied: C.V. Wigneswaran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Paddy Field",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mihinthalaya",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandana Sooriyabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුඹුරු යායෙන් අලි මළ සිරුරු තුනක් සොයා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) – මිහින්තලය ප්‍රදේශයේ වෙල්යායක තිබී දළ ඇතෙකු ඇතුළු වන අලි තිදෙනෙකුගේ මළ සිරුරු ඉරිදා (14) සොයා ගැනුණා.",
        "වනජීවී අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් චන්දන සූරියබණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසුවේ, ඒ ආසන්නයේ සවිකර තිබූ විදුලි රැහැනක ගැටීමෙන් විදුලිසැර වැදීමෙන් මෙම අලි පැටවා මිය ගොස් ඇති බව මූලික පරීක්ෂණයකදී හෙළි වූ බවයි.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව තෘප්තිමත් වන තුරු විපක්ෂයේ සහය දෙනවා: සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කුඹුර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහින්තලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දන සූරියබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெல் வயலில் மூன்று யானை சடலங்கள் கண்டுபிடிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo (News 1st) ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (14) மிஹிந்தலையில் உள்ள வயல்வெளியில் யானை உட்பட மூன்று காட்டு யானைகளின் சடலங்கள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "வனஜீவராசிகள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் சந்தன சூரியபண்டார கூறுகையில், முதற்கட்ட பரிசோதனையில், அருகில் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மின்சார கேபிளில் மோதி மின்சாரம் தாக்கி இறந்துள்ளதாக தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் திருப்தி அடையும் வரை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு: சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நெல் வயல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிஹிந்தாலய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்தன சூரியபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}