{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131075",
  "time_ut": 1657278935,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யாழ் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை சுகாதார பணியாளர்களுக்கு துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் வழங்கிவைப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Provision of two-wheelers to Jaffna Teaching Hospital health workers",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "10 two-wheelers were handed over to Jaffna Teaching Hospital to facilitate the transportation of health workers.",
        "The fuel shortage in the country has also affected the transport of health workers and the prices of two-wheelers have also increased.",
        "To solve this crisis, British Car Welfare Association has donated ten double wheeled cars to the Jaffna Teaching Hospital.",
        "On behalf of the association, vice-president Vinasithambi Nagendram, secretary Paramanathar Thavaraja and member of the executive council Kandasamy Balakrishnan were present on the occasion.",
        "Ten two-wheelers were also received by Deputy Superintendents Bhavanandaraja, Yamunananda and the Hospital Welfare Society. It is noted that Dr. Sathyamurthy had earlier made a request to Britannia Karai Welfare Association regarding the above issue."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaffna Teaching Hospital",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British Car Welfare Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vinasithambi Nagendram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thavaraja",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandasamy Balakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Superintendents Bhavanandaraja",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yamunananda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hospital Welfare Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sathyamurthy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britannia Karai Welfare Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල් සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින්ට රෝද රථ ලබාදීම",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින්ගේ ප්‍රවාහනය පහසු කිරීම සඳහා යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට ත්‍රිරෝද රථ 10ක් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "රට තුළ පවතින ඉන්ධන හිඟය සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින්ගේ ප්‍රවාහනයට ද බලපා ඇති අතර රෝද රථවල මිල ද ඉහළ ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මෙම අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මෝටර් රථ සුබසාධක සංගමය යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට ද්විත්ව රෝද සහිත මෝටර් රථ දහයක් පරිත්‍යාග කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට සංගමය වෙනුවෙන් උප සභාපති විනාසිතම්බි නාගේන්ද්‍රම්, ලේකම් පරමනාතර් තවරාජා සහ විධායක සභා සභික කන්දසාමි බාලක්‍රිෂ්ණන් යන මහත්වරු සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "නියෝජ්‍ය අධිකාරීවරුන් වන භවානන්දරාජා, යමුනානන්ද සහ රෝහල් සුබසාධක සංගමය විසින් ද ත්‍රිරෝද රථ 10ක් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. ඉහත ගැටලුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් වෛද්‍ය සත්‍යමූර්ති විසින් බ්‍රිටැනියා කරෙයි සුබසාධක සංගමයෙන් මීට පෙර ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබූ බව සටහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මෝටර් රථ සුබසාධන සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විනාසිතම්බි නාගේන්ද්‍රම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවරාජා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්දසාමි බාලක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භවානන්දරාජා අධිකාරීවරුන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යමුනානන්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහල් සුභසාධක සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සත්‍යමූර්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britannia Karai සුබසාධක සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை சுகாதார பணியாளர்களுக்கு துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் வழங்கிவைப்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை சுகாதார பணியாளர்களின் போக்குவரத்தை இலகுப்படுத்தும் வகையில் 10 துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் கையளிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு சுகாதார பணியாளர்களின் போக்குவரத்தையும் பாதித்துள்ள நிலையில் துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகளின் விலைகளும் அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்கும் முகமாக பிரித்தானியா காரை நலன்புரிச்சங்கத்தினர் ஏற்பாட்டில் பத்து துவிச்சககர வண்டிகள் யாழ் போதனா வைத்தியசாலைக்கு அன்பளிப்பாக வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "குறித்த வைபவத்தில் சங்கத்தின் சார்பாக உபதலைவர் விநாசித்தம்பி நாகேந்திரம், செயலாளர்  பரமநாதர் தவராஜா மற்றும் நிர்வாக சபை உறுப்பினர் கந்தசாமி பாலகிருஷ்ணன் ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டு சிறப்பித்திருந்தனர்.",
        "பத்து துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகளையும் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர்கள் பவானந்தராஜா, யமுனானந்தா மற்றும் வைத்தியசாலை நலன்புரிச் சங்கத்தினரும் பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர். பிரித்தானியா காரை நலன்புரிச் சங்கத்தினரிடம் வைத்தியர் த.சத்தியமூர்த்தி மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட விடயம் தொடர்பாக முன்னதாகவே கோரிக்கை விடுத்திருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் கார் நலன்புரி சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வினாசித்தம்பி நாகேந்திரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவராஜா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தசாமி பாலகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்தியட்சகர்கள் பவானந்தராஜா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யமுனாநந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருத்துவமனை நலன்புரி சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சத்தியமூர்த்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டானியா காரை நலன்புரி சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}