{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132102",
  "time_ut": 1658569518,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுக்கும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றியதற்கும் தொடர்பில்லை - எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court order has nothing to do with removal of demonstrators - MA Sumanthran",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil National Federation Media Spokesperson and Member of Parliament MA Sumanthran said that the removal of the Presidential Secretariat demonstrators has nothing to do with the court order.",
        "This was stated by MA Sumanthran at a media conference held at the Sri Lankan Tamil Republic Party's Vadamarachi office.",
        "JR 39 years after the July riots of 1983 during Jayawardena's presidency, J.R. Yesterday, when Ranil Wickremesinghe, Jayawardene's cousin, was the President, there was an attack on Khalimugat.",
        "The court order is that one should not go within 50 meters around the Bandaranaike statue by mentioning his name. The court order was unrelated to the removal of the Presidential Secretariat protesters.",
        "The attack was carried out by government forces in the dark after protesters said they would retake the presidential secretariat. The international community condemned the attack. The representative of the main country directly told the president that if such an incident happens again, we will help you.",
        "Last May 9 attack was carried out by gangsters. Yesterday's attack was carried out by government forces. Why did Ranil Wickramasinghe who condemned the May 9 attack not condemn it?",
        "Within hours the executive replaced Ranil. Yesterday's attack left the country reeling."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Federation Media Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament MA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MA Sumanthran",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Tamil Republic Party's",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vadamarachi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "J.R.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardene",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Khalimugat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙළපාලිකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීමට අධිකරණ නියෝගයේ කිසිදු සම්බන්ධයක් නැහැ - එම් ඒ සුමන්ත්‍රන්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සම්මේලනයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම් ඒ සුමන්ත්‍රන් පැවසුවේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීමේ අධිකරණ නියෝගයට කිසිදු සම්බන්ධයක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ද්‍රවිඩ ජනරජ පක්‍ෂයේ වඩමාරච්චි කාර්යාලයේ පැවැති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකදී එම්.ඒ.සුමන්ත්‍රන් මහතා මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "ජේ.ආර් ජයවර්ධන ජනාධිපතිව සිටි සමයේ 1983 ජූලි කෝලාහලයෙන් වසර 39කට පසු ජේ.ආර්. ඊයේ දිනයේදී ජයවර්ධනගේ ඥාති සොහොයුරා වන රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිව සිටියදී ඛලිමුගට් වෙත ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල විය.",
        "ඔහුගේ නම කියමින් බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව අවට මීටර් 50ක් ඇතුළත නොයා යුතු බව අධිකරණ නියෝගයයි. එම අධිකරණ නියෝගය ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීමට අදාළ නැත.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය යළි අත්පත් කර ගන්නා බව පැවසීමෙන් පසු අඳුරේම රජයේ හමුදා විසින් මෙම ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල කර ඇත. ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව මෙම ප්‍රහාරය හෙළා දැක ඇත. ප්‍රධාන රටේ නියෝජිතයා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට කෙළින්ම කියා සිටියේ එවැනි සිදුවීමක් නැවත සිදුවුවහොත් අපි ඔබට උදව් කරන බවයි.",
        "පසුගිය මැයි 9 වැනිදා මැර ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කළා. ඊයේ ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල කළේ රජයේ හමුදා විසිනි. මැයි 9 ප්‍රහාරය හෙළා දුටු රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ එය හෙළා නොදැක්කේ ඇයි?",
        "පැය කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත රනිල් වෙනුවට විධායකය ආවා. ඊයේ එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් රටම කම්පා විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එම්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දෙමළ ජනරජ පක්ෂයේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඩමාරච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 39 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.ආර්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛලිමුගට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுக்கும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றியதற்கும் தொடர்பில்லை - எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலக ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றியதற்கும் தொடர்பில்லை என தமிழ்த் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளரும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைத் தமிழரசுக் கட்சியின் வடமராட்சி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற ஊடக சந்திப்பிலேய எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் இதனை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜே.ஆர். ஜெயவர்த்தன ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த காலத்தில் 1983 ஜூலைக் கலவரம் ஏற்பட்டு 39 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு பிறகு மீண்டும் ஜூலை மாதத்தில் ஜே.ஆர். ஜெயவர்த்தனவின் உறவினர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக இருக்கும்போது நேற்றைய தினம் காலிமுகத்திடல் தாக்குதல் சம்பவம் பதிவாகியிருக்கிறது.",
        "பண்டாரநாயக்க சிலையை சுற்றி 50 மீற்றர் தூரத்திற்கு ஒருவரின் பெயரைக் குறிப்பிட்டு அவரை போகக்கூடாது என்பதே நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவு. நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலக ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றியதற்கும் தொடர்பில்லை.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தை மீள கையளிப்பதாக போராட்டகாரர்கள் சொன்ன பிறகு இந்த தாக்குதல் அரச படையினரால் இருட்டில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. சர்வதேச சமூகம் இந்த தாக்குதலை கண்டித்துள்ளது. இவ்வாறான சம்பவம் இனிமேல் நடந்தால் உங்களுக்கு உதவமெட்டோமென ஐனாதிபதிக்கு முக்கிய நாட்டு பிரதிநிதி முகத்துக்கு நேரே சொன்னார்.",
        "கடந்த மே 9 தாக்குதல் குண்டர்களால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. நேற்றைய தாக்குதல் அரசபடைகளால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. மே 9 தாக்குதலை கண்டித்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஏன் இதனை கண்டிக்கவில்லை.",
        "ஒருசில மணிநேரத்திற்குள் நிறைவேற்றதிகாரம் ரணிலை மாற்றிவிட்டது. நேற்றைய தாக்குதல் நாட்டை  பின்னடைய செய்துவிட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற எம்.ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழரசுக் கட்சியின்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமராச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்த்தனே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலிமுகத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}