{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Customs-seize-illegally-imported-scrap-metal/342-244019",
  "time_ut": 1661864359,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Customs seize illegally imported scrap metal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Customs seize illegally imported scrap metal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Officers attached to the Central Intelligence Directorate (CID) of Sri Lanka Customs today seized more than 140 metric tons of scrap metal, which was restricted by the government. While attempting to smuggle the scrap metal out of the country illegally, it was taken to customs. The contents of the 20-foot container was declared to customs as natural rubber. The restricted metal was about to be shipped to India when it was intercepted based on collective intelligence and suspicion. Pix by Pradeep Pathirana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Customs",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Intelligence Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 140 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-foot",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ආනයනය කරන ලද පරණ යකඩ රේගු භාරයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජය විසින් සීමා කරන ලද පරණ යකඩ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 140කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මධ්‍යම බුද්ධි අධ්‍යක්ෂ (CID) වෙත අනුයුක්ත නිලධාරීන් විසින් අද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙම පරණ යකඩ තොගය මෙරටින් රැගෙන යාමට උත්සහ කිරීමේදී රේගුවට රැගෙන ගොස් තිබෙනවා. අඩි 20 ක කන්ටේනරයේ අන්තර්ගතය ස්වභාවික රබර් ලෙස රේගුවට ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත. සාමූහික බුද්ධිය සහ සැකය මත එය අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් විට සීමා කරන ලද ලෝහය ඉන්දියාවට නැව්ගත කිරීමට සූදානම් විය. පික්ස් - ප්‍රදීප් පතිරණ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රේගුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම බුද්ධි අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 140 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-අඩි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டவிரோதமாக இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட பழைய உலோகங்களை சுங்கம் கைப்பற்றுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் மத்திய புலனாய்வு இயக்குநரகத்தின் (CID) அதிகாரிகள் இன்று அரசாங்கத்தால் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட 140 மெட்ரிக் தொன் பழைய உலோகத்தை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர். சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் ஸ்கிராப் உலோகத்தை நாட்டிலிருந்து கடத்த முற்பட்ட போது, ​​அது சுங்கத்திற்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டது. 20 அடி கொள்கலனில் இருந்த பொருட்கள் இயற்கை ரப்பர் என சுங்கத்துறைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. கூட்டு உளவுத்துறை மற்றும் சந்தேகத்தின் அடிப்படையில் தடுத்து நிறுத்தப்பட்டபோது தடைசெய்யப்பட்ட உலோகம் இந்தியாவுக்கு அனுப்பப்படவிருந்தது. படங்கள் பிரதீப் பத்திரன"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய புலனாய்வு இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 மெட்ரிக் டன்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}