{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/financial-services/AIA-delivers-resilient-performance-in-1H/42-739251",
  "time_ut": 1661810603,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "AIA delivers resilient performance in 1H",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "AIA delivers resilient performance in 1H",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "AIA Group Ltd. has delivered resilient performance in the first half of FY22 according to its Group Chief Executive and President Lee Yuan Siong.",
        "“AIA has delivered a resilient performance in the first half of 2022. Sales momentum in the second quarter improved as the temporary disruption caused by the initial outbreak of the Omicron variant declined and we delivered positive VONB growth in June,” Siong said.",
        "“Our growing high-quality in-force portfolio supported an increase in both OPAT and UFSG. The Group’s financial position remained very strong with free surplus increasing to $ 20.6 billion and a Group LCSM cover ratio of 277% despite the significant stress in capital markets. EV Equity was $ 72.3 billion, representing an increase of 3% in the first half before the return of $ 3.0 billion to shareholders through our share buy-back programme and payment of the 2021 final dividend.”",
        "The Board has declared a 6% increase in the interim dividend to 40.28 Hong Kong cents per share. This follows AIA’s established prudent, sustainable and progressive dividend policy, allowing for future growth opportunities and the financial flexibility of the Group.",
        "He said, “AIA’s wide adoption of technology, digital and analytics throughout the Group continues to enhance our business capabilities and resilience. Our agents rapidly switched from in-person to digital remote sales, helping to offset the effect of the initial Omicron wave on face-to-face sales activities, and leveraged our social-media-integrated leads management platforms as a powerful way to generate new customer leads. Agency new business momentum increased month-on-month in the second quarter and we returned to VONB growth in June. In July, AIA was ranked the number one global Million Dollar Round Table (MDRT) multinational for a record eighth year in a row, demonstrating our consistent focus on high-quality and professional advice.",
        "“Our strategic partnerships with leading banks delivered double-digit VONB growth in the first half, driven by very strong performances in Hong Kong, Malaysia and India. Overall, our partnership distribution business reported a positive increase in the first half and strong VONB growth in the second quarter, supported by double-digit growth in Malaysia, Indonesia and the Philippines and a material contribution from our partnership with The Bank of East Asia, Ltd. (BEA).",
        "“While sales activity in the second quarter for AIA China was substantially affected by stringent containment measures in Shanghai, Suzhou and Beijing, we achieved positive VONB growth across our other geographies. In the first half, VONB was lower due to the restrictions and following a record result in the first half of 2021, which was driven by an exceptionally high level of traditional protection sales, as previously reported. Our high-quality Premier Agency model remained resilient with growth in active agent productivity, new recruits and the overall agency force. As restrictions reduced across our operations, AIA China achieved positive VONB growth in July.”",
        "Siong also said the Mainland Chinese life insurance market remains significantly underpenetrated and offers tremendous growth potential for AIA. “We continue to make strong progress in geographical expansion and our new branch in Wuhan, Hubei province, commenced sales in the first half, making a strong contribution to the excellent VONB growth from our new geographies. In May, we received regulatory approval to prepare a new branch in Henan, the third most populous province in Mainland China.",
        "“In the first half of 2022, AIA Hong Kong delivered 3% growth in VONB, supported by growth in both agency and partnership distribution channels. Sales momentum in our domestic customer segment rebounded from May as daily infections subsided. While travel across the Hong Kong border remains limited, we delivered strong VONB growth from sales to Mainland Chinese visitors through our Macau branch.",
        "“The rest of the Group generated close to 50% of total VONB in the first half of 2022 with progressive improvements in sales activities in the second quarter. In June, our market-leading ASEAN businesses returned to growth with a very strong double-digit increase in VONB.",
        "“Tata AIA Life, our joint venture in India, is well positioned to capture the significant opportunities available in the life insurance market. We achieved excellent VONB growth in the first half, supported by the success of our multi-channel distribution platform. Our highly-digitalised Premier Agency delivered very strong increases in recruitment, agency leaders, active agents and productivity. We continued to strengthen relationships with a wide range of bank partners and brokers and generated excellent VONB growth in our partnership channel,” Siong said.",
        "“I am confident that the long-term prospects for AIA’s broad and diverse business remain exceptional. AIA’s geographical diversity across Asia and our unrivalled distribution platform are key strengths. We are focused on the disciplined execution of our strategic priorities which will continue to deliver long-term sustainable value for all our stakeholders,” he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1H",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA Group Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lee Yuan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OPAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UFSG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20.6 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group LCSM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "277%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "EV Equity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 72.3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.0 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong cents",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA’s",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a record eighth year in a row",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Bank of East Asia, Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the second quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanghai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suzhou",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Siong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mainland Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wuhan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hubei",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Henan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mainland China",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first half of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mainland Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Macau",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "AIA 1H හි ඔරොත්තු දෙන කාර්ය සාධනය ලබා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "AIA Group Ltd එහි සමූහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක සහ සභාපති Lee Yuan Siong ට අනුව FY22 මුල් භාගයේදී ඔරොත්තු දෙන කාර්ය සාධනයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "\"AIA 2022 පළමු භාගයේදී ඔරොත්තු දෙන කාර්ය සාධනයක් ලබා දී ඇත. Omicron ප්‍රභේදයේ ආරම්භක පිපිරීමෙන් ඇති වූ තාවකාලික බාධාව අඩු වීම නිසා දෙවන කාර්තුවේ විකුණුම් ගම්‍යතාවය වැඩි දියුණු වූ අතර අපි ජුනි මාසයේදී ධනාත්මක VONB වර්ධනයක් ලබා දුන්නෙමු,\" Siong පැවසීය.",
        "“අපගේ වර්ධනය වන උසස් තත්ත්වයේ බලගතු කළඹ OPAT සහ UFSG යන දෙකෙහිම වැඩි වීමක් සඳහා සහාය විය. ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙලඳපොලවල ඇති වූ සැලකිය යුතු ආතතිය නොතකා නිදහස් අතිරික්තය ඩොලර් බිලියන 20.6 දක්වා සහ 277% ක සමූහ LCSM ආවරණ අනුපාතය සමඟ සමූහයේ මූල්‍ය තත්ත්වය ඉතා ශක්තිමත්ව පැවතුනි. EV Equity ඩොලර් බිලියන 72.3 ක් වූ අතර, අපගේ කොටස් ආපසු මිලදී ගැනීමේ වැඩසටහන සහ 2021 අවසාන ලාභාංශය ගෙවීම හරහා කොටස් හිමියන්ට ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.0 ආපසු පැමිණීමට පෙර පළමු භාගයේ 3% ක වැඩිවීමක් නියෝජනය කරයි.",
        "මණ්ඩලය විසින් අතුරු ලාභාංශයේ 6%ක වැඩිවීමක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති අතර එය කොටසකට හොංකොං ශත 40.28 කි. මෙය AIA හි ස්ථාපිත විචක්ෂණශීලී, තිරසාර සහ ප්‍රගතිශීලී ලාභාංශ ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් අනුගමනය කරමින්, අනාගත වර්ධන අවස්ථා සහ සමූහයේ මූල්‍ය නම්‍යශීලීභාවයට ඉඩ සලසයි.",
        "ඔහු පැවසුවේ, “AIA විසින් සමූහය පුරාවට තාක්‍ෂණය, ඩිජිටල් සහ විශ්ලේෂණ පුළුල් ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීම අපගේ ව්‍යාපාරික හැකියාවන් සහ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව තවදුරටත් ඉහළ නංවයි. අපගේ නියෝජිතයින් ඉක්මනින් පුද්ගලයාගේ සිට ඩිජිටල් දුරස්ථ විකුණුම් වෙත මාරු වූ අතර, මුහුණට මුහුණ විකුණුම් ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මත ආරම්භක Omicron තරංගයේ බලපෑම සමනය කිරීමට උපකාරී වන අතර, අපගේ සමාජ මාධ්‍ය-ඒකාබද්ධ නායකත්වය කළමනාකරණ වේදිකා නව උත්පාදනය සඳහා ප්‍රබල ක්‍රමයක් ලෙස භාවිතා කළේය. පාරිභෝගික නායකත්වය. නියෝජිතායතනයේ නව ව්‍යාපාරික ප්‍රවේගය දෙවන කාර්තුවේදී මාසිකව වැඩි වූ අතර අපි ජුනි මාසයේදී VONB වර්ධනය වෙත ආපසු ගියෙමු. ජුලි මාසයේදී, උසස් තත්ත්වයේ සහ වෘත්තීය උපදෙස් කෙරෙහි අපගේ නිරන්තර අවධානය යොමු කරමින්, අඛණ්ඩව වාර්තාගත අටවැනි වසර සඳහා AIA ගෝලීය ඩොලර් මිලියන වට මේස (MDRT) බහුජාතික වශයෙන් අංක එකේ ශ්‍රේණිගත කරන ලදී.",
        "“ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ බැංකු සමඟ අපගේ උපායමාර්ගික හවුල්කාරිත්වය පළමු භාගයේදී VONB ඉලක්කම් දෙකක වර්ධනයක් ලබා දුන් අතර, එය හොංකොං, මැලේසියාව සහ ඉන්දියාවේ ඉතා ප්‍රබල කාර්ය සාධනයක් මගින් මෙහෙයවනු ලැබීය. සමස්තයක් වශයෙන්, අපගේ හවුල්කාරිත්ව බෙදා හැරීමේ ව්‍යාපාරය පළමු භාගයේ ධනාත්මක වර්ධනයක් සහ දෙවන කාර්තුවේ ශක්තිමත් VONB වර්ධනයක් වාර්තා කළ අතර, මැලේසියාව, ඉන්දුනීසියාව සහ පිලිපීනය යන රටවල ඉලක්කම් දෙකක වර්ධනයක් සහ නැගෙනහිර ආසියා බැංකුව සමඟ අපගේ හවුල්කාරිත්වයේ ද්‍රව්‍යමය දායකත්වයෙන් සහාය විය. Ltd. (BEA).",
        "“AIA චීනයේ දෙවන කාර්තුවේ විකුණුම් ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ෂැංහයි, සුෂෝ සහ බීජිං හි දැඩි පාලන ක්‍රියාමාර්ග මගින් සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස බලපා ඇති අතර, අපි අපගේ අනෙකුත් භූගෝලීය ප්‍රදේශ හරහා ධනාත්මක VONB වර්ධනයක් ලබා ගත්තෙමු. පළමු භාගයේ දී, සීමා කිරීම් හේතුවෙන් VONB අඩු වූ අතර 2021 පළමු භාගයේ වාර්තාගත ප්‍රතිඵලයක් අනුගමනය කරමින්, කලින් වාර්තා කළ පරිදි, සම්ප්‍රදායික ආරක්ෂණ විකුණුම්වල සුවිශේෂී ඉහළ මට්ටමක පැවතුනි. අපගේ උසස් තත්ත්වයේ Premier Agency ආකෘතිය ක්‍රියාකාරී නියෝජිතයින්ගේ ඵලදායිතාවයේ වර්ධනය, නව බඳවා ගැනීම් සහ සමස්ත නියෝජිතායතන බලකායේ වර්ධනය සමඟ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාවක් පැවතුනි. අපගේ මෙහෙයුම් හරහා සීමා කිරීම් අඩු වීමත් සමඟ, AIA චීනය ජූලි මාසයේදී ධනාත්මක VONB වර්ධනයක් අත්කර ගත්තේය.",
        "මේන්ලන්ඩ් චීන ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ වෙළෙඳපොළ සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස අඩු වී ඇති බවත් AIA සඳහා දැවැන්ත වර්ධන විභවයක් ලබා දෙන බවත් Siong පැවසීය. “අපි භූගෝලීය ව්‍යාප්තියෙහි ප්‍රබල ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කරගෙන සිටින අතර, Hubei පළාතේ වුහාන් හි අපගේ නව ශාඛාව, අපගේ නව භූගෝල විද්‍යාවෙන් විශිෂ්ට VONB වර්ධනයට ප්‍රබල දායකත්වයක් ලබා දෙමින් පළමු භාගයේදී විකුණුම් ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. චීනයේ මේන්ලන්ඩ් හි තුන්වන වැඩිම ජනගහනය සහිත පළාත වන හෙනාන්හි නව ශාඛාවක් සකස් කිරීමට මැයි මාසයේදී අපට නියාමන අනුමැතිය ලැබුණි.",
        "“2022 පළමු භාගයේදී, AIA හොංකොං VONB හි 3% වර්ධනයක් ලබා දුන් අතර, නියෝජිතායතන සහ හවුල් බෙදාහැරීමේ නාලිකා දෙකෙහිම වර්ධනයට සහාය විය. දෛනික ආසාදන අඩුවීමත් සමඟ අපගේ දේශීය පාරිභෝගික අංශයේ විකුණුම් ගම්‍යතාව මැයි මාසයේ සිට යළිත් ඉහළ ගියේය. හොංකොං දේශසීමා හරහා ගමන් කිරීම සීමාසහිතව පවතින අතර, අපි අපගේ මැකාවු ශාඛාව හරහා Mainland චීන අමුත්තන්ට අලෙවියෙන් ශක්තිමත් VONB වර්ධනයක් ලබා දුන්නෙමු.",
        "“දෙවන කාර්තුවේ විකුණුම් ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල ප්‍රගතිශීලී වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම් සමඟින් සමූහයේ සෙසු කොටස් 2022 පළමු භාගයේදී මුළු VONB වලින් 50% කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ජනනය කළහ. ජූනි මාසයේදී, VONB හි ඉතා ශක්තිමත් ඉලක්කම් දෙකක වැඩිවීමක් සමඟින් අපගේ වෙළඳපල-ප්‍රමුඛ ආසියාන් ව්‍යාපාර නැවත වර්ධනයට පැමිණියේය.",
        "“Tata AIA Life, ඉන්දියාවේ අපගේ හවුල් ව්‍යාපාරය, ජීවිත රක්‍ෂණ වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ පවතින සැලකිය යුතු අවස්ථාවන් ග්‍රහණය කර ගැනීමට හොඳින් ස්ථානගත වී ඇත. අපගේ බහු-නාලිකා බෙදාහැරීමේ වේදිකාවේ සාර්ථකත්වයේ සහාය ඇතිව අපි පළමු භාගයේ විශිෂ්ට VONB වර්ධනයක් අත්කර ගත්තෙමු. අපගේ ඉහළ-ඩිජිටල්කරණය වූ ප්‍රිමියර් ඒජන්සිය බඳවා ගැනීම්, නියෝජිතායතන නායකයින්, ක්‍රියාකාරී නියෝජිතයින් සහ ඵලදායිතාවයේ ඉතා ශක්තිමත් වර්ධනයක් ලබා දුන්නේය. අපි පුළුල් පරාසයක බැංකු හවුල්කරුවන් සහ තැරැව්කරුවන් සමඟ සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගත් අතර අපගේ හවුල්කාරිත්ව නාලිකාවේ විශිෂ්ට VONB වර්ධනයක් ඇති කළෙමු, ”සියොන්ග් පැවසීය.",
        "“AIA හි පුළුල් සහ විවිධ ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා දිගුකාලීන අපේක්ෂාවන් සුවිශේෂීව පවතින බව මට විශ්වාසයි. AIA හි ආසියාව පුරා ඇති භූගෝලීය විවිධත්වය සහ අපගේ අසමසම බෙදාහැරීමේ වේදිකාව ප්‍රධාන ශක්තීන් වේ. අපගේ සියලු පාර්ශ්වකරුවන් සඳහා දිගුකාලීන තිරසාර වටිනාකමක් අඛණ්ඩව ලබා දීම සඳහා අපගේ උපායමාර්ගික ප්‍රමුඛතා විනයගරුකව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම කෙරෙහි අපි අවධානය යොමු කර ඇත්තෙමු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1H",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA Group Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලී යුවාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OPAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UFSG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 20.6 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහ LCSM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "277%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "EV කොටස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 72.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.0 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.28 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං ශත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA ගේ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්තාගත අටවැනි වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත නැගෙනහිර ආසියා බැංකුව.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂැංහයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suzhou",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේන්ලන්ඩ් චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වුහාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුබෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙනාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනයේ ප්‍රධාන භූමිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේන්ලන්ඩ් චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැකාවු",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "AIA 1H இல் நெகிழ்ச்சியான செயல்திறனை வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "AIA குரூப் லிமிடெட், அதன் குழுமத்தின் தலைமை நிர்வாகி மற்றும் தலைவர் லீ யுவான் சியோங் கருத்துப்படி, FY22 இன் முதல் பாதியில் நெகிழ்ச்சியான செயல்திறனை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "\"2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதியில் AIA ஒரு நெகிழ்ச்சியான செயல்திறனை வழங்கியுள்ளது. Omicron மாறுபாட்டின் ஆரம்ப வெடிப்பினால் ஏற்பட்ட தற்காலிக இடையூறு குறைந்து, ஜூன் மாதத்தில் நேர்மறையான VONB வளர்ச்சியை நாங்கள் வழங்கியதால், இரண்டாம் காலாண்டில் விற்பனை வேகம் மேம்பட்டது\" என்று சியோங் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் வளர்ந்து வரும் உயர்தர இன்-ஃபோர்ஸ் போர்ட்ஃபோலியோ OPAT மற்றும் UFSG இரண்டிலும் அதிகரிப்புக்கு ஆதரவளித்தது. மூலதனச் சந்தைகளில் கணிசமான அழுத்தங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், குழுமத்தின் நிதி நிலை, இலவச உபரி $20.6 பில்லியனாக அதிகரித்து, குழுவின் LCSM கவரே விகிதம் 277% ஆக மிகவும் வலுவாக இருந்தது. EV ஈக்விட்டி $72.3 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது, இது முதல் பாதியில் 3% அதிகரிப்பைக் குறிக்கும், இது 2021 இறுதி ஈவுத்தொகையை செலுத்துவதன் மூலம் பங்குதாரர்களுக்கு $3.0 பில்லியனைத் திரும்பப்பெறும்.",
        "வாரியம் இடைக்கால ஈவுத்தொகையில் 6% அதிகரித்து ஒரு பங்கிற்கு 40.28 ஹாங்காங் சென்ட்களாக அறிவித்துள்ளது. இது AIA இன் நிறுவப்பட்ட விவேகமான, நிலையான மற்றும் முற்போக்கான டிவிடென்ட் கொள்கையைப் பின்பற்றுகிறது, இது எதிர்கால வளர்ச்சி வாய்ப்புகள் மற்றும் குழுவின் நிதி நெகிழ்வுத்தன்மையை அனுமதிக்கிறது.",
        "அவர் கூறினார், “AIA இன் தொழில்நுட்பம், டிஜிட்டல் மற்றும் பகுப்பாய்வுகளை குழு முழுவதும் பரவலாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்வது எங்கள் வணிக திறன்களையும் பின்னடைவையும் தொடர்ந்து மேம்படுத்துகிறது. எங்கள் முகவர்கள் நேருக்கு நேர் விற்பனை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஆரம்ப ஓமிக்ரான் அலையின் தாக்கத்தை ஈடுசெய்ய உதவுவதன் மூலம் நேரில் இருந்து டிஜிட்டல் ரிமோட் விற்பனைக்கு விரைவாக மாறினர், மேலும் எங்கள் சமூக-ஊடக-ஒருங்கிணைந்த முன்னணி மேலாண்மை தளங்களை புதியதை உருவாக்க ஒரு சக்திவாய்ந்த வழியாக பயன்படுத்துகின்றனர். வாடிக்கையாளர் வழிநடத்துகிறது. இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் ஏஜென்சியின் புதிய வணிக வேகம் மாதந்தோறும் அதிகரித்தது மற்றும் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் VONB வளர்ச்சிக்கு திரும்பினோம். ஜூலை மாதம், AIA ஆனது, தொடர்ச்சியாக எட்டாவது ஆண்டாக உலக மில்லியன் டாலர் வட்ட மேசை (MDRT) பன்னாட்டுத் தரவரிசையில் முதலிடத்தைப் பெற்றது.",
        "\"முன்னணி வங்கிகளுடனான எங்கள் மூலோபாய கூட்டாண்மை முதல் பாதியில் இரட்டை இலக்க VONB வளர்ச்சியை வழங்கியது, இது ஹாங்காங், மலேசியா மற்றும் இந்தியாவில் மிகவும் வலுவான செயல்திறன் மூலம் உந்தப்பட்டது. ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக, எங்கள் கூட்டாண்மை விநியோக வணிகமானது முதல் பாதியில் நேர்மறையான அதிகரிப்பையும், இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் வலுவான VONB வளர்ச்சியையும் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது, மலேசியா, இந்தோனேஷியா மற்றும் பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் ஆகிய நாடுகளில் இரட்டை இலக்க வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் The Bank of East Asia உடனான எங்கள் கூட்டுப் பங்களிப்பால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டது. லிமிடெட் (BEA).",
        "“AIA சீனாவின் இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் விற்பனை நடவடிக்கைகள் ஷாங்காய், சுஜோ மற்றும் பெய்ஜிங்கில் கடுமையான கட்டுப்பாட்டு நடவடிக்கைகளால் கணிசமாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், எங்களின் மற்ற புவியியல் பகுதிகளில் நேர்மறையான VONB வளர்ச்சியை அடைந்தோம். முதல் பாதியில், கட்டுப்பாடுகள் காரணமாக VONB குறைவாக இருந்தது மற்றும் 2021 இன் முதல் பாதியில் ஒரு சாதனை முடிவைத் தொடர்ந்து, இது முன்னர் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டபடி விதிவிலக்காக உயர்ந்த பாரம்பரிய பாதுகாப்பு விற்பனையால் இயக்கப்பட்டது. எங்களின் உயர்தர பிரீமியர் ஏஜென்சி மாதிரியானது செயலில் உள்ள முகவர் உற்பத்தித்திறன், புதிய ஆட்சேர்ப்பு மற்றும் ஒட்டுமொத்த ஏஜென்சி படை ஆகியவற்றின் வளர்ச்சியுடன் மீள்தன்மையுடன் இருந்தது. எங்கள் செயல்பாடுகள் முழுவதும் கட்டுப்பாடுகள் குறைக்கப்பட்டதால், ஜூலை மாதத்தில் AIA சீனா நேர்மறையான VONB வளர்ச்சியை அடைந்தது.",
        "மெயின்லேண்ட் சீன ஆயுள் காப்பீட்டு சந்தை குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அளவில் ஊடுருவி உள்ளது மற்றும் AIA க்கு மிகப்பெரிய வளர்ச்சி திறனை வழங்குகிறது என்று சியோங் கூறினார். \"புவியியல் விரிவாக்கத்தில் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து வலுவான முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைந்து வருகிறோம், ஹூபே மாகாணத்தின் வுஹானில் உள்ள எங்கள் புதிய கிளை, முதல் பாதியில் விற்பனையைத் தொடங்கியது, எங்கள் புதிய புவியியலில் இருந்து சிறந்த VONB வளர்ச்சிக்கு வலுவான பங்களிப்பை அளித்தது. மே மாதத்தில், சீனாவின் மெயின்லேண்டில் மூன்றாவது அதிக மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட மாகாணமான ஹெனானில் புதிய கிளையைத் தயாரிப்பதற்கான ஒழுங்குமுறை அனுமதியைப் பெற்றோம்.",
        "\"2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதியில், ஏஐஏ ஹாங்காங் VONB இல் 3% வளர்ச்சியை வழங்கியது, ஏஜென்சி மற்றும் கூட்டாண்மை விநியோக சேனல்களின் வளர்ச்சியால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டது. தினசரி நோய்த்தொற்றுகள் குறைந்து வருவதால், எங்கள் உள்நாட்டு வாடிக்கையாளர் பிரிவில் விற்பனை வேகம் மே மாதத்திலிருந்து மீண்டுள்ளது. ஹாங்காங் எல்லையில் பயணம் செய்வது குறைவாக இருந்தாலும், எங்கள் மக்காவ் கிளை மூலம் மெயின்லேண்ட் சீன பார்வையாளர்களுக்கு விற்பனையிலிருந்து வலுவான VONB வளர்ச்சியை வழங்கினோம்.",
        "\"இரண்டாம் காலாண்டில் விற்பனை நடவடிக்கைகளில் முற்போக்கான மேம்பாடுகளுடன் 2022 இன் முதல் பாதியில் மொத்த VONB இல் 50% ஐ மற்ற குழுக்கள் உருவாக்கியுள்ளன. ஜூன் மாதத்தில், எங்களின் சந்தையில் முன்னணியில் இருக்கும் ASEAN வணிகங்கள் VONB இல் மிகவும் வலுவான இரட்டை இலக்க அதிகரிப்புடன் வளர்ச்சிக்குத் திரும்பின.",
        "“இந்தியாவில் எங்களது கூட்டு நிறுவனமான Tata AIA Life, ஆயுள் காப்பீட்டு சந்தையில் கிடைக்கும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வாய்ப்புகளை கைப்பற்றுவதில் சிறந்த நிலையில் உள்ளது. எங்கள் பல சேனல் விநியோக தளத்தின் வெற்றியின் ஆதரவுடன் முதல் பாதியில் சிறந்த VONB வளர்ச்சியை அடைந்தோம். எங்கள் உயர் டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கப்பட்ட பிரீமியர் ஏஜென்சி ஆட்சேர்ப்பு, ஏஜென்சி தலைவர்கள், செயலில் உள்ள முகவர்கள் மற்றும் உற்பத்தித்திறன் ஆகியவற்றில் மிகவும் வலுவான அதிகரிப்பை வழங்கியுள்ளது. நாங்கள் பரந்த அளவிலான வங்கிக் கூட்டாளர்கள் மற்றும் தரகர்களுடன் உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்திக் கொண்டோம், மேலும் எங்கள் கூட்டாண்மை சேனலில் சிறந்த VONB வளர்ச்சியை உருவாக்கினோம்,” என்று சியோங் கூறினார்.",
        "“AIA இன் பரந்த மற்றும் மாறுபட்ட வணிகத்திற்கான நீண்ட கால வாய்ப்புகள் விதிவிலக்காக இருக்கும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன். ஆசியா முழுவதும் AIA இன் புவியியல் பன்முகத்தன்மை மற்றும் எங்கள் நிகரற்ற விநியோக தளம் ஆகியவை முக்கிய பலம். எங்களின் அனைத்து பங்குதாரர்களுக்கும் நீண்டகால நிலையான மதிப்பைத் தொடர்ந்து வழங்கும் எங்களின் மூலோபாய முன்னுரிமைகளை ஒழுக்கமான முறையில் செயல்படுத்துவதில் நாங்கள் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறோம், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1H",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஐஏ குரூப் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீ யுவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமிக்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "OPAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎஃப்எஸ்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20.6 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு LCSM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "277%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "EV ஈக்விட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 72.3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.0 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங் சென்ட்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA இன்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமிக்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ச்சியாக எட்டாவது ஆண்டு சாதனை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு ஆசியாவின் வங்கி, லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷாங்காய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suzhou",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சியோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெயின்லேண்ட் சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வுஹான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூபே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெனான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெயின்லேண்ட் சீனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெயின்லேண்ட் சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்காவ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "VONB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}