{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඉන්ධන-කිව්-ආර්--කේතයට-බාලගිරි-දෝෂය/1-617000",
  "time_ut": 1658737832,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන කිව්.ආර්. කේතයට බාලගිරි දෝෂය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel Q.R. Balagiri error to code",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Q.R. related to the 'National Fuel Licence' implemented by the Ministry of Energy. Power and Energy Minister Mr. Kanchana Wijesekera says that the implementation of the code has been postponed until the 1st of August.",
        "From the 1st of August, Q.R. Fuel will be released according to the code and the last digit of the number plate and the National Youth Corps, National Youth Council members and volunteers will report to Q.R. in the next 10 days. The minister also said that he supports the implementation of the code system at petrol stations.",
        "Energy Minister Mr. Kanchana Wijesekera has said on several occasions that this program will be implemented covering the entire country from a few weeks but it has not been implemented till now and the minister lastly said that it will be implemented from today (25)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Fuel Q.R. Balagiri",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Q.R.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 1st of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q.R. Fuel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Youth Corps",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Youth Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q.R.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන කිව්.ආර්. කේතයට බාලගිරි දෝෂය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යංශය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ‘ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍ර’යට අදාල කිව්.ආර්. කේතය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම ලබන අගෝස්තු මස 1 වැනිදා දක්වා කල්දමා ඇති බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු මස 1 වැනිදා සිට කිව්.ආර්. කේතය සහ අංක තහඩුවේ අවසාන ඉලක්කම අනුව ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන බවත් ජාතික යොවුන් සේනාංක, ජාතික තරුණ සභාවේ සාමාජිකයින් සහ ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන් ඉදිරි දින 10 තුළ කිව්.ආර්. කේත ක්‍රමය ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වල ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහයෝගය දක්වන බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා මෙම වැඩසටහන සති කීපයක සිට සමස්ත රටම ආවරණය වන පරිදි ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බවට අවස්ථා කීපයකදී පැවසුව ද මේ දක්වා ක්‍රියාත්මක නොවූ අතර අමාත්‍යවරයා අවසන් වරට පැවසුවේ අද (25) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්ධන Q.R. බාලගිරි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Q.R.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 1 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 1 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q.R. ඉන්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික යොවුන් සේනාංකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික තරුණ සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q.R.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் Q.R. குறியீட்டில் பாலகிரி பிழை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சகாருவின் வீட்டிற்கு முன்னால் நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் எரிபொருளை திருடும்போது சந்தேக நபருடன் ஏற்பட்ட வாக்குவாதம் முற்றி இந்த கொலை இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 1 ஆம் தேதி முதல், கே.ஆர். எண் தகட்டின் குறியீடு மற்றும் கடைசி இலக்கத்தின் படி எரிபொருள் வெளியிடப்படும் மற்றும் தேசிய இளைஞர் படை, தேசிய இளைஞர் பேரவை உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் தன்னார்வலர்கள் அடுத்த 10 நாட்களில் Q.R. எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் குறியீட்டு முறையை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "சில வாரங்களில் முழு நாட்டையும் உள்ளடக்கிய வகையில் இந்த வேலைத்திட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் திரு.காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர பல தடவைகள் தெரிவித்திருந்தும் இது வரை அமுல்படுத்தப்படவில்லை எனவும் இறுதியாக இன்று (25) முதல் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் எனவும் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எரிபொருள் Q.R. பாலகிரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கே.ஆர்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.ஆர். எரிபொருள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய இளைஞர் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய இளைஞர் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.ஆர்.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}