{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130209",
  "time_ut": 1656249546,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "எச்சரிக்கையும் எதிர்வினையும்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Warning and reaction",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"How many Buddhist clergy in Sri Lanka follow Buddhist doctrines and doctrines?\"",
        "\"When Minister Prasanna Ranatunga told parliament that Sarath Weerasekara, who was angry over the Kurundur hill issue, had set his house on fire by a Buddhist cleric, why could he not speak out against it?\"",
        "\"The country is experiencing the consequences of inciting violence, racism and hostility not only against Tamils ​​but also against Muslims by Buddhist monks and Sinhala Buddhists.\"",
        "PA MP Sarath Weerasekara's speech in parliament has provoked strong reactions from Tamils.",
        "He accused the TNA of making derogatory remarks about Buddhist clergy and Buddhist teachings.",
        "He also warned the Buddhists not to test their patience and that there was a limit to the patience of Sinhala Buddhists.",
        "His speech reveals that he is outraged that an attempt to place a Buddha statue outside a court order on Kurundur Hill has been thwarted by a protest by the Tamil people.",
        "When did Buddhists and most Buddhist clergy maintain patience? How many Buddhist clergymen in Sri Lanka follow Buddhist principles and doctrines?",
        "Had the Buddhist principles of Sri Lanka been fully followed and supported by the Buddhist clergy, the country would not have been plunged into such catastrophe.",
        "When Minister Prasanna Ranatunga said in Parliament a few days ago that it was the Buddhist clergy who played a key role in the May 9 violence and that it was the Buddhist clergy who came from the temples in the villages and set the house on fire, why was Sarath Weerasekara unable to speak out against it?",
        "But it was the Buddhist monks who used Buddhism for Sinhala chauvinist interests that brought about the demise of Buddhism as a whole, not just the Buddhist monks as a whole.",
        "Sarath Weerasekara has said that the Buddhist people are not harming the ordinary Tamil people.",
        "It was the genocide, ethnic oppression, land grabbing and violence unleashed against the Tamils ​​over time that prompted the Tamils ​​to fight for secession.",
        "Buddhist monks who incited violence against Tamils ​​are still inciting it.",
        "Today, the country is experiencing the consequences of inciting violence, racial hatred and animosity not only against Tamils ​​but also against Muslims by Buddhist monks and Sinhala Buddhists.",
        "A few days ago, Latif Barouk wrote an article in an English-language newspaper that highlights the interests of Sinhala-Buddhist chauvinism, entitled \"Sri Lanka's racist politics has tarnished the image of the Middle East.\"",
        "It stated that \"Sri Lanka's centuries-old historical relations with the Middle East have suffered a setback due to the island's racist politics, hostility to Islam and Muslims and narrow-minded policies.\"",
        "It is the dirty policies pursued by people like Sarath Weerasekara to come to power and retain it after coming, that have isolated the country internationally and plunged it into an irreversible crisis.",
        "Chairman of the Valpola Rahula Institute for Buddhist Studies, Vana. In an interview with an English daily a few weeks ago, Thero Kalkande Dhammananda described how the present government and previous governments have used Sinhala-Buddhist ideology to their advantage.",
        "“This time it was used dangerously against the Muslim community. They portrayed Muslims as a threat and tried to unite Sinhala-Buddhists and other ethnic groups.",
        "This government has used the Sinhala Buddhist armor for maximum benefit, ”he said. No one can forget that the Kota-Mahinda government used Sinhala Buddhist ideology for their own benefit.",
        "Mahinda Rajapaksa and Gotabhaya Rajapaksa built their politics from the temples. Those same temples stand against them today.",
        "In the 2019 presidential election, Sinhala Buddhists rallied together and everyone knows what is going on under the rule of the elected president.",
        "Even after realizing the dire consequences of a pure Sinhala-Buddhist government or president, people like Sarath Weerasekara have not lost their Sinhala-Buddhist chauvinist ideology.",
        "What have the Tamils ​​done to test the patience of the Sinhala Buddhists? Were the lands of Sinhala Buddhists confiscated? Did they demolish and seize the temples? Did you chase them away?",
        "But what is going on in Kurundur hill and Vedukunarimalai. The traditional historical places of worship of the Tamils ​​are being demolished and temples are being built.",
        "Tamils ​​are being driven out of their native agricultural lands. Their lands are being expropriated. Even after this, Tamils ​​are not raging.",
        "People like Sarath Weerasekara, who warns that there is a limit to the patience of Sinhala Buddhists, are not unaware that Sinhala Buddhists are going beyond the limits of Tamil tolerance.",
        "They have been promoting it themselves. The country is in ruins today because of the rise of Sinhala-Buddhist nationalism and chauvinism.",
        "The country is facing maximum trials today because it did not know how to coexist with other races and did not allow others to do so.",
        "Even after this, if people like Sarath Fonseka try to cool down by pitting Sinhala Buddhists against Tamils ​​and Muslims, they will end up in the fire."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamils ​​but",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamils",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhists",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurundur Hill",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhists",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamils",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamils ​​are",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamils ​​but",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latif",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-Buddhist",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islam",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Valpola Rahula Institute for Buddhist Studies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thero Kalkande Dhammananda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhist",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vedukunarimalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhists",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Buddhists against Tamils ​​and Muslims",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අනතුරු ඇඟවීම සහ ප්රතික්රියාව",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"ලංකාවේ බෞද්ධ පූජ්‍යවරු කී දෙනෙක් බෞද්ධ ධර්මයන් සහ ධර්මයන් අනුගමනය කරනවාද?\"",
        "\"කුරුඳුර් කඳුකරයේ ප්‍රශ්නය නිසා උරණ වූ සරත් වීරසේකර බෞද්ධ පූජකවරයකු විසින් තම නිවසට ගිනි තැබූ බව ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග අමාත්‍යවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළ විට ඔහුට ඊට එරෙහිව හඬක් නැගීමට නොහැකි වූයේ මන්ද?\"",
        "\"දෙමළ ජනයාට පමණක් නොව මුස්ලිම්වරුන්ට එරෙහිව බෞද්ධ භික්ෂූන් සහ සිංහල බෞද්ධයන් විසින් ද ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය, ජාතිවාදය සහ සතුරුකම අවුලුවාලීමේ ප්‍රතිවිපාක රට අත්විඳිමින් සිටී.\"",
        "පොදු පෙරමුණු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සරත් වීරසේකර මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කළ කතාව දෙමළ ජනතාවගෙන් දැඩි ප්‍රතිචාරවලට තුඩු දී තිබේ.",
        "බෞද්ධ පූජකවරුන් සහ බෞද්ධ ඉගැන්වීම් පිළිබඳව දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශ සිදු කරන බවට ඔහු චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම ඉවසීම පරීක්‍ෂා නොකරන ලෙසත්, සිංහල බෞද්ධයාගේ ඉවසීමේ සීමාවක් තිබෙන බවත් බෞද්ධයන්ට අවවාද කළේය.",
        "කුරුඳුර් කන්දේ අධිකරණ නියෝගයකට පිටින් බුද්ධ ප්‍රතිමාවක් තැබීමට ගත් උත්සාහයක් දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ විරෝධතාවයකින් ව්‍යර්ථ වීම ගැන ඔහු දැඩි කෝපයට පත්ව සිටින බව ඔහුගේ කතාවෙන් හෙළිවේ.",
        "බෞද්ධයන් සහ බොහෝ බෞද්ධ පූජකවරුන් ඉවසීම පවත්වාගත්තේ කවදාද? ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බෞද්ධ පූජකවරු කී දෙනෙක් බෞද්ධ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ප්‍රතිපත්ති අනුගමනය කරනවාද?",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බෞද්ධ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්පූර්ණයෙන් පිළිපැද්දා නම් සහ බෞද්ධ පූජ්‍ය පක්‍ෂයේ අනුග්‍රහය ලැබුවේ නම් රට මෙවන් ව්‍යසනයකට ඇද වැටෙන්නේ නැත.",
        "මැයි 9 ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළේ බෞද්ධ හාමුදුරුවරුන් බවත්, ගම්වල පන්සල්වලින් පැමිණ ගේ ගිනිබත් කළේ බෞද්ධ හාමුදුරුවරු බවත් අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා දින කිහිපයකට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඇයි? සරත් වීරසේකරට ඒකට විරුද්ධව කතා කරන්න බැරි වුණාද?",
        "නමුත් බෞද්ධ භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේලා පමණක් නොව සමස්තයක් ලෙස බුද්ධාගමේ විනාශය ගෙනාවේ සිංහල ස්වෝත්තමවාදී අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා බුදුදහම භාවිතා කළ බෞද්ධ භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේලාය.",
        "බෞද්ධ ජනතාව සාමාන්‍ය දෙමළ ජනතාවට හානියක් නොවන බව සරත් වීරසේකර මහතා පවසා තිබේ.",
        "කාලයත් සමඟ දෙමළ ජනයාට එරෙහිව මුදා හරින ලද ජන සංහාරය, වාර්ගික පීඩනය, ඉඩම් කොල්ලය සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය දෙමළ ජනයා වෙන්වීම සඳහා සටන් කිරීමට පෙළඹවූයේ ය.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහිව ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය ඇති කළ බෞද්ධ භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේලා තවමත් එය අවුස්සනවා.",
        "දෙමළ ජනයාට පමණක් නොව මුස්ලිම්වරුන්ට එරෙහිව බෞද්ධ භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේලා සහ සිංහල බෞද්ධයන් විසින් ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය, වාර්ගික වෛරය සහ වෛරය අවුලුවාලීමේ ප්‍රතිවිපාක අද රට අත්විඳිමින් සිටී.",
        "ලතීෆ් බාරුක් දින කිහිපයකට පෙර ඉංග්‍රීසි පුවත්පතකට \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතිවාදී දේශපාලනය මැදපෙරදිග ප්‍රතිරූපය කෙළෙසා ඇත\" යන මැයෙන් සිංහල-බෞද්ධ ස්වෝත්තමවාදයේ අවශ්‍යතා ඉස්මතු කරන ලිපියක් ලිවීය.",
        "එහි සඳහන් වූයේ \"දිවයිනේ ජාතිවාදී දේශපාලනය, ඉස්ලාම් ආගමට සහ මුස්ලිම්වරුන්ට එරෙහි වෛරය සහ පටු අදහස් සහිත ප්‍රතිපත්ති හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මැදපෙරදිග සමග ශතවර්ෂ ගණනාවක් පැරණි ඓතිහාසික සබඳතා පසුබෑමකට ලක්ව ඇති බවයි.\"",
        "සරත් වීරසේකර වැන්නවුන් බලයට පැමිණ බලයට පැමිණි පසු එය රඳවා ගැනීමට අනුගමනය කරන ජරා ප්‍රතිපත්ති තමයි ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් රට හුදකලා කර ආපසු හැරවිය නොහැකි අර්බුදයකට ඇද දමා තිබෙන්නේ.",
        "වල්පොල රාහුල බෞද්ධ අධ්‍යයන ආයතනයේ සභාපති වනවා. දැනට සති කිහිපයකට පෙර ඉංග්‍රීසි දිනපතා පුවත්පතක් සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් කල්කන්දේ ධම්මානන්ද හිමියෝ වත්මන් රජය සහ පසුගිය රජයන් සිංහල බෞද්ධ මතවාදය තම වාසියට යොදාගත් ආකාරය විස්තර කළහ.",
        "“මෙවර එය මුස්ලිම් ප්‍රජාවට එරෙහිව අනතුරුදායක ලෙස භාවිතා කරන ලදී. ඔවුන් මුස්ලිම්වරුන් තර්ජනයක් ලෙස පෙන්වා සිංහල-බෞද්ධ සහ අනෙකුත් ජනවර්ග එක් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළහ.",
        "මේ ආණ්ඩුව සිංහල බෞද්ධ සන්නාහය උපරිම ප්‍රයෝජනයට යොදාගෙන තිබෙනවා. කොටා-මහින්ද ආණ්ඩුව සිංහල බෞද්ධ මතවාදය තම වාසියට යොදාගත් බව කාටවත් අමතක කළ නොහැක.",
        "මහින්ද රාජපක්‍ෂ සහ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ තමන්ගේ දේශපාලනය ගොඩනගා ගත්තේ පන්සල්වලින්. ඒ පන්සල් තමයි අද ඔවුන්ට විරුද්ධව නැගී සිටින්නේ.",
        "2019 ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී සිංහල බෞද්ධයන් එකට පෙළ ගැසුණු අතර තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පාලනය යටතේ සිදුවන්නේ කුමක්ද යන්න කවුරුත් දනිති.",
        "නිර්මල සිංහල-බෞද්ධ ආණ්ඩුවක හෝ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ භයානක ප්‍රතිවිපාක තේරුම් ගැනීමෙන් පසුව වුවද, සරත් වීරසේකර වැනි අයගේ සිංහල-බෞද්ධ ස්වෝත්තමවාදී මතවාදය නැති වී නැත.",
        "සිංහල බෞද්ධයන්ගේ ඉවසීම උරගා බැලීමට දෙමළා කුමක් කර ඇත්ද? සිංහල බෞද්ධයන්ගේ ඉඩම් රාජසන්තක කළාද? පන්සල් කඩලා අල්ලගත්තද? ඔබ ඔවුන්ව එළවා දැමුවාද?",
        "නමුත් කුරුඳුර් කන්දේ සහ වෙඩුකුනරිමලෙයි මොකද වෙන්නේ. දෙමළ ජනයාගේ පාරම්පරික ඓතිහාසික සිද්ධස්ථාන කඩා බිඳ දමා පන්සල් ඉදිවෙමින් පවතී.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව ඔවුන්ගේ නිජබිම් කෘෂිකාර්මික ඉඩම්වලින් පන්නා දමනු ලැබේ. ඔවුන්ගේ ඉඩම් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් බලහත්කාරයෙන් අත්පත් කර ගනිමින් සිටී. මේකෙන් පස්සෙත් දෙමල මිනිස්සු තරහා නෑ.",
        "සිංහල බෞද්ධයාගේ ඉවසීමේ සීමාවක් ඇතැයි අනතුරු අඟවන සරත් වීරසේකර වැනි අය සිංහල බෞද්ධයන් දෙමළ ඉවසීමේ සීමාවෙන් ඔබ්බට යන බව නොදන්නවා නොවේ.",
        "ඔවුන් විසින්ම එය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කර ඇත. සිංහල-බෞද්ධ ජාතිකවාදය සහ ස්වෝත්තමවාදය හිස ඔසවමින් අද රට විනාශ වී ඇත.",
        "රට අද උපරිම පරීක්‍ෂණවලට මුහුණ දී සිටින්නේ වෙනත් ජාතීන් සමඟ සහජීවනයෙන් ජීවත් වීමට නොදැන සිටි නිසාත්, එසේ වීමට ඉඩ නොදුන් නිසාත් ය.",
        "මේකෙන් පස්සෙත් සරත් ෆොන්සේකා වැන්නන් සිංහල බෞද්ධයන් දෙමළ හා මුස්ලිම් ජනතාව අතරට පටවා සිසිල් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළහොත් ඔවුන් අවසන් වන්නේ ගින්නටය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ නමුත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධයෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ අය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධයෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුර් කන්ද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ අය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ අය තමයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ නමුත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධයෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතීෆ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල-බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වල්පොල රාහුල බෞද්ධ අධ්‍යයන ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වානා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්කන්දේ ධම්මානන්ද හිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල-බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධයෝ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල-බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල-බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධයෝ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙඩුකුනරිමලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල බෞද්ධයෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල-බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ සහ මුස්ලිම් ජනතාවට එරෙහිව සිංහල බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எச்சரிக்கையும் எதிர்வினையும்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "“இலங்கையில் உள்ள பௌத்த மதகுருமாரில் எத்தனை பேர் பௌத்த மத தத்துவங்களையும், கோட்பாடுகளையும் பின்பற்றுகிறார்கள்?”",
        "“குருந்தூர் மலை விடயத்திற்காக கொதித்தெழுந்த  சரத் வீரசேகர தனது வீட்டைக் கொளுத்தியது பௌத்த மதகுரு தான் என்றும் அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கூறிய போது,  ஏன் அதற்கெதிராக குரல் கொடுக்க முடியாமல் போனது?”",
        "“தமிழர்களுக்கு எதிராக மாத்திரமன்றி முஸ்லிம்களுக்கு எதிரான வன்முறைகளையும், இன விரோதங்களையும், குரோதங்களையும் பௌத்த பிக்குகளும், சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களும் தூண்டி விட்டதன் விளைவை நாடு அனுபவித்துக் கொண்டிருக்கிறது”",
        "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சரத் வீரசேகர, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிகழ்த்திய உரை, தமிழர் தரப்பில் கடும் எதிர்வினைகளுக்கு காரணமாகியிருக்கிறது.",
        "தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு பௌத்த மதகுருமார்களையும், பௌத்த போதனைகளையும், அவமதிக்கும் கருத்துக்களை வெளியிடுவதாக அவர், குற்றம்சாட்டியிருந்தார்.",
        "அத்துடன், பௌத்தர்களின் பொறுமையை சோதிக்க வேண்டாம், சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களின் பொறுமைக்கு எல்லையுள்ளது என்றும் எச்சரித்திருந்தார்.",
        "குருந்தூர் மலையில் நீதிமன்றக் கட்டளைக்குப் புறம்பாக புத்தர் சிலையை வைக்கும் முயற்சி, தமிழ் மக்கள் நடத்திய போராட்டத்தினால், தடுத்து நிறுத்தப்பட்டதால் அவர் ஆத்திரம் கொண்டுள்ளார் என்பதை, அவரது பேச்சு வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "பௌத்தர்களும், பெரும்பாலான பௌத்த மதகுருமாரும் எப்போது பொறுமையைக் கடைப்பிடித்திருக்கிறார்கள்? இலங்கையில் உள்ள பௌத்த மதகுருமாரில் எத்தனை பேர் பௌத்த மத தத்துவங்களையும், கோட்பாடுகளையும் பின்பற்றுகிறார்கள்?",
        "இலங்கையின் பௌத்த மத கோட்பாடுகள் முழுமையாக பின்பற்றப்பட்டிருந்தால், அதற்கு பௌத்த மதகுருமார் உறுதுணையாக இருந்திருந்தால், நாடு இந்தளவுக்குப் பேரழிவுக்குள் தள்ளப்பட்டிருக்காது.",
        "பௌத்த மதகுருமார் தான் மே 9 வன்முறைகளில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகித்தனர் என்றும், கிராமங்களில் உள்ள விகாரைகளில் இருந்து வந்து வன்முறைகளில் ஈடுபட்டனர் என்றும் தனது வீட்டைக் கொளுத்தியது பௌத்த மதகுரு தான் என்றும் அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்னதாக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கூறிய போது,  சரத் வீரசேகர ஏன் அதற்கெதிராக குரல் கொடுக்க முடியாமல் போனது?",
        "ஆனால், பௌத்த மதத்தை, சிங்கள பேரினவாத நலன்களுக்காக பயன்படுத்தும் பௌத்த பிக்குகளால் தான், ஒட்டுமொத்த பௌத்த மதமும், பௌத்த பிக்குகளும், மட்டுமன்றி நாடே தலைகுனியும் நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "பௌத்த மக்கள் சாதாரண தமிழ் மக்களுக்கு தீங்கிழைக்கவில்லை என்று சரத் வீரசேகர கூறியிருக்கிறார்.",
        "தமிழர்களுக்கு எதிராக காலம் காலமாக கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்ட இனக்கலவரங்களும், இன ஒடுக்குமுறைகளும், நில ஆக்கிரமிப்புகளும், வன்முறைகளும் தான், தமிழர்களை தனிநாடு கோரிப் போராடத் தூண்டியது.",
        "தமிழர்களுக்கு எதிராக வன்முறைகளைத் தூண்டிய பௌத்த பிக்குகள், இன்னமும் அதனை தூண்டிவிட்டுக் கொண்டே இருக்கின்றனர்.",
        "தமிழர்களுக்கு எதிராக மாத்திரமன்றி முஸ்லிம்களுக்கு எதிரான வன்முறைகளையும், இன விரோதங்களையும், குரோதங்களையும் பௌத்த பிக்குகளும், சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களும் தூண்டி விட்டதன் விளைவை நாடு இன்று அனுபவித்துக் கொண்டிருக்கிறது.",
        "சிங்கள பௌத்த பேரினவாத நலன்களை அதிகளவில் வெளிப்படுத்தும் ஆங்கில நாளிதழ் ஒன்றில் சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்னர், லதீப் பாருக் என்பவர் “இலங்கையின் இனவாத அரசியல், மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளின் நன்மதிப்பை இழந்துள்ளது” என்ற தலைப்பில் ஒரு கட்டுரை  எழுதியிருந்தார்.",
        "அதில், “ இலங்கைத் தீவின் இனவாத அரசியல், இஸ்லாம் மற்றும் முஸ்லிம்கள் மீதான குரோதம் மற்றும் குறுகிய நோக்குடைய கொள்கைகள் காரணமாக, மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளுடனான இலங்கையின் நூற்றாண்டுகள் பழமையான வரலாற்று உறவுகள் பின்னடைவைச் சந்தித்துள்ளன” என்று குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சரத் வீரசேகர போன்றவர்கள் அதிகாரத்துக்கு வருவதற்காகவும், வந்த பின்னர் அதனை தக்கவைத்துக் கொள்வதற்காகவும், கையாண்ட மலினத்தனமான கொள்கைகள் தான், சர்வதேச அளவிலும் நாட்டை தனிமைப்படுத்தி, மீள முடியாத நெருக்கடிகளுக்குள்ளேயும் சிக்க வைத்திருக்கிறது.",
        "பௌத்த கற்கைகளுக்கான வல்பொல ராகுல நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவராக உள்ள, வண. கல்கண்டே தம்மானந்த தேரர், ஆங்கில நாளிதழ் ஒன்றுக்கு சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் அளித்த செவ்வி ஒன்றில், தற்போதைய அரசாங்கமும், அதற்கு முந்திய அரசாங்கங்களும், சிங்கள-பௌத்த சித்தாந்தத்தை எவ்வாறு தங்களின் நலன்களுக்காக பயன்படுத்திக் கொண்டன என்று விபரித்திருந்தார்.",
        "“இம்முறை ஆபத்தான முறையில் முஸ்லிம் சமூகத்திற்கு எதிராக பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டது.  அவர்கள் முஸ்லிம்களை அச்சுறுத்தலாக சித்தரித்து, சிங்கள-பௌத்தர்களை ஒன்றாகவும், ஏனைய இனத்தவர்களை எதிரிகளாகவும் ஆக்க முயன்றனர்.",
        "இந்த அரசாங்கம் சிங்கள பௌத்த கவசத்தை அதிகபட்ச நன்மைக்காக பயன்படுத்தியது” என்று, அவர் குறிப்பிட்டிருக்கிறார். கோட்டா- மஹிந்த அரசாங்கம் சிங்கள பௌத்த சித்தாந்தத்தை, தங்களின் நலன்களுக்காக பயன்படுத்தியதை, எவரும் மறந்து விட முடியாது.",
        "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவும், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவும் விகாரைகளில் இருந்து தான், தங்களின் அரசியலை கட்டியெழுப்பினார்கள். அந்த விகாரைகளே இன்று அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக திரும்பி நிற்கின்றன.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில், சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள் ஒன்றாகத் திரண்டு, தெரிவு செய்த ஜனாதிபதியின் ஆட்சியில் என்ன நடந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறது என்பது அனைவருக்கும் தெரிந்த ஒன்று.",
        "தூய சிங்கள பௌத்த அரசாங்கம் அல்லது ஜனாதிபதி என்பது எந்தளவுக்கு ஆபத்தான விளைவுகளை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது என்பதைத் கண்டுணர்ந்த பின்னரும், சரத் வீரசேகர போன்றவர்களுக்கு சிங்கள பௌத்த பேரினவாத சிந்தனைகள் வற்றவில்லை.",
        "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களின் பொறுமையை சோதிக்கும் அளவுக்கு, தமிழர்கள் என்ன செய்து விட்டார்கள்? சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களின் நிலங்களை அபகரித்தனரா? விகாரைகளை இடித்து கைப்பற்றினார்களா?  அவர்களை விரட்டி அடித்தார்களா?",
        "ஆனால், குருந்தூர் மலையிலும் வெடுக்குநாறிமலையிலும் என்ன நடந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறது. தமிழரின் பாரம்பரிய வரலாற்று வழிபாட்டு இடங்கள் இடித்து அழிக்கப்பட்டு விகாரைகள் கட்டியெழுப்ப்ப்படுகின்றன.",
        "பூர்வீக விவசாய நிலங்களில் இருந்து தமிழர்கள் விரட்டப்படுகின்றனர். அவர்களின் காணிகள் அபகரிக்கப்படுகின்றன. இந்தளவுக்குப் பின்னரும் தமிழர்கள் பொங்கியெழாமல் இருக்கிறார்கள்.",
        "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களின் பொறுமைக்கும் எல்லையுண்டு என்று எச்சரிக்கும் சரத் வீரசேகர போன்றவர்கள், தமிழரின் பொறுமையின் எல்லையை தாண்டி, சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள் நடந்து கொள்வது தெரியாமல் இல்லை.",
        "அதனை அவர்களே ஊக்குவித்தும் வந்தனர். சிங்கள பௌத்த தேசியவாதம், பேரினவாதம் என்பனை தலைதூக்கியதால் தான், நாடு இன்று நாசமாகிப் போயிருக்கிறது.",
        "பிற இனங்களுடன் இணைந்து, பிணைந்து வாழத் தெரியாத, ஏனையவர்களை அவ்வாறு வாழ அனுமதிக்காதவர்களாக இருந்ததால் தான், நாடு இன்று அதிகபட்ச சோதனைகளை சந்தித்துக் கொண்டிருக்கிறது.",
        "இதற்குப் பின்னரும் சரத் பொன்சேகா போன்றவர்கள், தமிழ், முஸ்லிம்களுக்கு எதிராக சிங்கள பௌத்தர்களை மோதவிட்டு குளிர் காய முயன்றால், அந்த தீக்குள் அவர்களே பொசுங்கிப் போகின்ற நிலை தான் ஏற்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்கள் ஆனால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகரவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருந்தூர் மலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்கள் தான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்கள் ஆனால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லத்தீஃப்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள-பௌத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த ஆய்வுகளுக்கான வல்பொல ராகுல நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கண்டே தம்மானந்தா தேரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள-பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள-பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள-பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெடுக்குநரிமலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள-பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்களுக்கும் முஸ்லிம்களுக்கும் எதிரான சிங்கள பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}