{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Morison-begins-local-production-of-three-high-in-demand-medicines/273-243757",
  "time_ut": 1661466104,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Morison begins local production of three high-in-demand medicines",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Morison begins local production of three high-in-demand medicines",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Marking milestone in the local pharmaceutical industry, Hemas Group subsidiary Morison Ltd recently commenced manufacturing of Bisoprolol tablets B.P. 5mg 250s, Ros-10 (Rosuvastatin tablets I.P. 10mg 30s blister),and ChlorMor (Chlorphenamine tablets B.P. 4mg 100s blister).",
        "These high-in-demand medicines are now more affordable and accessible to Sri Lankans, the supply of which does not have to depend on imports.",
        "For the first time in Sri Lanka, Bisoprolol 5 mg tablets are now being manufactured locally by Morison and supplied to the Medical Supplies Division for the use in government hospitals. Used as a treatment for high blood pressure and other cardiovascular conditions, the annual requirement of Bisoprolol in the government sector is around 40 million tablets, which was being imported to-date.",
        "By producing the same locally, Morison is able to make a significant forex saving for the national economy during these unprecedented times. Plans are underway to make Bisoprolol B.P. 2.5mg and 5 mg available in all leading pharmacies as a branded medication in due course, to enable purchasing through a valid prescription.",
        "The second new product launched, Ros-10 (Rosuvastatin tablets I.P. 10mg 30s blister) is used to treat high blood cholesterol, a risk factor for cardiovascular disease. Morison launched Ros-10at approximately half of the current weighted average market price, offering significant savings to Sri Lankans.",
        "The third latest addition to the Morison portfolio, ChlorMor (Chlorphenamine tablets B.P. 4mg 100s blister) is an oral antihistamine that helps to relieve symptoms of allergies. This too was launched at a price less than the prevailing similar products in the market.",
        "“This indeed is a key milestone for Morison as well as the pharmaceutical manufacturing industry in the country. We commenced operations of our latest state-of-the-art manufacturing and research facility in Homagama in May this year, which is the largest investment to-date in the pharmaceutical manufacturing industry in Sri Lanka. This will be a great boost for the pharmaceutical supply of the country during this crucial hour,” Morison Limited Managing Director Dinesh Athapaththu said.",
        "Being the first and largest general oral solid dosage (OSD) and oral liquid dosage (OLD) manufacturing facility in compliance with WHO GMP and EU GMP infrastructure and quality management systems in Sri Lanka, the Morison’s second manufacturing facility in Homagama, has the inbuilt capacity to produce 5 billion tablets and 2 million litres of liquids per annum, which is equivalent to 40 percent of the national annual general OSD demand in Sri Lanka.",
        "Prior to introducing Ros-10, Bisoprolol and ChlorMor, Morison launched the first ever locally manufactured SGLT2 molecule (Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2), Empagliflozin tablets 10mg and 25mg in 2021. An oral medication to treat Type 2 diabetes, this was launched at approximately 50 percent price advantage from the market."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Morison",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hemas Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morison Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "B.P. 5mg",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ros-10",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rosuvastatin",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "I.P. 10",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ChlorMor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chlorphenamine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "B.P. 4mg 100s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Medical Supplies Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 40 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Morison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bisoprolol B.P.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ros-10",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rosuvastatin",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "I.P. 10",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morison",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ChlorMor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chlorphenamine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "B.P. 4mg 100s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Morison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this crucial hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Athapaththu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "OSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "OSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ChlorMor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SGLT2",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Empagliflozin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මොරිසන් ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමක් ඇති ඖෂධ තුනක දේශීය නිෂ්පාදනය ආරම්භ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශීය ඖෂධ කර්මාන්තයේ සන්ධිස්ථානයක් සනිටුහන් කරමින් හේමාස් සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ අනුබද්ධ මොරිසන් ලිමිටඩ් විසින් Bisoprolol පෙති නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීම පසුගියදා ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. 5mg 250s, Ros-10 (Rosuvastatin tablets I.P. 10mg 30s blister), සහ ChlorMor (Chlorphenamine tablets B.P. 4mg 100s blister).",
        "මෙම ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමක් ඇති ඖෂධ දැන් වඩාත් දැරිය හැකි මිලකට සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට ප්‍රවේශ විය හැකි අතර, ඒවායේ සැපයුම ආනයනය මත යැපෙන්නට අවශ්‍ය නොවේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම වතාවට Bisoprolol 5 mg පෙති දැන් Morison සමාගම විසින් දේශීයව නිෂ්පාදනය කර රජයේ රෝහල්වල භාවිතය සඳහා වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් අංශය වෙත සපයනු ලැබේ. අධි රුධිර පීඩනය සහ අනෙකුත් හෘද වාහිනී තත්වයන් සඳහා ප්‍රතිකාරයක් ලෙස භාවිතා කරන අතර, රජයේ අංශයේ වාර්ෂික Bisoprolol අවශ්‍යතාවය පෙති මිලියන 40 ක් පමණ වන අතර එය මේ දක්වා ආනයනය කෙරේ.",
        "එයම දේශීයව නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමෙන්, මෙම පෙර නොවූ විරූ කාලවලදී ජාතික ආර්ථිකය සඳහා සැලකිය යුතු විදේශ විනිමය ඉතිරියක් කිරීමට මොරිසන්ට හැකි වේ. Bisoprolol B.P බවට පත් කිරීමට සැලසුම් කරමින් පවතී. 2.5mg සහ 5 mg වලංගු බෙහෙත් වට්ටෝරුවක් හරහා මිලදී ගැනීම සක්‍රීය කිරීම සඳහා සියලුම ප්‍රමුඛ ඔසුසැල් වල සන්නාමගත ඖෂධයක් ලෙස නියමිත වේලාවට ලබා ගත හැකිය.",
        "දියත් කරන ලද දෙවන නව නිෂ්පාදනය වන Ros-10 (Rosuvastatin tablets I.P. 10mg 30s blister) හෘද වාහිනී රෝග සඳහා අවදානම් සාධකයක් වන අධි රුධිර කොලෙස්ටරෝල් වලට ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීමට භාවිතා කරයි. මොරිසන් විසින් Ros-10 දියත් කරන ලද්දේ වර්තමාන සාමාන්‍ය වෙළඳපල මිලෙන් අඩක් පමණ වන අතර, ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට සැලකිය යුතු ඉතිරියක් ලබාදෙයි.",
        "Morison portfolio සඳහා තුන්වන නවතම එකතු කිරීම වන ChlorMor (Chlorphenamine tablets B.P. 4mg 100s blister) යනු අසාත්මිකතාවන්ගේ රෝග ලක්ෂණ සමනය කිරීමට උපකාරී වන මුඛ ප්‍රතිහිස්ටමින් වර්ගයකි. මෙයද වෙළඳපොලේ පවතින සමාන නිෂ්පාදන වලට වඩා අඩු මිලකට දියත් කරන ලදී.",
        "“මෙය ඇත්තෙන්ම මොරිසන් සමාගමට මෙන්ම මෙරට ඖෂධ නිෂ්පාදන කර්මාන්තයට ද ප්‍රධාන සන්ධිස්ථානයකි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඖෂධ නිෂ්පාදන කර්මාන්තයේ මේ දක්වා විශාලතම ආයෝජනය වන හෝමාගම ප්‍රදේශයේ අපගේ නවතම නවීනතම නිෂ්පාදන හා පර්යේෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ මෙහෙයුම් අපි මේ වසරේ මැයි මාසයේදී ආරම්භ කළෙමු. මෙම තීරණාත්මක පැයේදී රටේ ඖෂධ සැපයුම සඳහා මෙය විශාල රුකුලක් වනු ඇත,” මොරිසන් ලිමිටඩ් කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ දිනේෂ් අතපත්තු මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ WHO GMP සහ EU GMP යටිතල පහසුකම් සහ තත්ත්ව කළමනාකරණ පද්ධතිවලට අනුකූලව ප්‍රථම සහ විශාලතම සාමාන්‍ය මුඛ ඝන මාත්‍රාව (OSD) සහ මුඛ ද්‍රව මාත්‍රාව (OLD) නිෂ්පාදන පහසුකම වීම, හෝමාගම Morison හි දෙවන නිෂ්පාදන මධ්‍යස්ථානය වන අතර ඉන්බිල්ට් ධාරිතාව ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික වාර්ෂික සාමාන්‍ය OSD ඉල්ලුමෙන් සියයට 40 ට සමාන වසරකට ටැබ්ලට් බිලියන 5ක් සහ දියර ලීටර් මිලියන 2ක් නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට.",
        "Ros-10, Bisoprolol සහ ChlorMor හඳුන්වා දීමට පෙර, Morison විසින් 2021 දී ප්‍රථම වරට දේශීයව නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලද SGLT2 අණුව (Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2), Empagliflozin පෙති 10mg සහ 25mg දියත් කරන ලදී. මෙය දියවැඩියා රෝගයට ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම සඳහා මුඛ ඖෂධයක් දියත් කරන ලදී. වෙළඳපොලෙන් ආසන්න වශයෙන් සියයට 50 ක මිල වාසියක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මොරිසන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හේමාස් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරිසන් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.පී. 5 mg",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝස-10",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝසුවස්ටැටින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.පී. 10",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ChlorMor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chlorphenamine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.පී. 4 mg 100s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරිසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෛද්ය සැපයුම් අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 40 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරිසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bisoprolol B.P.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝස-10",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝසුවස්ටැටින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.පී. 10",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරිසන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ChlorMor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chlorphenamine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.පී. 4 mg 100s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරිසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම තීරණාත්මක පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් අතපත්තු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "OSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 40 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "OSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ChlorMor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරිසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SGLT2",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්පාග්ලිෆ්ලොසින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් සියයට 50 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மோரிசன் மூன்று உயர்-தேவை மருந்துகளின் உள்ளூர் உற்பத்தியைத் தொடங்குகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உள்ளூர் மருந்துத் துறையில் மைல்கல்லைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில், ஹேமாஸ் குழுமத்தின் துணை நிறுவனமான மோரிசன் லிமிடெட் சமீபத்தில் Bisoprolol மாத்திரைகள் B.P. உற்பத்தியைத் தொடங்கியது. 5mg 250s, Ros-10 (Rosuvastatin மாத்திரைகள் I.P. 10mg 30s கொப்புளம்), மற்றும் ChlorMor (Chlorphenamine மாத்திரைகள் B.P. 4mg 100s கொப்புளம்).",
        "இந்த அதிக தேவையுடைய மருந்துகள் தற்போது மிகவும் மலிவு விலையிலும் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு அணுகக்கூடியதாகவும் உள்ளன, இவற்றின் விநியோகம் இறக்குமதியைச் சார்ந்திருக்க வேண்டியதில்லை.",
        "இலங்கையில் முதன்முறையாக Bisoprolol 5 mg மாத்திரைகள் தற்போது Morison நிறுவனத்தினால் உள்நாட்டிலேயே தயாரிக்கப்பட்டு அரச வைத்தியசாலைகளில் பயன்படுத்துவதற்காக மருத்துவ விநியோகப் பிரிவுக்கு வழங்கப்படுகின்றன. உயர் இரத்த அழுத்தம் மற்றும் பிற இருதய நோய்களுக்கான சிகிச்சையாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, அரசாங்கத் துறையில் Bisoprolol இன் ஆண்டுத் தேவை சுமார் 40 மில்லியன் மாத்திரைகள் ஆகும், இது இன்றுவரை இறக்குமதி செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "உள்நாட்டில் உற்பத்தி செய்வதன் மூலம், இந்த முன்னோடியில்லாத காலங்களில் தேசியப் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு கணிசமான அந்நியச் செலாவணி சேமிப்பை Morison செய்ய முடியும். Bisoprolol பி.எப். 2.5mg மற்றும் 5 mg அனைத்து முன்னணி மருந்தகங்களிலும் சரியான நேரத்தில் பிராண்டட் மருந்தாகக் கிடைக்கும், இது சரியான மருந்துச் சீட்டு மூலம் வாங்குவதை செயல்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட இரண்டாவது புதிய தயாரிப்பு, Ros-10 (Rosuvastatin மாத்திரைகள் I.P. 10mg 30s கொப்புளம்) உயர் இரத்த கொலஸ்ட்ரால் சிகிச்சைக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, இது இருதய நோய்க்கான ஆபத்து காரணியாகும். Morison Ros-10 ஐ அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது, தற்போதைய எடையுள்ள சராசரி சந்தை விலையில் ஏறத்தாழ பாதி, இலங்கையர்களுக்கு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சேமிப்பை வழங்குகிறது.",
        "மோரிசன் போர்ட்ஃபோலியோவில் மூன்றாவது சமீபத்திய சேர்க்கை, குளோர்மோர் (குளோர்பெனமைன் மாத்திரைகள் பி.பி. 4 மிகி 100s கொப்புளம்) என்பது வாய்வழி ஆண்டிஹிஸ்டமைன் ஆகும், இது ஒவ்வாமை அறிகுறிகளைப் போக்க உதவுகிறது. இதுவும் சந்தையில் நிலவும் இதே போன்ற தயாரிப்புகளை விட குறைவான விலையில் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "\"இது உண்மையில் மொரிசன் மற்றும் நாட்டின் மருந்து உற்பத்தித் துறைக்கு ஒரு முக்கிய மைல்கல் ஆகும். இலங்கையில் மருந்து உற்பத்தித் துறையில் இன்றுவரை மிகப் பெரிய முதலீடாக இருக்கும் ஹோமாகமவில் எங்களின் சமீபத்திய அதிநவீன உற்பத்தி மற்றும் ஆராய்ச்சி வசதியின் நடவடிக்கைகளை நாங்கள் இந்த ஆண்டு மே மாதம் ஆரம்பித்தோம். இந்த முக்கியமான நேரத்தில் நாட்டின் மருந்து விநியோகத்திற்கு இது ஒரு சிறந்த ஊக்கமாக இருக்கும்,” என்று மொரிசன் லிமிடெட் நிர்வாக இயக்குனர் தினேஷ் அத்தபத்து தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் WHO GMP மற்றும் EU GMP உள்கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் தர முகாமைத்துவ அமைப்புகளுக்கு இணங்க முதல் மற்றும் மிகப்பெரிய பொது வாய்வழி திடமான அளவு (OSD) மற்றும் வாய்வழி திரவ அளவு (OLD) உற்பத்தி வசதியாக இருப்பது, ஹோமாகமவில் உள்ள Morison இன் இரண்டாவது உற்பத்தி நிலையம் வருடத்திற்கு 5 பில்லியன் மாத்திரைகள் மற்றும் 2 மில்லியன் லீற்றர் திரவங்களை உற்பத்தி செய்ய, இது இலங்கையின் தேசிய வருடாந்த பொது OSD தேவையின் 40 சதவீதத்திற்கு சமமானதாகும்.",
        "Ros-10, Bisoprolol மற்றும் ChlorMor ஆகியவற்றை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதற்கு முன்பு, மொரிசன் 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில் உள்நாட்டில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட SGLT2 மூலக்கூறு (சோடியம்-குளுக்கோஸ் கோட்ரான்ஸ்போர்ட்டர்-2), எம்பாக்ளிஃப்ளோசின் மாத்திரைகள் 10mg மற்றும் 25mg ஆகியவற்றை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. சந்தையில் இருந்து சுமார் 50 சதவீதம் விலை நன்மை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மோரிசன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹேமாஸ் குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோரிசன் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பி. 5மி.கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஸ்-10",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோசுவாஸ்டாடின்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.பி. 10",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோர்மோர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோர்பெனமைன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பி. 4mg 100s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோரிசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருத்துவ விநியோக பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 40 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோரிசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bisoprolol பி.பி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஸ்-10",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோசுவாஸ்டாடின்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.பி. 10",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோரிசன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோர்மோர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோர்பெனமைன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பி. 4mg 100s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோரிசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த முக்கியமான மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் அத்தபத்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "OSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "OSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குளோர்மோர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோரிசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SGLT2",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்பாக்லிஃப்ளோசின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}