{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/12/indian-urea-suitable-for-sri-lanka-report/",
  "time_ut": 1657620840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian Urea suitable for Sri Lanka – Report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian Urea suitable for Sri Lanka – Report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Fertilizer Secretariat said that tests have confirmed that the urea fertilizer imported from India is suitable for Sri Lanka’s paddy cultivation and other crops.",
        "The National Fertilizer Secretariat had examined the samples and obtained the report regarding the percentage of biurate contained in them.",
        "Accordingly, the report states that the biurate percentage of the urea fertilizer is 0.9 percent.",
        "Previously, 03 international laboratory reports were obtained regarding this fertilizer, and those reports also stated that the percentage of biurate is 0.65 percent.",
        "Generally, the biurate percentage of urea used in Sri Lanka is 1%.",
        "Accordingly, arrangements have been made to distribute this fertilizer to agricultural service centers across the island by Ceylon Commercial Fertilizer Company for crops including rice and maize.",
        "PM, other MPs express condolences on behalf of former Japanese PM Abe"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Fertilizer Secretariat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Fertilizer Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "0.9 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.65 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Commercial Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සුදුසු ඉන්දීය යූරියා – වාර්තාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්දියාවෙන් ආනයනය කරන ලද යූරියා පොහොර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වී වගාව සහ අනෙකුත් භෝග සඳහා සුදුසු බව පරීක්ෂණවලින් තහවුරු වී ඇති බව පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සාම්පල පරීක්ෂා කර ඒවායේ අඩංගු Biurate ප්‍රතිශතය පිළිබඳ වාර්තාව ලබාගෙන තිබුණා.",
        "ඒ අනුව යූරියා පොහොරවල බයියුරේට් ප්‍රතිශතය සියයට 0.9ක් බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "මෙම පොහොර සම්බන්ධයෙන් මීට පෙර ජාත්‍යන්තර රසායනාගාර වාර්තා 03ක් ලබාගෙන ඇති අතර, එම වාර්තාවල ද සඳහන් වූයේ Biurate ප්‍රතිශතය සියයට 0.65ක් බවයි.",
        "සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ භාවිතා වන යූරියා වල biurate ප්‍රතිශතය 1% කි.",
        "ඒ අනුව සහල් සහ බඩඉරිඟු ඇතුළු භෝග සඳහා ලංකා කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම මගින් දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි කෘෂිකාර්මික සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත මෙම පොහොර බෙදා හැරීමට කටයුතු යොදා ඇත.",
        "හිටපු ජපාන අගමැති අබේ වෙනුවෙන් අගමැති සහ අනෙකුත් මන්ත්‍රීවරු ශෝකය ප්‍රකාශ කරති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.9 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.65 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய யூரியா இலங்கைக்கு ஏற்றது – அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இந்தியாவில் இருந்து இறக்குமதி செய்யப்படும் யூரியா உரமானது இலங்கையின் நெற்செய்கை மற்றும் ஏனைய பயிர்களுக்கு ஏற்றது என பரிசோதனைகள் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக உர செயலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தேசிய உரச் செயலகம் மாதிரிகளை ஆய்வு செய்து, அவற்றில் உள்ள பைரேட் சதவீதம் குறித்த அறிக்கையைப் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, யூரியா உரத்தின் பையூரேட் சதவீதம் 0.9 சதவீதம் என்று அந்த அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னர் இந்த உரம் தொடர்பில் 03 சர்வதேச ஆய்வுகூட அறிக்கைகள் பெறப்பட்டிருந்த நிலையில், அந்த அறிக்கைகளில் பையூரேட்டின் வீதம் 0.65 வீதம் எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொதுவாக, இலங்கையில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் யூரியாவின் பையூரேட் சதவீதம் 1% ஆகும்.",
        "இதன்படி, அரிசி, சோளம் உள்ளிட்ட பயிர்களுக்கு இலங்கை வர்த்தக உர நிறுவனத்தினால் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உள்ள விவசாய சேவை நிலையங்களுக்கு இந்த உரம் விநியோகிக்க ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஜப்பான் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் அபேயின் சார்பில் பிரதமர், மற்ற எம்பிக்கள் இரங்கல் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உர செயலகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய உர செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "0.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.65 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}