{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/29/desecration-of-president-s-flag-trade-union-leader-arrested/",
  "time_ut": 1659077040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Desecration of President’s Flag : Trade Union Leader Arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Desecration of President’s Flag : Trade Union Leader Arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Trade Union Leader Udeni Kalutantri was arrested by the police today.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said that he was arrested for unlafully entering the President's Office and for desecration of the President's Flag."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trade Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udeni Kalutantri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ධජය කෙලෙසීම : වෘත්තීය සමිති නායක අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වෘත්තීය සමිති නායක උදේනි කළුතන්ත්‍රි පොලිසිය විසින් අද අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට අයුතු ලෙස ඇතුළුවීම සහ ජනාධිපති කොඩිය කෙලෙසීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සමිතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදේනි කළුතන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியின் கொடி அவமதிப்பு: தொழிற்சங்க தலைவர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தொழிற்சங்க தலைவர் உதேனி களுதந்திரி பொலிஸாரால் இன்று கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்துக்குள் சட்டவிரோதமாக பிரவேசித்தமை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் கொடியை அவமதித்தமைக்காக அவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழிற்சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதேனி களுதந்திரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}