{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Japan-seeks-to-organise-Sri-Lanka-creditors-meeting-on-debt-crisis/342-243780",
  "time_ut": 1661492013,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan seeks to organise Sri Lanka creditors’ meeting on debt crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan seeks to organise Sri Lanka creditors’ meeting on debt crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japan is seeking to organise a Sri Lanka creditors' conference, hoping it could help solve the South Asia nation's debt crisis, but uncertainties cloud the outlook for any talks, three people with knowledge of the planning said.",
        "Tokyo is open to hosting talks among all the creditor nations aimed at lifting Colombo from its worst debt crisis since independence, but it is not clear whether top creditor China would join and a lack of clarity remains about Sri Lanka's finances, one source told Reuters.",
        "Japan would be willing to chair such a meeting with China if that would speed up the process for addressing Sri Lanka's debt, estimated at $6.2 billion on a bilateral basis at the end of 2020, this source said.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe told Reuters last week that Sri Lanka would ask Japan to invite the main creditor nations to talks on restructuring bilateral debts. He said he would discuss the issue with Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in Tokyo next month, when he is expected to attend the funeral of the assassinated former premier Shinzo Abe.",
        "Tokyo, the number two creditor, has a stake in rescuing Sri Lanka, not just to recoup its $3 billion in loans but also its diplomatic interest in checking China's growing presence in the region.",
        "S&P Global this month downgraded Sri Lanka's government bonds to default after it missed interest and principal payments. The island nation of 22 million people off India's southern tip, with debt at 114% of annual economic output, is in social and financial upheaval from the impact of COVID-19 pandemic on top of years of economic mismanagement.",
        "An International Monetary Fund (IMF) team met Wickremesinghe on Wednesday to discuss a bailout, including restructuring $29 billion in debt, as Colombo seeks a $3 billion IMF aid programme.",
        "Tokyo believes a new \"platform\" is needed to pull creditors together, the sources said.",
        "\"Sri Lanka is running out of time since it defaulted on its debt. The priority is for creditor nations to agree on an effective scheme,\" one source said.",
        "\"Japan is keen to move this forward. But it's not something Japan alone can raise its hand and push through,\" said the source, adding that the cooperation of other nations was crucial.",
        "Japan's Foreign Ministry declined to comment. Sri Lanka's central bank and Finance Ministry did not immediately respond to requests for comment. An IMF spokesperson declined to comment.(Reuters)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P Global",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "114%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$29 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන්ගේ රැස්වීමක් සංවිධානය කිරීමට ජපානය උත්සාහ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන්ගේ සමුළුවක් සංවිධානය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන අතර එය දකුණු ආසියාවේ ණය අර්බුදය විසඳීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරයි, නමුත් අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයන් ඕනෑම සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා අපේක්ෂාවන් වළක්වන බව සැලසුම් කිරීම පිළිබඳ දැනුමක් ඇති පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු පැවසීය.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු එහි දරුණුතම ණය අර්බුදයෙන් කොළඹ මුදාගැනීමේ අරමුණින් ටෝකියෝ සියලු ණයහිමි රටවල් අතර සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට විවෘතව ඇත, නමුත් ඉහළ ණය හිමියා වන චීනය එයට සම්බන්ධ වන්නේද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මූල්‍ය පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලිකමක් නොමැති බව එක් මූලාශ්‍රයක් රොයිටර් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "2020 අවසානයේ දී ද්විපාර්ශ්වික පදනමින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය පියවීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය වේගවත් කරන්නේ නම්, චීනය සමඟ එවැනි රැස්වීමක මුලසුන දැරීමට ජපානය කැමැත්තෙන් සිටින බව මෙම මූලාශ්‍රය පවසයි.",
        "ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ප්‍රධාන ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ට ආරාධනා කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පසුගිය සතියේ රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පැවසීය. ඝාතනයට ලක් වූ හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ෂින්සෝ අබේගේ අවමංගල්‍ය උත්සවයට සහභාගී වීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන විට ලබන මාසයේ ටෝකියෝ නුවරදී අගමැති ෆුමියෝ කිෂිඩා සමඟ ගැටලුව සාකච්ඡා කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අංක දෙකේ ණයහිමියා වන ටෝකියෝවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුදාගැනීමේ වගකීමක් ඇත, එහි ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 ක ණය ආපසු ලබා ගැනීමට පමණක් නොව, කලාපය තුළ චීනයේ වර්ධනය වන පැවැත්ම පරීක්ෂා කිරීමට එහි රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික උනන්දුව ද ඇත.",
        "S&P Global විසින් මෙම මාසයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජයේ බැඳුම්කර පොලී සහ මූලික ගෙවීම් පැහැර හැරීමෙන් පසු පැහැර හැරීමට ශ්‍රේණිගත කරන ලදී. වාර්ෂික ආර්ථික නිමැවුමෙන් 114%ක ණය බරින් යුතු මිලියන 22ක ජනගහනයක් සිටින ඉන්දීය දූපත් රාජ්‍යය, වසර ගණනාවක ආර්ථික වැරදි කළමනාකරණය හේතුවෙන් COVID-19 වසංගතයේ බලපෑමෙන් සමාජීය සහ මූල්‍ය නැගිටීමකට ලක්ව ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) කණ්ඩායමක් බදාදා වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවූයේ, කොළඹ ඩොලර් බිලියන 3ක IMF ආධාර වැඩසටහනක් අපේක්ෂා කරන බැවින්, ඩොලර් බිලියන 29ක නය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ඇතුළු ඇපදීමක් ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමටය.",
        "ණයහිමියන් එකට ඇද ගැනීමට නව \"වේදිකාවක්\" අවශ්‍ය බව ටෝකියෝ විශ්වාස කරන බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හැර ඇති බැවින් කාලය අවසන් වෙමින් පවතී. ප්‍රමුඛතාවය වන්නේ ණයහිමි ජාතීන් ඵලදායී යෝජනා ක්‍රමයක් සඳහා එකඟ වීමයි,\" එක් මූලාශ්‍රයක් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ජපානය මෙය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට උනන්දු වෙයි. නමුත් එය ජපානයට පමණක් අත ඔසවා තල්ලු කළ හැකි දෙයක් නොවේ,\" මූලාශ්‍රය පැවසුවේ අනෙකුත් ජාතීන්ගේ සහයෝගීතාවය තීරණාත්මක වූ බවයි.",
        "ජපානයේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය අදහස් දැක්වීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මහ බැංකුව සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය අදහස් දැක්වීමේ ඉල්ලීම්වලට ක්ෂණිකව ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ නැත. IMF ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු අදහස් දැක්වීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.(රොයිටර්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P Global",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "114%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 29 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடன் நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக இலங்கை கடனாளர்களின் கூட்டத்தை ஏற்பாடு செய்ய ஜப்பான் முயற்சிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தெற்காசிய நாட்டின் கடன் நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்க உதவும் என்று நம்பும் ஜப்பான், இலங்கை கடன் வழங்குநர்கள் மாநாட்டை ஏற்பாடு செய்ய முயல்கிறது, ஆனால் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மைகள் எந்தவொரு பேச்சுக்களுக்கான கண்ணோட்டத்தையும் மறைக்கின்றன, திட்டமிடல் பற்றி அறிந்த மூன்று பேர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "டோக்கியோ சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் கொழும்பை அதன் மோசமான கடன் நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீட்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளுக்கிடையில் பேச்சுக்களை நடத்தத் தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "2020 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் இருதரப்பு அடிப்படையில் $6.2 பில்லியன் என மதிப்பிடப்படும் இலங்கையின் கடனைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கான செயல்முறையை விரைவுபடுத்தினால், சீனாவுடனான அத்தகைய சந்திப்பிற்கு தலைமை தாங்க ஜப்பான் தயாராக இருக்கும் என்று அந்த வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கடந்த வாரம் ரொய்ட்டர்ஸிடம், இருதரப்பு கடன்களை மறுசீரமைப்பது தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு பிரதான கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளை அழைக்குமாறு ஜப்பானை இலங்கை கோரும் என்று கூறினார். படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபேயின் இறுதிச் சடங்கில் கலந்துகொள்வார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் போது, ​​அடுத்த மாதம் டோக்கியோவில் பிரதமர் ஃபுமியோ கிஷிடாவுடன் இந்த விவகாரம் குறித்து விவாதிப்பதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "டோக்கியோவில் நம்பர் டூ கடனாளி, இலங்கையை மீட்பதில் பங்கு உள்ளது, அதன் 3 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடனை திரும்பப் பெறுவதோடு மட்டுமல்லாமல், பிராந்தியத்தில் சீனாவின் வளர்ந்து வரும் பிரசன்னத்தை சரிபார்க்கும் ராஜதந்திர ஆர்வமும் உள்ளது.",
        "S&P Global இந்த மாதம் இலங்கையின் அரசாங்கப் பத்திரங்களை வட்டி மற்றும் அசல் கொடுப்பனவுகளைத் தவறவிட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து இயல்புநிலைக்குக் குறைத்தது. இந்தியாவின் தெற்கு முனையிலிருந்து 22 மில்லியன் மக்களைக் கொண்ட தீவு தேசம், ஆண்டுப் பொருளாதார உற்பத்தியில் 114% கடனுடன், பல ஆண்டுகளாக பொருளாதாரத் தவறான நிர்வாகத்தின் மேல் COVID-19 தொற்றுநோயின் தாக்கத்தால் சமூக மற்றும் நிதியியல் எழுச்சியில் உள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) குழு ஒன்று புதனன்று விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து பிணை எடுப்பு, 29 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடனை மறுசீரமைப்பது உட்பட, கொழும்பு 3 பில்லியன் டாலர் IMF உதவித் திட்டத்தை நாடுகிறது.",
        "டோக்கியோ ஒரு புதிய \"தளம்\" கடன் வழங்குபவர்களை ஒன்றாக இழுக்க வேண்டும் என்று நம்புகிறது, ஆதாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "\"இலங்கை அதன் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாததால் நேரம் முடிவடைகிறது. கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகள் ஒரு பயனுள்ள திட்டத்தை ஒப்புக்கொள்வதே முன்னுரிமை\" என்று ஒரு வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"ஜப்பான் இதை முன்னோக்கி நகர்த்த ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது. ஆனால் இது ஜப்பானால் மட்டும் கையை உயர்த்தி தள்ளக்கூடிய ஒன்றல்ல\" என்று அந்த வட்டாரம் கூறியது, மற்ற நாடுகளின் ஒத்துழைப்பு மிக முக்கியமானது.",
        "ஜப்பான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டது. கருத்துக்கான கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு இலங்கையின் மத்திய வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சகம் உடனடியாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை. IMF செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டார்.(ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்&பி குளோபல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "114%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$29 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}