{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/cse-bounces-back-despite-sls-dismal-q1-growth-stats/",
  "time_ut": 1656511200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CSE bounces back despite SL’s dismal Q1 growth stats",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CSE bounces back despite SL’s dismal Q1 growth stats",
      "author": "Dilshan Nadeera",
      "body_lines": [
        "The CSE did not react yesterday to the survey done by the US Consumer Confidence Survey, when the US and all Asian stock markets were recorded as performing negatively, stock market analysts said.",
        "The US survey revealed that United States’ consumer confidence edged lower in May as Americans’ view of their present and future prospects dimmed in the midst of persistent inflation.",
        "The Conference Board said on Tuesday that its consumer confidence index dipped to 106.4 in May, still a strong reading from 108.6 in April.",
        "Amid those developments the CSE bounced back following the previous days’ dip without a proper fundamental base. However, the economy in the first quarter had contracted by 1.6 per cent, the Department of Census and Statistics (DCS) revealed yesterday.",
        "It was confirming that the country was in bad shape long before the current crisis emerged. The dismal performance in the first quarter is despite the 2021 fourth quarter registering a 1.8% growth, despite the COVID-19 pandemic and 3.3 per cent growth overall last year. In 2021 1Q the economy grew by 4%.",
        "Agriculture and Industrial sectors suffered contractions of 6.8 per cent and 4.7 per cent respectively in 1Q of 2022, while the Service sector recorded a trivial expansion of 0.7per cent when compared to these values in the first quarter of year 2021. This would likely affect listed companies that engaged in the agriculture and industrial sectors, market analysts said.",
        "Amid those developments both indices moved upwards. All Share Price Index went up by 53.2 points and S and P SL20 rose by 25.2 points. Turnover stood at Rs 778 million with three crossings. Those crossings were reported in Lanka IOC, which crossed 1.7 million shares to the tune of Rs 115.5 million and its shares traded at Rs 68, Print Care two million shares crossed to the tune of Rs 60 million; its shares traded at Rs 30 and Access Engineering 2.5 million shares crossed to the tune of Rs 25 million; its shares traded at Rs 10.",
        "In the retail market, top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were, Expolanka Holdings Rs 149.2 million (151,000 shares traded), Lanka IOC Rs 84.4 million (1.2 million shares traded), HNB Rs 61.4 million (786,000 shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 47.5 million (6.3 million shares traded), Vallibel One Rs 26.6 million (one million shares traded), LOLC Finance Rs 16.1 million (2.4 million shares traded) and Sampath Bank 14.8 million (494,000 shares traded). During the day 34.7 million share volumes changed hands in 8000 transactions.",
        "Yesterday the Central Bank announced the US dollar rate. Its buying rate was Rs 355.81 and the selling rate Rs 367.07.",
        "Constant ‘monetary financing’ had little backing from fiscal side, says Central Bank",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Americans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Conference Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106.4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "108.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Census and Statistics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2021 fourth quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.8 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.7 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1Q of 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.7per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first quarter of year 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "S and P SL20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "778 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "115.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "149.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "151,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "786,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vallibel One Rs 26.6 million",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC Finance Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampath Bank 14.8 million",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "494,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "367.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SL හි නීරස Q1 වර්ධන සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන නොතකා CSE නැවත ඉහල යයි",
      "author": "ඩිල්ෂාන් නදීර",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සහ සියලුම ආසියානු කොටස් වෙලඳපොලවල් සෘණාත්මක ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරන බව වාර්තා වූ විට, එක්සත් ජනපද පාරිභෝගික විශ්වාසනීය සමීක්ෂණය විසින් කරන ලද සමීක්ෂණයට CSE ඊයේ ප්‍රතිචාර නොදැක්වූ බව කොටස් වෙළඳපල විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "අඛණ්ඩ උද්ධමනය මධ්‍යයේ ඔවුන්ගේ වර්තමාන සහ අනාගත අපේක්ෂාවන් පිළිබඳ ඇමරිකානුවන්ගේ දැක්ම අඳුරු වීම නිසා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පාරිභෝගික විශ්වාසය මැයි මාසයේදී පහත වැටුණු බව එක්සත් ජනපද සමීක්ෂණයෙන් හෙළි විය.",
        "සම්මන්ත්‍රණ මණ්ඩලය අඟහරුවාදා කියා සිටියේ එහි පාරිභෝගික විශ්වාසනීය දර්ශකය මැයි මාසයේදී 106.4 දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇති අතර එය තවමත් අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී 108.6 සිට ශක්තිමත් කියවීමකි.",
        "එම වර්ධනයන් මධ්‍යයේ CSE නිසි මූලික පදනමක් නොමැතිව පෙර දින වල පහත වැටීමෙන් පසු ආපසු හැරී ගියේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, පළමු කාර්තුවේ ආර්ථිකය සියයට 1.6 කින් හැකිලී ඇති බව ජනලේඛන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (DCS) ඊයේ අනාවරණය කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් අර්බුදය මතුවීමට බොහෝ කලකට පෙර රට නරක තත්ත්වයක තිබූ බව එයින් තහවුරු විය. COVID-19 වසංගතය සහ පසුගිය වසරේ සමස්ත වර්ධනය සියයට 3.3ක් තිබියදීත්, 2021 සිව්වන කාර්තුව 1.8% ක වර්ධනයක් වාර්තා කර තිබියදීත් පළමු කාර්තුවේ දුර්වල කාර්ය සාධනයයි. 2021 1Q හි ආර්ථිකය 4% කින් වර්ධනය විය.",
        "2022 පළමු කාර්තුවේදී කෘෂිකාර්මික සහ කාර්මික අංශයන් පිළිවෙළින් සියයට 6.8 සහ සියයට 4.7 ක හැකිලීම්වලට ලක් වූ අතර සේවා අංශය 2021 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුවේ මෙම අගයන්ට සාපේක්ෂව සියයට 0.7 ක සුළු ප්‍රසාරණයක් වාර්තා කර ඇත. කෘෂිකාර්මික හා කාර්මික අංශවල නියැලී සිටින සමාගම්, වෙළඳපල විශ්ලේෂකයින් පැවසීය.",
        "එම වර්ධනයන් මධ්‍යයේ දර්ශක දෙකම ඉහළට ගමන් කළේය. සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 53.2 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 25.2 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. හරස් මාර්ග තුනකින් පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් මිලියන 778 ක් විය. ලංකා IOC හි එම හරස්වීම් වාර්තා වූ අතර, එහි කොටස් මිලියන 1.7 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 115.5 දක්වා සහ එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 68 දක්වා ගනුදෙනු වූ අතර, Print Care කොටස් මිලියන 2ක් රුපියල් මිලියන 60 දක්වා ඉක්මවා ඇත. එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 30 ට ගනුදෙනු වූ අතර Access Engineering කොටස් මිලියන 2.5 ක් රුපියල් මිලියන 25 ක් ඉක්මවා ගියේය. එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 10 ට ගනුදෙනු විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ, පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ ප්‍රමුඛ සමාගම් හත වූයේ, එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 149.2 (කොටස් 151,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 84.4 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.2 ක්), HNB රුපියල් මිලියන 61.4 (කොටස් 786,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), Browns ය. ආයෝජන රුපියල් මිලියන 47.5 (කොටස් මිලියන 6.3 ක්), Vallibel One රුපියල් මිලියන 26.6 (කොටස් මිලියනයක් වෙළඳාම් කර ඇත), LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 16.1 (කොටස් මිලියන 2.4 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ සම්පත් බැංකුව මිලියන 14.8 (කොටස් 494,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 8000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 34.7 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "ඊයේ මහ බැංකුව එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර අනුපාතය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය. එහි ගැනුම් මිල රුපියල් 355.81ක් වූ අතර විකුණුම් මිල රුපියල් 367.07ක් විය.",
        "නිරන්තර ‘මුදල් මූල්‍යකරණයට’ මූල්‍ය අංශයෙන් එතරම් සහයෝගයක් නොලැබුණු බව මහ බැංකුව පවසයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සම්මන්ත්රණ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106.4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "108.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.6 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනලේඛන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 සිව්වන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 3.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 4.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 1Q",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "S සහ P SL20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 778 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 115.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 60 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 149.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "151,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 84.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 61.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "786,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 47.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිබල් වන් රුපියල් මිලියන 26.6 කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස් රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පත් බැංකුව මිලියන 14.8 කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "494,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 34.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "367.07 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL இன் மோசமான Q1 வளர்ச்சி புள்ளிவிவரங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும் CSE மீண்டும் எழுகிறது",
      "author": "தில்ஷான் நதீரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் அனைத்து ஆசிய பங்குச் சந்தைகளும் எதிர்மறையாகச் செயல்பட்டதாகப் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டபோது, ​​அமெரிக்க நுகர்வோர் நம்பிக்கைக் கணக்கெடுப்பு நடத்திய கருத்துக்கணிப்புக்கு சிஎஸ்இ நேற்று எதிர்வினையாற்றவில்லை என்று பங்குச் சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தொடர்ச்சியான பணவீக்கத்தின் மத்தியில் அமெரிக்கர்களின் தற்போதைய மற்றும் எதிர்கால வாய்ப்புகள் பற்றிய பார்வை மங்கியதால், மே மாதத்தில் அமெரிக்காவின் நுகர்வோர் நம்பிக்கை குறைந்துள்ளதாக அமெரிக்க கணக்கெடுப்பு வெளிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "மாநாட்டு வாரியம் செவ்வாயன்று, அதன் நுகர்வோர் நம்பிக்கைக் குறியீடு மே மாதத்தில் 106.4 ஆகக் குறைந்துள்ளது, இன்னும் ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் 108.6 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "அந்த முன்னேற்றங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் சரியான அடிப்படை அடிப்படை இல்லாமல் முந்தைய நாட்களின் சரிவைத் தொடர்ந்து CSE மீண்டும் எழுச்சி பெற்றது. எவ்வாறாயினும், முதல் காலாண்டில் பொருளாதாரம் 1.6 சதவீதத்தால் சுருங்கியுள்ளது என்று மக்கள் தொகை கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றும் புள்ளிவிபரத் திணைக்களம் (டிசிஎஸ்) நேற்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடி தோன்றுவதற்கு நீண்ட காலத்திற்கு முன்பே நாடு மோசமான நிலையில் இருந்தது என்பதை இது உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது. 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நான்காம் காலாண்டில் 1.8% வளர்ச்சியைப் பதிவு செய்த போதிலும் முதல் காலாண்டில் மோசமான செயல்திறன் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் மற்றும் கடந்த ஆண்டு ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக 3.3 சதவீத வளர்ச்சியைப் பெற்றிருந்தாலும். 2021 1Q இல் பொருளாதாரம் 4% வளர்ந்தது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டில் விவசாயம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை துறைகள் முறையே 6.8 சதவிகிதம் மற்றும் 4.7 சதவிகிதம் சுருக்கங்களைச் சந்தித்தன, அதே நேரத்தில் சேவைத் துறையானது 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டில் இந்த மதிப்புகளுடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது 0.7 சதவிகிதம் அற்பமான விரிவாக்கத்தைப் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது. விவசாயம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள நிறுவனங்கள், சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அந்த முன்னேற்றங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் இரு குறியீடுகளும் மேல் நோக்கி நகர்ந்தன. அனைத்து பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 53.2 புள்ளிகளாலும், S மற்றும் P SL20 25.2 புள்ளிகளாலும் உயர்ந்தன. மூன்று குறுக்குவழிகள் மூலம் 778 மில்லியனாக விற்றுமுதல் இருந்தது. அந்த கிராசிங்குகள் லங்கா ஐஓசியில் பதிவாகியுள்ளன, இது 1.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகளைத் தாண்டி ரூ. 115.5 மில்லியன் மற்றும் அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 68 ஆக வர்த்தகமானது, பிரிண்ட் கேர் இரண்டு மில்லியன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 60 மில்லியனைத் தாண்டியது; அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 30 ஆகவும், அக்சஸ் இன்ஜினியரிங் 2.5 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் ரூ. 25 மில்லியனாகவும் வர்த்தகமானது; அதன் பங்குகள் 10 ரூபாய்க்கு வர்த்தகம் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனை சந்தையில், வருவாயில் முக்கியமாக பங்களித்த முதல் ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள், எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 149.2 மில்லியன் (151,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ 84.4 மில்லியன் (1.2 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), HNB ரூ 61.4 மில்லியன் (786,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள் ரூ 47.5 மில்லியன் (6.3 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), வாலிபெல் ஒன் ரூ 26.6 மில்லியன் (ஒரு மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), LOLC ஃபினான்ஸ் ரூ 16.1 மில்லியன் (2.4 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் சம்பத் வங்கி 14.8 மில்லியன் (494,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) நாளின் போது 8000 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 34.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் கைமாறின.",
        "அமெரிக்க டாலர் விலையை மத்திய வங்கி நேற்று அறிவித்தது. இதன் கொள்முதல் விலை ரூ.355.81 ஆகவும், விற்பனை விலை ரூ.367.07 ஆகவும் இருந்தது.",
        "நிலையான 'பண நிதியளிப்பு' நிதி தரப்பிலிருந்து சிறிய ஆதரவைக் கொண்டிருந்தது என்று மத்திய வங்கி கூறுகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநாட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106.4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "108.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் தொகை கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றும் புள்ளியியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 நான்காவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் 1Q",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ் மற்றும் பி SL20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "778 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "115.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "149.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "151,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "786,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாலிபெல் ஒன் ரூ 26.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC நிதி ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பத் வங்கி 14.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "494,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "367.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}