{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84628/sri-lanka-to-introduce-5-year-multiple-entry-tourist-visa",
  "time_ut": 1661841240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to introduce 5-year multiple entry tourist visa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to introduce 5-year multiple entry tourist visa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka will introduce a five-year multiple entry tourist visa with a six-month stay for 35 countries, Minister of Tourism Harin Fernando says.",
        "In a tweet posted on his official account today, the lawmaker said the Cabinet of Ministers has green-lighted the proposal.",
        "Minister Fernando noted that this is in an addition to the one-year multiple entry and single entry tourist visas which have a six-month stay period, which was previously limited to 30 days.",
        "The decision was taken to boost “repeat tourism” in Sri Lanka, he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "5-year",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tourism Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වසර 5ක බහු ප්‍රවේශ සංචාරක වීසා බලපත්‍රයක් හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රටවල් 35ක් සඳහා මාස හයක කාලයක් රැඳී සිටින පස් අවුරුදු බහු ප්‍රවේශ සංචාරක වීසා බලපත්‍රයක් හඳුන්වා දෙන බව සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අද දින සිය නිල ගිණුමේ පළ කරන ලද ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක නීති සම්පාදකවරයා කියා සිටියේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් මෙම යෝජනාවට හරිත ආලෝකය ලබා දී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රනාන්දු අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේ, මීට පෙර දින 30කට සීමා කර තිබූ මාස හයක නවාතැන් කාලයක් සහිත වසරක බහු ප්‍රවේශ සහ තනි ප්‍රවේශ සංචාරක වීසාවලට අමතරව මෙය බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ \"පුනරාවර්තන සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය\" නංවාලීම සඳහා මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇති බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස් අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක් වසරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "5 வருட பல நுழைவு சுற்றுலா விசாவை இலங்கை அறிமுகப்படுத்தவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "35 நாடுகளுக்கு ஆறு மாதங்கள் தங்கக்கூடிய ஐந்து வருட பல நுழைவு சுற்றுலா விசாவை இலங்கை அறிமுகப்படுத்தவுள்ளதாக சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ கணக்கில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட ட்வீட்டில், சட்டமியற்றுபவர் மந்திரிசபை இந்த திட்டத்திற்கு பச்சை விளக்கு காட்டியதாக கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னர் 30 நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஆறுமாத கால அவகாசம் கொண்ட ஒரு வருட மல்டிபிள் என்ட்ரி மற்றும் சிங்கிள் என்ட்ரி டூரிஸ்ட் விசாக்களுக்கு இது கூடுதலாகும் என அமைச்சர் பெர்னாண்டோ குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் \"மீண்டும் சுற்றுலாவை\" ஊக்குவிப்பதற்காக இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டதாக அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}