{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Almost-50-filling-stations-test-National-Fuel-Pass-Kanchana/56-738004",
  "time_ut": 1658951918,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Almost 50% filling stations test National Fuel Pass: Kanchana",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Almost 50% filling stations test National Fuel Pass: Kanchana",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "481 filling stations have adopted or tested National Fuel Pass QR system, including 409 CEYPETCO and 72 LIOC",
        "Total of 4,296,950 motorists register for National Fuel Pass so far",
        "Cabinet nod to appoint Advisory and Officers’ Committees to ensure continuous supply of fuel",
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera yesterday said nearly 50% of the filling stations have already adopted the National Fuel Pass QR system, attributing that the system is successful.",
        "As per the Minister, a total of 481 filling stations have already adopted or tested the National Fuel Pass QR system, which includes 409 State-run CEYPETCO and 72 Lanka IOC filling stations. The system has also completed 158,208 transactions as of yesterday.",
        "The registration of vehicles includes 2,488,395 motorcycles, 759,119 three-wheels, 604,945 cars, 215,347 vans, 182,657 lorries, 28,724 buses, 12,835 special purpose vehicles, 4,215 land vehicles and 805 quadricycles.",
        "Minister Wijesekera also confirmed that 4,296,950 motorists have registered with the National Fuel Pass system as of 8:30 p.m. yesterday. Of the total, 4,264,368 have registered using the National Identity Card (NIC) number, while 18,164 using the business registration number (BRN) and 15,086 with a passport.",
        "The system is being tested as a pilot project across the country, whilst it will be fully rolled out from 1 August.",
        "The Cabinet of Ministers at its meeting on Monday approved appointing an Advisory Committee and Officers’ Committee to ensure continuous supply through effective management of the limited fuel imports.",
        "The proposal to this effect was submitted by the Power and Energy Minister Wijesekera and was approved by the Cabinet of Ministers.",
        "“In a detailed explanation, Minister Wijesekera briefed the Cabinet of Ministers on the ongoing energy crisis and strategies in place to effectively manage the limited fuel imports,” Cabinet Spokesman Bandula Gunawardena said at the post-Cabinet meeting media briefing on Tuesday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Almost 50%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Fuel Pass:",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "481",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "409",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4,296,950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Advisory",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Fuel Pass QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "481",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Fuel Pass QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "409",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEYPETCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "158,208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,488,395",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "759,119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "604,945",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "215,347",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "182,657",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28,724",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,835",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,215",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "805",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,296,950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8:30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,264,368",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Identity Card",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,164",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,086",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advisory Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "50%කට ආසන්න පිරවුම්හල් ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රය පරීක්ෂා කරයි: කාංචනා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "CEYPETCO 409 සහ LIOC 72 ඇතුළුව පිරවුම්හල් 481ක් ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍ර QR පද්ධතිය අනුගමනය කර හෝ පරීක්ෂා කර ඇත.",
        "මේ වන විට ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රය සඳහා ලියාපදිංචි වූ මුළු මෝටර් රථ රියදුරන් සංඛ්‍යාව 4,296,950කි",
        "අඛණ්ඩව ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා උපදේශක සහ නිලධාරීන්ගේ කමිටු පත් කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය",
        "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලින් 50%කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් දැනටමත් ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍ර QR ක්‍රමය අනුගමනය කර ඇති බවත්, එම ක්‍රමය සාර්ථක බව පෙන්වා දෙමිනි.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයාට අනුව, ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් 481ක් දැනටමත් ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍ර QR ක්‍රමය අනුගමනය කර හෝ පරීක්‍ෂාවට ලක් කර ඇති අතර එයට රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන CEYPETCO 409ක් සහ ලංකා IOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් 72ක් ඇතුළත් වේ. පද්ධතිය ඊයේ වන විට ගනුදෙනු 158,208 ක් ද සම්පූර්ණ කර ඇත.",
        "වාහන ලියාපදිංචියට යතුරුපැදි 2,488,395ක්, ත්‍රිරෝද රථ 759,119ක්, කාර් 604,945ක්, වෑන් රථ 215,347ක්, ලොරි රථ 182,657ක්, බස් රථ 28,724ක්, විශේෂ කාර්ය වාහන 12,835ක්, ඉඩම් වාහන 4,215ක් සහ හතරේ සයිකල් 805ක් ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "රාත්‍රී 8.30 වන විට ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍ර ක්‍රමයේ රියදුරන් 4,296,950ක් ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති බවද විජේසේකර අමාත්‍යවරයා තහවුරු කළේය. ඊයේ. මුළු සංඛ්‍යාවෙන් 4,264,368 ක් ජාතික හැඳුනුම්පත් (NIC) අංකය භාවිතා කර ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති අතර 18,164 ව්‍යාපාර ලියාපදිංචි අංකය (BRN) සහ 15,086 විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රයක් භාවිතා කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම පද්ධතිය නියමු ව්‍යාපෘතියක් ලෙස රට පුරා අත්හදා බලමින් පවතින අතර අගෝස්තු 1 වැනිදා සිට එය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ක්‍රියාත්මක කෙරේ.",
        "සීමිත ඉන්ධන ආනයනය ඵලදායී ලෙස කළමනාකරණය කිරීම තුළින් අඛණ්ඩ සැපයුම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා උපදේශක කමිටුවක් සහ නිලධාරීන්ගේ කමිටුවක් පත් කිරීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සඳුදා රැස්වූ අවස්ථාවේදී අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ඒ සඳහා වූ යෝජනාව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද අතර ඊට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය හිමි විය.",
        "“දැනට පවතින බලශක්ති අර්බුදය සහ සීමිත ඉන්ධන ආනයනය ඵලදායි ලෙස කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන උපාය මාර්ග පිළිබඳව සවිස්තරාත්මක පැහැදිලි කිරීමකින් විජේසේකර අමාත්‍යවරයා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට කරුණු දැක්වීය” යනුවෙන් කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන අඟහරුවාදා පශ්චාත් කැබිනට් රැස්වීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 50%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය:",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "481",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "409",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4,296,950 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උපදේශන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "481",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "409",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEYPETCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "158,208 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,488,395 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "759,119 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "604,945 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "215,347 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "182,657 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28,724 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,835 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,215 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "805",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,296,950 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8:30 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,264,368 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික හැඳුනුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,164 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,086 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஏறக்குறைய 50% நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் தேசிய எரிபொருள் அனுமதிச் சீட்டைச் சோதிக்கின்றன: காஞ்சனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "409 CEYPETCO மற்றும் 72 LIOC உட்பட 481 நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR அமைப்பை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டன அல்லது சோதனை செய்துள்ளன.",
        "இதுவரை 4,296,950 வாகன ஓட்டிகள் தேசிய எரிபொருள் அனுமதிச் சீட்டுக்காக பதிவு செய்துள்ளனர்",
        "தொடர்ந்து எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக ஆலோசனை மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் குழுக்களை நியமிக்க அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல்",
        "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர நேற்று கூறுகையில், ஏறக்குறைய 50% எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் ஏற்கனவே தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR முறையை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ளன, இந்த அமைப்பு வெற்றிகரமாக உள்ளது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "அமைச்சரின் கூற்றுப்படி, மொத்தம் 481 நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் ஏற்கனவே தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR முறையை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ளன அல்லது சோதனை செய்துள்ளன, இதில் 409 அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் CEYPETCO மற்றும் 72 Lanka IOC நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் அடங்கும். இந்த அமைப்பு நேற்றைய நிலவரப்படி 158,208 பரிவர்த்தனைகளையும் நிறைவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "வாகனங்களின் பதிவில் 2,488,395 மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்கள், 759,119 முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள், 604,945 கார்கள், 215,347 வேன்கள், 182,657 லொறிகள், 28,724 பேருந்துகள், 12,835 சிறப்பு நோக்க வாகனங்கள், 4,215 தரைவழி வாகனங்கள், 4,215 குவாட்ரி சைக்கிள்கள் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "இரவு 8.30 மணி நிலவரப்படி 4,296,950 வாகன சாரதிகள் தேசிய எரிபொருள் அனுமதிச் சீட்டில் பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார். நேற்று. மொத்தத்தில், 4,264,368 பேர் தேசிய அடையாள அட்டை (NIC) எண்ணையும், 18,164 பேர் வணிக பதிவு எண்ணையும் (BRN) மற்றும் 15,086 பேர் பாஸ்போர்ட்டைப் பயன்படுத்தி பதிவு செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த அமைப்பு நாடு முழுவதும் ஒரு முன்னோடி திட்டமாக சோதிக்கப்படுகிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் இது ஆகஸ்ட் 1 முதல் முழுமையாக வெளியிடப்படும்.",
        "வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதியை திறம்பட நிர்வகிப்பதன் மூலம் தொடர்ச்சியான விநியோகத்தை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக ஆலோசனைக் குழு மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவை நியமிப்பதற்கு திங்கள்கிழமையன்று நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில் ஒப்புதல் அளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இதற்கான பிரேரணை மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகரவினால் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "\"தற்போது நிலவும் எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடி மற்றும் மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதியை திறம்பட நிர்வகிப்பதற்கான தந்திரோபாயங்கள் குறித்து அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர அமைச்சரவைக்கு விரிவான விளக்கமளித்தார்\" என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன செவ்வாய்கிழமையன்று நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்திற்குப் பின்னரான ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 50%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ்:",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "481",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "409",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4,296,950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "481",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "409",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "158,208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,488,395",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "759,119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "604,945",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "215,347",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "182,657",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28,724",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,835",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,215",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "805",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,296,950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 8:30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,264,368",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அடையாள அட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,164",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஆர்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,086",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசனை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}