{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/சட்டமா-அதிபர்-விடுத்துள்ள-கோரிக்கை/175-299377",
  "time_ut": 1656424696,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சட்டமா அதிபர் விடுத்துள்ள கோரிக்கை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Request made by the Attorney General",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Airport Services Company, through the Attorney General's Department, today (28) filed a transfer letter in the Colombo Commercial High Court seeking the dismissal of the case filed against Russia's Aeroflot aircraft.",
        "Colombo Commercial High Court Judge Harsha Sethunga had on the 6th issued an order suspending the execution of the restraining order issued against the Russian Aeroflot aircraft.",
        "The aforesaid order was issued after taking into consideration the facts presented by the parties including the Attorney General that the restraining order was obtained by misleading the court and misrepresenting the facts.",
        "Additional Solicitor General Presidential Counsel Sumathi Dharmawardena, appearing on behalf of the 2nd respondent Airport Services Company, requested the court to dismiss the petition as the Russian Aeroflot flight had left the court premises.",
        "Dr. Lasantha Hettiarachchi, appearing for the Russian airline, demanded a possible expeditious date for the investigation into the matter as Aeroflot has suspended operations in Sri Lanka.",
        "Considering the facts, Colombo Commercial High Court Judge Harsha Sethunga adjourned the case to July 5.",
        "On June 2, the Colombo Chamber of Commerce issued a restraining order preventing Russian Aeroflot aircraft from taking off from Sri Lankan territory, in response to a request from Celestial Aviation Trading Limited in Ireland.",
        "It is noteworthy that Celestial Aviation Trading Ltd. of Ireland received the injunction for failure to comply with the terms of the lease agreement between the two parties of Russia Aeroflot Airlines."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Airport Services Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha Sethunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumathi Dharmawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airport Services Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lasantha Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha Sethunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia Aeroflot Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියාවේ Aeroflot ගුවන් යානාවලට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති නඩුව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ගුවන්තොටුපල සේවා සමාගම නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හරහා අද (28) කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණයට ස්ථාන මාරු ලිපියක් ගොනු කළේය.",
        "කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු හර්ෂ සේතුංග මහතා පසුගිය 06 වැනිදා රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානයට නිකුත් කර තිබූ තහනම් නියෝගය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අත්හිටුවමින් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කර තිබුණා.",
        "අධිකරණය නොමග යවමින් සාවද්‍ය කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් මෙම තහනම් නියෝගය ලබාගෙන ඇති බවට නීතිපතිවරයා ඇතුළු පාර්ශවයන් ඉදිරිපත් කළ කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ඉහත නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "2 වැනි වගඋත්තරකාර ගුවන්තොටුපළ සේවා සමාගම වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සුමති ධර්මවර්ධන මහත්මිය අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානය අධිකරණ භූමියෙන් පිටව ගොස් ඇති බැවින් පෙත්සම නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "රුසියානු ගුවන් සේවය වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි වෛද්‍ය ලසන්ත හෙට්ටිආරච්චි මහතා ඉල්ලා සිටියේ Aeroflot ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙහෙයුම් අත්හිටුවා ඇති බැවින් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කිරීමට හැකි කඩිනම් දිනයක් ලබාදෙන ලෙසයි.",
        "කරුණු සලකා බැලූ කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු හර්ෂ සේතුංග මහතා නඩුව ජූලි 5 වැනිදාට කල් තැබීය.",
        "අයර්ලන්තයේ Celestial Aviation Trading Limited වෙතින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන්, ජූනි 2 වන දින කොළඹ වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය විසින් රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානා ශ්‍රී ලංකා භූමියෙන් ගුවන්ගත වීම වළක්වමින් තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "රුසියාවේ Aeroflot එයාර්ලයින්ස් හි පාර්ශව දෙක අතර කල්බදු ගිවිසුමේ නියමයන්ට අනුකූල නොවීම හේතුවෙන් අයර්ලන්තයේ Celestial Aviation Trading Ltd සමාගමට වාරණ නියෝගය ලැබුණු බව සැලකිය යුතු කරුණකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන්තොටුපල සේවා සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ සේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමති ධර්මවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් තොටුපල සේවා සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලසන්ත හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ සේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව Aeroflot ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டமா அதிபர் விடுத்துள்ள கோரிக்கை",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரஷ்யாவின் ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்துக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கை தள்ளுபடி செய்யுமாறு கோரிக்கை விடுத்து, விமான நிலைய சேவைகள் நிறுவனம், சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடாக கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்றில் இன்று (28) நகர்த்தல் பத்திரம் ஒன்றை தாக்கல் செய்தது.",
        "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்துக்கு எதிராக பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட தடை உத்தரவின் செயல்பாட்டை இடைநிறுத்தி கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி ஹர்ஷ சேதுங்க, கடந்த 6ஆம் திகதி உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்திருந்தார்.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை தவறாக வழிநடத்தி உண்மைகளை தவறாக சித்தரித்து இந்த தடை உத்தரவு பெறப்பட்டதாக சட்டமா அதிபர் உள்ளிட்ட தரப்பினரால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட உண்மைகளை கவனத்தில் எடுத்ததன் பின்னரே மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் நீதிமன்றத்தின் எல்லையை விட்டு வெளியேறியதால் இந்த மனுவை தள்ளுபடி செய்யுமாறு, 2ஆவது பிரதிவாதியான விமான நிலைய சேவைகள் நிறுவன சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சுமதி தர்மவர்தன மன்றில் கோரிநின்றார்.",
        "ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானங்கள் இலங்கைக்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை இடைநிறுத்தியுள்ளதால், இந்த விவகாரம் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படுவதற்கான சாத்தியமான விரைவான திகதியை ரஷ்ய விமான நிறுவனம் சார்பில் ஆஜரான கலாநிதி லசந்த ஹெட்டியாராச்சி கோரினார்.",
        "உண்மைகளை கருத்திற்கொண்ட கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி ஹர்ஷ சேதுங்க இந்த வழக்கை ஜூலை 5 ஆம் திகதி விசாரணைக்கு ஒத்திவைத்தார்.",
        "அயர்லாந்தில் உள்ள செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் லிமிடெட் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு இணங்க, இலங்கையின் எல்லைக்குள் இருந்து ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் புறப்படுவதைத் தடுக்கும் தடை உத்தரவை ஜூன் 2 அன்று கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்றம் பிறப்பித்தது.",
        "ரஷ்யாவின் ஏரோஃப்ளோட்  எயர்லைன்ஸ் இரு தரப்பினருக்கு இடையேயான குத்தகை ஒப்பந்தத்தின் விதிமுறைகளுக்கு இணங்கத் தவறியமைக்காக அயர்லாந்தில் உள்ள செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனமானது இந்தத் தடை உத்தரவைப் பெற்றிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலைய சேவைகள் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷா சேதுங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமதி தர்மவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலைய சேவைகள் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லசந்த ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷா சேதுங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா ஏரோஃப்ளோட் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}