{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/දුලාංජලී-රටෙන්-යයි/1-618830",
  "time_ut": 1661573919,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දුලාංජලී රටෙන් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dulangali leaves the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that Mrs. Dulangali Jayakodi, the sister of opposition leader Mr. Sajith Premadasa, who was recently recorded by the Criminal Investigation Department regarding the incident of Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe's personal home in Kollupitiya being destroyed by fire, has left the island yesterday (26) morning.",
        "She has left the island with the two children Sanjay Jayakodi and Amaya Jayakodi on Sri Lankan Airlines flight UL 505.",
        "Ms. Dulangali Jayakodi was summoned to the Criminal Investigation Department and a statement was recorded on the last 20th Saturday regarding the incident of Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe's personal house in Kollupitiya being destroyed by fire.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe's private house in Kollupitiya was set on fire by a group of violent people on 9th July last, and many valuable books and other property were destroyed.",
        "The Criminal Investigation Department recorded a statement from Mrs. Dulanjali Jayagoda based on information that she was present at the time of the incident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dulangali",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dulangali Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjay Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaya Jayakodi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "505",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dulangali Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 20th Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th July last",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulanjali Jayagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුලාංජලී රටෙන් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ  කොල්ලුපිටියේ පිහිටි  සිය පෞද්ගලික නිවෙසට ගිනි තබා විනාශ කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් පසුගියදා ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනුණු විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ සහෝදරිය වන දුලාංජලී ජයකොඩි මහත්මිය ඊයේ (26) උදේ දිවයිනෙන් පිටව ගොස් ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ඇය  ශ්‍රී ලන්කන් ගුවන් සේවයේ යූ.එල් 505 දරණ ගුවන් යානයෙන්  මෙසේ දිවයිනෙන් පිටව ගොස් ඇත්තේ සන්ජේ ජයකොඩි සහ  අමායා ජයකොඩි යන දරු දෙදෙනාද සමඟය",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොල්ලුපිටියේ පිහිටි සිය පෞද්ගලික නිවෙසට  ගිනි තබා විනාශ කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් දුලාංජලී ජයකොඩි මහත්මිය අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට කැඳවා ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කර ගැනුණේ පසුගිය 20  වෙනිදා සෙනසුරාදා දිනයේය.",
        "කිසියම් ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොල්ලුපිටියේ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවෙසට  ඉකුත් ජුලි මස 9 වැනිදා ගිනි තබනු ලැබීමෙන්  එහි  වටිනා පොත්පත් ඇතුළු  දේපළ  රැසක්  විනාශවිය.",
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දුලාංජලී ජයගොඩ මහත්මියගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කරගත්තේ ඇය එම සිද්ධියවූ අවස්ථාවේදී  ඒ  ස්ථානයේ සිටි බවට ලැබුණු තොරතුරක් අනුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දුලංගලි",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දුලංගලි ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජය ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමායා ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "505",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුලංගලි ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 20 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ජූලි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුලංජලී ජයගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "துலங்கலி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டியில் உள்ள திரு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வீடு தீயில் எரிந்து நாசமான சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் அண்மையில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரால் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு சஜித் பிரேமதாசவின் சகோதரி திருமதி துலங்கலி ஜயக்கொடி நேற்று நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் வெளியேறியதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. (26) காலை.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானமான UL 505 இல் சஞ்சய் ஜெயக்கொடி மற்றும் அமயா ஜெயக்கொடி ஆகிய இரு குழந்தைகளுடன் அவர் தீவை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளார்.",
        "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டியில் உள்ள திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வீடு தீயில் எரிந்து நாசமான சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கடந்த 20 ஆம் திகதி சனிக்கிழமை திருமதி துலங்கலி ஜெயக்கொடி குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்திற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டு வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கொள்ளுப்பிட்டியில் உள்ள தனியார் வீடு கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி வன்முறையாளர்களால் தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்டதுடன், பல பெறுமதியான புத்தகங்கள் மற்றும் ஏனைய சொத்துக்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "சம்பவத்தின் போது திருமதி துலாஞ்சலி ஜயகொட இருந்ததாக கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் அவரிடம் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துலங்கலி",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "துலங்கலி ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சய் ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமையா ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "505",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துலங்கலி ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 20வது சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஜூலை 9ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துலாஞ்சலி ஜயகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}