{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84597/six-indian-fishermen-arrested-by-sri-lanka-navy",
  "time_ut": 1661711220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Six Indian fishermen arrested by Sri Lanka Navy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Six Indian fishermen arrested by Sri Lanka Navy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Navy personnel have intercepted an Indian trawler with 06 Indian fishermen, while poaching in Sri Lanka’s waters off Talaimannar, via the International Maritime Boundary Line (IMBL).",
        "The arrests were made during an operation on the night of 27th August conducted to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in the island’s waters.",
        "In this special operation mounted by the North Central Naval Command to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in Sri Lanka’s waters, via the IMBL, the apprehension was made by the Fast Attack Craft attached to the Northern Naval Command.",
        "In this operation, the Navy seized an Indian poaching trawler remaining off Talaimannar, with 06 Indian fishermen and their fishing gears.",
        "The Indian trawler and 06 Indian fishermen held by the Navy are in naval custody in Talaimannar as of now and they will be handed over to the Fisheries Inspector of Mannar for onward legal action, the SLN said.",
        "In a similar operation conducted on 22nd August, the Navy held an Indian poaching trawler with 10 Indian fishers off Mullaitivu and produced them for legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Maritime Boundary Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the night of 27th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fisheries Inspector of Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් හය දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර සීමා රේඛාව (IMBL) හරහා තලෙයිමන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු තීරයේ ධීවර කටයුතුවල නිරත වෙමින් සිටි ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පසුගිය අගෝස්තු 27 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ දඩයම් කළ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීමේ මෙහෙයුමකදී මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "IMBL හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ දඩයම් කරන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීම සඳහා උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද මෙම විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමේදී උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව විසින් මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ධීවර ආම්පන්න සමඟ තලෙයිමන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව භාරයේ සිටින ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව සහ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු මේ වන විට තලෙයිමන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශයේ නාවික අත්අඩංගුවේ පසුවන අතර ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඔවුන් මන්නාරම ධීවර පරීක්ෂක වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිත බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 22 වැනි දින සිදු කරන ලද මෙවන් මෙහෙයුමකදී නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 10 දෙනෙකු සමඟ මුලතිව් ඔබ්බෙන් ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් රඳවාගෙන නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර මායිම් රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 වැනිදා රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම ධීවර පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய மீனவர்கள் 6 பேர் இலங்கை கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு (IMBL) ஊடாக இலங்கையின் தலைமன்னார் கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடிக்கொண்டிருந்த 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் இந்திய இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் இடைமறித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தீவின் கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டியடிப்பதற்காக ஆகஸ்ட் 27ஆம் திகதி இரவு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கையின் போது இவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டுவதற்காக வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இந்த விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட விரைவுத் தாக்குதல் கப்பலினால் IMBL ஊடாக அச்சம் கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில், 06 இந்திய மீனவர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களது மீன்பிடி சாதனங்களுடன் தலைமன்னார் கடற்பரப்பில் எஞ்சியிருந்த இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இந்திய இழுவை படகு மற்றும் 06 இந்திய மீனவர்கள் தற்போது தலைமன்னாரில் கடற்படை காவலில் உள்ளதாகவும், அவர்கள் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக மன்னார் கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக SLN தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 22 ஆம் திகதி மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இதேபோன்ற நடவடிக்கையில், கடற்படையினர் 10 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் முல்லைத்தீவில் இருந்து இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் இழுவை படகை பிடித்து சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஆஜர்படுத்தினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27ம் தேதி இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}