{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/J-apura-Uni-Dept-of-BEC-Economic-Forum-on-Friday/34-738984",
  "time_ut": 1661199147,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "J’apura Uni. Dept. of BEC Economic Forum on Friday",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "J’apura Uni. Dept. of BEC Economic Forum on Friday",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An economic forum on the theme “Confronting the Economic and Political Crisis in Sri Lanka: Priorities for Transformation” has been organised by the Research Centre for Business Economics and Development Studies (RCBEDS) of the Department of Business Economics, Faculty of Management Studies and Commerce, University of Sri Jayewardenepura.",
        "The forum will commemorate the third Annual Conference on Business Economics 2022 and the 20th Anniversary of the Department of Business Economics.",
        "The forum is scheduled on Friday 26 August 2022 from 4.30 p.m. onwards virtually via Zoom. Eminent resource persons from leading institutes in Sri Lanka and foreign institutes will address the theme under different perspectives.",
        "The panellists are: Central Bank of Sri Lanka former Governor Dr. Indrajit Coomaraswamy; Central Bank of Sri Lanka former Deputy Governor Dr. W.A. Wijewardene; Australian National University Professor in Economics Professor Premachandra Athukorala; Institute of Policy Studies Executive Director Dr. Dushni Weerakoon and The Ceylon Chamber of Commerce Chief Economist Shiran Fernando. Daily FT Chief Executive Officer Nisthar Cassim will moderate the forum.",
        "This forum is expected to enrich ongoing discussions on Sri Lanka’s present economic and political turmoil. The Department of Business Economics extends an open invitation for everyone to take part in the forum virtually."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "J’apura Uni.",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "BEC Economic Forum",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Friday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Confronting the Economic and Political Crisis in Sri Lanka: Priorities for Transformation",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Research Centre for Business Economics and Development Studies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Business Economics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faculty of Management Studies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th Anniversary of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Business Economics",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday 26 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indrajit Coomaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.A. Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian National University Professor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premachandra Athukorala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Institute of Policy Studies Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushni Weerakoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nisthar Cassim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Business Economics",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපුර යුනි. සිකුරාදා BEC ආර්ථික සංසදයේ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කළමනාකරණ අධ්‍යයන හා වාණිජ පීඨයේ ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික හා සංවර්ධන අධ්‍යයන පර්යේෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය (RCBEDS) විසින් “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම: පරිවර්තනය සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛතා” යන තේමාව යටතේ ආර්ථික සංසදයක් සංවිධානය කර ඇත. , ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය.",
        "මෙම සංසදය 2022 ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ තුන්වන වාර්ෂික සමුළුව සහ ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ 20 වැනි සංවත්සරය සමරනු ඇත.",
        "සංසදය 2022 අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා සවස 4.30 සිට පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය. Zoom හරහා ප්‍රායෝගිකව ඉදිරියට. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ආයතනවල සහ විදේශීය ආයතනවල කීර්තිමත් සම්පත් දායකයන් විවිධ දෘෂ්ටිකෝණ යටතේ තේමාව ආමන්ත්‍රණය කරනු ඇත.",
        "කමිටුවේ සාමාජිකයන් වන්නේ: ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ හිටපු අධිපති ආචාර්ය ඉන්ද්‍රජිත් කුමාරස්වාමි; ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය අධිපති ආචාර්ය ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ. ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ජාතික විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ආර්ථික විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ මහාචාර්ය ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර අතුකෝරල; ප්‍රතිපත්ති අධ්‍යයන ආයතනයේ විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ ආචාර්ය දුෂ්නි වීරකෝන් සහ ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ ප්‍රධාන ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥ ශිරාන් ප්‍රනාන්දු. Daily FT හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී Nishar Cassim විසින් සංසදය පාලනය කරනු ඇත.",
        "මෙම සංසදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන කැලඹීම පිළිබඳ අඛණ්ඩ සාකච්ඡා සාරවත් කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සෑම කෙනෙකුටම පාහේ සංසදයට සහභාගී වන ලෙස විවෘත ආරාධනාවක් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපුර යුනි.",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "BEC ආර්ථික සංසදය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිකුරාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම: පරිවර්තනය සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛතා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික විද්‍යාව සහ සංවර්ධන අධ්‍යයනය සඳහා පර්යේෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යාපාර ආර්ථික දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ අධ්‍යයන පීඨය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි සංවත්සරය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යාපාර ආර්ථික දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ද්‍රජිත් කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ.විජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ජාතික විශ්වවිද්‍යාල මහාචාර්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර අතුකෝරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රතිපත්ති අධ්‍යයන ආයතනය විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුෂ්නි වීරකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිස්තාර් කැසිම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්‍යාපාර ආර්ථික විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜபுரா யூனி. வெள்ளிக்கிழமை BEC பொருளாதார மன்றத்தின் துறை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"இலங்கையில் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்வது: மாற்றத்திற்கான முன்னுரிமைகள்\" என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் ஒரு பொருளாதார மன்றம் வணிக பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு ஆய்வுகளுக்கான ஆராய்ச்சி மையத்தால் (RCBEDS) வணிக பொருளாதாரம், மேலாண்மை கற்கைகள் மற்றும் வர்த்தக பீடத்தால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. , ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்.",
        "இந்த மன்றம் வணிகப் பொருளாதாரம் 2022 மற்றும் வணிகப் பொருளாதாரத் துறையின் 20வது ஆண்டு விழாவின் மூன்றாவது வருடாந்திர மாநாட்டை நினைவுகூரும்.",
        "மன்றம் 26 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை மாலை 4.30 மணிக்குத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஜூம் மூலம் கிட்டத்தட்ட. இலங்கையில் உள்ள முன்னணி நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு நிறுவனங்களைச் சேர்ந்த பிரபல வளவாளர்கள் வெவ்வேறு கண்ணோட்டங்களில் கருப்பொருளை உரையாற்றுவார்கள்.",
        "குழுவில் உள்ளவர்கள்: இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி இந்திரஜித் குமாரசுவாமி; இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் பிரதி ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி டபிள்யூ.ஏ.விஜேவர்தன; அவுஸ்திரேலிய தேசிய பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் பொருளாதாரப் பேராசிரியர் பிரேமச்சந்திர அத்துகோரள; கொள்கை கற்கைகள் நிறுவகத்தின் நிறைவேற்றுப் பணிப்பாளர் கலாநிதி துஷ்னி வீரகோன் மற்றும் இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் பிரதம பொருளாதார நிபுணர் ஷிரான் பெர்னாண்டோ. டெய்லி எஃப்டி தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி நிஸ்தர் காசிம் மன்றத்தை நடத்துவார்.",
        "இந்த மன்றம் இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் கொந்தளிப்பு தொடர்பான விவாதங்களை செழுமைப்படுத்தும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. வணிகப் பொருளாதாரத் திணைக்களம் அனைவருக்கும் மன்றத்தில் கிட்டத்தட்ட பங்குபெற ஒரு திறந்த அழைப்பை வழங்குகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜபுரா யூனி.",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "BEC பொருளாதார மன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "வெள்ளி",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையில் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்வது: மாற்றத்திற்கான முன்னுரிமைகள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு ஆய்வுகளுக்கான ஆராய்ச்சி மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக பொருளாதார துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை ஆய்வுகள் பீடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது ஆண்டு விழா",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக பொருளாதார துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.30 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திரஜித் குமாரசுவாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.ஏ.விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய தேசிய பல்கலைக்கழக பேராசிரியர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர அத்துகோரல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்டிடியூட் ஆஃப் பாலிசி ஸ்டடீஸ் எக்ஸிகியூட்டிவ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துஷ்னி வீரகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஸ்தர் காசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிகப் பொருளாதாரத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}