{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84722/gotabaya-arrives-at-residence-in-colombo",
  "time_ut": 1662176340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya arrives at residence in Colombo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya arrives at residence in Colombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who returned to the island last night, arrived at his residence at Malalasekara Mawatha in Colombo 07 at around 12.50 a.m. today.",
        "He returned to Sri Lanka via SQ 468 flight belonging to Singapore Airlines that touched down at the Bandaranaike International Airport (BIA) in Katunayake last night.",
        "The security in the area had been beefed up by the security forces and the police.",
        "The beleaguered president fled the country giving into months-long mass public demonstrations, demanding his immediate resignation, gained momentum in July after protesters stormed the President’s House in Colombo and several other state buildings in the capital.",
        "His first destination was the Maldives where he arrived in late on July 12, with his wife Ioma Rajapaksa and two security officers in a military plane. Sri Lanka Air Force (SLAF) had provided a military plane for Rajapaksa’s departure upon a request made by the government.",
        "The 73-year-old subsequently travelled to Singapore on a Saudi Airlines flight from the Maldives. He reached Changi International Airport in Singapore on July 14. His stay was later extended by the Singaporean authorities, issuing him another 14-day visit pass expiring on August 11.",
        "The Singapore government clarified that Rajapaksa was on a private visit and not granted asylum. During his temporary stay in Singapore, Rajapaksa tendered his letter of resignation to Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, officially stepping down from the presidency.",
        "Rajapaksa later flew to Thailand, seeking temporary shelter. Thailand’s foreign minister Don Pramudwinai clarified that Rajapaksa can stay in Thailand for 90 days because he is still a diplomatic passport holder.",
        "His return to Sri Lanka comes nearly 50 days after he fled the country to the Maldives in July."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malalasekara Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 12.50 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "468",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ioma Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changi International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singaporean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Pramudwinai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 50 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය කොළඹ නිවසට පැමිණෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ යළි දිවයිනට පැමිණි හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අද අලුයම 12.50 ට පමණ කොළඹ 07 මලලසේකර මාවතේ පිහිටි ඔහුගේ නිවසට පැමිණියා.",
        "ඔහු ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ කටුනායක බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළට (BIA) ළඟා වූ සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් SQ 468 ගුවන් යානයෙන් ආපසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය.",
        "ආරක්ෂක අංශ සහ පොලිසිය එක්ව ප්‍රදේශයේ ආරක්ෂාව තර කර තිබුණි.",
        "ව්‍යාකූල වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා මහජන මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ පවත්වමින් රටින් පලා ගියේය, විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ අගනුවර තවත් රාජ්‍ය ගොඩනැගිලි කිහිපයකට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසුව ජූලි මාසයේදී වේගවත් විය.",
        "ඔහුගේ පළමු ගමනාන්තය වූයේ මාලදිවයින වන අතර එහිදී ඔහු ජූලි 12 අගභාගයේදී ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනෙකු සමඟ හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් පැමිණියේය. රජය විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව (ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව) රාජපක්ෂගේ නික්මයාම සඳහා හමුදා ගුවන් යානයක් ලබා දී තිබුණි.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි ඔහු පසුව මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සෞදි ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව ගියේය. ඔහු ජූලි 14 වැනි දින සිංගප්පූරුවේ චැංගි ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළට ළඟා විය. පසුව සිංගප්පූරු බලධාරීන් විසින් ඔහුගේ රැඳී සිටීම දීර්ඝ කරන ලද අතර, අගෝස්තු 11 දිනෙන් කල් ඉකුත් වන තවත් දින 14ක සංචාරයක අවසර පත්‍රයක් ඔහුට නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක යෙදී සිටින බවත් සරණාගතභාවය ලබා නොදුන් බවත් සිංගප්පූරු රජය පැහැදිලි කළේය. සිංගප්පූරුවේ තාවකාලිකව රැඳී සිටින කාලය තුළ රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත භාරදෙමින් නිල වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් විය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ පසුව තාවකාලික නවාතැන් පතා තායිලන්තයට පියාසර කළේය. තායිලන්ත විදේශ අමාත්‍ය දොන් ප්‍රමුද්විනායි පැහැදිලි කළේ රාජපක්ෂ තවමත් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර හිමියෙකු බැවින් ඔහුට දින 90ක් තායිලන්තයේ රැඳී සිටිය හැකි බවයි.",
        "ඔහු නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන්නේ ජූලි මාසයේදී රටින් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගොස් දින 50 කට ආසන්න කාලයකට පසුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලලසේකර මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.50 පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "468",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැංගි ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොන් ප්‍රමුද්විනයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 50 කට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய கொழும்பில் உள்ள இல்லத்தை வந்தடைந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்றிரவு நாடு திரும்பிய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, இன்று நள்ளிரவு 12.50 மணியளவில் கொழும்பு 07 மலலசேகர மாவத்தையில் உள்ள அவரது இல்லத்திற்கு வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "நேற்றிரவு கட்டுநாயக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை (BIA) தொட்ட சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸுக்குச் சொந்தமான SQ 468 விமானத்தின் ஊடாக அவர் இலங்கை திரும்பினார்.",
        "இதையடுத்து அப்பகுதியில் பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் மற்றும் போலீசார் பலப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தடுமாறிய ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி பல மாதங்களாக வெகுஜன பொது ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களில் ஈடுபட்டார், அவர் உடனடியாக ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று கோரி, ஜூலை மாதம் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் தலைநகரில் உள்ள பல அரச கட்டிடங்களை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் தாக்கியதை அடுத்து வேகம் அதிகரித்தது.",
        "ஜூலை 12 ஆம் தேதி பிற்பகுதியில் அவர் தனது மனைவி அயோமா ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளுடன் இராணுவ விமானத்தில் மாலத்தீவு வந்தடைந்தார். அரசாங்கத்தின் கோரிக்கையின் பேரில் இலங்கை விமானப்படை (SLAF) ராஜபக்சேவின் புறப்படுவதற்கு இராணுவ விமானத்தை வழங்கியது.",
        "73 வயதான அவர் மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து சவுதி ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றார். அவர் ஜூலை 14 அன்று சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள சாங்கி சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை அடைந்தார். பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூர் அதிகாரிகளால் அவரது தங்குமிடம் நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் 14 நாள் பயண அனுமதியை அவருக்கு வழங்கியது ஆகஸ்ட் 11 அன்று காலாவதியாகும்.",
        "ராஜபக்சே தனிப்பட்ட பயணத்தில் இருப்பதாகவும், அடைக்கலம் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் சிங்கப்பூர் அரசு தெளிவுபடுத்தியது. சிங்கப்பூரில் தற்காலிகமாக தங்கியிருந்தபோது, ​​ராஜபக்ச தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவிடம் அளித்து, அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக அதிபர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகினார்.",
        "பின்னர் ராஜபக்ச தற்காலிக தங்குமிடம் தேடி தாய்லாந்து சென்றார். ராஜபக்ச இன்னும் ராஜதந்திர பாஸ்போர்ட் வைத்திருப்பதால் தாய்லாந்தில் 90 நாட்கள் தங்கலாம் என்று தாய்லாந்து வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் டான் பிரமுத்வினாய் தெளிவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "ஜூலை மாதம் நாட்டை விட்டு மாலத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்ற அவர் கிட்டத்தட்ட 50 நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு இலங்கைக்கு திரும்பினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலலசேகர மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12.50 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "468",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயோமா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் பிரமுத்வினை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 50 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}