{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131632",
  "time_ut": 1658045269,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தலைமன்னார் கடலில் மீன்பிடிக்காகச் சென்ற 3 மீனவர்களை காணவில்லை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "3 fishermen who went fishing in Thalaimannar sea are missing",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been reported that three fishermen who went to the sea in a boat from Thalaimannar Pier are missing, but the said three fishermen are being searched for and there is no information about them from anywhere.",
        "Three fishermen belonging to Thalaimannar Pier, Rasathurai Rasasekar (52 years old), Rajamurthy Mohanraj (50 years old) and Raji Janath (27 years old) as usual, from Thalaimannar Pier sector to catch net fish in the North Sea on Thursday 14th in an outboard motor boat (boat) .OVRB-A-4138 MNRI) have departed.",
        "Since they did not return to the shore as usual, the fishermen and marines of this area are searching from Friday 15th until today.",
        "But till the 16th Saturday, it is reported that neither they nor the boat they went to have been found. It is also reported that strong winds have been blowing in this area for the past couple of days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thalaimannar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar Pier",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar Pier",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rasathurai Rasasekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajamurthy Mohanraj",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Raji Janath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar Pier",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Sea",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday 15th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 16th Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past couple of days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම මුහුදේ මසුන් ඇල්ලීමට ගිය ධීවරයින් තිදෙනෙකු අතුරුදන්",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "තලෙයිමන්නාරම තොටුපළේ සිට බෝට්ටුවකින් මුහුදට ගිය ධීවරයින් තිදෙනෙකු අතුරුදන්ව ඇති බව වාර්තා වූ නමුත් එම ධීවරයින් තිදෙනා සෙවීමේ කටයුතු සිදුකරන අතර ඔවුන් පිළිබඳ කිසිඳු ස්ථානයකින් තොරතුරක් ලැබී නොමැත.",
        "තලෙයිමන්නාරම තොටුපළට අයත් රාසතුරෙයි රාසසේකර් (අවුරුදු 52), රාජමූර්ති මොහාන්රාජ් (අවුරුදු 50) සහ රාජි ජනත් (අවුරුදු 27) යන ධීවරයින් තිදෙනා සුපුරුදු පරිදි තලෙයිමන්නාරම පියර් අංශයේ සිට උතුරු මුහුදේ දැල් මසුන් ඇල්ලීම සඳහා 14 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා විවෘත එන්ජින් ඔරුවකින් (බෝට්ටුව) .OVRB-A-4138 MNRI) පිටත් වී ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන් සුපුරුදු පරිදි ගොඩබිමට නොපැමිණි බැවින් 15 සිකුරාදා සිට අද දක්වා මෙම ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවරයින් සහ නාවිකයින් සෝදිසි කරති.",
        "එහෙත් 16 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා වනතුරුත් ඔවුන් හෝ ඔවුන් ගිය බෝට්ටුව හමු වී නොමැති බව වාර්තා වේ. පසුගිය දින දෙකේ සිට මෙම ප්‍රදේශයට තද සුළං හමා ගිය බවද වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම පියර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම පියර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාසතුරෙයි රාසසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 52 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජමූර්ති මොහාන්රාජ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 50 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජි ජනත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 27 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම පියර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මුහුද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தலைமன்னார் கடலில் மீன்பிடிக்காகச் சென்ற 3 மீனவர்களை காணவில்லை",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "தலைமன்னார் பியரிலிருந்து ஒரு படகில் மீன் பிடிக்காக கடலுக்குச் சென்ற மீனவர்கள் மூவரை காணவில்லையென தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், குறித்த 3 மீனவர்களும் தேடப்பட்டு வருவதுடன் இவர்களைப்பற்றி இதுவரை எங்கிருந்தும் தகவல்கள் வரவில்லையெனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தலைமன்னார் பியரைச் சார்ந்த மூன்று மீனவர்கள் ராசதுரை இராசசேகர் (வயது 52) ராஜமூர்த்தி மோகன்ராஜ் (வயது 50) ராஜி ஜனாத் (வயது 27) ஆகிய மூவரும் வழமைபோன்று தலைமன்னார் பியர் துறையிலிருந்து வட கடலில் வலிச்சல் வலை மீன் பிடிக்காக வியாழக்கிழமை 14 ஆம் திகதி) பிற்பகல் ஒரு மணியளவில் ஒரு வெளிக்கள இயந்திரப் படகில் (படகு இல. ஓஎவ்ஆர்பி-ஏ-4138 எம்என்ரி)  புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் அன்று வழமைபோன்று கரை திரும்பாததால் இப் பகுதி மீனவர்களும் கடற்படையினரும் 15 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை  தொடக்கம் இன்று வரை தேடுதலில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "ஆனால் 16 ஆம் திகதி சனிக்கிழமை வரைக்கும் இவர்களையோ இவர்கள் சென்ற படகையோ இதுவரை கண்டு பிடிக்கப்படவில்லையென தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது. கடந்த ஓரிரு தினங்களாக இவ் பகுதியில் பலத்த காற்று வீசியதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் பையர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் பையர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராசதுரை ராசசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜமூர்த்தி மோகன்ராஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜி ஜனத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் பையர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன் 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16வது சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}