{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/3rd-session-of-9th-parliament-tomorrow-3/",
  "time_ut": 1659422820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "3rd session of 9th Parliament tomorrow (3)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "3rd session of 9th Parliament tomorrow (3)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The gazette notification issued concluding the second session of the Ninth Parliament on the 28th of July with effect from midnight.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe prorogued the Parliament following the powers vested in him with Article 70 (1) of the Constitution with effect from midnight yesterday (28) announcing that the third session of the Ninth Parliament will commence on August 3rd at 10.30 am.",
        "According to subsections (a) and (b) of Article 33 of the Constitution, after the end of one session of Parliament and a new session commences, the President has the opportunity to ceremonially declare open the Parliament and preside over it to present the Government's Policy Statement.",
        "When the Parliament is prorogued, the questions and motions which were not considered by the Parliament up until then are abolished, and the Members of Parliament thus have to take it up under the standing orders.",
        "Furthermore, the Committees other than the Liaison Committee of Parliament, Committee on High Posts, and Select Committees should be re-constituted following the beginning of the new session.",
        "The second session of the Ninth Parliament was from January 18, 2022, to July 28, 2022, under which the Parliament met for 48 days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3rd",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9th Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 28th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight yesterday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 3rd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Article 33 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Committees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Liaison Committee of Parliament, Committee on High Posts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Select Committees",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 18, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "9 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 3 වැනි සැසිවාරය හෙට (3)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවැනි සැසිවාරය ජූලි මස 28 වැනිදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි අවසන් කරමින් නිකුත් කළ ගැසට් නිවේදනය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 (1) වගන්තියෙන් තමා වෙත පැවරී ඇති බලතල අනුව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ (28) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තැබුවේ නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තෙවැනි සැසිවාරය අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා පෙරවරු 10.30ට ආරම්භ වන බව ය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 33 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ (අ) සහ (ආ) උප වගන්තිවලට අනුව, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ එක් සැසිවාරයක් අවසන් වී නව සැසිවාරයක් ආරම්භ වූ පසු, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව උත්සවාකාරයෙන් විවෘත කිරීමටත්, එහි මුලසුන දැරීමටත්, රජයේ කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අවස්ථාව තිබේ. ප්රතිපත්ති ප්රකාශය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තබන විට එතෙක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් සලකා නොබැලූ ප්‍රශ්න සහ යෝජනා අහෝසි වන අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ස්ථාවර නියෝග යටතේ එය විභාගයට ගැනීමට සිදුවේ.",
        "තවද, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ කමිටුව, උසස් තනතුරු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව සහ තේරීම් කාරක සභා හැර අනෙකුත් කාරක සභා නව සැසිවාරය ආරම්භයෙන් පසුව නැවත පිහිටුවනු ලැබිය යුතුය.",
        "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවන සැසිවාරය 2022 ජනවාරි 18 සිට 2022 ජූලි 28 දක්වා වූ අතර ඒ යටතේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දින 48ක් රැස්විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 28 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 33 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරක සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සම්බන්ධතා කමිටුව, උසස් තනතුරු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරක සභා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 48 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "9வது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் 3வது அமர்வு நாளை (3)",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது அமர்வை ஜூலை 28 ஆம் திகதி நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் நிறைவு செய்யும் வகையில் வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றாவது அமர்வு ஆகஸ்ட் 3 ஆம் திகதி காலை 10.30 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பமாகும் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று (28) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் அரசியலமைப்பின் 70 (1) வது சரத்தின் மூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்தை ஒத்திவைத்தார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 33வது பிரிவு (a) மற்றும் (b) இன் உட்பிரிவுகளின்படி, பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஒரு கூட்டத்தொடர் முடிவடைந்து புதிய அமர்வு தொடங்கும் போது, ​​பாராளுமன்றத்தை சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக திறப்பதாக அறிவித்து அதற்கு தலைமை தாங்கி அரசாங்கத்தை முன்வைக்க ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது. காப்புறுதி அறிக்கை.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் போது, ​​அதுவரை பாராளுமன்றத்தால் பரிசீலிக்கப்படாத கேள்விகள் மற்றும் பிரேரணைகள் இரத்து செய்யப்பட்டு, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் நிலையியற் கட்டளையின் கீழ் அதனை எடுத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "மேலும், பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இணைப்புக் குழு, உயர் பதவிகளுக்கான குழு மற்றும் தெரிவுக்குழுக்கள் தவிர ஏனைய குழுக்கள் புதிய அமர்வின் தொடக்கத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து மீண்டும் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது அமர்வு ஜனவரி 18, 2022 முதல் ஜூலை 28, 2022 வரை நடைபெற்றது, இதன் கீழ் பாராளுமன்றம் 48 நாட்களுக்கு கூடியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9வது பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 33",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழுக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இணைப்புக் குழு, உயர் பதவிகளுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்வுக் குழுக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 18, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}