{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/பிரதான-செய்திகள்/தலதா-மாளிகைக்கு-ஜனாதிபதி-விஜயம்/46-301364",
  "time_ut": 1659171954,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தலதா மாளிகைக்கு ஜனாதிபதி விஜயம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President's visit to Dalatha Palace",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe visited Kandy's historic Talatha House this morning (30) and engaged in religious activities.",
        "On his visit to Dalatha Palace, the President was welcomed by Kandy Mayor Kesara Senanayake and ministers and escorted to the main entrance of Dalatha Palace.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe was welcomed by Thiavadana Nilame Pradeep Nilanga Thela and Basnayake Nilamemar of the Four Great Churches.",
        "After that, the President went to the upper floor where the Holy Tantadatu is enshrined in the Dalatha House, where he offered floral tributes, performed religious services and received the blessings of the Maha Sangha.",
        "After participating in the religious services, President Ranil went to the space reserved for special guests in the Talatha House and left a memorial note.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe is scheduled to meet Malwattu-Askiri Mahanayake Theras this afternoon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dalatha Palace",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talatha House",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dalatha Palace",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesara Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalatha Palace",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiavadana Nilame",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilanga Thela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basnayake Nilamemar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Dalatha House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Talatha House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahanayake Theras",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති දළදා මාලිගාවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (30) පෙරවරුවේ මහනුවර ඓතිහාසික තලතා නිවස වෙත ගොස් ආගමික වතාවත්වල නිරත විය.",
        "දළදා මාලිගය වෙත ගිය ජනාධිපතිතුමා මහනුවර නගරාධිපති කේසර සේනානායක මහතා ඇතුළු මැති ඇමැතිවරුන් විසින් පිළිගෙන දළදා මාලිගාවේ ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව වෙත කැඳවාගෙන යනු ලැබීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පිළිගනු ලැබුවේ තියවඩන නිලමේ ප්‍රදීප් නිලංග තෙල සහ සතර මහා දෙව්මැදුරේ බස්නායක නිලමේමාර විසිනි.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව දළදා මන්දිරයේ ශුද්ධ වූ තන්තදාතු සමිඳුන් තැන්පත් කර ඇති උඩුමහලට ගිය ජනාධිපතිතුමා එහිදී පුෂ්පෝපහාර පුද කර ආගමික වතාවත් සිදු කර මහා සංඝරත්නයේ ආශිර්වාද ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "ආගමික වතාවත්වලට සහභාගි වීමෙන් අනතුරුව තලතා මන්දිරයේ විශේෂ අමුත්තන් සඳහා වෙන් කර තිබූ ඉඩ ප්‍රදේශයට ගිය ජනාධිපති රනිල් සමරු සටහනක් තැබීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පස්වරුවේ මල්වතු - අස්කිරි මහානායක හිමිවරුන් බැහැ දැකීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දලතා වලව්ව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලතා නිවස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දලතා වලව්ව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesara Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දලතා වලව්ව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තියවඩන නිලමේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලංග තෙල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නායක නිලමේමර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දලතා නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලතා නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහානායක හිමිවරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தலதா மாளிகைக்கு ஜனாதிபதி விஜயம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, கண்டி வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க தலதா மாளிகைக்கு இன்று (30) காலை சென்று சமயக்கிரியைகளில் ஈடுபட்டார்.",
        "தலதா மாளிகைக்கு வருகை தந்த ஜனாதிபதி, கண்டி நகரபிதா கேசர சேனநாயக்க மற்றும் அமைச்சர்களினால் வரவேற்கப்பட்டு தலதா மாளிகையின் பிரதான நுழைவாயிலுக்கு அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தியவடன நிலமே பிரதீப் நிலங்க தேல மற்றும் நான்கு மகா தேவாலய பஸ்நாயக்க நிலமேமார் வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர், தலதா மாளிகையில் புனித தந்ததாது பிரதிஷ்டை செய்யப்பட்டிருக்கும் மேல்மாடிக்குச் சென்ற ஜனாதிபதி, அங்கு மலர் அஞ்சலி செலுத்தி சமய வழிபாடுகளில் ஈடுபட்டு மகா சங்கத்தினரின் ஆசிர்வாதங்களைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "சமய வழிபாடுகளில் ஈடுபட்டதன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில்,  தலதா மாளிகையில் சிறப்பு விருந்தினர்களுக்காக ஒதுக்கப்பட்டிருக்கும் இடத்துக்குக்குச் சென்று நினைவுக் குறிப்பேட்டில் நினைவுக் குறிப்பொன்றை இட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இன்று பிற்பகல் மல்வத்து - அஸ்கிரி மகாநாயக்க தேரர்களை சந்திக்க உள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தலதா அரண்மனை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலதா வீடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலதா அரண்மனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesara Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலதா அரண்மனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தியவதன நிலமே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீலாங்க தேலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஸ்நாயக்க நிலமேமர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலதா மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலதா வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாநாயக்க தேரர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}