{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/‘ටෝකන්’-ඉවරයි-‘ඇප්එක‘-වැඩ/1-616683",
  "time_ut": 1658221702,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘ටෝකන්’ ඉවරයි ‘ඇප්එක‘ වැඩ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The 'token' is over, the 'app' is working",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Kumara Rajapaksa, President of the Gas Station Owners Association, said today (19) morning that all the 'tokens' previously given to obtain fuel are invalid and from tomorrow (21) fuel will be issued only according to the last digit of the vehicle's registration number according to the 'National Fuel Licence'.",
        "Mr. Kumara Rajapaksa, President of the Petrol Station Owners' Association, said this at a press conference currently being held in Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gas Station Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petrol Station Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘ටෝකන්’ ඉවරයි ‘ඇප්එක‘ වැඩ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීම සඳහා මීට පෙර දුන් සියලුම ‘ටෝකන්’ අවලංගු බවත් අනිද්දා (21) සිට ‘ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රය’ අනුව වාහනයේ ලියාපදිංචි අංකයේ අවසන් ඉලක්කම අනුව පමණක් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන බවත් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද (19) පෙරවරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "කොළඹදී දැන් පැවැත්වෙන මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ මහතා එසේ පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "'டோக்கன்' முடிந்தது, 'ஆப்' வேலை செய்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள் பெறுவதற்கு முன்னர் வழங்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து 'டோக்கன்'களும் செல்லுபடியற்றவை எனவும், நாளை (21) முதல் எரிபொருளின் கடைசி இலக்கத்தின் அடிப்படையில் மட்டுமே எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படும் எனவும் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.குமார ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று (19) காலை தெரிவித்தார். 'தேசிய எரிபொருள் உரிமத்தின்' படி வாகனத்தின் பதிவு எண்.",
        "கொழும்பில் தற்போது இடம்பெற்றுவரும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.குமார ராஜபக்ஷ இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிவாயு நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}