{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132224",
  "time_ut": 1658733787,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்ப கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் -  பெல்பொல விபஸ்சி நாயக்க தேரர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President should be given time to build the nation - Belbola Vipassi Nayake Thera",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The registrar of Kota Viharai Party, Japan's Prime Sanganayakar Venerable Belbola Vipassi Nayake Thera has said that the current President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who has a long political experience, should be given time to build the country.",
        "Thera pointed out that everyone should give up the system of ousting the rulers by conducting protests and cooperate with the President's plan to free the country from the current economic crisis and solve the problems of the people.",
        "Pointing out that the present President has fearlessly accepted the challenge while the country faces disaster, Thera expressed confidence that he will be able to overcome all challenges.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe, yesterday afternoon (24) went to Veheragoda Puradhana Viharai, Setavatta yesterday afternoon and while he was engaged in religious worship, the thera mentioned this while delivering a dedication speech.",
        "After visiting the vicar, the President worshiped Bodhi and engaged in religious activities, the Maha Sangha including Ambanwala Gnanaloka Thera of the Vicar President Sangha recited Prith and offered blessings to the President.",
        "After that, the President met the members of the Maha Sangha and inquired about their welfare.",
        "Historical Vihara Setavatta, Veharakoda Puradhana Viharai, Smt. Helena Wijewardena and Mr. It is a holy land given to Buddhism by Don Philip Wijewardana.",
        "Buddha Sasana Minister Vidura Wickramanayake, Member of Parliament Suren Raghavan and Executive Council President Amari Manthika Wijewardana and Secretary Channa Wickramasinghe were also present in the event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Belbola Vipassi Nayake",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota Viharai Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veheragoda Puradhana Viharai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Setavatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maha",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambanwala Gnanaloka Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vicar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prith",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Historical Vihara Setavatta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puradhana Viharai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Smt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Helena Wijewardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "It",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Philip Wijewardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha Sasana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidura Wickramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Suren Raghavan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amari Manthika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channa Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතිය ගොඩනැගීමට ජනපතිට කල් දිය යුතුයි - බෙල්බොල විපස්සි නාහිමි",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "දීර්ඝ දේශපාලන අත්දැකීම් ඇති වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට රට ගොඩනැගීමට කාලය ලබාදිය යුතු බව කොට විහාරයි පක්ෂයේ ලේඛකාධිකාරී, ජපාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය සංඝනායක පූජ්‍ය බෙල්පොල විපස්සි නාහිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "උද්ඝෝෂණ පවත්වමින් පාලකයින් එළවා දැමීමේ ක්‍රමය සියලු දෙනාම අත්හැර වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් රට මුදාගෙන ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ වැඩපිළිවෙළට සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කළ යුතු බවද උන්වහන්සේ පෙන්වා දුන්හ.",
        "රට විපතට පත්වෙමින් තිබියදී වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා නොබියව එම අභියෝගය භාරගෙන ඇති බව පෙන්වා දුන් උන්වහන්සේ සියලු අභියෝග ජයගැනීමට හැකිවනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාසය පළ කළහ.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ (24) පස්වරුවේ සේතාවත්ත වෙහෙරගොඩ පුරාධාන විහාරස්ථානය වෙත ගොස් ආගමික වතාවත්වල නිරත වෙමින් සිටියදී පුණ්‍ය මහෝත්සවයේ පුණ්‍යෝත්සවය පවත්වමින් උන්වහන්සේ මේ බව සඳහන් කළහ.",
        "විහාරාධිපති හිමියන් බැහැදැක බෝධිය වැඳ පුදාගෙන ආගමික වතාවත්වල නිරත වූ ජනාධිපතිතුමා අනතුරුව විහාරාධිපති අඹන්වල ඤාණාලෝක හිමියන් ඇතුළු මහා සංඝරත්නය පිරිත් සජ්ඣායනා කර ජනාධිපතිතුමා වෙත ආශිර්වාද පළ කළහ.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව මහා සංඝරත්නය ද හමු වූ ජනාධිපතිතුමා උන්වහන්සේගේ සුවදුක් විමසා සිටියේය.",
        "ඓතිහාසික විහාර සේතාවත්ත, වෙහරකොඩ පුරාණ විහාරය, ශ්‍රීමා. හෙලේනා විජේවර්ධන සහ Mr. එය දොන් පිලිප් විජේවර්ධනයන් විසින් බුදුදහමට දායාද කළ පුණ්‍ය භූමියකි.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට බුද්ධ ශාසන අමාත්‍ය විදුර වික්‍රමනායක, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සුරේන් රාඝවන්, විධායක සභාවේ සභාපතිනී අමාරි මන්තිකා විජේවර්ධන, ලේකම් චන්න වික්‍රමසිංහ යන මහත්ම මහත්මීහුද එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බෙල්බෝල විපස්සි නායක",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හිමියෝය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොට විහාරයි පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙහෙරගොඩ පුරාණ විහාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙටවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹන්වල ඤාණාලෝක හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රිත්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඓතිහාසික විහාර සෙටවත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුරාධාන විහාරයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Smt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙලේනා විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොන් පිලිප් විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ ශාසන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුර වික්‍රමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සුරේන් රාඝවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාරි මන්තිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්න වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்ப கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் -  பெல்பொல விபஸ்சி நாயக்க தேரர்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீண்டகால அரசியல் அனுபவமுள்ள தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்ப கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டுமென கோட்டை விகாரை தரப்பின் பதிவாளர், ஜப்பானின் பிரதம சங்கநாயக்கர் வணக்கத்திற்குரிய பெல்பொல விபஸ்சி நாயக்க தேரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "போராட்டங்களை நடத்தி ஆட்சியாளர்களை விரட்டியடிக்கும் முறையை விட்டுவிட்டு, தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து நாட்டை விடுவித்து மக்கள் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும் ஜனாதிபதியின் திட்டத்திற்கு அனைவரும் ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்க வேண்டும் எனவும் தேரர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "நாடு பேரழிவை எதிர்நோக்கியிருக்கும் வேளையில், தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி அச்சமின்றி சவாலை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ளதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டிய தேரர், சகல சவால்களையும் வெற்றிகொள்ள அவரால் முடியும் என நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நேற்று (24) பிற்பகல் சேதவத்த, வெஹெரகொட புராதன விகாரைக்கு சென்று சமய வழிபாடுகளில் ஈடுபட்ட வேளையில், அனுசாசனை உரை நிகழ்த்திய தேரர் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "விகாரைக்கு வருகை தந்த ஜனாதிபதி, போதியை வழிபட்டு சமய கிரியைகளில் ஈடுபட்டதுடன், விகாராதிபதி சங்கைக்குரிய அம்பன்வல ஞானாலோக தேரர் உள்ளிட்ட மகா சங்கத்தினர் பிரித் பாராயணம் செய்து ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஆசீர்வாதங்களை வழங்கினர்.",
        "அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி, மகா சங்கத்தினரை சந்தித்து அவர்களின் சுக நலன்களை கேட்டறிந்தார்.",
        "வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க விகாரையான சேதவத்த, வெஹரகொட புராதன விகாரை, திருமதி. ஹெலெனா விஜேவர்தன மற்றும் திரு. டொன் பிலிப் விஜேவர்தன பௌத்த மதத்துக்கு வழங்கிய புண்ணிய பூமியாகும்.",
        "புத்தசாசன அமைச்சர் விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்க, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சுரேன் ராகவன் மற்றும் நிறைவேற்று சபையின் தலைவர் அமரி மந்திகா விஜேவர்தன, செயலாளர் சன்ன விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் உள்ளிட்ட பலரும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பெல்போலா விபாசி நாயகே",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா விஹாரை கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெஹெரகொட புராதன விகாரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேடவட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பன்வல ஞானலோக தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விகார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரித்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரலாற்றுச் சிறப்புமிக்க விகாரை செதவத்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புராண விஹாரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீமதி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெலினா விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொன் பிலிப் விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்த சாசனம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் சுரேன் ராகவன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரி மந்திகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ன விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}