{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132028",
  "time_ut": 1658477313,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் முன்னிலையில் அமைச்சர்கள் பதவிப்பிரமாணம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ministers taking oath in presence of President Ranil",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "While Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as President yesterday in the presence of the Chief Justice, the new cabinet including the Prime Minister was sworn in in the presence of the President.",
        "Dinesh Gunawardena was sworn in as the new Prime Minister in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe at the Prime Minister's Office on Friday morning, 22nd today.",
        "In this case, Dinesh Gunawardena was sworn in as the 15th Prime Minister in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Sushil Premajayantha was sworn in as Education Minister in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Douglas Devananda was sworn in as Minister of Fisheries and Resources in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Keheliya Rambukwela was sworn in as Minister of Health and Water Supply in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Bandula Gunawardena was sworn in as the Minister of Transport, Highways and Media in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Mahinda Amaraweera was sworn in as the Minister of Agriculture and Wildlife Conservation in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "President's Counsel Vijayadasa Rajapaksa was sworn in as the Minister of Justice, Constitutional Reform and Prison Affairs in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Hareen Fernando was sworn in as Minister of Tourism and Land Affairs in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Ramesh Patirana was sworn in as Minister of Industries and Plantation Development in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Prasanna Ranatunga was sworn in as the Minister of Urban and Housing Development in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Ali Sabri was sworn in as Minister of External Affairs in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Vidura Wickramanayake was sworn in as the Minister of Buddhism and Religious Affairs in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Kanchana Wijesekera was sworn in as Minister of Power and Electricity in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Nazir Ahkamad was sworn in as Environment Minister in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Roshan Ranasinghe was sworn in as Minister of Sports and Youth Affairs in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Manusha Nanayakkara was sworn in as Minister of Foreign Employment and Industry in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Tran Alas was sworn in as Minister of Public Security in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Nalin Fernando was sworn in as Minister of Trade and Food Security in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena was sworn in as the Minister of Local Government and Public Administration in the presence of President Ranil Wickremesinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sushil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Counsel Vijayadasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hareen Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Minister of Industries and Plantation Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Housing Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vidura Wickramanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nazir Ahkamad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Roshan Ranasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Youth Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Employment and Industry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tran Alas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති රනිල් ඉදිරියේ ඇමැතිවරු දිවුරුම් දෙති",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගවිනිසුරුවරයා ඉදිරියේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දුන් අතර, අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඇතුළු නව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා නව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස අද (22) සිකුරාදා පෙරවරුවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා 15 වැනි අගමැතිවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "සුෂිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද මහතා ධීවර හා සම්පත් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය හා ජල සම්පාදන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වෙල මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග හා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම හා වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "අධිකරණ, ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "සංචාරක හා ඉඩම් කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "රමේෂ් පතිරණ මහතා කර්මාන්ත හා වැවිලි සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "නාගරික හා නිවාස සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "අලි සබ්රි මහතා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "විදුර වික්‍රමනායක මහතා බුද්ධාගම හා ආගමික කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "කංචන විජේසේකර විදුලිබල හා විදුලිබල අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "නසීර් අහමඩ් මහතා පරිසර අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ක්‍රීඩා හා යෞවන කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස රොෂාන් රණසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "විදේශ රැකියා හා කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ට්‍රාන් අලස් මහතා මහජන ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා වෙළෙඳ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පළාත් පාලන හා රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුෂිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වෙල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කර්මාන්ත හා වැවිලි සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවාස සංවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුර වික්‍රමනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොෂාන් රණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෞවන කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ රැකියා සහ කර්මාන්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රාන් අලාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் முன்னிலையில் அமைச்சர்கள் பதவிப்பிரமாணம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்றையதினம் பாராளுமன்ற கட்டத்தொகுதியில் பிரதம நீதியரசர் முன்னிலையில் பதவியேற்ற நிலையில் இன்றையதினம் பிரதமர் உள்ளிட்ட புதிய அமைச்சரவை ஜனாதிபதி முன்னிலையில் பதவியேற்றுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று 22 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை காலை புதிய பிரதமராக தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்துள்ள நிலையில் தற்போது அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்தனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், 15 ஆவது பிரதமராக தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்துக்கொண்டார்.",
        "கல்வி அமைச்சராக சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "கடற்றொழில் வளங்கள் அமைச்சராக டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் நீர் வழங்கல் அமைச்சராக கெஹெலிய ரம்புக்வெல ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சராக பந்துல குணவர்தன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "விவசாயத்துறை மற்றும் வனவிலங்கு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சராக மஹிந்த அமரவீர ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "நீதி, அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரம் அமைச்சராக ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி விஜயதாஸ ராஜபக்‌ஷ ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "சுற்றுலாத்துறை மற்றும் காணி விவகாரத்துறை அமைச்சராக ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "கைத்தொழில் மற்றும் பெருந்தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அமைச்சராக ரமேஷ் பத்திரன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "நகர மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அபிவிருத்தி அமைச்சராக பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "வெளிவிவகாரத்துறை அமைச்சராக அலி சப்ரி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "பௌத்த மதம் மற்றும் மத விவகார அமைச்சராக விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "வலுச்சக்தி மற்றும் மின்சாரத்துறை அமைச்சராக காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "சுற்றாடற்றுறை அமைச்சராக நஸீர் அஹகமட் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "விளையாட்டுத்துறை மற்றும் இளைஞர் விவகார அமைச்சராக ரொஷான் ரணசிங்க ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்புகள் மற்றும் தொழில் அமைச்சராக மனுஷ நாணயக்கார ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "பொதுமக்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சராக டிரான் அலஸ் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சராக நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "உள்ளூராட்சி மற்றும் அரச நிர்வாக அமைச்சராக பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கைத்தொழில் மற்றும் பெருந்தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அமைச்சர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீட்டு வசதி மேம்படுத்துதல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு விவகாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொஷான் ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளைஞர் விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் தொழில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிரான் ஐயோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}