{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-power-regulator-proposes-average-tariff-hike-to-rs32-a-unit-96528/",
  "time_ut": 1656328620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka power regulator proposes average tariff hike to Rs32 a unit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka power regulator proposes average tariff hike to Rs32 a unit",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s power regulator has proposed an average tariff hike to 28 a kilowatt hour  from the current about 16 rupees, with low users to get a subsidy from the Treasury, Public Utilities Commission Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said.",
        "The Ceylon Electricity Board has requested revenue of 512 billion rupees.",
        "The regulator has asked for a Treasury subsidy of 65 billion rupees a year to from the Treasury for low income users.",
        "The Treasury has raised value added tax to 12 percent from 8 percent to get more taxes from the people.",
        "The CEB has requested total revenue of 512 billion rupees, but it does not include the most recent diesel price hikes, Ratnayake said.",
        "The CEB’s proposed tariff hike and the counter proposal will be place for public consultation from tomorrow, he said.",
        "Foreign currency earnings customers would be required to settle bill in US dollars, he said. (Colombo/June27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "512 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලි බල නියාමකය සාමාන්‍ය ගාස්තු ඒකකයක් රුපියල් 32 දක්වා වැඩි කිරීමට යෝජනා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල නියාමකයා විසින් දැනට පවතින රුපියල් 16 සිට කිලෝවොට් පැයක් 28 දක්වා සාමාන්‍ය ගාස්තු වැඩිවීමක් යෝජනා කර ඇති අතර, භාණ්ඩාගාරයෙන් සහනාධාරයක් ලබා ගැනීමට අඩු පරිශීලකයින්ට හැකි බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය රුපියල් බිලියන 512 ක ආදායමක් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "නියාමකයා අඩු ආදායම්ලාභීන් සඳහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයෙන් වසරකට රුපියල් බිලියන 65 ක භාණ්ඩාගාර සහනාධාරයක් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "භාණ්ඩාගාරය ජනතාවගෙන් වැඩි බදු මුදලක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා එකතු කළ අගය මත බද්ද සියයට 8 සිට සියයට 12 දක්වා ඉහළ දමා තිබෙනවා.",
        "ලංවිම සමස්ත ආදායම රුපියල් බිලියන 512 ක් ඉල්ලා ඇති නමුත් මෑතකාලීන ඩීසල් මිල ඉහළ දැමීම් එයට ඇතුළත් නොවන බව රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ යෝජිත ගාස්තු ඉහළ නැංවීම සහ ප්‍රති යෝජනාව හෙට සිට මහජන අදහස් විමසීමට නියමිත බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "විදේශ මුදල් ඉපැයීමේ ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට බිල්පත් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් වලින් පියවිය යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 512 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 65 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 12 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 512 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மின்சார ஒழுங்குமுறை நிறுவனம் சராசரியாக ஒரு யூனிட் கட்டணத்தை 32 ரூபாயாக உயர்த்த முன்மொழிகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் மின்சார ஒழுங்குமுறை நிறுவனம் சராசரியாக ஒரு கிலோவொட் மணித்தியாலத்திற்கு 16 ரூபாயில் இருந்து சராசரியாக ஒரு கிலோவொட் மணித்தியாலத்திற்கு 28 கட்டண உயர்வை முன்மொழிந்துள்ளது, குறைந்த பாவனையாளர்கள் திறைசேரியிலிருந்து மானியத்தைப் பெறுவார்கள் என பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் ஜானக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை 512 பில்லியன் ரூபா வருமானத்தை கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் பாவனையாளர்களுக்காக திறைசேரியிலிருந்து வருடத்திற்கு 65 பில்லியன் ரூபாவை திறைசேரி மானியமாக வழங்குமாறு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம் கேட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மக்களிடம் இருந்து அதிக வரிகளை பெறுவதற்காக திறைசேரி மதிப்பு கூட்டு வரியை 8 சதவீதத்தில் இருந்து 12 சதவீதமாக உயர்த்தியுள்ளது.",
        "CEB மொத்த வருமானமாக 512 பில்லியன் ரூபாவைக் கோரியுள்ளது, ஆனால் அதில் சமீபத்திய டீசல் விலை உயர்வுகள் அடங்கவில்லை என்று ரத்நாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "CEBயின் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட கட்டண உயர்வு மற்றும் எதிர் முன்மொழிவு நாளை முதல் பொதுமக்களின் ஆலோசனைக்கு வைக்கப்படும், என்றார்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு நாணயம் ஈட்டும் வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் அமெரிக்க டாலரில் பில் செலுத்த வேண்டும், என்றார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "512 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}