{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/rambukkana-shooting-hr-commission-tells-ag-to-file-criminal-action-against-ssp-keerthiratne/",
  "time_ut": 1656402840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "#Rambukkana Shooting: HR Commission tells AG to file criminal action against SSP Keerthiratne",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "#Rambukkana Shooting: HR Commission tells AG to file criminal action against SSP Keerthiratne",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka has advised the Attorney General to Investigate and file appropriate criminal proceedings against SSP K. B. Keerthiratne with regard to the Rambukkana Shooting.",
        "The Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka also directed the Inspector General of Police to take disciplinary action against Former SSP for Kegalle K. B. Keerthiratne over the Rambukkana shooting.",
        "The HRCSL in a statement said that the report on the shooting on protestors by police was prepared and is ready.",
        "“Orders to shoot at people who were running away, and not a threat to police is illegal,” said the Human Rights Commission.",
        "The Rambukkana protests erupted over delayed petrol deliveries and sharp price increases in petrol and diesel announced on Monday, the 18th of April 2022.",
        "On Tuesday, the 19th of April 2022, demonstrators blocked main roads and a railway line.",
        "Police began directing tear gas at thousands of protesters in the afternoon and then suddenly, without warning, opened fire with live rounds.",
        "Chaminda Lakshan, a 40-year-old father of two from Naranbedda, a village near Rambukkana, was shot. He died soon after being admitted to Kegalle hospital.",
        "Earlier, Sri Lanka’s Public Security Minister told Parliament on Friday (22) that preliminary investigations have revealed that Assistant Superintendent of Police C. W. C. Dharmaratne & Senior Superintendent of Police K. B. Keerthiratne had instructed to open fire to control the situation in Rambukkana on the 19th of April 2022.",
        "Former SSP for Kegalle K. B. Keerthiratne, and three police contables were in connection to the shooting incident during a protest in Rambukkana, Kegalle.",
        "#Rambukkana Shooting: HR Commission tells AG to file criminal action against SSP Keerthiratne",
        "CBSL to liquidate five failed finance companies including ETI Finance Limited"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rambukkana",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "HR Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SSP Keerthiratne",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investigate",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP K. B. Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle K. B. Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 18th of April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th of April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Lakshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naranbedda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "C. W. C. Dharmaratne & Senior Superintendent of Police K. B. Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th of April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle K. B. Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HR Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETI Finance Limited",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "#රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම: ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්නට එරෙහිව අපරාධ නඩු පවරන්නැයි මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම නීතිපතිට කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න මහතාට එරෙහිව විමර්ශනය කර සුදුසු අපරාධ නඩු පවරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව නීතිපතිවරයාට උපදෙස් දී තිබේ.",
        "රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෑගල්ල හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්නට එරෙහිව විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව ද පොලිස්පතිවරයාට නියෝග කළා.",
        "HRCSL නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ පොලිසිය විසින් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය පිළිබඳ වාර්තාව සකස් කර ඇති අතර එය සූදානම් බවයි.",
        "\"පොලීසියට තර්ජනයක් නොව පලා යන මිනිසුන්ට වෙඩි තැබීමට නියෝග කිරීම නීති විරෝධී ය\" යනුවෙන් මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම පැවසීය.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් 18 වැනි සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල්වල ප්‍රමාද වූ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් මිල ඉහළ දැමීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රඹුක්කන විරෝධතා ඇවිලී ගියේය.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් 19 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා, පෙළපාලිකරුවන් ප්‍රධාන මාර්ග සහ දුම්රිය මාර්ගයක් අවහිර කළහ.",
        "දහවල් වන විට විරෝධතාකරුවන් දහස් ගණනකට පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කිරීමට පටන් ගත් අතර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමකින් තොරව හදිසියේම සජීවී වටවලින් වෙඩි තැබීය.",
        "වෙඩි තබා ඇත්තේ රඹුක්කන ආසන්නයේ පිහිටි නාරංබැද්ද ගම්මානයේ පදිංචි 40 හැවිරිදි චමින්ද ලක්ෂාන් නමැති දෙදරු පියෙකි. කෑගල්ල රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසු ඔහු මිය ගියේය.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් 19 වන දින රඹුක්කන ප්‍රදේශයේ ඇති වූ තත්ත්වය පාලනය කිරීම සඳහා වෙඩි තැබීමට සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරී සී.ඩබ්ලිව්.සී.ධර්මරත්න සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න යන මහත්වරුන් උපදෙස් දී ඇති බව මූලික විමර්ශනවලින් අනාවරණය වී ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මහජන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යවරයා සිකුරාදා (22) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. .",
        "කෑගල්ල රඹුක්කන ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවති විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුර වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෑගල්ල හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න මහතා සහ පොලිස් කොස්තාපල්වරුන් තිදෙනෙකු සම්බන්ධ විය.",
        "#රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම: ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්නට එරෙහිව අපරාධ නඩු පවරන්නැයි මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම නීතිපතිට කියයි",
        "සීමාසහිත ETI ෆිනෑන්ස් ඇතුළු අසාර්ථක මූල්‍ය සමාගම් පහක් ඈවර කිරීමට CBSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රඹුක්කන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමර්ශනය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් 18 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද ලක්ෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරංබැද්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "C. W. C. ධර්මරත්න සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී K. B. කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETI ෆිනෑන්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "#ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: எஸ்எஸ்பி கீர்த்திரத்ன மீது குற்றவியல் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு மனிதவள ஆணையம் ஏஜியிடம் கூறியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ரம்புக்கனை துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்னவுக்கு எதிராக விசாரணை நடத்தி உரிய குற்றவியல் நடவடிக்கைகளைத் தாக்கல் செய்யுமாறு இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு சட்டமா அதிபருக்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ரம்புக்கனை துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கேகாலை முன்னாள் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கே.பி கீர்த்திரத்னவுக்கு எதிராக ஒழுக்காற்று நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது காவல்துறை நடத்திய துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு தொடர்பான அறிக்கை தயாரிக்கப்பட்டு தயாராக உள்ளது என்று HRCSL ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"ஓடிப்போகும் மக்களைச் சுடுமாறு உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்தது, காவல்துறைக்கு அச்சுறுத்தல் இல்லை\" என்று மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம் கூறியது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் 18 ஆம் திகதி திங்கட்கிழமை அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசலின் தாமதமான பெட்ரோல் விநியோகம் மற்றும் கூர்மையான விலை அதிகரிப்பு ஆகியவற்றிற்காக ரம்புக்கன போராட்டம் வெடித்தது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 19, 2022 செவ்வாய்கிழமை, ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பிரதான சாலைகள் மற்றும் ரயில் பாதையை அடைத்தனர்.",
        "மதியம் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது போலீசார் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசத் தொடங்கினர், பின்னர் திடீரென, எந்த முன்னறிவிப்பும் இன்றி, நேரடி துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டனர்.",
        "ரம்புக்கனையை அண்மித்த நாரணபெத்த என்ற கிராமத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 40 வயதுடைய இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையான சமிந்த லக்ஷான் என்பவரே துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு இலக்காகியுள்ளார். கேகாலை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் அவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் 19 ஆம் திகதி ரம்புக்கனையில் நிலைமையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்துமாறு உதவிப் பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் சி.டபிள்யூ.சி. தர்மரத்ன மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன ஆகியோர் அறிவுறுத்தியதாக ஆரம்பகட்ட விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளதாக இலங்கையின் பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (22) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "கேகாலை ரம்புக்கனையில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கேகாலை முன்னாள் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி. கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன மற்றும் மூன்று பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள்.",
        "#ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: எஸ்எஸ்பி கீர்த்திரத்ன மீது குற்றவியல் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு மனிதவள ஆணையம் ஏஜியிடம் கூறியுள்ளது",
        "ETI ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட் உட்பட ஐந்து தோல்வியடைந்த நிதி நிறுவனங்களை கலைக்க CBSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மனிதவள ஆணையம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏஜி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கீர்த்திரத்ன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விசாரிக்கவும்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP K. B. கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 18, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 19, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த லக்ஷன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரன்பெத்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "C. W. C. தர்மரத்ன மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் K. B. கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 19, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதவள ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETI ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}