{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කෝප්---කෝපා-පස්ස-ගහන-හේතුව-නලින්-කතා-කරයි/1-618909",
  "time_ut": 1661746996,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝප් - කෝපා පස්ස ගහන හේතුව නලින් කතා කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cope - Nalin talks about the reason why Cope is holding back",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Nalin Bandara, the Kurunegala District Councilor of the Samagi Jana Balavega, said that the formation of COP and COPA committees is being pushed back because the party has to give its chairman positions.",
        "Cope and Cope Committees have not yet been formed. Why are these being pulled back? Is this trying to destroy the opportunity to give the chairmanship of these committees to the opposition?",
        "It has been agreed to announce the COP and COPA committees as soon as the speaker returns from abroad. He is scheduled to arrive in the island today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cope - Nalin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cope",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala District",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cope Committees",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝප් - කෝපා පස්ස ගහන හේතුව නලින් කතා කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කෝප් සහ කෝපා කමිටු පිහිටුවීම පස්සට අදින්නේ පක්ෂෙට එහි සභාපති ධුර දෙන්නට වෙන නිසා දැයි සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී නලින් බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කෝප් සහ කෝපා කමිටු තවමත් පිහිටුවා නැහැ. මේවා පස්සට අදින්නෙ ඇයි? මේ කමිටු සභාපති ධුර විපක්ෂයට දෙන්න තියෙන අවස්ථාව නැති කරන්නද මේ හදන්නේ.",
        "කතානායක විදේශ ගතව සිට පැමිණි සැනින් කෝප් සහ කෝපා කමිටු ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට එකඟතාව පළ වී තිබෙනවා.එතුමා අද දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝප් - නලින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මුහුණ දෙන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோப் - கோப் பின்வாங்குவதற்கான காரணம் பற்றி நளின் பேசுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் குருநாகல் மாவட்ட கவுன்சிலர் திரு.நளின் பண்டார கூறுகையில், கட்சிக்கு தலைவர் பதவிகளை வழங்க வேண்டியிருப்பதால், கோப் மற்றும் கோபா குழுக்களை அமைப்பது பின்னுக்கு தள்ளப்படுகிறது.",
        "கோப் மற்றும் கோப் குழுக்கள் இன்னும் அமைக்கப்படவில்லை. இவை ஏன் பின்வாங்கப்படுகின்றன? இந்தக் குழுக்களின் தலைவர் பதவியை எதிர்கட்சிக்குக் கொடுக்கும் வாய்ப்பை அழிக்க முயல்கிறதா?",
        "சபாநாயகர் வெளிநாட்டில் இருந்து நாடு திரும்பியதும் சிஓபி மற்றும் கோபா குழுக்களை அறிவிப்பதற்கு இணக்கம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளது.அவர் இன்று நாடு திரும்பவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சமாளிக்க - நளின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சமாளிக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப் குழுக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}