{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රුසියාවේන්-සුබදායි-ප්‍රකාශයක්/101-615688",
  "time_ut": 1656656371,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රුසියාවේන් සුබදායි ප්‍රකාශයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A positive statement from Russia",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ambassador of the Russian Federation to Sri Lanka Mr. Yuri Materi said that Russia's support will be provided to Sri Lanka.",
        "Russian Ambassador to Sri Lanka Yuri Materi called on Foreign Minister Prof. GL Peiris.",
        "Several issues have been discussed in the hope of strengthening multi-faceted bilateral relations. Prof. G. L. Peiris informed Ambassador Uri Materi about the steps taken to overcome the economic crisis that Sri Lanka is facing.",
        "It has also been stated in the meeting with Mr. Ambassador Uri Materi that they have worked with close cooperation regarding the unfinished engagements to further strengthen the bilateral relations between Sri Lanka and Russia."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Russian Federation",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියාවේන් සුබදායි ප්‍රකාශයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියාවේ සහාය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩු තානාපති යූරි මැටෙරි මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩු තානාපති යූරි මැටෙරි මහතා සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා අතර හමුවක් පැවැත්විණ.",
        "එහිදී බහුවිධ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමේ බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් කරුණු කිහිපයක් සාකච්ඡා කර ඇත.ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණදෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා ගෙන ඇති පියවර කිහිපයක් පිළිබඳව මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා තානාපති යූරි මැටෙරි මහතා දැනුවත් කර බව පැවැසෙයි.",
        "තවද ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ රුසියාව අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට අවසන් නොකළ නිරතවීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමීප සහයෝගයෙන් යුක්තව කටයුතු කළ බව  තානාපති යූරි මැටෙරි මහතා හමුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි මැටේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි මැටේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்யாவிலிருந்து ஒரு நேர்மறையான அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு ரஷ்யா தனது ஆதரவை வழங்கும் என இலங்கைக்கான ரஷ்ய தூதுவர் யூரி மேடேரி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பின் தூதுவர் யூரி மேட்டேரி மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் சந்திப்பொன்று இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "பலதரப்பு இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்தும் நம்பிக்கையில் பல விடயங்கள் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டுள்ளன.இலங்கை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் தூதுவர் உரி மேட்டரிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு இலங்கையும் ரஷ்யாவும் நெருக்கமாக இணைந்து செயற்பட வேண்டுமெனவும் அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}