{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ලංකාව-අර්බුදයෙන්-ගොඩගන්න-ජාත්‍යන්තර-සහාය-දෙන්න/1-616176",
  "time_ut": 1657455947,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාව අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩගන්න ජාත්‍යන්තර සහාය දෙන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Give international support to recover Sri Lanka from the crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian Congress Party requested the central government and the international community to provide the necessary support to Sri Lanka to recover from the current crisis.",
        "Mrs. Sonia Gandhi, President of the Indian Congress Party, said in a statement that her party is concerned about the current political situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "The announcement shows that Sri Lankans have to face great difficulties and hardships due to the economic challenges Sri Lanka is facing, the rise in the prices of essential goods and the shortage of essential goods. The Congress Party believes that the people of Sri Lanka can overcome the current challenges and the support of the Congress Party to Sri Lanka and the people. The announcement further states that the Congress party hopes that the Government of India will continue to support the people and the government of Sri Lanka to face the current difficulties."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Congress Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sonia Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Congress Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Congress Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Congress Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාව අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩගන්න ජාත්‍යන්තර සහාය දෙන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වත්මන් අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සහාය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දෙන ලෙස ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය මධ්‍යම රජයෙන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් දේශපාලන තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව තම පක්ෂය කණසල්ලෙන් පසුවන බව ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපති සෝනියා ගාන්ධි මහත්මිය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණදී සිටින ආර්ථික අභියෝග,අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ මිල ඉහළ යාම,අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට විශාල දුෂ්කරතා සහ පීඩාවන්ට මුහුණදීමට සිදු වී ඇතැයි එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනතාවට වත්මන් අභියෝග ජයගැනීමට හැකිවෙතැයි කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය විශ්වාස කරන බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහ ජනතාවට කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂයේ සහයෝගය හිමිවන බවත් එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.වත්මන් දුෂ්කරතා වලට මුහුණදීමට ඉන්දීය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට සහ රජයට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වනු ඇතැයි කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩි දුරටත් දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝනියා ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්ග්‍රස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து இலங்கையை மீட்பதற்கு சர்வதேச ஆதரவை வழங்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கு தேவையான ஆதரவை வழங்குமாறு மத்திய அரசாங்கத்திடமும் சர்வதேச சமூகத்திடமும் இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியின் தலைவர் திருமதி சோனியா காந்தி, இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய அரசியல் சூழ்நிலை குறித்து தமது கட்சி கவலையடைவதாக அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பொருளாதார சவால்கள், அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் விலையேற்றம், அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் தட்டுப்பாடு போன்றவற்றால் இலங்கையர்கள் பெரும் சிரமங்களையும் இன்னல்களையும் எதிர்கொள்ள வேண்டியுள்ளதாக இந்த அறிவிப்பு காட்டுகின்றது.இலங்கை மக்களால் சமாளிக்க முடியும் என காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி நம்புகிறது. தற்போதைய சவால்கள் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கும் மக்களுக்கும் காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியின் ஆதரவு, தற்போதைய சிரமங்களை எதிர்கொள்ள இந்திய அரசு மக்களுக்கும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி நம்புவதாகவும் அந்த அறிவிப்பில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோனியா காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}