{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/නව-අගමැති-දිනේෂ්ට-චීන-අගමැතිගෛන්-සුබ-පැතුම්/11-395795",
  "time_ut": 1658920027,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නව අගමැති දිනේෂ්ට චීන අගමැතිගෛන් සුබ පැතුම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese Prime Minister congratulates new Prime Minister Dinesh",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese Prime Minister Li Keqiang has sent a message to the new Prime Minister of Sri Lanka, Mr. Dinesh Gunawardena, congratulating him.",
        "Li said in his message that China and Sri Lanka enjoy deep traditional friendship and are friendly neighbors and strategic partners.",
        "Li said that since the establishment of diplomatic relations 65 years ago, the two sides have always treated each other with respect and equality, continuously strengthened mutual political trust and promoted mutually beneficial cooperation and joined hands to deal with difficulties and challenges. Bilateral relations have maintained a strong and stable development.",
        "Li said the Chinese side strongly supports the friendly cooperation between China and Sri Lanka, sympathizes with the Sri Lankan people in the current difficulties they face, and is ready to continue to support and assist them in their capacity.",
        "The Chinese Premier said he is willing to work with Prime Minister Gunawardena to strengthen cooperation and mutual support among developing countries, deepen practical cooperation in various fields, and bring more benefits to the two countries and their people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Li",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Li",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Li",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව අගමැති දිනේෂ්ට චීන අගමැතිගෛන් සුබ පැතුම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස වැඩ භාරගත් නව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා වෙත චීන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලී කෙකියැං මහතා දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාට සුබපැතුම් එක් කරමින් පණිවිඩයක් යොමුකර තිබේ.",
        "චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගැඹුරු සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍රත්වයක් භුක්ති විඳින බවත් මිත්‍රශීලී අසල්වැසියන් සහ උපායමාර්ගික  හවුල්කරුවන් බවත් ලී සිය පණිවිඩයේ සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "වසර 65 කට පෙර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා ස්ථාපිත කිරීමෙන් පසු දෙපාර්ශ්වය සැමවිටම එකිනෙකාට ගෞරවයෙන් හා සමානව සලකමින්, අඛණ්ඩව අන්‍යෝන්‍ය දේශපාලන විශ්වාසය ශක්තිමත් කර අන්‍යෝන්‍ය වශයෙන් වාසිදායක සහයෝගීතාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරමින් දුෂ්කරතා සහ අභියෝග සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට අත්වැල් බැඳගත් බව ලී පැවසීය. ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් සහ ස්ථාවර සංවර්ධනයක් පවත්වා ගෙන ගොස් ඇති බවයි.",
        "චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර මිත්‍රශීලී සහයෝගීතාවයට චීන පාර්ශවය දැඩි ලෙස සහාය දෙන අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන වත්මන් දුෂ්කරතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන් සමඟ සංවේදනය වන අතර ඔවුන්ගේ ධාරිතාවය තුළ ඔවුන්ට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගය සහ සහාය ලබා දීමට සූදානම් බව ලී පැවසීය.",
        "සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල් අතර සහයෝගීතාවය සහ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය සහයෝගය ශක්තිමත් කිරීමටත්, විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ප්‍රායෝගික සහයෝගීතාව ගැඹුරු කිරීමටත්, දෙරටට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ජනතාවට වැඩි ප්‍රතිලාභ ගෙන ඒම සඳහා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට තමා කැමති බව චීන අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 65 කට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய பிரதமர் தினேஷிற்கு சீன பிரதமர் வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் புதிய பிரதமர் திரு.தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவுக்கு சீனப் பிரதமர் லீ கெகியாங் வாழ்த்துச் செய்தி அனுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "சீனாவும் இலங்கையும் ஆழ்ந்த பாரம்பரிய நட்பை அனுபவித்து வருவதாகவும், நட்பு அண்டை நாடுகள் மற்றும் மூலோபாய பங்காளிகள் என்றும் லி தனது செய்தியில் கூறினார்.",
        "65 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு இராஜதந்திர உறவுகள் நிறுவப்பட்டதிலிருந்து, இரு தரப்பினரும் எப்போதும் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் மரியாதையுடனும் சமத்துவத்துடனும் நடந்துகொண்டனர், பரஸ்பர அரசியல் நம்பிக்கையை தொடர்ந்து வலுப்படுத்தி, பரஸ்பர நன்மை பயக்கும் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்தி, சிரமங்களையும் சவால்களையும் சமாளிக்க கைகோர்த்தனர். இருதரப்பு உறவுகள் வலுவான மற்றும் நிலையான வளர்ச்சியைப் பேணி வருகின்றன.",
        "சீனாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான நட்புறவு ஒத்துழைப்பை சீனத் தரப்பு வலுவாக ஆதரிப்பதாகவும், இலங்கை மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் தற்போதைய சிரமங்களில் அவர்களுக்கு அனுதாபங்கள் தெரிவிப்பதாகவும், அவர்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கும் அவர்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்கும் தயாராக இருப்பதாக லி கூறினார்.",
        "வளரும் நாடுகளிடையே ஒத்துழைப்பையும் பரஸ்பர ஆதரவையும் வலுப்படுத்தவும், பல்வேறு துறைகளில் நடைமுறை ஒத்துழைப்பை ஆழப்படுத்தவும், இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் அதன் மக்களுக்கும் அதிக நன்மைகளை கொண்டு வருவதற்கும் பிரதமர் குணவர்தனவுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக சீனப் பிரதமர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}