{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අගමැතිට-කාලය-දෙන්න/1-615566",
  "time_ut": 1656430602,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගමැතිට කාලය දෙන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Give the Prime Minister time",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Palani Digambaran, the Nuwara Eliya District MP of the Samagi Jana Balawegaya, said that the Prime Minister should be given time to resolve the issues of the country and that there was no point in blaming Ranil Wickremesinghe who took over as the Prime Minister when no one else accepted him.",
        "Mr. Tigambaran also said that even if Sajith Premadasa takes over the country tomorrow or Anura Kumara takes over, even if the whole parliament convenes, it will not be possible to resolve the issues immediately.",
        "He said that since it was a bankrupt country, no one could solve the problems in two or three weeks, adding that the Prime Minister should be given at least another two months.",
        "Speaking to the media after meeting the Indian High Commissioner in Sri Lanka, Palani Thigambaran said that he had met the Indian High Commissioner in Sri Lanka and told him about the suffering of the Sri Lankan people.",
        "He also met the Prime Minister and informed him of the suffering of the people in the plantation areas.",
        "Mr. India has been assisting Sri Lanka so far and will continue to do so, he said.",
        "He said the crisis would not be resolved as long as Gotabhaya was in power."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Palani Digambaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tigambaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two or three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least another two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palani Thigambaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැතිට කාලය දෙන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගමැතිවරයාට රටෙි ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට කාලය ලබාදිය යුතු යැයි ද කවුරුත් බාර නොගත් අවස්ථාවේ අගමැති ධුරය බාරගත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට දොස් කියා පලක් නැතැයි ද සමගි ජන ජනබලවේගයේ නුවරඑළිය දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී පලනි දිගම්බරන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "හෙට දිනයේ දී රට සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස බාරගත්තත්, අනුර කුමාර බාර ගත්තත්, මුළු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එකතු වුණත් ක්ෂණිකව ප්‍රශ්න විසඳන්නට හැකියාවක් නැතැයිද තිගාම්බරන් මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "බංකොලොත් වූ රටක් හෙයින් කවුරු ආවත් සති දෙක තුනෙන් ප්‍රශ්න විසඳන්නට නොහැකි  බව කී මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට තව මාසයක් දෙකක් වත් කාලය ලබාදිය යුතුව ඇතැයි ද කීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා හමු වීමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍යයට  ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් පලනි තිගාම්බරන් මහතා සඳහන් කළේ තමා ඉන්දීය මහ මහකොමසාරිස්වරයා හමුවී ලාංකික ජනතාව විඳින දුක ගැන පැවසූ බවයි.",
        "අනතුරුව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ද හමුවී  වතුකරයේ ජනතාව විඳින දුක ගැන දැනුම්දීමක් කළ බව ද සජබ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කීය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙත මේ දක්වා  උපකාර කර තිබෙන අතර ඉදිරියේදීත් එලෙසම උපකාර කරනු ඇතැයි ද තිගාම්බරන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය සිටින තුරු අර්බුදයෙන් විසඳෙන්නේ නැතැයි කී මන්ත්‍රීවරයා රාජපක්ෂ නඩය ජනතාවගෙන් ඇත්ත සැඟ වූ බවද අලුත් අගමැතිවරයාට පැමිණ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඇත්ත කියා තිබෙන බවද දැන් එය ද විවේචනයට ලක්ව තිබෙන්නේ යැයිද කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පලනි දිගම්බරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටිගම්බරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක් හෝ තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් තවත් මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලනි තිගාම්බරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமருக்கு அவகாசம் கொடுங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்ப்பதற்கு பிரதமருக்கு கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டுமெனவும், பிரதமராக பதவியேற்ற ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை யாரும் குறை கூறுவதில் அர்த்தமில்லை எனவும் சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் நுவரெலியா மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பழனி திகாம்பரன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். மற்றபடி அவரை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "நாளை சஜித் பிரேமதாச நாட்டைப் பொறுப்பேற்றாலும் அல்லது அநுரகுமார ஆட்சிப் பொறுப்பேற்றாலும், முழுப் பாராளுமன்றத்தையும் கூட்டினாலும் பிரச்சினைகளை உடனடியாகத் தீர்க்க முடியாது எனவும் திகாம்பரன் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வங்குரோத்து நாடாக இருப்பதால் இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று வாரங்களில் எவராலும் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க முடியாது என தெரிவித்த அவர், பிரதமருக்கு இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்களாவது அவகாசம் வழங்க வேண்டும் எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகரை சந்தித்த பின்னர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த பழனி திகாம்பரன், இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகரை சந்தித்து இலங்கை மக்கள் படும் இன்னல்கள் குறித்து கூறியதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும் அவர் பிரதமரை சந்தித்து பெருந்தோட்ட பகுதி மக்கள் படும் இன்னல்களை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திரு இந்தியா இதுவரை இலங்கைக்கு உதவி செய்து வருவதாகவும், அதனை தொடர்ந்தும் செய்யும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கோத்தபாய ஆட்சியில் இருக்கும் வரை இந்த நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு கிடைக்காது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பழனி திகம்பரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திகாம்பரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பழனி திகாம்பரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}