{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/බෝට්ටුවෙන්-ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට-යෑමට-තැත්-කළ-67ක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395317",
  "time_ut": 1657525331,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට යෑමට තැත් කළ 67ක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "67 who tried to go to Australia by boat are trapped",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Navy says that yesterday (10th) 67 people who tried to go to Australia using an unprotected multi-day fishing vessel were arrested in the Eastern Seaboard.",
        "During a search operation carried out by the Sri Lanka Naval Ship Ranarisi, belonging to the Eastern Naval Command, the relevant vessel was inspected due to the observation of a multi-day fishing vessel that was unsafely loaded with more people.",
        "There, due to the confirmation that the relevant personnel had attempted to migrate to another country illegally, measures were taken to take custody of the Navy, and there 53 men, 06 women, 08 children and in addition 06 persons involved in the smuggling of the relevant personnel to another country were arrested. Steps had been taken.",
        "Information has been revealed that the relevant personnel have tried to go to Australia and the personnel taken into custody by the Navy are revealed to be persons in the age limits of 01 to 56 years residing in Mannar, Vavuniya, Mullaitivu, Trincomalee and Batticaloa.",
        "The Navy has taken steps to hand over the people taken into custody by the Navy to the Trincomalee Port Police for further investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Seaboard",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Naval Ship Ranarisi",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "multi-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 to 56 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee and Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trincomalee Port Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට යෑමට තැත් කළ 67ක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතිවිරෝධී අයුරින් අනාරක්ෂිතව බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් යොදාගනිමින් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට යාමට උත්සහ ගත් පුද්ගලයින් 67 දෙනෙකු ඊයේ (10දා)  නැගෙනහිර මුහුදු සීමාවේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවට නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රණරිසි නෞකාව විසින් කල්මුනේ මුහුදු තීරයේ සිදුකරන ලද සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමක් අතරතුරදී අනාරක්ෂිතව ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා වැඩියෙන් පුද්ගලයින් පටවාගත් බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් නිරීක්ෂණය වීම හේතුවෙන් අදාල යාත්‍රාව පරික්ෂාවට ලක්කොට ඇත.",
        "එහිදී අදාල පිරිස් නීතිවිරෝධීව වෙනත් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ ගෙන ඇති බවට තහවුරු වීම හේතුවෙන් නාවික හමුදාභාරයට ගැනීමට පියවර ගත් අතර එහිදී පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 53 දෙනෙකු, කාන්තාවන් 06 දෙනෙක්, ළමුන් 08 ක්ද ඊට අමතරව අදාල පිරිස් වෙනත් රටකට රැගෙන යාමේ ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ වූ පුද්ගලයින් 06 දෙනෙකුද අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පියවර ගෙන තිබුණි.",
        "අදාල පිරිස් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට යාමට උත්සහ ගෙන ඇති බවට තොරතුරු අනාරවනය වී ඇති අතර නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් පිරිස් මන්නාරම , වව්නියාව, මුලතිව් , ත්‍රීකුණාමලය සහ මඩකලපුව ප්‍රදේශයන්හි පදිංචි අවුරුදු 01 සිට අවුරුදු 56 දක්වා වූ වයස් සීමාවන්හි පුද්ගලයින් බවට අනාවරන වෙයි.",
        "නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් පිරිස වැඩිදුර පරික්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා ත්‍රීකුණාමලය වරාය පොලීසිය වෙතට භාරදීම නාවික හමුදාව විසින් පියවර ගනු ලැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර මුහුදු තීරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රණරිසි",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 01 සිට 56 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "படகில் ஆஸ்திரேலியா செல்ல முயன்ற 67 பேர் சிக்கினர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாதுகாப்பற்ற பலநாள் மீன்பிடிக் கப்பலைப் பயன்படுத்தி அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்குச் செல்ல முற்பட்ட 67 பேர் நேற்று (10ஆம் திகதி) கிழக்கு கடற்பரப்பில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கடற்படையினர் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்கு சொந்தமான இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பலான ரணரிசி மேற்கொண்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​பாதுகாப்பற்ற முறையில் அதிகளவான ஆட்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற பலநாள் மீன்பிடி படகு அவதானித்தமையினால் குறித்த கப்பல் பரிசோதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அங்கு, குறித்த நபர்கள் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் வேறு நாட்டிற்கு இடம்பெயர முற்பட்டமை உறுதிசெய்யப்பட்டதையடுத்து, கடற்படையினரால் பொறுப்பேற்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டதுடன், அங்கு 53 ஆண்கள், 06 பெண்கள், 08 சிறுவர்கள் மற்றும் மேலும் 06 பேர் கடத்தலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். வேறு நாட்டிற்குச் சென்றவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "குறித்த நபர்கள் அவுஸ்திரேலியா செல்ல முற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் மன்னார், வவுனியா, முல்லைத்தீவு, திருகோணமலை மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் 01 முதல் 56 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்கள் எனத் தகவல்கள் வெளியாகியுள்ளன.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களை மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக திருகோணமலை துறைமுக பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்க கடற்படையினர் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல் ரனாரிசி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 முதல் 56 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை துறைமுக காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}