{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පාස්පෝට්-ප්‍රා-දේශීය-කාර්යාල-මගින්-දිනකට-100කට-එක්දින-සේවාව/11-395034",
  "time_ut": 1656766787,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාස්පෝට් ප්‍රා දේශීය කාර්යාල මගින් දිනකට 100කට එක්දින සේවාව",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "100 per day by local passport offices for one-day service",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The department said that they are working to implement the one-day service at 100 per day through four local offices under the Department of Immigration and Emigration.",
        "Thus, the Matara, Kandy and Vavuniya offices provide one-day service to 100 applicants who have booked a date and time in advance. Accordingly. There is an opportunity to reserve a date and time by handing in the applications to the above mentioned offices through the www.immigration.gov.lk website."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "one-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.immigration.gov.lk",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාස්පෝට් ප්‍රා දේශීය කාර්යාල මගින් දිනකට 100කට එක්දින සේවාව",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව යටතේ පවතින ප්‍රා දේශීය කාර්යාල හතරක් හරහා දිනකට 100 බැගින් එක්දින සේවාව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "මේ අනුව මාතර, මහනුවර හා වව්නියාව යන කාර්යාල මගින් කලින් දිනයක් හා වේලාවක් වෙන්කර ගත් අයදුම්කරුවන් 100ක් වෙත ඉක්දින සේවාව ලබාදෙයි. ඒ අනුව ලැදේ. www.immigration.gov.lk වෙබ් අඩවිය හරහා ඉහත සඳහන් කල කාර්යාල වෙත අයදුම්පත් භාරදී දිනයක් හා වේලාවක් වෙන් කර ගැනීමට අවස්තාව තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක දවසක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.immigration.gov.lk",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு நாள் சேவைக்கு உள்ளூர் பாஸ்போர்ட் அலுவலகங்கள் மூலம் ஒரு நாளைக்கு 100",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள நான்கு உள்ளுர் அலுவலகங்கள் ஊடாக நாளொன்றுக்கு 100 என்ற ஒருநாள் சேவையை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருவதாக திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இவ்வாறு, மாத்தறை, கண்டி மற்றும் வவுனியா அலுவலகங்களில் தேதி மற்றும் நேரத்தை முன்கூட்டியே பதிவு செய்துள்ள 100 விண்ணப்பதாரர்களுக்கு ஒரு நாள் சேவை வழங்கப்படுகிறது. அதன்படி. www.immigration.gov.lk என்ற இணையத்தளத்தின் ஊடாக மேற்படி அலுவலகங்களில் விண்ணப்பங்களை கையளித்து தேதி மற்றும் நேரத்தை முன்பதிவு செய்ய வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.immigration.gov.lk",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}