{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84368/undco-regional-director-for-asia-pacific-calls-on-minister-ali-sabry",
  "time_ut": 1660764300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UNDCO Regional Director for Asia-Pacific calls on Minister Ali Sabry",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNDCO Regional Director for Asia-Pacific calls on Minister Ali Sabry",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Regional Director for Asia-Pacific from the United Nations Development Coordination Office (UNDCO) David McLachlan-Karr has called on Sri Lanka’s Minister of Foreign Affairs on Wednesday (Aug 17), UN Resident Coordinator in Sri Lanka, Hanaa Singer says.",
        "At this meeting, the efforts of the United Nations Sri Lanka to coordinate multi-sectoral support to address challenges in Sri Lanka and prevent a humanitarian crisis were taken up for discussion.",
        "In a tweet, the UN resident coordinator noted that the UN Agencies have raised USD 37.6 million in funding thus far.",
        "UNDCO Regional Director for Asia-Pacific Mr. McLachlan-Karr arrived in Sri Lanka on Tuesday (Aug 16). His visit is focused on the launch of the United Nations Sustainable Development Cooperation Framework (UNSDCF) 2023-2027 which will guide the work of all UN Agencies in Sri Lanka over the next five years.",
        "He also met with Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa for talks on the economic, peace and development concerns facing Sri Lanka and the way forward to ensure stability and recovery from the crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Asia-Pacific",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ali Sabry",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia-Pacific",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Development Coordination Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "David McLachlan-Karr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hanaa Singer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Agencies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "37.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia-Pacific",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "McLachlan-Karr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Sustainable Development Cooperation Framework",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNSDCF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2027",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "all UN Agencies in Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "UNDCO ආසියා පැසිෆික් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලයේ (UNDCO) ආසියා පැසිෆික් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ඩේවිඩ් මැක්ලච්ලන් කාර් බදාදා (අගෝස්තු 17) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවී ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නේවාසික සම්බන්ධීකාරක හනා සිංගර් පවසයි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින අභියෝගවලට මුහුණදීම සඳහා සහ මානුෂීය අර්බුදයක් ඇතිවීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා බහුආංශික සහයෝගය සම්බන්ධීකරණය කිරීමට එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දරන උත්සාහය සාකච්ඡාවට ගැනිණි.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නේවාසික සම්බන්ධීකාරකවරයා සඳහන් කළේ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන මේ වන විට ඩොලර් මිලියන 37.6 ක අරමුදල් රැස් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "UNDCO ආසියා-පැසිෆික් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර් මහතා අඟහරුවාදා (අගෝස්තු 16) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය. ඉදිරි වසර පහ තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතනවල කටයුතු මෙහෙයවන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ තිරසාර සංවර්ධන සහයෝගීතා රාමුව (UNSDCF) 2023-2027 දියත් කිරීම කෙරෙහි ඔහුගේ සංචාරය අවධානය යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහු විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ද හමුවී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික, සාමය සහ සංවර්ධන අවශ්‍යතා සහ ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමේ ඉදිරි මාවත පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආසියා-පැසිෆික්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියා-පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හනා ගායිකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 37.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියා-පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ තිරසාර සංවර්ධන සහයෝගීතා රාමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNSDCF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2027",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UNDCO ஆசிய-பசிபிக் பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தி ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அலுவலகத்தின் (UNDCO) ஆசிய-பசிபிக் பிராந்தியப் பணிப்பாளர் டேவிட் மெக்லாக்லன்-கார் புதன்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 17) இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சரை சந்தித்துள்ளார் என இலங்கைக்கான ஐ.நா வதிவிட இணைப்பாளர் ஹனா சிங்கர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில், இலங்கையில் உள்ள சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்ளவும் மனிதாபிமான நெருக்கடியைத் தடுக்கவும் பல துறைகளின் ஆதரவை ஒருங்கிணைக்க ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் இலங்கையின் முயற்சிகள் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் வதிவிட ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் ஒரு ட்வீட்டில், ஐ.நா. முகமைகள் இதுவரை 37.6 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை நிதி திரட்டியுள்ளதாக குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "UNDCO ஆசிய-பசிபிக் பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் திரு. McLachlan-Karr செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 16) இலங்கை வந்தடைந்தார். ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் நிலையான அபிவிருத்தி ஒத்துழைப்புக் கட்டமைப்பின் (UNSDCF) 2023-2027 தொடக்கத்தில் அவரது விஜயம் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது, இது அடுத்த ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளில் இலங்கையில் உள்ள அனைத்து ஐநா முகவர் நிறுவனங்களின் பணிகளையும் வழிநடத்தும்.",
        "அவர் எதிர்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை சந்தித்து, இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பொருளாதார, சமாதானம் மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி கவலைகள் மற்றும் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கான முன்னோக்கி வழிகள் குறித்து பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சி ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் மெக்லாக்லன்-கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹனா பாடகி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "37.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெக்லாக்லன்-கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் நிலையான வளர்ச்சி ஒத்துழைப்பு கட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNSDCF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2027",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையில் உள்ள அனைத்து ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}