{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84729/paris-club-ready-to-start-debt-relief-for-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1662209160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Paris Club ready to start debt relief for Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Paris Club ready to start debt relief for Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Paris Club said on Friday it is ready to start the debt relief process for Sri Lanka, the President’s Media Division (PMD) says.",
        "It reiterated its willingness to coordinate with non-Paris Club official bilateral creditors to provide the necessary financing assurances in a timely manner, the PMD said citing a statement from the Paris Club.",
        "The Paris Club statement said, “Paris Club members welcome the Staff-Level Agreement (SLA) concluded between Sri Lankan Authorities and IMF staff for a 48-month arrangement under the Extended-Fund Facility (EFF). This agreement represents an important step to restore macroeconomic stability and public debt sustainability.”",
        "Noting the IMF’s assessment for the need for a debt treatment in the context of the IMF program, the Paris club said it is ready to start the debt treatment process and reiterated its willingness to coordinate with non-Paris Club official bilateral creditors to provide the necessary financing assurances in a timely manner and ensure fair burden sharing, as already proposed to the largest other official bilateral creditors.",
        "The statement also assured that, “The Paris Club remains at the disposal of the Sri Lankan authorities and non-Paris Club official bilateral creditors to further discuss the next steps of the debt treatment process."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Paris Club",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "non-Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Authorities",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Extended-Fund Facility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "non-Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "non-Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය සහන ලබාදීමට පැරිස් සමාජය සූදානම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා ණය සහන ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කිරීමට සූදානම් බව පැරිස් සමාජය සිකුරාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය (PMD) පවසයි.",
        "අවශ්‍ය මූල්‍ය සහතික කිරීම් නියමිත වේලාවට ලබා දීම සඳහා පැරිස් සමාජයේ නොවන නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කිරීමට ඇති කැමැත්ත නැවත අවධාරණය කළ බව පැරිස් සමාජයේ ප්‍රකාශයක් උපුටා දක්වමින් පීඑම්ඩී පැවසීය.",
        "පැරිස් ක්ලබ් ප්‍රකාශය පැවසුවේ, “විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) යටතේ මාස 48ක විධිවිධානයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් සහ IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අතර අවසන් කර ඇති මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම (SLA) පැරිස් සමාජයේ සාමාජිකයින් සාදරයෙන් පිළිගනිති. මෙම ගිවිසුම සාර්ව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ රාජ්‍ය ණය තිරසාරභාවය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමේ වැදගත් පියවරක් නියෝජනය කරයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනේ සන්දර්භය තුළ ණය ප්‍රතිකාරයක අවශ්‍යතාවය පිළිබඳ IMF තක්සේරුව සඳහන් කරමින්, පැරිස් සමාජය ණය ප්‍රතිකාර ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කිරීමට සූදානම් බව පැවසූ අතර අවශ්‍ය දේ සැපයීම සඳහා පැරිස් නොවන නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කිරීමට ඇති කැමැත්ත නැවත අවධාරණය කළේය. අනෙකුත් විශාලතම නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්ට දැනටමත් යෝජනා කර ඇති පරිදි, නියමිත වේලාවට මූල්‍යමය සහතික කිරීම් සහ සාධාරණ බර බෙදාගැනීම සහතික කිරීම.",
        "“ණය ප්‍රතිකාර ක්‍රියාවලියේ මීළඟ පියවර තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා පැරිස් සමාජය ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන්ගේ සහ පැරිස් ක්ලබ් නොවන නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්ගේ අභිමතය පරිදි පවතී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් නොවන සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් නොවන සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් නොවන සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கான கடன் நிவாரணத்தை ஆரம்பிக்க பரிஸ் கிளப் தயார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான கடன் நிவாரண நடவடிக்கைகளை ஆரம்பிக்க தயாராக இருப்பதாக பாரிஸ் கிளப் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்ததாக ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பாரிஸ் கிளப் அல்லாத அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடனாளர்களுடன் ஒருங்கிணைத்து தேவையான நிதி உத்தரவாதங்களை சரியான நேரத்தில் வழங்குவதற்கான அதன் விருப்பத்தை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியது, பாரிஸ் கிளப்பின் அறிக்கையை மேற்கோள் காட்டி PMD தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பாரிஸ் கிளப் அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது, “விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியின் (EFF) கீழ் 48 மாத ஏற்பாட்டிற்காக இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் IMF ஊழியர்களுக்கும் இடையில் முடிவடைந்த பணியாளர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தை (SLA) பாரிஸ் கிளப் உறுப்பினர்கள் வரவேற்கின்றனர். இந்த ஒப்பந்தம் மேக்ரோ பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொதுக் கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான ஒரு முக்கியமான படியை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது.",
        "IMF திட்டத்தின் பின்னணியில் கடன் சிகிச்சைக்கான தேவைக்கான IMF இன் மதிப்பீட்டைக் குறிப்பிட்டு, பாரிஸ் கிளப் கடன் சிகிச்சை செயல்முறையைத் தொடங்கத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகக் கூறியது மற்றும் தேவையானவற்றை வழங்க பாரிஸ் கிளப் அல்லாத அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் ஒருங்கிணைக்க தனது விருப்பத்தை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியது. மிகப் பெரிய பிற உத்தியோகபூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களுக்கு ஏற்கனவே முன்மொழியப்பட்டதைப் போல, சரியான நேரத்தில் உத்தரவாதங்களுக்கு நிதியளித்தல் மற்றும் நியாயமான சுமை பகிர்வை உறுதி செய்தல்.",
        "அந்த அறிக்கை மேலும் உறுதியளித்தது, “கடன் சிகிச்சை செயல்முறையின் அடுத்த படிகளை மேலும் விவாதிக்க, இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் பாரிஸ் கிளப் அல்லாத அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களின் வசம் பாரிஸ் கிளப் உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் அல்லாத கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் அல்லாத கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் அல்லாத கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}