{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SJB-to-vote-against-emergency-lawtoday/56-737943",
  "time_ut": 1658875199,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB to vote against emergency law today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB to vote against emergency law today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Government attempting to suppress people’s right to expression and dissent",
        "The MPs of the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) are set to unanimously vote against the emergency law during today’s parliamentary session.",
        "The decision was made yesterday during a meeting between the party’s working committee and its parliamentary group. The party said the Government is attempting to continue the imposed emergency regulations to suppress the freedom of expression and the right to dissent and therefore its members will vote against it.",
        "The party releasing a statement said it was also decided the SJB will not be part of an oppressive Government which is both directly and indirectly unleashing State terrorism on the country’s people while failing to provide solutions to the issues faced by them.",
        "The SJB said however the party will support the establishment of a committee system in Parliament in order to seek solutions to the main issues faced by the people. SJB sources said the party will not accept any Cabinet positions and will continue to function as the Opposition on behalf of the people and their wellbeing.",
        "The Parliament will today take up for debate and vote on the continuity of the State of Emergency declared by President Ranil Wickremesinghe on 17 July. Chief Opposition Whip Kandy District SJB MP Lakshman Kiriella recently said all Opposition MPs had been asked to be present in Parliament today. “I have written to all MPs and asked them to be present in Parliament during the vote,” he said.",
        "According to Kiriella, it is clear how the Government plans to make use of the emergency regulations. “We witnessed how the police and the security forces assaulted the protestors at the Galle Face Green.",
        "This is a foreshadow of what’s to come,” he said.  Kiriella said it is therefore the duty of all parliamentarians to uphold the rule of law and democratic principles against the continuation of emergency regulations. (MB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State of Emergency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB අද හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මිනිසුන්ගේ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට සහ විරුද්ධ වීමට ඇති අයිතිය යටපත් කිරීමට රජය උත්සාහ කරයි",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අද පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසියේදී හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඒකමතිකව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "එම පක්ෂයේ කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය සහ එහි පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම අතර ඊයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත. අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස සහ විසම්මුතිය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය යටපත් කිරීම සඳහා පනවා ඇති හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි තවදුරටත් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට රජය උත්සාහ කරන බවත් එම නිසා තම සාමාජිකයින් ඊට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන බවත් එම පක්ෂය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් එම පක්ෂය කියා සිටියේ රටේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් ලබාදීමට අපොහොසත් වන අතරම රාජ්‍ය ත්‍රස්තවාදය සෘජුව සහ වක්‍රව ඔවුන් වෙත මුදාහරින පීඩාකාරී ආණ්ඩුවක SJB කොටස්කරුවෙකු නොවන බව ද තීරණය කළ බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ප්‍රධාන ගැටලුවලට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කාරක සභා ක්‍රමයක් ස්ථාපිත කිරීමට පක්ෂය සහාය දෙන බව SJB පවසයි. SJB ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේ පක්ෂය කිසිදු කැබිනට් තනතුරක් භාර නොගන්නා බවත් ජනතාව සහ ඔවුන්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම වෙනුවෙන් විපක්ෂය ලෙස දිගටම කටයුතු කරන බවත්ය.",
        "ජුලි 17 වැනි දින ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීතිය අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද විවාදයට සහ ඡන්ද විමසීමට නියමිතය. විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික් SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පසුගියදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ විපක්ෂයේ සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණෙන ලෙස දන්වා ඇති බවයි. “මම සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ලිඛිතව දන්වා ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන විට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටිමි,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කිරිඇල්ලට අනුව, හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි භාවිතා කිරීමට රජය සැලසුම් කර ඇති ආකාරය පැහැදිලිය. “ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පොලිසිය සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ පහරදුන් ආකාරය අපි දැක්කා.",
        "මෙය ඉදිරියේදී සිදුවීමට නියමිත දේ පිළිබඳ පෙර නිමිත්තකි, ”ඔහු පැවසීය. එබැවින් හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට එරෙහිව නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මූලධර්ම ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සියලුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ යුතුකම බව කිරිඇල්ල පැවසීය. (MB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හදිසි තත්ත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று அவசர சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்க SJB",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்களின் கருத்து மற்றும் கருத்து வேறுபாடு உரிமையை நசுக்க அரசு முயற்சிக்கிறது",
        "இன்றைய பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வின் போது அவசர சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா (SJB) எம்பிக்கள் ஒருமனதாக வாக்களிக்க உள்ளனர்.",
        "கட்சியின் செயற்குழுவிற்கும் அதன் பாராளுமன்றக் குழுவிற்கும் இடையில் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. கருத்துச் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் கருத்து வேறுபாடு உரிமையை நசுக்குவதற்கு விதிக்கப்பட்ட அவசரகாலச் சட்டங்களைத் தொடர அரசாங்கம் முயற்சிப்பதாகவும், எனவே அதன் உறுப்பினர்கள் அதற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிப்பார்கள் என்றும் அக்கட்சி தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டு மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வை வழங்கத் தவறிய அதேவேளை, நேரடியாகவும் மறைமுகமாகவும் அரச பயங்கரவாதத்தை நாட்டு மக்கள் மீது கட்டவிழ்த்து விடுகின்ற அடக்குமுறை அரசாங்கத்தில் SJB அங்கம் வகிக்காது எனவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அக்கட்சி அறிக்கை ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரதான பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் குழு அமைப்பை நிறுவுவதற்கு கட்சி ஆதரவளிக்கும் என SJB தெரிவித்துள்ளது. கட்சி எந்த அமைச்சரவை பதவிகளையும் ஏற்காது என்றும், மக்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களின் நல்வாழ்வுக்காக எதிர்க்கட்சியாக தொடர்ந்து செயல்படும் என்றும் எஸ்ஜேபி வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் ஜூலை 17ஆம் திகதி பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் தொடர்வது தொடர்பிலான விவாதம் மற்றும் வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது. எதிர்கட்சியின் கண்டி மாவட்ட SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல, அனைத்து எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களும் இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரசன்னமாக இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அண்மையில் தெரிவித்தார். \"நான் அனைத்து எம்.பி.க்களுக்கும் கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளேன், மேலும் வாக்கெடுப்பின் போது அவர்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கிரியெல்லவின் கூற்றுப்படி, அவசரகாலச் சட்டங்களை எவ்வாறு பயன்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரிகிறது. “காலி முகத்திடலில் பொலிஸாரும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரும் எவ்வாறு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை தாக்கினார்கள் என்பதை நாங்கள் கண்டோம்.",
        "இது என்ன வரப்போகிறது என்பதற்கான முன்னறிவிப்பு,” என்றார். எனவே அவசரகாலச் சட்டங்கள் தொடர்வதற்கு எதிராக சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியையும் ஜனநாயகக் கோட்பாடுகளையும் நிலைநாட்டுவது சகல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் கடமையாகும் என கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (எம்பி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவசர நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}