{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/25/summer-hill-leopard-tragedy-cause-of-death-revealed/",
  "time_ut": 1661440680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Summer Hill Leopard Tragedy: Cause of Death revealed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Summer Hill Leopard Tragedy: Cause of Death revealed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The final report of the committee appointed to investigate the death of a Sri Lankan Leopard at the Summer Hill Estate in Hatton was submitted to Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife, and Forest Resources Conservation Mahinda Amaraweera on Thursday (25).",
        "The report notes that the Leopard was hanging from a tree for several hours after it entangled with a wire set up for a snare in the Summer Hill Estate.",
        "The Investigiation revealed that as a result the Leopard's interal organs were severely damaged leading to its death.",
        "The report also noted that the Leopard was not crushed under the tree it was hanging from, after it was cut down.",
        "The committee had made 25 recommendations to the Minister in the report in order to protect and conserve the Sri Lankan Leopard population.",
        "Sri Lanka's Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife, and Forest Resources Conservation Mahinda Amaraweera called for an investigation on the death of a Sri Lankan Leopard in the Summer Hill Estate in Hatton, a day after the incident was widely reported on local media.",
        "The Minister on 8th August said that an immediate investigation will be conducted into the death of the Leopard, and if proven that the death was a direct result of negligence on the part of the Wildlife Officers, necessary disciplinary action will be taken against them.",
        "The Leopard was discovered trapped in a snare set up for wild boars in the Summer Hill Estate which is part of the Wanarajah Tea Estate in Hatton on 7th August.",
        "The Leopard had managed to somewhat break free from the Snare, however, its body was entangled with the snare wire, and it had later managed to climb onto a tree.",
        "Locals had seen the leopard hanging from the tree on and informed the Wildlife Officers.",
        "Wildlife Officers launched a rescue operation immediately upon arrival, however, the Leopard died after the tree it was hanging on to was cut down, it was reported at the time.",
        "Delayed Super Diesel cargo being unloaded, distribution to continue tonight",
        "Time for Ranil to fulfil pledge on repealing PTA made five years ago – Sumanthiran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Summer Hill Leopard Tragedy: Cause of Death",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Summer Hill Estate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation Mahinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leopard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "several hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Summer Hill Estate",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leopard",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leopard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation Mahinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Summer Hill Estate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leopard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wildlife Officers",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Summer Hill Estate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wanarajah Tea Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Snare",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Wildlife Officers",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leopard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delayed Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගිම්හාන හිල් දිවියාගේ ඛේදවාචකය: මරණයට හේතුව හෙළිවේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හැටන්, සමර් හිල් වතුයායේ දී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දිවියෙකු මියයාම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බැලීමට පත්කළ කමිටුවේ අවසන් වාර්තාව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) කෘෂිකර්ම, වනජීවී හා වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා වෙත භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "සමර් හිල් වතුයායේ උගුලක් සඳහා අටවා තිබූ කම්බියක පැටලී දිවියා පැය කිහිපයක් ගසක එල්ලී සිටි බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස දිවියාගේ අභ්‍යන්තර අවයවවලට දැඩි ලෙස හානි සිදුවී ඇත්ගොව්වා මරණයට පත්වී ඇති බව පරීක්‍ෂණවලදී අනාවරණය විය.",
        "දිවියා කපා දැමීමෙන් පසු එල්ලී සිටි ගස යටට තැලී නොසිටි බවද වාර්තාවේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොටි ගහනය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ සංරක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා එම කමිටුව විසින් වාර්තාව මගින් අමාත්‍යවරයා වෙත නිර්දේශ 25ක් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කෘෂිකර්ම, වනජීවී සහ වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා හැටන් ග්‍රීෂ්ම හිල් වතුයායේ දී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දිවියෙකු මියයාමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "දිවියාගේ මරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කඩිනම් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බවත්, එම මරණය වනජීවී නිලධාරීන්ගේ නොසැලකිලිමත්කමේ සෘජු ප්‍රතිඵලයක් බව ඔප්පු වුවහොත් ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව අවශ්‍ය විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා අගෝස්තු 8 වැනිදා පැවසීය.",
        "හැටන්, වනරාජා තේ වත්තට අයත් සමර් හිල් වතුයායේ වල් ඌරන් සඳහා අටවා තිබූ උගුලක සිරවී සිටි දිවියා සොයාගනු ලැබුවේ පසුගිය අගෝස්තු මස 07 වනදායි.",
        "උගුලෙන් තරමක් මිදීමට දිවියා සමත්ව ඇතත්, උගේ සිරුර උගුලේ කම්බිවල පැටලී තිබූ අතර පසුව ගසකට නැගීමට දිවියා සමත්ව ඇත.",
        "දිවියා ගසක එල්ලී සිටිනු ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් දැක වනජීවී නිලධාරීන්ට දැනුම් දී තිබෙනවා.",
        "පැමිණි විගස වනජීවී නිලධාරීන් බේරා ගැනීමේ මෙහෙයුමක් දියත් කර ඇතත් දිවියා එල්ලී සිටි ගස කපා දැමීමෙන් පසු මිය ගිය බව එකල වාර්තා විය.",
        "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑම, බෙදා හැරීම අද රාත්‍රියේ සිදු කෙරේ",
        "වසර පහකට පෙර දුන් ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අහෝසි කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඥාව ඉටු කිරීමට රනිල්ට කාලයයි - සුමන්තිරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගිම්හාන හිල් දිවියාගේ ඛේදවාචකය: මරණයට හේතුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිම්හාන හිල් වතුයාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය මහින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිම්හාන හිල් වතුයාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය මහින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිම්හාන හිල් වතුයාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 8 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිම්හාන හිල් වතුයාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනරාජා තේ වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උගුල",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිවියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோடை மலை சிறுத்தை சோகம்: இறப்புக்கான காரணம் தெரியவந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஹட்டனில் உள்ள சம்மர் ஹில் தோட்டத்தில் இலங்கையைச் சேர்ந்த சிறுத்தைப்புலி உயிரிழந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் ஆராய்வதற்காக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட குழுவின் இறுதி அறிக்கை விவசாயம், வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீரவிடம் வியாழக்கிழமை (25) சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சம்மர் ஹில் எஸ்டேட்டில் கண்ணிக்காக அமைக்கப்பட்ட கம்பியில் சிக்கிய சிறுத்தை பல மணி நேரம் மரத்தில் தொங்கிக் கொண்டிருந்ததாக அறிக்கை குறிப்பிடுகிறது.",
        "இதன் விளைவாக சிறுத்தையின் உள் உறுப்புகள் பலத்த சேதமடைந்து இறந்து போனது விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்தது.",
        "சிறுத்தை வெட்டப்பட்ட பின்னர் அது தொங்கிய மரத்தின் கீழ் நசுக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் அந்த அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை சிறுத்தைப்புலிகளின் எண்ணிக்கையை பாதுகாப்பதற்கும், பாதுகாப்பதற்கும் குழுவானது 25 பரிந்துரைகளை அமைச்சருக்கு அறிக்கையில் முன்வைத்திருந்தது.",
        "ஹட்டனில் உள்ள சம்மர் ஹில் தோட்டத்தில் இலங்கை சிறுத்தை உயிரிழந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டுமென இலங்கையின் விவசாயம், வனவிலங்கு மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "சிறுத்தைப்புலி இறந்தது குறித்து உடனடி விசாரணை நடத்தப்படும் என்றும், வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகளின் அலட்சியத்தால் இந்த மரணம் நேரிட்டது என நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டால், அவர்கள் மீது உரிய ஒழுங்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் ஆகஸ்ட் 8ஆம் தேதி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அட்டன் வனராஜா தேயிலை தோட்டத்திற்கு உட்பட்ட சம்மர் ஹில் தோட்டத்தில் காட்டுப்பன்றிகளுக்காக அமைக்கப்பட்ட வலையில் சிறுத்தை சிக்குண்ட நிலையில் கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 7 ஆம் திகதி கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சிறுத்தை கண்ணியில் இருந்து ஓரளவுக்கு விடுபட முடிந்தது, இருப்பினும், அதன் உடல் கண்ணி கம்பியில் சிக்கியது, பின்னர் அது மரத்தின் மீது ஏற முடிந்தது.",
        "சிறுத்தை மரத்தில் தொங்குவதை கண்ட அப்பகுதி மக்கள் வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு தகவல் கொடுத்தனர்.",
        "அங்கு வந்த வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகள் உடனடியாக மீட்புப் பணியை மேற்கொண்டனர், எனினும், சிறுத்தை மரத்தில் தொங்கிக் கொண்டிருந்த மரத்தை வெட்டியதால் உயிரிழந்ததாக அப்போது தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல் சரக்குகள் இறக்கப்படும், விநியோகம் இன்று இரவு தொடரும்",
        "பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தை நீக்குவது தொடர்பான உறுதிமொழியை ரணில் நிறைவேற்றும் தருணம் ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் – சுமந்திரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோடை மலை சிறுத்தை சோகம்: இறப்புக்கான காரணம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்மர் ஹில் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வள பாதுகாப்பு மஹிந்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறுத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்மர் ஹில் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறுத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறுத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வள பாதுகாப்பு மஹிந்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்மர் ஹில் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறுத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சம்மர் ஹில் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனராஜா தேயிலை தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்ணி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறுத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}