{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/25/warrant-against-lahiru-weerasekara-recalled/",
  "time_ut": 1661431320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Warrant against Lahiru Weerasekara recalled",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Warrant against Lahiru Weerasekara recalled",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The arrest warrant issued against the national organizer of the 'Youth for Change' movement Lahiru Weerasekara was recalled by Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage on Thursday (25).",
        "A warrant was issued for Weerasekara's arrest for failing to appear for a case, and he appeared in court through counsel.",
        "The warrant was issued as he failed to appear in the case where he was named as being part of an unlawful protest in Fort, Colombo in 2017.",
        "Delayed Super Diesel cargo being unloaded, distribution to continue tonight",
        "Time for Ranil to fulfil pledge on repealing PTA made five years ago – Sumanthiran",
        "Deputy Police Chief testifies in probe on assault on journalists"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delayed Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලහිරු වීරසේකරට එරෙහි වරෙන්තුව යළි කැඳවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ‘වෙනසට තාරුණ්‍යය’ ව්‍යාපාරයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක ළහිරු වීරසේකර මහතා අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා විසින් යළි කැඳවනු ලැබීය.",
        "නඩුවකට පෙනී නොසිටීම හේතුවෙන් වීරසේකර අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙස වරෙන්තු නිකුත් කළ අතර ඔහු නීතිඥවරයා මාර්ගයෙන් අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටියේය.",
        "2017 වසරේ කොළඹ කොටුවේ පැවති නීතිවිරෝධී විරෝධතාවයක කොටස්කරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කර තිබූ නඩුවට පෙනී නොසිටීම හේතුවෙන් මෙම වරෙන්තුව නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑම, බෙදා හැරීම අද රාත්‍රියේ සිදු කෙරේ",
        "වසර පහකට පෙර දුන් ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අහෝසි කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඥාව ඉටු කිරීමට රනිල්ට කාලයයි - සුමන්තිරන්",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියේ විමර්ශනයේදී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති සාක්ෂි දෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லஹிரு வீரசேகரவுக்கு எதிரான பிடியாணை திரும்பப் பெறப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 'மாற்றத்திற்கான இளைஞர்கள்' இயக்கத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் லஹிரு வீரசேகரவுக்கு எதிராக பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட பிடியாணையை கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே வியாழக்கிழமை (25) மீள அழைப்பார்.",
        "வழக்கு ஒன்றுக்கு ஆஜராகத் தவறியதால் வீரசேகரவை கைது செய்ய பிடியாணை பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டு, அவர் சட்டத்தரணி மூலம் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜரானார்.",
        "2017ஆம் ஆண்டு கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் இடம்பெற்ற சட்டவிரோத போராட்டத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாக அவர் பெயரிடப்பட்ட வழக்கில் அவர் ஆஜராகத் தவறியதால் இந்த பிடியாணை பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல் சரக்குகள் இறக்கப்படும், விநியோகம் இன்று இரவு தொடரும்",
        "பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தை நீக்குவது தொடர்பான உறுதிமொழியை ரணில் நிறைவேற்றும் தருணம் ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் – சுமந்திரன்",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான விசாரணையில் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சாட்சியமளித்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}