{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/’’අරගලකරුවන්ට-විහාර-මහා-දේවි-උද්‍යානය-වෙන්කර-දෙනවා’’/1-616884",
  "time_ut": 1658490824,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’අරගලකරුවන්ට විහාර මහා දේවි උද්‍යානය වෙන්කර දෙනවා’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vihara Maha Devi Park will be reserved for the activists.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chief organizer of the opposition MP Lakshman Kiriella said in Colombo today (22) that he regrets the way the president is acting when he announced at the party leader's meeting that Vihara Maha Devi Park will be reserved for the activists.",
        "Mr. Kiriella said that the attack on the activists, lawyers and media persons has caused a lot of damage to the country's image, despite the fact that the activists have declared that they will leave within 24 hours.",
        "Mr. Lakshman Kiriella, the main organization of the opposition, who further commented at a press conference held in Colombo, also said:",
        "\"The whole world was watching this peaceful struggle. And they had announced that within 24 hours this struggle would be temporarily stopped. Despite this, we cannot accept this attack at all. The new president told us in the recent party leader meeting that Vihara Maha Devi Park will be reserved for the strugglers. He said clearly. Attacking innocent activists, lawyers, journalists and international journalists while we have declared that we will withdraw within 24 hours is a big damage to our image. At a time when our country is bankrupt, especially when we are asking for help from the rest of the world, this kind of attack is putting Sri Lanka in a frying pan. States like the European Union, Great Britain, America, and Canada have already strongly condemned this attack. A plan against our country has already been passed before the International Human Rights Council. It is very clear that what is happening is that this government is following the same path as the previous government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vihara Maha Devi Park",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vihara Maha Devi Park",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vihara Maha Devi Park",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Great Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’අරගලකරුවන්ට විහාර මහා දේවි උද්‍යානය වෙන්කර දෙනවා’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලකරුවන්ට විහාර මහා දේවි උද්‍යානය වෙන් කර දෙනබව පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා කටයුතු කරන ආකාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කනගාටු වන බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා කොළඹදී  අද (22)පැවසීය.",
        "අරගලකරුවන් පැය 24න් ඉවත් වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබියදි අරගලකරුවන්ට, නීතීඥයින්ට, මාද්‍යවෙදීන්ට පහරදිම රටේ  ප්‍රතිරුපයට විශාල හානියක් බවත් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කොළඹදී පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී තවදුරටත් අදහස් දැක්වූ  විපක්ශයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධානය ලක්ශ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා මෙසේ ද කීවේය.",
        "\"මෙම සාමකාමී අරගලය  දෙස මුළු ජත්‍යන්තරයම බලගෙන හිටියා. එමෙන්ම ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුනා පැය 24ක් ඇතුලත මෙම අරගලය තාවකාලිකව නවත්වන බවත්. එසේ තිබියදි මෙම පහරදිම ගැන අපිට කිසිසෙත්ම පිලිගන්න බැහැ. අරගලකරුවන්ට වීහාර මහා දේවි උද්‍යානය වෙන් කර දෙනවා කියලා පසුගියදා පක්ශ නායක් රැස්වීමෙදි නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා අපිට පැහදිලිවම කිව්වා. පැය 24න් ඉවත් වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබියදි අහින්සක අරගලකරුවන්ට,නීතිඥ මහත්වරුට, මාද්‍යවෙදීන්ට ,ජත්‍යන්තර මාද්‍යවෙදීන්ට පහරදිම අපේ ප්‍රතිරුපයට විශාල හානියක්. අපේ රට බංකොලොත් වෙලා තියන අවස්ථාවක විශේෂයෙන්ම බටහිට රටවල් වලින් අපි උදව් ඉල්ලන අවස්ථාවක මෙවනි ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කිරිම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කබලෙන් ලිපට දැමිමක් බව ප්‍රකාශ කරනවා. ඒවාගෙම දැනටමත් මෙම ප්‍රහාරය යුරොපා හවුල ,මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ,ඇමෙරිකව,කැනඩාව වැනි රටවල් තරයේ හෙලා දැකලා තියනවා. දැනටමත් අපේ රටට විරුද්ධව ජත්‍යන්තර මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය ඉදිරියේ යොජනාවක් සම්මත වෙලා තියනවා. දැන් මේ ප්‍රශ්න ඒවාට එකතු වුනාම අපිට විශාල ජත්‍යන්තර අර්බුදයකට මුහුන දෙන්න සිද්ද වෙනවා මේ රජය යන්නෙත් පරන රජය ගිය පාරේමයි කියන එක ඉතාමත් පැහැදිලියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විහාර මහා දේවී උද්‍යානය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විහාර මහා දේවී උද්‍යානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "විහාර මහා දේවී උද්‍යානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விஹார மகா தேவி பூங்கா ஆர்வலர்களுக்காக ஒதுக்கப்படும்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "விகார மகாதேவி பூங்காவை செயற்பாட்டாளர்களுக்காக ஒதுக்குவதாக கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் அறிவித்த ஜனாதிபதியின் செயற்பாடு குறித்து வருந்துவதாக எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் எம்.பி லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல இன்று (22) கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள், சட்டத்தரணிகள், ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குள் வெளியேறப்போவதாக செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் அறிவித்துள்ள போதிலும், நாட்டின் நற்பெயருக்கு பெரும் சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக திரு.கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் மேலும் கருத்துத் தெரிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பான திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல மேலும் கூறியதாவது:",
        "“இந்த அமைதிப் போராட்டத்தை முழு உலகமும் பார்த்துக் கொண்டிருந்தது. இன்னும் 24 மணி நேரத்திற்குள் இந்தப் போராட்டம் தற்காலிகமாக நிறுத்தப்படும் என்று அவர்கள் அறிவித்தனர். இருந்த போதிலும் இந்தத் தாக்குதலை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளவே முடியாது. புதிய ஜனாதிபதி அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் விஹார மகா தேவி பார்க் போராட்டத்தினருக்கே ஒதுக்கப்படும் என்றார்.. 24 மணி நேரத்தில் வாபஸ் பெறுவோம் என அறிவித்திருந்த நிலையில் அப்பாவி ஆர்வலர்கள், வழக்கறிஞர்கள், பத்திரிக்கையாளர்கள், சர்வதேச பத்திரிக்கையாளர்கள் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்துவது நமது இமேஜுக்கு பெரும் சேதாரம்.நாடு திவாலாகும் வேளையில். , குறிப்பாக உலகின் பிற நாடுகளிடம் உதவி கேட்கும் போது, ​​இதுபோன்ற தாக்குதல்கள் இலங்கையை வறுக்க வைக்கிறது.ஐரோப்பிய யூனியன், கிரேட் பிரிட்டன், அமெரிக்கா, கனடா போன்ற நாடுகள் ஏற்கனவே இந்த தாக்குதலுக்கு கடும் கண்டனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.ஒரு திட்டம் எமது நாட்டுக்கு எதிராக ஏற்கனவே சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.இதற்கு முன்னைய அரசாங்கத்தின் பாதையையே இந்த அரசாங்கமும் பின்பற்றி வருகின்றமை மிகவும் தெளிவாகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விஹார மகா தேவி பூங்கா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஹார மகா தேவி பூங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஹார மகா தேவி பூங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}