{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Red-alert-issued-for-20-districts-as-rains-intensify-Met-Dept/108-244062",
  "time_ut": 1661922823,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Red alert issued for 20 districts as rains intensify: Met Dept.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Red alert issued for 20 districts as rains intensify: Met Dept.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A red alert (High risk) for heavy deluge has been issued for 20 districts, the Meteorology Department said today.",
        "They said with the low-level atmospheric disturbance in the vicinity of Sri Lanka, fairly heavy rainfall of more than 150 mm could be expected in some places in Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central, and Uva provinces.",
        "The Department requests that people living in hilly slopes (particularly landslide-prone areas) and low-lying areas adjacent to river basins to be vigilant.",
        "Motorists who are using the roads in the hilly areas and along the slopes are cautioned to be vigilant and watchful against underlying dangers caused by lightning, landslides etc. and also beware of fallen trees, rock slips and power lines.",
        "Accordingly, the 20 districts, including Trincomalee, Anuradhapura, Puttalam, Polonnaruwa, Matale, Batticaloa, Kurunegala, Gampaha, Kegalla, Kandy, Nuwara Eliya, Badulla, Ampara, Monaragala, Kalutara, Ratnapura, Kalutara, Galle, Matara and Hambantota have been alerted over the weather conditions.",
        "Furthermore, the department requested to be alerted on the advisories issued by the Meteorology Department and to contact the local disaster management authorities for emergency assistance. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Met Dept",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Meteorology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalla, Kandy, Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara, Monaragala, Kalutara,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Meteorology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වර්ෂාවත් සමඟ දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 20කට රතු නිවේදන නිකුත් කරයි: කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 20කට අධික ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් පිළිබඳ රතු නිවේදනයක් (අධි අවදානම්) නිකුත් කර ඇති බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසන්න පහළ වායුගෝලයේ කැළඹීමත් සමඟ බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ඉක්ම වූ තරමක තද වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කළ හැකි බව ඔවුහු පවසති.",
        "කඳු බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල (විශේෂයෙන් නාය යාම් අවදානම් සහිත ප්‍රදේශවල) සහ ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම්වල ජීවත් වන ජනතාව අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙස එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල සහ බෑවුම් ආශ්‍රිත මාර්ග භාවිත කරන රියදුරන්ට අකුණු, නායයෑම් ආදියෙන් සිදුවන යටින් පවතින අනතුරු පිළිබඳව විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙසත්, ගස් කඩාවැටීම්, ගල් පෙරළීම් සහ විදුලි රැහැන් ආදියෙන් ප්‍රවේශම් වන ලෙසත් ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, අනුරාධපුරය, පුත්තලම, පොළොන්නරුව, මාතලේ, මඩකලපුව, කුරුණෑගල, ගම්පහ, කෑගල්ල, මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, බදුල්ල, අම්පාර, මොණරාගල, කළුතර, රත්නපුර, කළුතර, ගාල්ල, මාතර සහ හම්බන්තොට ඇතුළු දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 20 සඳහා අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කර ඇත. කාලගුණික තත්ත්වයන් මත.",
        "තවද, කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද උපදෙස් පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙසත්, හදිසි සහන සඳහා ප්‍රාදේශීය ආපදා කළමනාකරණ බලධාරීන් අමතන ලෙසත් එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඉල්ලා සිටියි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙට් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල, මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර, මොණරාගල, කළුතර,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கனமழை தீவிரமடைந்துள்ளதால் 20 மாவட்டங்களுக்கு ரெட் அலர்ட் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது: வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "20 மாவட்டங்களுக்கு கடும் பிரளயம் காரணமாக ரெட் அலர்ட் (அதிக ஆபத்து) விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையை அண்மித்துள்ள குறைந்த வளிமண்டல குழப்பத்துடன், மேற்கு, தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான கனமழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என்று அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மலைப்பாங்கான சரிவுகளில் (குறிப்பாக மண்சரிவு அபாயம் உள்ள பகுதிகள்) மற்றும் ஆற்றுப் படுகைகளை அண்டிய தாழ்நிலப் பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் அவதானத்துடன் இருக்குமாறு திணைக்களம் கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "மலைப்பாங்கான பகுதிகளிலும் சரிவுகளிலும் உள்ள சாலைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தும் வாகன ஓட்டிகள், மின்னல், நிலச்சரிவு போன்றவற்றால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய ஆபத்துகள் குறித்து அவதானமாகவும் அவதானமாகவும் இருக்குமாறும், மரங்கள், பாறை சரிவுகள் மற்றும் மின்கம்பிகள் விழுவதைக் குறித்தும் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு எச்சரிக்கப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "இதன்படி, திருகோணமலை, அனுராதபுரம், புத்தளம், பொலன்னறுவை, மாத்தளை, மட்டக்களப்பு, குருநாகல், கம்பஹா, கேகாலை, கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, பதுளை, அம்பாறை, மொனராகலை, களுத்துறை, இரத்தினபுரி, களுத்துறை, காலி, மாத்தறை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோ உள்ளிட்ட 20 மாவட்டங்களுக்கு எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. வானிலை நிலைமைகள் மீது.",
        "மேலும், வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களத்தினால் வழங்கப்படும் ஆலோசனைகள் தொடர்பில் விழிப்புடன் இருக்குமாறும், அவசர உதவிக்கு உள்ளூர் அனர்த்த முகாமைத்துவ அதிகாரிகளை தொடர்பு கொள்ளுமாறும் திணைக்களம் கோரியுள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சந்தித்தது துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை, கண்டி, நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை, மொனராகலை, களுத்துறை,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}