{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Yellow-is-our-colour-SJB/108-239740",
  "time_ut": 1656089664,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Yellow is our colour -SJB",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Yellow is our colour -SJB",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "“We are not against paying tribute to Australians who came to Sri Lanka for a tour at this difficult period”",
        "No one should use yellow for political purposes as it is the party colour of Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), an MP representing the party said yesterday.",
        "SJB MP Thushara Indunil Amarasena told a press conference that no one should use yellow for any political matters as it is the official colour of his party.   The MP was referring to the message which was circulated on social media asking those who come to view Sri Lanka-Australia one day international at Premadasa stadium to pay tribute to Australians.",
        "“We are not against paying tribute to Australians who came to Sri Lanka for a tour at this difficult period but we are against using our colour. The official colour of SJB is yellow, while green is also used to symbolise that we are a UNP breakaway group. We have also seen in social media asking those who go for the one day match to come in yellow and then go to Galle Face to join the struggle to topple the government after the match. We also would like to state that we the SJB are the architects of the Aragalaya (struggle), he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yellow",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thushara Indunil Amarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කහ අපේ වර්ණය -SJB",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"මෙම දුෂ්කර කාල පරිච්ඡේදයේදී සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන්ට උපහාර දැක්වීමට අපි විරුද්ධ නැහැ\"",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පක්‍ෂයේ වර්ණය බැවින් කිසිවකු දේශපාලන අරමුණු සඳහා කහ භාවිතා නොකළ යුතු බව එම පක්‍ෂය නියෝජනය කරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල් අමරසේන මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පවත්වමින් කියා සිටියේ කහ වර්ණය තම පක්ෂයේ නිල වර්ණය බැවින් කිසිඳු දේශපාලන කටයුත්තකට කහ භාවිතා නොකළ යුතු බවයි. පේ‍්‍රමදාස ක‍්‍රීඩාංගණයේ පැවැත්වෙන ශ‍්‍රී ලංකා – ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියා එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරග නැරඹීමට පැමිණෙන අයට ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියානුවන්ට උපහාර දක්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ ප‍්‍රචාරය වූ පණිවිඩය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් මන්ත‍්‍රීවරයා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“මෙම දුෂ්කර කාල පරිච්ඡේදයේදී සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන්ට උපහාර දැක්වීමට අපි විරුද්ධ නොවෙමු, නමුත් අපගේ වර්ණය භාවිතා කිරීමට අපි විරුද්ධ වෙමු. SJB හි නිල වර්ණය කහ වන අතර, අපි එජාපයෙන් කැඩී ගිය කණ්ඩායමක් බව සංකේතවත් කිරීමට කොළ පැහැය ද භාවිතා වේ. ඒ වගේම අපි සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල දැකලා තියෙනවා එක්දින තරගයට යන අයට කහ ඇඳගෙන ඇවිත් ගාලු මුවදොරට යන අයට තරගයෙන් පස්සේ ආණ්ඩුව පෙරළීමේ සටනට එකතු වෙන්න කියලා. SJB අපි අරගලයේ (අරගලයේ) නිර්මාණකරුවන් බව ද ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කහ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල් අමරසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மஞ்சள் எங்கள் நிறம் -SJB",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இக்கட்டான காலகட்டத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலா வந்த அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள் அல்ல.",
        "மஞ்சள் நிறத்தை அரசியல் நோக்கங்களுக்காக யாரும் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம், ஏனெனில் இது சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா (SJB) கட்சியின் நிறம் என்பதால், அக்கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் எம்பி நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மஞ்சள் நிறமானது தமது கட்சியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ நிறம் என்பதனால் எவரும் எந்த அரசியல் விடயங்களுக்கும் மஞ்சள் நிறத்தை பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம் என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் துஷார இந்துனில் அமரசேன ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார். பிரேமதாச மைதானத்தில் இலங்கை - அவுஸ்திரேலியா ஒருநாள் சர்வதேச போட்டிகளை பார்வையிட வருபவர்கள் அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்துமாறு சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பரப்பப்பட்ட செய்தி தொடர்பில் எம்.பி.",
        "“இந்த இக்கட்டான காலகட்டத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலா வந்த அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள் அல்ல, ஆனால் எங்கள் நிறத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள். SJB இன் உத்தியோகபூர்வ நிறம் மஞ்சள், அதே சமயம் நாங்கள் UNP பிரிந்து சென்ற குழு என்பதை அடையாளப்படுத்த பச்சை நிறமும் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. ஒரு நாள் போட்டிக்கு செல்பவர்களை மஞ்சளில் வருமாறும், பின்னர் காலி முகத்திடலுக்குச் செல்பவர்களை போட்டி முடிந்து அரசை கவிழ்க்கும் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுமாறும் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் கூறுவதையும் நாம் பார்த்திருக்கிறோம். நாங்கள் SJB அரகலயாவின் (போராட்டத்தின்) சிற்பிகள் என்பதையும் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்ள விரும்புகிறோம், என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஞ்சள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துஷார இந்துனில் அமரசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Yellow is our colour -SJB",
  "body_lines": [
    "“We are not against paying tribute to Australians who came to Sri Lanka for a tour at this difficult period”",
    "No one should use yellow for political purposes as it is the party colour of Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), an MP representing the party said yesterday.",
    "SJB MP Thushara Indunil Amarasena told a press conference that no one should use yellow for any political matters as it is the official colour of his party.   The MP was referring to the message which was circulated on social media asking those who come to view Sri Lanka-Australia one day international at Premadasa stadium to pay tribute to Australians.",
    "“We are not against paying tribute to Australians who came to Sri Lanka for a tour at this difficult period but we are against using our colour. The official colour of SJB is yellow, while green is also used to symbolise that we are a UNP breakaway group. We have also seen in social media asking those who go for the one day match to come in yellow and then go to Galle Face to join the struggle to topple the government after the match. We also would like to state that we the SJB are the architects of the Aragalaya (struggle), he said."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Yellow is our colour -SJB",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "“We are not against paying tribute to Australians who came to Sri Lanka for a tour at this difficult period”",
        "No one should use yellow for political purposes as it is the party colour of Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), an MP representing the party said yesterday.",
        "SJB MP Thushara Indunil Amarasena told a press conference that no one should use yellow for any political matters as it is the official colour of his party.   The MP was referring to the message which was circulated on social media asking those who come to view Sri Lanka-Australia one day international at Premadasa stadium to pay tribute to Australians.",
        "“We are not against paying tribute to Australians who came to Sri Lanka for a tour at this difficult period but we are against using our colour. The official colour of SJB is yellow, while green is also used to symbolise that we are a UNP breakaway group. We have also seen in social media asking those who go for the one day match to come in yellow and then go to Galle Face to join the struggle to topple the government after the match. We also would like to state that we the SJB are the architects of the Aragalaya (struggle), he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yellow",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thushara Indunil Amarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කහ අපේ වර්ණය -SJB",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"මෙම දුෂ්කර කාල පරිච්ඡේදයේදී සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන්ට උපහාර දැක්වීමට අපි විරුද්ධ නැහැ\"",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පක්‍ෂයේ වර්ණය බැවින් කිසිවකු දේශපාලන අරමුණු සඳහා කහ භාවිතා නොකළ යුතු බව එම පක්‍ෂය නියෝජනය කරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල් අමරසේන මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පවත්වමින් කියා සිටියේ කහ වර්ණය තම පක්ෂයේ නිල වර්ණය බැවින් කිසිඳු දේශපාලන කටයුත්තකට කහ භාවිතා නොකළ යුතු බවයි. පේ‍්‍රමදාස ක‍්‍රීඩාංගණයේ පැවැත්වෙන ශ‍්‍රී ලංකා – ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියා එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරග නැරඹීමට පැමිණෙන අයට ඕස්ටේ‍්‍රලියානුවන්ට උපහාර දක්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ ප‍්‍රචාරය වූ පණිවිඩය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් මන්ත‍්‍රීවරයා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“මෙම දුෂ්කර කාල පරිච්ඡේදයේදී සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන්ට උපහාර දැක්වීමට අපි විරුද්ධ නොවෙමු, නමුත් අපගේ වර්ණය භාවිතා කිරීමට අපි විරුද්ධ වෙමු. SJB හි නිල වර්ණය කහ වන අතර, අපි එජාපයෙන් කැඩී ගිය කණ්ඩායමක් බව සංකේතවත් කිරීමට කොළ පැහැය ද භාවිතා වේ. ඒ වගේම අපි සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල දැකලා තියෙනවා එක්දින තරගයට යන අයට කහ ඇඳගෙන ඇවිත් ගාලු මුවදොරට යන අයට තරගයෙන් පස්සේ ආණ්ඩුව පෙරළීමේ සටනට එකතු වෙන්න කියලා. SJB අපි අරගලයේ (අරගලයේ) නිර්මාණකරුවන් බව ද ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කහ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල් අමරසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மஞ்சள் எங்கள் நிறம் -SJB",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இக்கட்டான காலகட்டத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலா வந்த அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள் அல்ல.",
        "மஞ்சள் நிறத்தை அரசியல் நோக்கங்களுக்காக யாரும் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம், ஏனெனில் இது சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா (SJB) கட்சியின் நிறம் என்பதால், அக்கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் எம்பி நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மஞ்சள் நிறமானது தமது கட்சியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ நிறம் என்பதனால் எவரும் எந்த அரசியல் விடயங்களுக்கும் மஞ்சள் நிறத்தை பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம் என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் துஷார இந்துனில் அமரசேன ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார். பிரேமதாச மைதானத்தில் இலங்கை - அவுஸ்திரேலியா ஒருநாள் சர்வதேச போட்டிகளை பார்வையிட வருபவர்கள் அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்துமாறு சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பரப்பப்பட்ட செய்தி தொடர்பில் எம்.பி.",
        "“இந்த இக்கட்டான காலகட்டத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலா வந்த அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள் அல்ல, ஆனால் எங்கள் நிறத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள். SJB இன் உத்தியோகபூர்வ நிறம் மஞ்சள், அதே சமயம் நாங்கள் UNP பிரிந்து சென்ற குழு என்பதை அடையாளப்படுத்த பச்சை நிறமும் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. ஒரு நாள் போட்டிக்கு செல்பவர்களை மஞ்சளில் வருமாறும், பின்னர் காலி முகத்திடலுக்குச் செல்பவர்களை போட்டி முடிந்து அரசை கவிழ்க்கும் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுமாறும் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் கூறுவதையும் நாம் பார்த்திருக்கிறோம். நாங்கள் SJB அரகலயாவின் (போராட்டத்தின்) சிற்பிகள் என்பதையும் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்ள விரும்புகிறோம், என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஞ்சள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துஷார இந்துனில் அமரசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}