{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78783",
  "time_ut": 1658949840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India sends “clear message” that it is monitoring the ship’s progress “carefully” of Chinese space and satellite tracking research vessel “Yuan Wang 5” expected to dock in Sri Lanka’s Hambantota port from August 11-17 for “replenishment” but  Sri Lanka Defence Ministry  Spolesman says “We have no confirmation of such a vessel calling at the Hambantota port,”",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India sends “clear message” that it is monitoring the ship’s progress “carefully” of Chinese space and satellite tracking research vessel “Yuan Wang 5” expected to dock in Sri Lanka’s Hambantota port from August 11-17 for “replenishment” but  Sri Lanka Defence Ministry  Spolesman says “We have no confirmation of such a vessel calling at the Hambantota port,”",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s Defence Ministry on Thursday denied reports that a Chinese research vessel involved in space and satellite tracking would enter the Hambantota port in August this year, even as India sent a “clear message” that it was monitoring the ship’s progress “carefully”.",
        "“We have no confirmation of such a vessel calling at the Hambantota port,” a Defence Ministry spokesman told The Hindu in Colombo, when asked about the reports. The vessel’s arrival was highlighted by BRISL (Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka), a Colombo-based organisation studying China’s ambitious connectivity project.",
        "On its website, the BRISL said “Yuan Wang 5, which set sail from the Chinese port of Jiangyin on July 13, and passed by Taiwan is now in the East China Sea, and was expected to dock in Sri Lanka’s Hambantota port from August 11-17 for ‘replenishment’ while it continues to conduct Space and Satellite control and research activities in the north-western part of the Indian Ocean Region” through August and September.",
        "“The visit of Yuan Wang 5 to Hambantota Port will be excellent opportunity for Sri Lanka and the regional developing nations to learn and develop their own space programmes,” the report published by the “education and consulting platform” BRISL said last week.",
        "“It is not a military vessel. The details of the course of the vessel are available online for anyone to see,” BRISL Director Yasiru Ranaraja told The Hindu.",
        "When asked, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) confirmed it had seen the report, which had appeared in TheEconomic Times. “We are aware of reports of a proposed visit by this vessel combined to the port in August. Let me just say that the government carefully monitors any development having a bearing on India’s security and economic interests and takes all necessary measures to safeguard them. I think that should be a clear message,” said MEA spokesperson Arindam Bagchi during a weekly media briefing.",
        "According to information on a global marine tracking website (www.marinetraffic.com), the Yuang Wan 5 is currently sailing “at 19.0 knots”, and headed to Hambantota, expected to arrive on August 11 at noon. It is unclear whether the Sri Lankan Defence Ministry’s statement indicates that the ship was not actually bound for Hambantota, or that India’s objections have been taken on board and the ship has been diverted. The Hindu is yet to receive a response from Sri Lanka’s Ministry of Defence to its query citing the MEA spokesman’s comment.",
        "India has traditionally taken a stern view of Chinese military or suspected dual-purpose vessels in the Indian ocean, and the MEA has protested such visits with Sri Lanka in the past. India’s concerns have been focused on Hambantota in particular. In 2017, Colombo leased the southern port to China Merchant Port Holdings, after Sri Lanka was unable to keep its loan repayment commitments, fanning fears over potential use of the port for military purposes.",
        "In 2014, Sri Lanka’s decision to allow a Chinese nuclear-powered submarine Changzheng 2 in Colombo became a diplomatic flashpoint, as New Delhi expressed serious concern. Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who was then Secretary to the Ministry of Defence, flew to New Delhi to meet with National Security Adviser (NSA) Ajit Doval and discuss the decision. In 2019, the Indian Navy had pushed out a Chinese Naval ship Shi Yan 1, that had come into waters close to the Andaman Islands, and in 2020, two Chinese Research vessels in the Indian Ocean near the Andaman islands had also sparked concerns similar to the current proposed visit of the satellite tracking ship."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 11-17",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Defence Ministry  Spolesman",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hambantota",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jiangyin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the East China Sea",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Satellite",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yasiru Ranaraja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TheEconomic Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Yuang Wan 5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11 at noon",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Defence Ministry’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China Merchant Port Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changzheng 2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajit Doval",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan 1",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Andaman Islands",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Research",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Andaman",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාව වන “යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5” නෞකාවේ ප්‍රගතිය “ප්‍රවේශමෙන්” නිරීක්ෂණය කරන බවට ඉන්දියාව “පැහැදිලි පණිවිඩයක්” යවමින් “නැවත පිරවීම” සඳහා අගෝස්තු 11-17 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක එවැනි යාත්‍රාවක් හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණි බවට කිසිදු තහවුරුවක් නොමැති බව අමාත්‍යාංශ ස්පෝල්ස්මන් පවසයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "නෞකාවේ ප්‍රගතිය “ප්‍රවේශමෙන්” නිරීක්ෂණය කරන බවට ඉන්දියාව “පැහැදිලි පණිවිඩයක්” යවා තිබියදීත්, මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමට සම්බන්ධ චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඇතුළු වන බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "“එවැනි යාත්‍රාවක් හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන බවට අපට කිසිදු තහවුරුවක් නැත,” යැයි ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් කොළඹ ද හින්දු පුවත්පතට එම වාර්තා පිළිබඳව විමසූ විට පැවසීය. චීනයේ අභිලාෂකාමී සම්බන්ධතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය අධ්‍යයනය කරන කොළඹ පදනම් කරගත් සංවිධානයක් වන BRISL (Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka) විසින් නෞකාවේ පැමිණීම කැපී පෙනුණි.",
        "BRISL සිය වෙබ් අඩවියේ සඳහන් කළේ, “ජූලි 13 වන දින චීනයේ ජියැන්ග්යින් වරායෙන් යාත්‍රා කර තායිවානය පසුකර ගිය යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 දැන් නැගෙනහිර චීන මුහුදේ පවතින අතර අගෝස්තු 11 සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන ලදී. ඉන්දියන් සාගර කලාපයේ වයඹ දිග ප්‍රදේශයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා පාලන සහ පර්යේෂණ කටයුතු අඛණ්ඩව කරගෙන යන අතරතුර 'නැවත පිරවීම' සඳහා -17\" අගෝස්තු සහ සැප්තැම්බර් දක්වා.",
        "“යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහ කලාපීය සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවලට ඔවුන්ගේම අභ්‍යවකාශ වැඩසටහන් ඉගෙන ගැනීමට සහ සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට කදිම අවස්ථාවක් වනු ඇත,” “අධ්‍යාපන සහ උපදේශන වේදිකාව” BRISL විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද වාර්තාව පසුගිය සතියේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“එය හමුදා යාත්‍රාවක් නොවේ. යාත්‍රාවේ ගමන් මග පිළිබඳ විස්තර ඕනෑම කෙනෙකුට දැකගත හැකි පරිදි අන්තර්ජාලය හරහා ලබා ගත හැකිය,” BRISL අධ්‍යක්ෂ යසිරු රණරාජා ද හින්දු වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "විමසූ විට, TheEconomic Times හි පළ වූ වාර්තාව තමන් දුටු බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය (MEA) තහවුරු කළේය. “මෙම යාත්‍රාව අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී වරායට ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීමට යෝජිත සංචාරයක් පිළිබඳ වාර්තා පිළිබඳව අපි දනිමු. ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම සංවර්ධනයක් රජය පරෙස්සමින් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කරන අතර ඒවා ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය සියලු පියවර ගන්නා බව පමණක් මට කියන්නට ඉඩ දෙන්න. එය පැහැදිලි පණිවිඩයක් විය යුතු යැයි මම සිතනවා,” MEA ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi සතිපතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝලීය සමුද්‍ර ලුහුබැඳීමේ වෙබ් අඩවියක (www.marinetraffic.com) තොරතුරුවලට අනුව, Yuang Wan 5 දැනට \"ගැට 19.0 ට\" යාත්‍රා කරමින් සිටින අතර, අගෝස්තු 11 වන දින මධ්‍යහ්නයට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂාවෙන් හම්බන්තොට බලා ගමන් කරයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශයෙන් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ නෞකාව ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම හම්බන්තොට බලා නොපැමිණි බව ද, නැතහොත් ඉන්දියාවේ විරෝධතා රැගෙන නැව හරවා යවා ඇති බව ද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත. MEA ප්‍රකාශකයාගේ ප්‍රකාශය උපුටා දක්වමින් හින්දු පුවත්පතට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් තවමත් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබී නොමැත.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සාම්ප්‍රදායිකව චීන හමුදාව හෝ ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ ද්විත්ව කාර්ය යාත්‍රා සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැඩි දෘෂ්ටියක් ගෙන ඇති අතර, MEA විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ එවැනි සංචාරවලට විරෝධය පළ කර ඇත. විශේෂයෙන්ම හම්බන්තොට කෙරෙහි ඉන්දියාවේ අවධානය යොමු වී ඇත. 2017 දී කොළඹ, දකුණු වරාය චයිනා මර්චන්ට් පෝට් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් වෙත බදු දුන්නේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සිය ණය ආපසු ගෙවීමේ වගකීම් තබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වීමෙන් පසුව, වරාය යුදමය අරමුණු සඳහා භාවිතා කළ හැකි බවට බියක් ඇති කරමිනි.",
        "2014 දී, නව දිල්ලිය බරපතල කනස්සල්ලක් ප්‍රකාශ කළ බැවින්, චීන න්‍යෂ්ටික බලයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන Changzheng 2 සබ්මැරීනයකට කොළඹ දී අවසර දීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගත් තීරණය රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ප්‍රබෝධයක් බවට පත් විය. එවකට ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්ව සිටි හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා ජාතික ආරක්‍ෂක උපදේශක (NSA) අජිත් දොවාල් මුණගැසී මෙම තීරණය ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නවදිල්ලියට ගියේය. 2019 වසරේ අන්දමන් දූපත් ආශ්‍රිතව මුහුදට පැමිණි චීන නාවික හමුදාවට අයත් Shi Yan 1 නෞකාවක් ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදාව විසින් පිටතට තල්ලු කර ඇති අතර 2020 වසරේ අන්දමන් දූපත් ආසන්නයේ ඉන්දීය සාගරයේ චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රා දෙකක් ද මෙවැනිම ගැටළු ඇති කර තිබේ. චන්ද්‍රිකා නිරීක්ෂණ නෞකාවේ වත්මන් යෝජිත සංචාරය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 11-17",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ඔත්තුකරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජියැන්ග්යින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර චීන මුහුද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්රිකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යසිරු රණරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද ඉකොනොමික් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුවාං වන් 5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11 දවල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චයිනා මර්චන්ට් පෝට් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changzheng 2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් දොවාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan 1",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්දමන් දූපත්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන පර්යේෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්දමන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனாவின் விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலான “யுவான் வாங் 5” கப்பலின் முன்னேற்றத்தை “கவனமாக” கண்காணித்து வருவதாக இந்தியா “தெளிவான செய்தியை” அனுப்புகிறது, ஆனால் இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்புக்காக “மறுபரிசீலனை” க்காக ஆகஸ்ட் 11-17 முதல் இலங்கையின் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு அவ்வாறான கப்பல் வருவதை எங்களிடம் உறுதிப்படுத்தவில்லை என அமைச்சின் ஸ்போல்ஸ்மேன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல் இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்குள் நுழையும் என்ற செய்தியை இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் வியாழக்கிழமை மறுத்துள்ளது, இந்தியா கப்பலின் முன்னேற்றத்தை \"கவனமாக\" கண்காணித்து வருவதாக \"தெளிவான செய்தியை\" அனுப்பிய போதும்.",
        "\"அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு அத்தகைய கப்பல் வருவதை எங்களிடம் உறுதிப்படுத்தவில்லை\" என்று பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள தி ஹிந்துவிடம் அறிக்கைகள் குறித்து கேட்டபோது கூறினார். கப்பலின் வருகையை BRISL (Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka), கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட அமைப்பானது, சீனாவின் லட்சிய இணைப்புத் திட்டத்தை ஆய்வு செய்கிறது.",
        "BRISL தனது இணையத்தளத்தில், “யுவான் வாங் 5, ஜூலை 13 அன்று சீன துறைமுகமான ஜியாங்யினில் இருந்து புறப்பட்டு, தைவானைக் கடந்து இப்போது கிழக்கு சீனக் கடலில் உள்ளது, மேலும் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் இலங்கையின் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டா துறைமுகத்தில் கப்பல்துறை வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. -17 ஆகஸ்ட் மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் வரை இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பிராந்தியத்தின் வடமேற்குப் பகுதியில் விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து நடத்தும் போது 'மறு நிரப்புதல்'.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 இன் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு விஜயம் செய்வது, இலங்கை மற்றும் பிராந்திய வளரும் நாடுகளுக்கு தங்களின் சொந்த விண்வெளி திட்டங்களை கற்றுக்கொள்வதற்கும் அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதற்கும் சிறந்த வாய்ப்பாக அமையும் என கடந்த வாரம் BRISL வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“இது இராணுவக் கப்பல் அல்ல. கப்பலின் போக்குவரத்தின் விவரங்கள் எவரும் பார்க்க ஆன்லைனில் கிடைக்கின்றன, ”என்று BRISL இயக்குனர் யசிரு ரணராஜா தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "என்று கேட்டபோது, ​​TheEconomic Times இல் வெளிவந்த அந்த அறிக்கையை தான் பார்த்ததாக வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் (MEA) உறுதிப்படுத்தியது. “ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் துறைமுகத்திற்கு இந்தக் கப்பலின் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட வருகை பற்றிய அறிக்கைகள் எங்களுக்குத் தெரியும். இந்தியாவின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் எந்தவொரு வளர்ச்சியையும் அரசாங்கம் கவனமாகக் கண்காணித்து, அவற்றைப் பாதுகாக்க தேவையான அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளையும் எடுக்கிறது என்பதை மட்டும் சொல்லிவிடுகிறேன். இது ஒரு தெளிவான செய்தியாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று நான் நினைக்கிறேன், ”என்று MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி வாராந்திர ஊடக சந்திப்பின் போது கூறினார்.",
        "உலகளாவிய கடல் கண்காணிப்பு இணையத்தளத்தின் (www.marinetraffic.com) தகவலின்படி, யுவாங் வான் 5 தற்போது \"19.0 முடிச்சுகளில்\" பயணிக்கிறது, மேலும் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி நண்பகல் அம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. கப்பல் உண்மையில் அம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு செல்லவில்லை என்பதை இலங்கை பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் அறிக்கை குறிப்பிடுகிறதா அல்லது இந்தியாவின் ஆட்சேபனைகளை ஏற்று கப்பல் திருப்பி விடப்பட்டதா என்பது தெளிவாக இல்லை. MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளரின் கருத்தை மேற்கோள் காட்டி தனது கேள்விக்கு இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்திடம் இருந்து தி இந்து இன்னும் பதிலைப் பெறவில்லை.",
        "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் சீன இராணுவம் அல்லது சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான இரட்டை நோக்கம் கொண்ட கப்பல்கள் குறித்து இந்தியா பாரம்பரியமாக கடுமையான பார்வையை எடுத்து வருகிறது, மேலும் MEA கடந்த காலங்களில் இலங்கையுடனான இத்தகைய வருகைகளுக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தது. குறிப்பாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் இந்தியாவின் கவலைகள் குவிந்துள்ளன. 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டில், கொழும்பு தெற்கு துறைமுகத்தை சைனா மெர்ச்சன்ட் போர்ட் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திற்கு குத்தகைக்கு வழங்கியது, இலங்கை தனது கடனை திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் கடப்பாடுகளைக் கடைப்பிடிக்க முடியாததால், துறைமுகத்தை இராணுவ நோக்கங்களுக்காகப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் பற்றிய அச்சத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது.",
        "2014 இல், புது தில்லி தீவிர கவலையை வெளிப்படுத்தியதால், கொழும்பில் சீனாவின் அணுசக்தியால் இயங்கும் சாங்செங் 2 நீர்மூழ்கிக் கப்பலை அனுமதிப்பதற்கான இலங்கையின் முடிவு இராஜதந்திர ஃப்ளாஷ் புள்ளியாக மாறியது. அப்போது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளராக இருந்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர் (என்எஸ்ஏ) அஜித் தோவலைச் சந்தித்து இந்த முடிவைப் பற்றி விவாதிப்பதற்காக புதுடெல்லி சென்றார். 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டில், அந்தமான் தீவுகளுக்கு அருகில் உள்ள கடலுக்குள் வந்த சீன கடற்படைக் கப்பலான ஷி யான் 1 ஐ இந்திய கடற்படை வெளியேற்றியது, மேலும் 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டில், அந்தமான் தீவுகளுக்கு அருகிலுள்ள இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் இரண்டு சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல்களும் இதே போன்ற கவலைகளைத் தூண்டின. செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலின் தற்போதைய உத்தேச வருகை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11-17",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் ஸ்போல்ஸ்மேன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜியாங்யின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு சீன கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயற்கைக்கோள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாசிரு ரணராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி எகனாமிக் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுவாங் வான் 5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11 மதியம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைனா மெர்ச்சன்ட் போர்ட் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்செங் 2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் தோவல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan 1",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தமான் தீவுகள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தமான்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}