{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/Ranjan-leaves-prison/155-243788",
  "time_ut": 1661506672,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranjan leaves prison",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranjan leaves prison",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake, who was serving a four-year sentence on charges of contempt of court, left the prison a short while ago after being granted presidential pardon.",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, Minister Manusha Nanayakkara and several other SJB MPs had gathered outside the Welikada prison to welcome him.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe signed the document granting conditional presidential pardon to former Parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake this morning."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන් බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත සිව් වසරක සිරදඬුවමක් විඳිමින් සිටි හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා ජනාධිපති සමාව ලැබීමෙන් පසු මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටව ගියේය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර ඇතුළු SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඔහු පිළිගැනීමට වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටත රැස්ව සිටියා.",
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීමේ ලියවිල්ලට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පෙරවරුවේ අත්සන් තැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சன் சிறையிலிருந்து வெளியேறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் நான்கு வருட சிறைத்தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வந்த முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் பொது மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டு சற்று முன்னர் சிறையிலிருந்து வெளியேறினார்.",
        "அவரை வரவேற்க எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார மற்றும் பல SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலைக்கு வெளியே கூடியிருந்தனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கும் ஆவணத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று காலை கையொப்பமிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}