{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නිරිත-දිග-කොටසට-තද-වැසි/1-619223",
  "time_ut": 1662173293,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිරිත දිග කොටසට තද වැසි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy rains in south-western part",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Department of Meteorology, an increase in the rainfall in the south-western part of the island is expected from today (3) afternoon.",
        "Accordingly, a spokesperson of the department said that on today (3), heavy rains of more than 50 mm will occur in some places in Western, Sabaragamuwa and North-Western provinces, Kandy, Nuwara Eliya and Kalutara districts.",
        "The spokesperson mentioned that there will be some rains in Jaffna district, and in Uva province, Batticaloa and Ampara districts, there will be rain or thundershowers at a few places in the evening or at night.",
        "He also said that in the western slopes of the Central Hills, strong winds of about 50 km per hour will occur from time to time.",
        "The Department of Meteorology advises people to take action to avoid accidents as lightning accidents and temporary strong winds are also possible along with thunderstorms."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy, Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50 km per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිරිත දිග කොටසට තද වැසි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ නිරිත දිග කොටසෙහි පවතින වැසි තත්වයේ වැඩිවීමක් අද (3) පස්වරුවේ සිට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව අද (3) දිනයේදී බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත්, මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය සහ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 50 ට වැඩි තරමක තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන අතර, ඌව පළාතේත්, මඩකලපුව, අම්පාර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් සවස් කාලයේ හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ ස්ථාන ස්වල්පයක වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර 50 ක පමණ වේගවත් සුළං ඇතිවන බව ද ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ද ඇතිවිය හැකි බැවින් අනතුරු වළක්වාගැනීමට ක්‍රියා කරන්නැයි කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ජනතාවට දැනුම්දීමක් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3) දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 50ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தென்மேற்கு பகுதியில் கனமழை பெய்து வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (3) பிற்பகல் முதல் தீவின் தென்மேற்குப் பகுதியில் மழைவீழ்ச்சி அதிகரிக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, இன்று (3) மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும், கண்டி, நுவரெலியா மற்றும் களுத்துறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சில இடங்களில் 50 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யும் என திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாண மாவட்டத்தில் ஓரளவு மழை பெய்யும் எனவும், ஊவா மாகாணம், மட்டக்களப்பு மற்றும் அம்பாறை மாவட்டங்களில் சில இடங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுவதாகவும் பேச்சாளர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளில் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் கூடிய மின்னல் விபத்துக்கள் மற்றும் தற்காலிக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் என்பதால், விபத்துக்களை தவிர்ப்பதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் மக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி, நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு சுமார் 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}