{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/දයාසිරි-වැඩි-කාලයක්-ඉල්ලයි/1-618679",
  "time_ut": 1661333600,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දයාසිරි වැඩි කාලයක් ඉල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dayasiri asks for more time",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliamentarian Mr. Dayasiri Jayasekara requested Deputy Speaker Mr. Ajith Rajapaksa to give more time to the forty-two MPs who were independent from the government to speak in Parliament.",
        "He mentioned that time should be allocated to his team by the government as well as the opposition.",
        "The chief organizer of the opposition, Mr. Lakshman Kiriella, has stated that since the independent group in the parliament is supporting the government's activities, it is not possible to give time from the opposition.",
        "He has further mentioned that the real opposition in the Parliament is Samagi Jana Balawega."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "forty-two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දයාසිරි වැඩි කාලයක් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුවේ සිට ස්වාධීන වූ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් හතළිස් දෙදෙනාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කතා කිරීම සඳහා ලබාදී ඇති කාලය ප්‍රමාණවත් නැති හෙයින් වැඩි කාල වේලාවක් ලබාදෙන්නැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායක අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "තම කණ්ඩායමට ආණ්ඩුවෙන් මෙන්ම විපක්ෂයෙත්ද කාලය වෙන් කර දිය යුතු බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙහිදී අදහස් දක්වා ඇති විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන වූ කණ්ඩායම ආණ්ඩුවේ කටයුතුවලට සහාය දක්වමින් කටයුතු කරන හෙයින් විපක්ෂයෙන් කාලය ලබා දීමට නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නියම විපක්ෂය සමගි ජන බලවේගය බවද ඔහු මෙහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතලිස් දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தயாசிறி மேலும் கால அவகாசம் கேட்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்து சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் நாற்பத்திரண்டு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பேசுவதற்கு மேலும் கால அவகாசம் வழங்குமாறு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர பிரதி சபாநாயகர் அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்கமும் எதிர்க்கட்சியும் தனது அணிக்கு நேரம் ஒதுக்க வேண்டும் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தின் செயற்பாடுகளுக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள சுயேச்சைக் குழு ஆதரவளிப்பதால் எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இருந்து கால அவகாசம் வழங்க முடியாது என எதிர்கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளர் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உண்மையான எதிர்க்கட்சி சமகி ஜன பலவேக என்று அவர் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாற்பத்தி இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}