{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/limra-holdings-subsidiary-kti-to-boost-sri-lankas-forex-earnings-with-plex-toys-launch-in-india/",
  "time_ut": 1658661600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "LIMRA Holdings subsidiary KTI to boost Sri Lanka’s forex earnings with PLEX toys launch in India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "LIMRA Holdings subsidiary KTI to boost Sri Lanka’s forex earnings with PLEX toys launch in India",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kiddies & Toys International (KTI), a subsidiary of leading Sri Lankan conglomerate LIMRA Holdings Limited, has launched PLEX toys in India by unveiling its first toy range “The Playing Blocks”. The toys were launched in partnership with Viacom18 Media, India’s fastest growing entertainment network and a house of more iconic brands including Nick and Nick Jr., the number-one entertainment brands for kids.",
        "PLEX, an own intellectual property under KTI, in keeping with the brand’s motto of ‘Shaping Leaders of Tomorrow’ was created to help nurture the next generation through toys that drive creativity, inspiration and innovation. PLEX toys range is specially made for children from the ages of 3 months to 9 years and comprises infant toys, puzzles, activities, wooden toys, building blocks, steam toys, role play toys, seasonal toys, and licensed toys. All PLEX toys are made with child safety standards, provide value for money, and are backed by international certifications.",
        "Being a Sri Lankan company, the export and sale of PLEX toys by KTI in the Indian market will help bring in valuable foreign exchange earnings to Sri Lanka which in turn will contribute towards easing of the current economic situation. LIMRA Holdings is present internationally through strategic joint ventures in the SAARC, Middle East and South East Asia such as Bangladesh, Oman and Singapore, thereby giving it multiple opportunities to bring in foreign exchange earnings to Sri Lanka.",
        "Sharing his thoughts on the launch, Nabhan Akeel – Chairman/Group CEO of LIMRA Holdings Limited stated, “Sri Lanka is in the midst of an economy crisis and it is vital that exporting companies ramp up their efforts in order to bring in valuable foreign exchange and prop up the local economy. As a leading corporate entity in Sri Lanka, we have taken on this responsibility by enhancing our efforts on multiple fronts to achieve this national goal.",
        "Deepak Senthil succeeds outgoing managing director of Coca-Cola Sri Lanka",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "LIMRA Holdings",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "KTI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PLEX",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiddies & Toys International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIMRA Holdings Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Playing Blocks",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viacom18 Media",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nick",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nick Jr.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ages of 3 months to 9 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIMRA Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "South East Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sharing",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nabhan Akeel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIMRA Holdings Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deepak Senthil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coca-Cola Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LIMRA හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් අනුබද්ධිත KTI හි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ විනිමය ඉපැයීම් ඉහළ නැංවීමට PLEX සෙල්ලම් බඩු ඉන්දියාවේදී දියත් කෙරේ.",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලිම්රා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් ලිමිටඩ් හි ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයට අනුබද්ධිත Kiddies & Toys International (KTI) සිය පළමු සෙල්ලම් බඩු පරාසය \"The Playing Blocks\" එළිදක්වමින් PLEX සෙල්ලම් බඩු ඉන්දියාවේදී දියත් කර ඇත. මෙම සෙල්ලම් බඩු දියත් කරන ලද්දේ ඉන්දියාවේ වේගයෙන්ම වර්ධනය වන විනෝදාස්වාද ජාලය වන Viacom18 Media සහ ළමුන් සඳහා අංක එකේ විනෝදාස්වාද සන්නාමයන් වන Nick සහ Nick Jr. ඇතුළු වඩාත් කැපී පෙනෙන සන්නාමයන්ගෙන් යුත් නිවසකි.",
        "KTI යටතේ ඇති තමන්ගේම බුද්ධිමය දේපලක් වන PLEX, 'හෙට නායකයින් හැඩගස්වන්න' යන සන්නාමයේ ආදර්ශ පාඨයට අනුකූලව, නිර්මාණශීලිත්වය, ආශ්වාදය සහ නවෝත්පාදනය මෙහෙයවන සෙල්ලම් බඩු හරහා ඊළඟ පරම්පරාව පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා නිර්මාණය කරන ලදී. PLEX සෙල්ලම් බඩු පරාසය මාස 3 සිට අවුරුදු 9 දක්වා ළමුන් සඳහා විශේෂයෙන් සාදා ඇති අතර ළදරු සෙල්ලම් බඩු, ප්‍රහේලිකා, ක්‍රියාකාරකම්, ලී සෙල්ලම් බඩු, ගොඩනැගිලි කුට්ටි, වාෂ්ප සෙල්ලම් බඩු, භූමිකා සෙල්ලම් බඩු, සෘතුමය සෙල්ලම් බඩු සහ බලපත්‍රලාභී සෙල්ලම් බඩු වලින් සමන්විත වේ. සියලුම PLEX සෙල්ලම් බඩු ළමා ආරක්ෂණ ප්‍රමිතීන් සමඟ සාදා ඇත, මුදලට වටිනාකමක් ලබා දෙයි, සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සහතික වලින් අනුබල දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සමාගමක් වීම, KTI විසින් ඉන්දියානු වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ PLEX සෙල්ලම් බඩු අපනයනය කිරීම සහ විකිණීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වටිනා විදේශ විනිමය ඉපැයීම් ගෙන ඒමට උපකාරී වන අතර එමඟින් වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය ලිහිල් කිරීමට දායක වේ. LIMRA හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්, බංග්ලාදේශය, ඕමානය සහ සිංගප්පූරුව වැනි SAARC, මැදපෙරදිග සහ අග්නිදිග ආසියාවේ උපායමාර්ගික හවුල් ව්‍යාපාර හරහා ජාත්‍යන්තරව ඉදිරිපත් වන අතර එමඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විදේශ විනිමය ඉපැයීමට විවිධ අවස්ථා ලබා දෙයි.",
        "LIMRA Holdings Limited හි සභාපති/ සමූහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී Nabhan Akeel මෙම දියත් කිරීම පිළිබඳව සිය අදහස් බෙදාහදා ගනිමින්, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මැදිව සිටින අතර වටිනා විදේශ විනිමය ගෙන ඒම සඳහා අපනයන සමාගම් සිය උත්සාහයන් වේගවත් කිරීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ. සහ දේශීය ආර්ථිකයට මුක්කු ගහන්න. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ආයතනික ආයතනයක් ලෙස, මෙම ජාතික ඉලක්කය සපුරා ගැනීම සඳහා විවිධ පැතිවලින් අපගේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් වැඩි දියුණු කරමින් අපි මෙම වගකීම භාරගෙන ඇත්තෙමු.",
        "දීපක් සෙන්තිල් Coca-Cola Sri Lanka හි කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වේ",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "LIMRA හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "KTI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PLEX",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiddies & Toys International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIMRA Holdings Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්ලම් බ්ලොක්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viacom18 මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නික්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නික් ජූනියර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස මාස 3 සිට අවුරුදු 9 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIMRA හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිකොනදිග ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙදාගැනීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නභාන් අකීල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIMRA Holdings Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දීපක් සෙන්තිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coca-Cola Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "LIMRA ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் துணை நிறுவனமான KTI, இந்தியாவில் PLEX பொம்மைகள் அறிமுகம் மூலம் இலங்கையின் அந்நிய செலாவணி வருவாயை அதிகரிக்க",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னணி கூட்டு நிறுவனமான LIMRA ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் லிமிடெட்டின் துணை நிறுவனமான Kiddies & Toys International (KTI), அதன் முதல் பொம்மை வரம்பான “The Playing Blocks” ஐ வெளியிட்டதன் மூலம் இந்தியாவில் PLEX பொம்மைகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது. இந்தியாவின் மிக வேகமாக வளர்ந்து வரும் பொழுதுபோக்கு வலையமைப்பான Viacom18 மீடியாவுடன் இணைந்து இந்த பொம்மைகள் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டன, மேலும் குழந்தைகளுக்கான முதல் பொழுதுபோக்கு பிராண்டுகளான நிக் மற்றும் நிக் ஜூனியர் உள்ளிட்ட மிகவும் பிரபலமான பிராண்டுகளின் வீடு.",
        "PLEX, KTI இன் கீழ் உள்ள ஒரு சொந்த அறிவுசார் சொத்து, 'நாளைய தலைவர்களை வடிவமைப்பது' என்ற பிராண்டின் பொன்மொழிக்கு ஏற்ப, அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்கு படைப்பாற்றல், உத்வேகம் மற்றும் புதுமைகளை வழங்கும் பொம்மைகள் மூலம் வளர்ப்பதற்கு உதவுவதற்காக உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. PLEX பொம்மைகள் வரம்பானது 3 மாதங்கள் முதல் 9 வயது வரையிலான குழந்தைகளுக்காக பிரத்யேகமாக உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் குழந்தை பொம்மைகள், புதிர்கள், செயல்பாடுகள், மர பொம்மைகள், கட்டிடத் தொகுதிகள், நீராவி பொம்மைகள், பங்கு விளையாடும் பொம்மைகள், பருவகால பொம்மைகள் மற்றும் உரிமம் பெற்ற பொம்மைகளை உள்ளடக்கியது. அனைத்து PLEX பொம்மைகளும் குழந்தை பாதுகாப்பு தரங்களுடன் தயாரிக்கப்படுகின்றன, பணத்திற்கான மதிப்பை வழங்குகின்றன மற்றும் சர்வதேச சான்றிதழ்களால் ஆதரிக்கப்படுகின்றன.",
        "இலங்கை நிறுவனமாக இருப்பதால், இந்திய சந்தையில் KTI இன் PLEX பொம்மைகளின் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் விற்பனையானது இலங்கைக்கு மதிப்புமிக்க அந்நிய செலாவணி வருவாயைக் கொண்டு வர உதவும், இது தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமையை எளிதாக்குவதற்கு பங்களிக்கும். LIMRA ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் சர்வதேச அளவில் சார்க், மத்திய கிழக்கு மற்றும் பங்களாதேஷ், ஓமன் மற்றும் சிங்கப்பூர் போன்ற தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியாவில் மூலோபாய கூட்டு முயற்சிகள் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு அந்நிய செலாவணி வருமானத்தை கொண்டு வருவதற்கு பல வாய்ப்புகளை வழங்குகிறது.",
        "LIMRA ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர்/குழு பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி நபன் அகீல் தனது எண்ணங்களைப் பகிர்ந்துகொண்டார், \"இலங்கை பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் உள்ளது மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி நிறுவனங்கள் மதிப்புமிக்க அந்நிய செலாவணியை ஈர்ப்பதற்காக தங்கள் முயற்சிகளை விரைவுபடுத்துவது இன்றியமையாதது. மற்றும் உள்ளூர் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு முட்டுக்கட்டை. இலங்கையில் ஒரு முன்னணி கூட்டுத்தாபன நிறுவனமாக, இந்த தேசிய இலக்கை அடைவதற்காக பல முனைகளில் எங்களது முயற்சிகளை மேம்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் இந்த பொறுப்பை நாங்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ளோம்.",
        "தீபக் செந்தில் Coca-Cola Sri Lanka இன் நிர்வாக இயக்குநராக இருந்து வெளியேறுகிறார்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிம்ரா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "KTI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PLEX",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டீஸ் & டாய்ஸ் இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிம்ரா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளையாடும் தொகுதிகள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viacom18 மீடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக் ஜூனியர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மாதங்கள் முதல் 9 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PLEX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிம்ரா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பகிர்தல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நபன் அகீல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிம்ரா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தீபக் செந்தில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகோ கோலா இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}