{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/PUCSL-to-convene-stakeholder-consultation/342-239883",
  "time_ut": 1656331260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PUCSL to convene stakeholder consultation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PUCSL to convene stakeholder consultation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) is to convene a stakeholder consultation on the proposed revision of electricity tariffs.",
        "PUCSL Chairman Janaka Rathnayake said the electricity bill will not be increased as the recent fuel price, but will come into effect after five weeks.",
        "He said the PUCSL is of the view that the tariff increase should not exceed 57% as a concession to the majority of household electricity consumers.",
        "The PUCSL requests all parties, including the public, to submit their views and proposals regarding the tariff revision. Written comments can be submitted by email or fax until July 18, and details of the date and venue for the oral public consultation session will be announced in due course. The oral session will also be facilitated online, he said.",
        "This increase will not be done according to any single person's choice but as per the accepted scientific methodology. No one can involve with this increase.",
        "\"The average monthly electricity bill for consumers below 30 units can be maintained at Rs. 227.\" The average monthly electricity bill for consumers with more than 30 units but less than 60 units can be maintained at Rs. 658. The PUCSL points out that although a 138% tariff increase has been proposed for the entire domestic sector, it should not exceed 67%. The CEB also proposed to increase electricity tariffs by 45% for general purpose consumers, 61% for industrial consumers, 43% for hotels, 43% for government agencies, and 189% for the places of worship,\" he said.",
        "The PUCSL also requested CEB to accept the monthly electricity bills in dollars from the companies that earn their revenue in dollars. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janaka Rathnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "227",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than 60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "658",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "138%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "67%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "61%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "hotels",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "189%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශන කැඳවීමට PUCSL",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "යෝජිත විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශනයක් කැඳවීමට නියමිතය.",
        "PUCSL සභාපති ජානක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසුවේ පසුගිය ඉන්ධන මිලට අනුව විදුලි බිල වැඩි නොකරන බවත් සති පහකින් පසුව ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත්ය.",
        "බහුතර ගෘහ විදුලි පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට සහනයක් ලෙස ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීම 57% නොඉක්මවිය යුතු බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ අදහස බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් සහ යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම මහජනතාව ඇතුළු සියලු පාර්ශ්වවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටී. ලිඛිත අදහස් ජූලි 18 දක්වා විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් හෝ ෆැක්ස් මගින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකි අතර, වාචික මහජන උපදේශන සැසිය පැවැත්වෙන දිනය සහ ස්ථානය පිළිබඳ විස්තර ඉදිරියේදී දැනුම් දෙනු ඇත. වාචික සැසිවාරය අන්තර්ජාලය හරහා ද සිදු කිරීමට පහසුකම් සලසන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම වැඩි කිරීම කිසිවකුගේ කැමැත්තට අනුව නොව පිළිගත් විද්‍යාත්මක ක්‍රමවේදයට අනුව සිදු කෙරේ. මේ වැඩිවීමට කාටවත් සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න බැහැ.",
        "\"ඒකක 30 ට අඩු පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය මාසික විදුලි බිල රුපියල් 227 කින් පවත්වා ගත හැක.\" ඒකක 30 ට වැඩි නමුත් ඒකක 60 ට අඩු පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය මාසික විදුලි බිල රු. 658. සමස්ත ගෘහස්ථ අංශය සඳහා 138%ක තීරුබදු වැඩිවීමක් යෝජනා කර ඇතත් එය 67% නොඉක්මවිය යුතු බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම පෙන්වා දෙයි. සාමාන්‍ය පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා 45% කින් ද කාර්මික පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා 61% කින් ද හෝටල් සඳහා 43% කින් ද රාජ්‍ය ආයතන සඳහා 43% කින් ද පූජනීය ස්ථාන සඳහා 189% කින් ද විදුලි ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීමට ලංවිම යෝජනා කර ඇත.",
        "තම ආදායම ඩොලර්වලින් උපයන සමාගම්වලින් මාසික විදුලි බිල්පත් ඩොලර්වලින් භාර ගන්නා ලෙස ද මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම ලංවිමෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "227",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 ට අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "658",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "138%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "67%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "61%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝටල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "189%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பங்குதாரர்களின் ஆலோசனையை கூட்ட PUCSL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) உத்தேச மின்சாரக் கட்டணத் திருத்தம் தொடர்பாக பங்குதாரர்களின் ஆலோசனைக் கூட்டத்தை நடத்த உள்ளது.",
        "அண்மைய எரிபொருள் விலையைப் போன்று மின் கட்டணம் அதிகரிக்கப்படாது, ஐந்து வாரங்களின் பின்னர் அமுலுக்கு வரும் என PUCSL தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பெரும்பாலான வீட்டு மின் நுகர்வோருக்கு சலுகையாக கட்டண உயர்வு 57%க்கு மிகாமல் இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று PUCSL கருதுகிறது என்றார்.",
        "கட்டண திருத்தம் தொடர்பாக பொதுமக்கள் உட்பட அனைத்து தரப்பினரும் தங்கள் கருத்துக்களையும் முன்மொழிவுகளையும் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு PUCSL கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது. எழுத்துப்பூர்வ கருத்துகளை மின்னஞ்சல் அல்லது தொலைநகல் மூலம் ஜூலை 18 வரை சமர்ப்பிக்கலாம், மேலும் வாய்வழி பொது கலந்தாய்வுக்கான தேதி மற்றும் இடம் பற்றிய விவரங்கள் உரிய நேரத்தில் அறிவிக்கப்படும். ஆன்லைனிலும் வாய்மொழி அமர்வு வசதி செய்யப்படும், என்றார்.",
        "இந்த அதிகரிப்பு எந்தவொரு தனி நபரின் விருப்பத்தின்படியும் செய்யப்படாது, மாறாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட அறிவியல் முறைப்படி செய்யப்படும். இந்த அதிகரிப்பில் யாரும் ஈடுபட முடியாது.",
        "30 யூனிட்டுக்கு கீழ் உள்ள நுகர்வோரின் சராசரி மாதாந்திர மின்கட்டணத்தை ரூ.227 ஆக பராமரிக்கலாம். 30 யூனிட்டுகளுக்கு மேல் ஆனால் 60 யூனிட்டுகளுக்கு குறைவாக உள்ள நுகர்வோரின் சராசரி மாத மின் கட்டணம் ரூ. 658. முழு உள்நாட்டுத் துறைக்கும் 138% கட்டண உயர்வு முன்மொழியப்பட்டாலும், அது 67%க்கு மிகாமல் இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று PUCSL சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது. பொது பயன்பாட்டு நுகர்வோருக்கு 45%, தொழில்துறை நுகர்வோருக்கு 61%, ஹோட்டல்களுக்கு 43%, அரசு நிறுவனங்களுக்கு 43% மற்றும் வழிபாட்டுத் தலங்களுக்கு 189% மின் கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிக்கவும் CEB முன்மொழிந்துள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "டாலர்களில் வருமானம் ஈட்டும் நிறுவனங்களிடம் இருந்து மாதாந்திர மின்சாரக் கட்டணங்களை டாலர்களில் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறும் PUCSL CEBயிடம் கோரியது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "227",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "658",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "138%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "67%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "61%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோட்டல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "43%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "189%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}