{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-lifts-ban-on-six-tamil-diaspora-groups-316-individuals-report-98542/",
  "time_ut": 1660464420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka lifts ban on six Tamil diaspora groups, 316 individuals: report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka lifts ban on six Tamil diaspora groups, 316 individuals: report",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has de-listed six international Tamil diaspora organisations including the UK-based Global Tamil Forum (GTF) and 316 individuals.",
        "According to a report by the privately owned Ada Derana, the organistions de-listed are",
        "The de-listing was announced through an amendment to the List of Designated Persons under Regulation 4(7) of the United Nations Regulations No. 1 of 2012. (Colombo/Aug14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "316",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Tamil Forum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "316",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the List of Designated Persons",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Regulations No",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරා කණ්ඩායම් හයකට, පුද්ගලයන් 316කට පනවා තිබූ තහනම ඉවත් කරයි: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එක්සත් රාජධානිය පදනම් කරගත් ගෝලීය දෙමළ සංසදය (GTF) සහ පුද්ගලයන් 316 ක් ඇතුළුව ජාත්‍යන්තර දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධාන හයක් ලැයිස්තුගත කර නැත.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයට අයත් අද දෙරණ විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද වාර්තාවකට අනුව ලැයිස්තුගත නොකළ සංවිධාන වේ",
        "2012 අංක 1 දරන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි වල 4(7) රෙගුලාසි යටතේ නම් කරන ලද පුද්ගලයින්ගේ ලැයිස්තුවට සංශෝධනයක් මගින් මෙම ඉවත් කිරීම ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "316",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය දෙමළ සංසදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "316",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නම් කරන ලද පුද්ගලයින්ගේ ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි අංක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆறு தமிழ் புலம்பெயர் குழுக்கள், 316 நபர்கள் மீதான தடையை இலங்கை நீக்கியது: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – UK-ஐ தளமாகக் கொண்ட Global Tamil Forum (GTF) மற்றும் 316 தனிநபர்கள் உட்பட ஆறு சர்வதேச புலம்பெயர்ந்த தமிழ் அமைப்புகளை இலங்கை பட்டியலிலிருந்து நீக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "தனியாருக்குச் சொந்தமான Ada Derana இன் அறிக்கையின்படி, பட்டியலிலிருந்து நீக்கப்பட்ட அமைப்புக்கள்",
        "2012 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் ஒழுங்குமுறை எண். 1 இன் ஒழுங்குமுறை 4(7) இன் கீழ் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நபர்களின் பட்டியலின் திருத்தத்தின் மூலம் பட்டியல் நீக்கம் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "316",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோபல் தமிழ் மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "316",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நபர்களின் பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் விதிமுறைகள் எண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}