{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/CoL-committee-headed-by-President-re-appointed/342-240386",
  "time_ut": 1657008238,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CoL committee headed by President re-appointed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CoL committee headed by President re-appointed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Cabinet Sub Committee which was formed to look into Cost of Living (CoL) earlier by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, was re-appointed today.",
        "Addressing the weekly cabinet meeting today, the spokesman said the Cost of Living Committee will be responsible for tabling policy decisions and practical solutions pertaining to maintaining a stable cost of living to receive Cabinet approval.",
        "Accordingly, the eight-member Cabinet Sub Committee headed by President Rajapaksa was appointed.",
        "The following members have been re-appointed: Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Fisheries Minister Douglas Devananda, Transport and Highways Minister Bandula Gunawardana, Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera, Plantations and Industries Minister Ramesh Pathirana, Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera and Trade, Commerce and Food Security Minister Nalin Fernando were appointed as the rest of the members of the CoL committee.",
        "Furthermore, the Cabinet has also approved the establishment of a Food Security Committee headed by Minister Nalin Fernando with the participation of the Secretaries of the relevant Ministries to assist the CoL Committee. (Chatuanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CoL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Cabinet Sub Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cost of Living Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Sub Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CoL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Food Security Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministries",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the CoL Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chatuanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කෝල් කමිටුව යළි පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජීවන වියදම සොයා බැලීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් මීට පෙර පිහිටුවන ලද කැබිනට් අනුකාරක සභාව අද යළි පත් කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "අද සතිපතා පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් රැස්වීම අමතමින් එම ප්‍රකාශකයා කියා සිටියේ ස්ථාවර ජීවන වියදමක් පවත්වා ගැනීමට අදාළ ප්‍රතිපත්ති තීරණ සහ ප්‍රායෝගික විසඳුම් කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා සභාගත කිරීමේ වගකීම ජීවන වියදම් කමිටුවට පැවරෙන බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අට පුද්ගල කැබිනට් අනුකාරක සභාව පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද, ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර, වැවිලි හා කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍ය රමේෂ් පතිරණ, විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචනා විජේසේකර සහ වෙළඳ, වාණිජ සහ ආහාර යන මහත්වරුන් විසින් පහත සඳහන් සාමාජිකයින් නැවත පත් කර ඇත. එම කමිටුවේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් ලෙස ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "තවද, CL කමිටුවට සහය වීම සඳහා අදාළ අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා කමිටුවක් පිහිටුවීමටද අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය හිමිව තිබේ. (චතුරාංග සමරාවික්රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CoL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් අනුකාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන වියදම් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් අනු කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CoL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍යාංශ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "CL කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුඅංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தலைமையில் COL குழு மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் வாழ்க்கைச் செலவு (CoL) குறித்து ஆராய்வதற்காக அமைக்கப்பட்ட அமைச்சரவை உபகுழு இன்று மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இன்று வாராந்த அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில் உரையாற்றிய பேச்சாளர், அமைச்சரவையின் அங்கீகாரத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கு நிலையான வாழ்க்கைச் செலவைப் பேணுவது தொடர்பான கொள்கை முடிவுகள் மற்றும் நடைமுறை தீர்வுகளை சமர்ப்பிப்பதற்கு வாழ்க்கைச் செலவுக் குழு பொறுப்பாகும் என்றார்.",
        "அதன்படி, அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே தலைமையில் எட்டு பேர் கொண்ட அமைச்சரவை துணைக்குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, மீன்பிடி அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா, போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் பெருந்தெருக்கள் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன, விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர, பெருந்தோட்ட மற்றும் கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சர் ரமேஷ் பத்திரன, மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர மற்றும் வர்த்தகம், வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உணவுப் பிரிவினர் ஆகியோர் மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, சிஓஎல் குழுவின் மற்ற உறுப்பினர்களாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "மேலும், அமைச்சர் நலின் பெர்னாண்டோ தலைமையில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்புக் குழுவொன்றை அமைப்பதற்கும், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட அமைச்சுக்களின் செயலாளர்களின் பங்கேற்புடன் COL குழுவிற்கு உதவுவதற்கும் அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது. (சதுங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை துணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழ்க்கைச் செலவுக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை துணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்பு குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சுக்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "COL குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}