{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131157",
  "time_ut": 1657365922,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையின் நிலைவரத்தை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருகின்றோம் - பிரித்தானியா",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We are closely monitoring the situation in Sri Lanka - Britain",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Britain has said that it is closely monitoring the events taking place in Sri Lanka. In addition, Britain has also emphasized that those participating in the demonstration and the security forces should observe moderation in these cases.",
        "The British High Commissioner to Sri Lanka, Sarah Houlton, and the country's Minister of Foreign Affairs, Tariq Ahmed, have said this in a Twitter post as anti-government protests have intensified in areas including the capital, Colombo.",
        "High Commissioner Sarah Houlton has posted on Twitter about the protests taking place in the country, \"The British government is watching the events happening in Sri Lanka very closely. Peaceful protest and freedom of expression are vital to Sri Lanka's democracy. ' has mentioned.",
        "At the same time, the British Minister of Foreign Affairs said in his Twitter post, \"The situation in Sri Lanka is worrying. Peaceful protests must be protected. Demonstrators and security forces should exercise restraint. We can find solutions by working together.",
        "It is noteworthy that Britain has issued a travel warning to avoid traveling to Sri Lanka except for essential needs after a police curfew was issued to some police units in Colombo with effect from 9 pm yesterday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka - Britain",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarah Houlton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tariq Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarah Houlton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ - බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ තත්ත්වය අපි හොඳින් නිරීක්ෂණය කරනවා",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිදුවන සිදුවීම් පිළිබඳව දැඩි අවධානයෙන් පසුවන බව බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය පවසා තිබේ. මීට අමතරව, උද්ඝෝෂණයට සහභාගී වන අය සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ මෙම අවස්ථා වලදී මධ්‍යස්ථව කටයුතු කළ යුතු බව බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය ද අවධාරණය කර ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ අගනුවර ඇතුළු ප්‍රදේශවල රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී විරෝධතා උත්සන්න වී ඇති බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් සාරා හෝල්ටන් සහ එරට විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය තාරික් අහමඩ් ට්විටර් සටහනක් තබමින් මේ බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් සාරා හූල්ටන් ට්විටර් වෙබ් අඩවියේ සටහනක් තබමින් රට තුළ සිදුවෙමින් පවතින විරෝධතා පිළිබඳව “බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිදුවන සිදුවීම් දෙස ඉතා සමීපව බලා සිටී. සාමකාමී විරෝධතා සහ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ. ' යනුවෙන් සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ සමගම බි‍්‍රතාන්‍ය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා සිය ට්විටර් සටහනේ සඳහන් කර ඇත්තේ, ‘‘ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය කණගාටුදායකයි. සාමකාමී විරෝධතා ආරක්ෂා කළ යුතුයි. විරෝධතාකරුවන් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ සංයමයෙන් කටයුතු කළ යුතුයි. එකට වැඩ කිරීමෙන් විසඳුම් සෙවිය හැකියි.",
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රී 9 සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි කොළඹ පොලිස් ඒකක කිහිපයකට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීමෙන් පසු අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා හැර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය සංචාරක අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව - බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරා හෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාරික් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාරා හෝල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.9",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் நிலைவரத்தை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருகின்றோம் - பிரித்தானியா",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் நடைபெற்று வரும் நிகழ்வுகளை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருவதாக பிரித்தானியா தெரிவித்துள்ளது. அத்தோடு ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுபவர்களும் , பாதுகாப்பு படையினரும் இந்த சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் நிதானத்தை கடைபிடிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் பிரித்தானியா வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "தலைநகர் கொழும்பு உள்ளிட்ட பகுதிகளில் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் வலுப்பெற்றுள்ள நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கான பிரித்தானிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹூல்டன் மற்றும் அந்நாட்டு வெளிநாட்டலுவல்கள் அமைச்சர் தாரிக் அஹமட் ஆகியோர் டுவிட்டர் பதிவொன்றை இட்டு இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நாட்டில் இடம்பெற்றுவரும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் தொடர்பில் டுவிட்டரில் பதிவிட்டுள்ள உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் சாரா ஹூல்டன் , '' இலங்கையில் நடக்கும் நிகழ்வுகளை பிரித்தானிய அரசு மிகவும் உன்னிப்பாக கவனித்து வருகிறது. அமைதியான ஆர்ப்பாட்டமும் , கருத்து சுதந்திரமும் இலங்கையின் ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு இன்றியமையாதது. ' என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதே வேளை இது தொடர்பில் பிரித்தானிய வெளிநாட்டலுவல்கள் அமைச்சர் தனது டுவிட்டர் பதிவில் , ''இலங்கையின் நிலைமை கவலைக்கிடமாக உள்ளது. அமைதியான போராட்டங்கள் பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டும். ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுபவர்கள் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு படையினர் நிதானத்தைக் கடைபிடிக்க வேண்டும். ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்படுவதன் மூலம் தீர்வுகளை காண முடியும்.'' என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இரவு 9 மணி முதல் அமுலாகும் வகையில் கொழும்பின் சில பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளுக்கு பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்கு சட்டம் பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, அத்தியாவசிய தேவைகளை தவிர்த்து இலங்கைக்கு பயணிப்பதை தவிர்த்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு பிரித்தானியா பயண எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை - பிரிட்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹோல்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாரிக் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாரா ஹோல்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}