{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62238861",
  "time_ut": 1658312119,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "\"අරගලය අවසන් නැහැ,ඉදිරියට ගෙනියනවා\"",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"The struggle is not over, it continues\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "On this occasion when Parliament has elected Ranil Wickremesinghe for the post of President with a majority of 52 votes, activists held a press conference at Gotagogama struggle ground in Galle mouth.",
        "They told the media that the struggle is not over and will continue.",
        "There, Father Jivantha Peiris said that the struggle was a struggle that achieved public victories and sacrificed lives. He stated that the second aim of the struggle is the resignation of Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Sugathananda Thero of Tampitiya said that Ranil Wickramasinghe was appointed as anti-democratic.",
        "\"Who is behind Ranil? The people of this country did not ask for the appointment of Ranil. This appointment was due to other ambitions,\" he said.",
        "Lawyer Nuwan Bopage said that the people were oppressed by the existing government. He said that the Parliament is responsible for this, and from this week there will be an era when the people will have to take to the streets again.",
        "Eranga Gunasekara, the national organizer of the Socialist Youth Union, said, \"It was not Ranil who became the president, but Gotabaya, the ghosts of Gotabaya.\"",
        "The convener of the Inter-University Student Council, Wasantha Mudalige, also said: \"Even when the struggle has succeeded in driving out Gotabhaya, there is a conspiracy in the parliament. The members of Pohottuve made Ranil president to cover up their fraud and become ministers.\"",
        "He said that Ranil Wickremesinghe was brought to the presidency because of \"Rajapaksha's fraud\", and he will continue the struggle to oust Wickremesinghe from office.",
        "Currently, Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage has issued an order today (July 20) preventing any party from entering the area 50 meters from the Galle mouthpiece Bandaranaike statue.",
        "It is said that the Magistrate took this step after considering a request made by the Fort Police to the court saying that they had received information that there were plans to damage the statue."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotagogama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jivantha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sugathananda Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Socialist Youth Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inter-University Student Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pohottuve",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "\"අරගලය අවසන් නැහැ,ඉදිරියට ගෙනියනවා\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් වැඩි ඡන්ද 52කින් ජනපති පදවිය සඳහා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පත්කරගෙන ඇති මේ අවස්ථාවේ දී ගාලු මුවදොර ගෝඨාගෝගම අරගල භූමියේ අරගලකරුවන් මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "අරගලය අවසන් නැතිබව ද, ඉදිරියටම ගෙනයනබව ද ඔවුහු මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ කියා සිටියහ.",
        "එහිදී, අරගලය මහජන ජයග්‍රහණ අත්කරගත්, ජීවිත පූජා කළ අරගලයකැ යි ජීවන්ත පීරිස් පියතුමා කියා සිටියේ ය. අරගලයේ දෙවන අරමුණ වන්නේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමබව ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය.",
        "ටැම්පිටියේ සුගතානන්ද හිමි මෙහිදී කියාසිටියේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ නව පදවියට පත්වූයේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී-විරෝධීව බවකි.",
        "\"රනිල් පිටුපස ඉන්නේ කවුද? මේ රටේ මහජනතාව රනිල්ව පත්කරන්න කිව්වේ නෑ. වෙනත් අභිලාෂයන්වලට මේ පත්වීම සිදුවුණේ,\" උන්වහන්සේ කියා සිටියෝ ය.",
        "ජනතාව පීඩාවට පත්කළේ පවතින රජය විසින්යැ යි මෙහිදී නීතිඥ නුවන් බෝපගේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය. මෙයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වගකිව යුතුබව ද, මෙම සතියේ සිට ජනතාවට නැවතත් පාරට බසින්නට සිදුවන යුගයක් ඇතිවේයැ යි ද ඔහු පැවසුවේ ය.",
        "සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක එරංග ගුණසේකර පැවසුවේ, \"ජනාධිපති වුණේ රනිල් නෙමෙයි ගෝඨාභය, ගෝඨාභයලාගේ අවතාර,\" බව යි.",
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයීය ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැදවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ ද මෙසේ පැවසීය: \"අරගලය ගෝඨාභය එලවන්න සමත්වෙලා තියෙද්දිත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු තුළ කුමන්ත්‍රණය කරනවා. පොහොට්ටුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු තමන්ගේ හොරවැඩ වහගන්න, ඇමතිකම් කරගන්න රනිල් ජනාධිපති කළා.\"",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනපතිධුරයට ගෙන ආවේ \"රාජපක්ෂලාගේ හොරවැඩ\" නිසාවෙන්, වික්‍රමසිංහ ධුරයෙන් පළවාහැරීම පිණිස අඛන්ඩව අරගලය ගෙනයනබව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මේ වන විට ගාලු මුවදොර බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුවේ සිට මීටර් 50ක ප්‍රදේශයට කිසිදු පාර්ශවයක් ඇතුළුවීම වළකමින් කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිලිණ ගමගේ  අද (ජූලි 20) නියෝගයක් නිකුත්කර ඇත.",
        "පිළිමයට හානි කිරීමට සූදානමක් පවතින වගට තොරතුරු ලැබී ඇතැ යි පවසමින් කොටුව පොලීසිය අධිකරණයෙන් සිදුකළ ඉල්ලීමක් සලකා බැලූ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා මෙම පියවර ගත්බව පැවසේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨගෝගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජිවන්ත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුගතානන්ද හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටුවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"போராட்டம் ஓயவில்லை, தொடர்கிறது\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க 52 மேலதிக வாக்குகளால் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதையொட்டி, காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள கோட்டகோகம போராட்ட மைதானத்தில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பொன்றை நடத்தினர்.",
        "போராட்டம் ஓயவில்லை என்றும் தொடரும் என்றும் அவர்கள் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பொது வெற்றிகளை பெற்று உயிர்களை தியாகம் செய்த போராட்டமே போராட்டம் என அங்கு தந்தை ஜிவந்த பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார். ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பதவி விலகல் போராட்டத்தின் இரண்டாவது நோக்கமாகும் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனநாயக விரோதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார் என தம்பிட்டிய சுகதானந்த தேரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ரணிலுக்குப் பின்னால் இருப்பது யார்?, இந்த நாட்டு மக்கள் ரணிலை நியமிக்குமாறு கேட்கவில்லை, வேறு லட்சியங்களுக்காக இந்த நியமனம் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள அரசாங்கத்தினால் மக்கள் ஒடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர் என சட்டத்தரணி நுவான் போபகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இதற்கு பாராளுமன்றமே பொறுப்பு என்றும், இந்த வாரத்தில் இருந்து மக்கள் மீண்டும் வீதியில் இறங்க வேண்டிய சகாப்தம் உருவாகும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சோசலிச வாலிபர் சங்கத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் எரங்க குணசேகர, 'ஜனாதிபதியானவர் ரணில் அல்ல, கோட்டாபயவின் பேய்கள் கோட்டாபய' என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் பேரவையின் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில்: கோத்தபாயவை விரட்டியடிப்பதில் போராட்டம் வெற்றியடைந்த போதும் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சதி நடக்கிறது.பொஹொட்டுவே உறுப்பினர்கள் தமது மோசடியை மூடி மறைத்து ரணிலை ஜனாதிபதியாக்கினர். அமைச்சர்கள்.\"",
        "“ராஜபக்ஷவின் மோசடியால்” ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு கொண்டு வந்ததாகவும், விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றும் போராட்டத்தை தொடர்ந்தும் முன்னெடுக்கவுள்ளதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது, ​​காலி முகத்திடலான பண்டாரநாயக்க சிலையிலிருந்து 50 மீற்றர் பகுதிக்குள் எந்தவொரு தரப்பினரும் பிரவேசிக்கக் கூடாது என கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இன்று (ஜூலை 20) உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சிலையை சேதப்படுத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தமக்கு தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக கோட்டை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை பரிசீலித்த நீதவான் இந்த நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோடகோகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜிவந்த பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகதானந்த தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோசலிச இளைஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டுவே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}