{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/military-strategies-must-be-preserved-shavendra-tells-malwathu-theros/",
  "time_ut": 1661774700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Military strategies must be preserved; Shavendra tells Malwathu Theros",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Military strategies must be preserved; Shavendra tells Malwathu Theros",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The military strategies used by Sri Lankan forces to defeat terrorism must be preserved, said Chief of Defence Staff, General Shavendra Silva during his visit to Kandy on Monday (29).",
        "\"I recall we had to dig trenches to move about at night. At times, we could not even move 100m. So we changed the battlefield using self-developed strategies. Even in the United States of America, they were keener on learning the strategies we used,\" said General Shavendra Silva in a conversation with Most Venerable Aggamaha Panditha (Dr) Niyangoda Sri Vijithasiri Thero, the Anunayake of the Malwathu Chapter.",
        "Earlier in the day, General Shavendra Silva called on the Mahanayaka of the Malwathu Chapter, Most Venerable Thibbatuwawe Sri Sumangala Thero at the Malwathu Temple in Kandy.",
        "The Mahanayake Thero appreciated and recognized the services rendered by the Former Army Commander and the present Chief of Defence Staff, for the country, and the people, as well as during the floods and the COVID pandemic.",
        "Both the Mahanayake and Anunayake Theros of the Malwathu Chapter invoked their blessings",
        "In appreciation and recognition of the noble and exceptional service rendered towards the nation and Buddhism in the country, the present Chief of Defence Staff, General Shavendra Silva WWV RWP RSP VSV USP ndc psc MPhil was honored with the honorary title “Mahamannya Prathapadhikeshwara” on Sunday (28 August).",
        "Declaring the title officially, the Chief Incumbent of the Asgiriya chapter, Most Ven. Warakagoda Sri Gnanarathana Mahanayaka Thera presented the ‘Sannas Patraya’ to General Shavendra Silva.",
        "The highest Buddhist accolade that is bestowed to any lay personality was presented to the Chief of Defence Staff at a prestigious religious ceremony held at the Ceremonial Higher Ordination Hall of the historic Asgiriya Monastery.",
        "The honorary title is a recognition of the noble service, untiring commitment, and enormous sacrifices made by this most senior serving military officer towards the country, race, and religion for decades. The accomplished command over the successful control of the novel COVID-19 pandemic in the motherland and during the recent incidents that took place in the country was highlighted by the Mahanayaka Theros and eminent personalities present.",
        "The ‘Sannas Pathraya’ (Parchment) signifying the honourary title, was bestowed by the Most Ven Warakagoda Dhammasiddhi Sri Pannananda Gnanarathanabhidhana Thero, the Chief Prelate of the Asgiri Chapter and on behalf of the Malwathu Chapter, Most Ven Dimbulkumbure Sri Saranankara Wimala Dhammawidhana Anunayaka to the Chief of Defence Staff at the Ceremonial Higher Ordination Hall.",
        "Most Ven Medagama Dammananda Thero readout the consent letters of the Ramanna Maha Nikaya and Amarapura Nikaya well educating the distinguished gathering on the title.",
        "The conferring of this title initiated by the Ven Maha Sangha of Asgiriya Chapter was endorsed by both the Most Ven Makulewe Wimala Thero, the Mahanayaka Thero of Ramanna Maha Nikaya and Dodampahala Chandasiri Maha Nayaka Thero of Amarapura Maha Nikaya.",
        "Japan Hands Over Food Donation to Help Sri Lanka Respond to Rising Food Insecurity"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shavendra",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about at night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100m.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Venerable Aggamaha Panditha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Vijithasiri Thero",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier in the day",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RWP RSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VSV USP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahamannya Prathapadhikeshwara",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asgiriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Warakagoda Sri Gnanarathana Mahanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Sannas Patraya’",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceremonial Higher Ordination Hall",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asgiriya Monastery",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Pannananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gnanarathanabhidhana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimala Dhammawidhana Anunayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceremonial Higher Ordination Hall",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ramanna Maha Nikaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarapura Nikaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ven Maha",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asgiriya Chapter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makulewe Wimala Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanna Maha Nikaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dodampahala Chandasiri Maha Nayaka Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarapura Maha Nikaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan Hands Over Food Donation to Help Sri Lanka Respond",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rising Food Insecurity",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිලිටරි උපාය මාර්ග ආරක්ෂා කළ යුතුය; ශවේන්ද්‍ර මල්වතු හාමුදුරුවන්ට කියනවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ත‍්‍රස්තවාදය පරාජය කිරීමට ශ‍්‍රී ලංකා හමුදාවන් යොදාගත් යුධ උපක්‍රම සුරැකිය යුතු බව ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා සඳුදා (29) මහනුවර සංචාරයක නිරත වෙමින් පැවසීය.",
        "\"මට මතකයි අපිට රෑට එහා මෙහා යන්න අගල් හාරන්න වුණා. සමහර වෙලාවට අපිට මීටර් 100ක්වත් යන්න බැරි වුණා. ඒ නිසා අපි ස්වයං-නිර්මාණය කළ උපාය මාර්ග භාවිතා කරමින් සටන් බිම වෙනස් කළා. ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පවා ඔවුන් උපාය මාර්ග ඉගෙන ගැනීමට උනන්දු වුණා. අපි පාවිච්චි කළා\" යනුවෙන් ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා මල්වතු පාර්ශ්වයේ අනුනායක අතිපූජ්‍ය අග්ගමහා පණ්ඩිත (ආචාර්ය) නියංගොඩ ශ්‍රී විජිතසිරි හිමියන් සමඟ කළ සංවාදයකදී පැවසීය.",
        "ඊට පෙර සෙන්පති ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා මහනුවර මල්වතු විහාරස්ථානයේදී මල්වතු පාර්ශ්වයේ මහානායක අතිපූජ්‍ය තිබ්බටුවාවේ ශ්‍රී සුමංගල නාහිමියන් බැහැදුටුවා.",
        "හිටපු යුධ හමුදාපති වත්මන් ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානියා රට වෙනුවෙන්, ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් මෙන්ම ගංවතුර සහ කොවිඩ් වසංගතය හමුවේ සිදු කළ සේවය මහානායක ස්වාමීන් වහන්සේ විසින් ඇගයීමට ලක් කරන ලදී.",
        "මල්වතු පාර්ශ්වයේ මහානායක හා අනුනායක හිමිවරුන් දෙනම ආශිර්වාද කළහ",
        "රට තුළ ජාතියට සහ බුද්ධාගමට සිදු කරන ලද උදාර සහ සුවිශේෂී මෙහෙවර අගය කිරීම සහ ඇගයීම සඳහා වත්මන් ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා WWV RWP RSP VSV USP ndc psc MPhil ඉරිදා දින “මහාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතාපාධිකේශ්වර” යන ගෞරව නාමයෙන් ගෞරව කරන ලදී. (අගෝස්තු 28).",
        "එම පදවි නාමය නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් අස්ගිරි පාර්ශවයේ මහානායක අතිපූජ්‍ය නාහිමිපාණන් වහන්සේ ප්‍රකාශ කළහ. වරකාගොඩ ශ්‍රී ඤාණරතන මහනාහිමියෝ සෙන්පති ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා වෙත ‘සන්නස් පත්‍රය’ පිළිගැන්වූහ.",
        "ඕනෑම ගිහි පෞරුෂයකට හිමිවන උසස්ම බෞද්ධ උපහාරය ආරක්‍ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානියා වෙත පිළිගැන්වීම ඓතිහාසික අස්ගිරි මහා සංඝාරාමයේ පූජ්‍ය මහා උපසම්පදා ශාලාවේදී පැවැති ගෞරවනීය ආගමික උත්සවයකදීය.",
        "මෙම ගෞරව නාමය යනු දශක ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ රට, ජාතිය සහ ආගම වෙනුවෙන් මෙම ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨතම සේවයේ නියුතු හමුදා නිලධාරියා විසින් කරන ලද උදාර සේවය, නොපසුබස්නා කැපවීම සහ දැවැන්ත කැපකිරීම් ඇගයීමකි. කොවිඩ් 19 වසංගතය මාතෘභූමිය තුළ සාර්ථක ලෙස පාලනය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සහ පසුගිය දිනවල රට තුළ ඇති වූ සිද්ධීන් අතරවාරයේදී ඉටුකළ අණදීම මහානායක හිමිවරුන් ප්‍රමුඛ කීර්තිමත් පුද්ගලයන් විසින් විශේෂ අවධානයට ලක් කරන ලදී.",
        "මල්වතු පාර්ශ්වයේ මහානායක අතිපූජ්‍ය දිඹුල්කුඹුරේ ශ්‍රී සරණංකර විමල ධම්මානන්ද හිමියන් වෙත අස්ගිරි පාර්ශවයේ මහානායක අතිපූජ්‍ය වරකාගොඩ ධම්මසිද්ධි ශ්‍රී පඤ්ඤානන්ද ඤාණරතනාභිධාන ස්වාමීන් වහන්සේ විසින් සන්නස් පත්‍රය පිරිනමන ලදී. ආරක්‍ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී විසින් උත්සවාකාර උසස් පැවිදි කිරීමේ ශාලාවේදී.",
        "අතිපූජ්‍ය මැදගම ධම්මානන්ද හිමිපාණන් වහන්සේ රාමඤ්ඤ මහා නිකායේ සහ අමරපුර නිකායේ අනුදැනුම ලිපි කියවා ගෞරවනීය පිරිස දැනුවත් කළහ.",
        "අස්ගිරි පාර්ශ්වයේ මහා සංඝරත්නය විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලද මෙම පදවිය පිරිනැමීම රාමඤ්ඤ මහා නිකායේ මහානායක අතිපූජ්‍ය මකුලෑවේ විමල නාහිමිපාණන් වහන්සේ සහ අමරපුර මහා නිකායේ දොඩම්පහල චන්දසිරි මහා නායක ස්වාමින්ද්‍රයන් වහන්සේ දෙනමගේ අනුදැනුම මත අනුදැන වදාළහ.",
        "ඉහළ යන ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ජපානය ආහාර පරිත්‍යාගයක් භාර දෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාත්රියේදී ගැන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්ගමහා පණ්ඩිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී විජිතසිරි හිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින් දවසේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RWP RSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VSV USP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතාපධිකේශ්වර",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අස්ගිරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරකාගොඩ ශ්‍රී ඤාණරතන මහනාහිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘සන්නස් පත්‍රය’",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාරිත්රානුකූල උසස් පැවිදි ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අස්ගිරි අසපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී පන්නානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඤාණරතනාභිධාන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල ධම්මවිධාන අනුනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාරිත්රානුකූල උසස් පැවිදි ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමඤ්ඤ මහා නිකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරපුර නිකාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අස්ගිරි පාර්ශවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකුලෑවේ විමල හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමඤ්ඤ මහා නිකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොඩම්පහල චන්දසිරි මහා නායක හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරපුර මහා නිකාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීම සඳහා ආහාර පරිත්‍යාගයක් භාර දෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවය ඉහළ යාම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இராணுவ உத்திகள் பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டும்; சவேந்திர மல்வத்து தேரர்களிடம் கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பயங்கரவாதத்தை தோற்கடிப்பதற்காக சிறிலங்காப் படைகள் பயன்படுத்தும் இராணுவ உத்திகள் பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா திங்கட்கிழமை (29) கண்டிக்கான விஜயத்தின் போது தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இரவில் நடமாட பள்ளம் தோண்ட வேண்டியிருந்தது. சில சமயங்களில் 100 மீட்டர் கூட நகர்த்த முடியவில்லை. அதனால் நாங்கள் சுயமாக உருவாக்கிய உத்திகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி போர்க்களத்தை மாற்றினோம். அமெரிக்காவில் கூட, அவர்கள் உத்திகளைக் கற்றுக்கொள்வதில் ஆர்வமாக இருந்தனர். நாங்கள் பயன்படுத்தினோம்” என்று மல்வத்து பிரிவின் அனுநாயக்க அதி வணக்கத்திற்குரிய அக்கமஹா பண்டித (டாக்டர்) நியங்கொட ஸ்ரீ விஜிதசிறி தேரர் உடனான உரையாடலில் ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா கண்டி மல்வத்து கோவிலில் வைத்து மல்வத்து பீடத்தின் மகாநாயக்கர் வணக்கத்திற்குரிய திப்பட்டுவாவே ஸ்ரீ சுமங்கல தேரரை சந்தித்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தளபதியும் தற்போதைய பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தளபதியும் நாட்டுக்காகவும் மக்களுக்காகவும் வெள்ளம் மற்றும் கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய்களின் போது ஆற்றிய சேவைகளை மகாநாயக்க தேரர் பாராட்டி அங்கீகரித்தார்.",
        "மல்வத்து பீடத்தின் மகாநாயக்க தேரர்கள் மற்றும் அனுநாயக்க தேரர்கள் இருவரும் தமது ஆசிகளை வேண்டிக்கொண்டனர்",
        "நாட்டில் தேசம் மற்றும் பௌத்த மதத்திற்கு ஆற்றிய உன்னதமான மற்றும் விதிவிலக்கான சேவையைப் பாராட்டும் வகையில், தற்போதைய பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தலைவர் ஜெனரல் ஷவேந்திர சில்வா WWV RWP RSP VSV USP ndc psc MPhil ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை \"மகாமன்ய பிரதாபதிகேஸ்வரா\" என்ற கௌரவப் பட்டத்துடன் கௌரவிக்கப்பட்டார். (ஆகஸ்ட் 28).",
        "பட்டத்தை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவித்து, அஸ்கிரிய பீடாதிபதி அதி வண. வரகாகொட ஸ்ரீ ஞானரதன மகாநாயக்க தேரர் ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வாவுக்கு ‘சன்னஸ் பத்திரய’ வழங்கினார்.",
        "வரலாற்றுச் சிறப்புமிக்க அஸ்கிரிய மடாலயத்தின் சம்பிரதாய உயர்பீட மண்டபத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கௌரவமான சமய நிகழ்வில், எந்தவொரு பாமர ஆளுமைக்கும் வழங்கப்படும் மிக உயர்ந்த பௌத்த விருது பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பல தசாப்தங்களாக நாடு, இனம் மற்றும் மதத்திற்காக இந்த மிக மூத்த இராணுவ அதிகாரி ஆற்றிய உன்னத சேவை, அயராத அர்ப்பணிப்பு மற்றும் மகத்தான தியாகத்திற்கான அங்கீகாரம் இந்த கௌரவப் பட்டமாகும். தாய்நாட்டில் கொவிட்-19 தொற்றை வெற்றிகரமாகக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவது மற்றும் நாட்டில் அண்மையில் இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவங்களின் போது நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட கட்டளை மகாநாயக்க தேரர்கள் மற்றும் பிரமுகர்களால் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "மல்வத்து பீடத்தின் சார்பாக அஸ்கிரிய பீடத்தின் பிரதான பீடாதிபதியான அதிவேக வரகாகொட தம்மாசித்தி ஸ்ரீ பன்னாநந்த ஞானரதனாபிதான தேரர் அவர்களினால் இந்த கௌரவப் பட்டத்தை குறிக்கும் 'சன்னஸ் பத்திரய' (பார்ச்மென்ட்) வழங்கப்பட்டது. செரிமோனியல் ஹையர் ஆர்டினேஷன் ஹாலில் பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தலைவர்.",
        "ராமண்ணா மகா நிகாயா மற்றும் அமரபுர நிகாயாவின் ஒப்புதல் கடிதங்களை மிக வணக்கம் மெதகம தம்மானந்த தேரர் வாசித்து, தலைப்பைப் பற்றி சிறப்புரையாற்றினார்.",
        "அஸ்கிரிய பீடத்தின் மகா சங்கத்தினரால் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட இந்த பட்டத்தை வழங்குவதற்கு ராமன்ன மகா நிகாயாவின் மகாநாயக்க தேரர் அதி வணக்க மகுலேவே விமல தேரர் மற்றும் அமரபுர மகா நிகாயாவின் தொடம்பஹல சாந்தசிறி மகா நாயக்க தேரர் ஆகிய இருவராலும் ஆமோதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அதிகரித்து வரும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மைக்கு இலங்கைக்கு உதவ ஜப்பான் உணவு நன்கொடையை வழங்கியுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சவேந்திரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் இரவில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100மீ.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணக்கத்திற்குரிய அக்கமஹா பண்டிதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ விஜிதசிறி தேரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாநாயக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RWP RSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஎஸ்வி யுஎஸ்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாமந்நியா ப்ரதாபதிகேஶ்வர",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஸ்கிரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரகாகொட ஸ்ரீ ஞானரதன மகாநாயக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'சன்னாஸ் பத்ரயா'",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சடங்கு உயர் அர்டினேஷன் ஹால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஸ்கிரிய மடாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ பன்னானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞானரதனாபிதான தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல தம்மவிதான அனுநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சடங்கு உயர் அர்டினேஷன் ஹால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமண்ணா மகா நிகாயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரபுர நிகாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெண் மகா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஸ்கிரிய அத்தியாயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகுலேவே விமல தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமண்ண மகா நிகாயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடம்பஹல சாந்தசிறி மகா நாயக்க தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரபுர மகா நிகாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைக்கு பதிலளிக்க ஜப்பான் உணவு நன்கொடையை வழங்கியுள்ளது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகரித்து வரும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}