{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පස්-පොඩ්ඩා-සමග-වෙඩි-කෑ-තවත්-අයෙක්-මරුට/1-617279",
  "time_ut": 1659152579,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පස් පොඩ්ඩා සමග වෙඩි කෑ තවත් අයෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another person was killed after being shot with a gun",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A hospital spokesman said that another person who was receiving treatment at the Gampaha District General Hospital after being injured in the shooting incident that took place in front of the Gampaha High Court on the 27th, died early this morning.",
        "Piyathilaka Thisera, the neighbor of Basnayaka Appuhamila, who resided in Kotugoda, Maduruvita, has died.",
        "Mr. Pas Podda died earlier in this shooting incident and two others who were injured by gunshots are receiving treatment at the Gampaha Hospital, said Hospital Director Specialist Dr. Saman Pathirana in response to a query."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha District General Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Piyathilaka Thisera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basnayaka Appuhamila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotugoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maduruvita",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pas Podda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Specialist",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පස් පොඩ්ඩා සමග වෙඩි කෑ තවත් අයෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගම්පහ මහාධිකරණය ඉදිරිපිටදී ඉකුත් 27 වෙනි දින සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියේදී තුවාල ලබා ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහලෙහි ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටි තවත් අයෙකු අද අලුයම ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වූ බව රෝහල් ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "කොටුගොඩ , මදුරුවිට පදිංචිව සිටි බස්නායක අප්පුහාමිලාගේ ගාමිණී පියතිලක තිසේරා නමැති අය මිය ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මෙම වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියේදී පස් පොඩ්ඩා නමැත්තා මීට පෙර මියගිය අතර වෙඩි වැදීමෙන් තුවාල ලැබූ තවත් දෙදෙනකු ගම්පහ රෝහලෙහි ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටින බව , කළ විමසුමකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් රෝහල් අධ්‍යක්ෂ විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය සමන් පතිරණ මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පියතිලක තිසේර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නායක අප්පුහාමිලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මදුරුවිට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස් පොඩ්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂඥ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேலும் ஒருவர் துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டு கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த 27ஆம் திகதி கம்பஹா மேல் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு முன்பாக இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்தில் காயமடைந்து கம்பஹா மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த மற்றுமொருவர் இன்று அதிகாலை உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக வைத்தியசாலைப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொட்டுகொட, மதுருவிட்ட பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் பஸ்நாயக்க அப்புஹாமிலவின் அயலவரான பியதிலக திசேரா என்பவரே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டு சம்பவத்தில் திரு.பாஸ் போட்டா முன்னதாக உயிரிழந்ததுடன், துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு இலக்கான மேலும் இருவர் கம்பஹா வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக வைத்தியசாலை பணிப்பாளர் விசேட வைத்திய நிபுணர் டாக்டர் சமன் பத்திரன வினவலுக்கு பதிலளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பியதிலக திசேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஸ்நாயக்க அப்புஹாமில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடுகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுருவிட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஸ் போட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிபுணர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}