{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78685",
  "time_ut": 1658430900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith Denies Allegation that he blocked Karu  Jayasuriya from Entering Parliament by Vetoing Moves by Mayantha  Dissanayake and Harin Fernando to Resign their National List MP Seats  for  Karu to be Appointed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith Denies Allegation that he blocked Karu  Jayasuriya from Entering Parliament by Vetoing Moves by Mayantha  Dissanayake and Harin Fernando to Resign their National List MP Seats  for  Karu to be Appointed",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Although two Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) National List Opposition MPs had expressed their desire to resign from their positions as MPs to enable former Speaker of Parliament and incumbent National Movement for Social Justice (NMSJ) Chairman Karu Jayasuriya the opportunity to enter Parliament, Opposition and SJB Leader Sajith Premadasa had allegedly vetoed the move, The Morning learnt.",
        "Speaking to The Morning, sources close to Premadasa claimed that in the early days of the talks regarding the formation of an interim all party Government in the wake of the economic crisis in the country, there were discussions within the SJB about giving Jayasuriya the opportunity to enter Parliament.",
        "The sources further claimed that during those discussions, two National List MPs representing the SJB, namely Mayantha Dissanayake who is also related to Jayasuriya, and incumbent Minister Harin Fernando, had expressed their consent to resign as MPs and to give Jayasuriya the opportunity to enter the Parliament. According to the sources, discussions had been held regarding offering Jayasuriya a high-level position in an interim Government to be formed according to that plan.",
        "However, the sources alleged that Premadasa had not provided permission to Dissanayake or Fernando to resign. According to the sources, it was one reason that Fernando had subsequently accepted a Ministerial post in the Government led by then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and then-Prime Minister and incumbent President Ranil Wickremesinghe. The sources opined that if Premadasa had, at that time, given Jayasuriya the opportunity to enter Parliament, Jayasuriya could have been appointed to the position of the President left vacant by the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, with the agreement of all the parties, a vacancy which has since been filled by Wickremesinghe.",
        "However, when The Morning contacted the Opposition Leader, he vehemently rejected the claim.",
        "In April, 2022, The Morning reported that Jayasuriya was likely to be given a leading position in an interim all party Government to be formed, considering the economic and political crisis situation in the country. Sources said at the time, that in such a case, several parties, including groups that had left the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) led Government and since declared themselves as independent in the Parliament, and the Opposition, would have agreed to facilitate his appointment as a MP from the National List.",
        "When contacted to inquire about such reports at the time, Jayasuriya said: “I have not applied for any post, but I know that people are talking about such a matter. So let us consider it if such an invitation is received. We are ready to fulfill any role in order to build the country.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Karu  Jayasuriya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mayantha  Dissanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Harin Fernando to Resign",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Movement for Social Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karu Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mayantha Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කරු ජයසූරිය මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීම වැළැක්වූ බවට එල්ල වන චෝදනාව සජිත් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි මයන්ත දිසානායක සහ හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු කරු පත්කිරීම සඳහා ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට කළ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග නිෂේධනය කරමින්.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට කැමැත්ත ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණද, හිටපු කථානායක සහ වත්මන් සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය සඳහා වූ ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරයේ (NMSJ) සභාපති කරු ජයසූරිය මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීමට අවස්ථාව සැලසීම සඳහා විපක්ෂය සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා එම පියවර නිෂේධ බලයෙන් භාවිතා කළ බව ද මෝනිං වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "The Morning වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රේමදාසට සමීප ආරංචි මාර්ග කියා සිටියේ රට තුළ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ අන්තර්කාලීන සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ වූ මුල් දිනවල ජයසූරියට අවස්ථාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් SJB තුළ සාකච්ඡා පැවති බවයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන්න.",
        "එම සාකච්ඡාවලදී ජයසූරියගේ ඥාතියෙකු වන මයන්ත දිසානායක සහ වත්මන් අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු යන SJB නියෝජනය කරන ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු ජයසූරිය මහතාට මන්ත්‍රී ධූරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සහ ජයසූරිය මහතාට ඇතුළුවීමට අවස්ථාව ලබාදීමට කැමැත්ත ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බව එම ආරංචි මාර්ග වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව. එම සැලැස්මට අනුව පිහිටුවන අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවක ඉහළ පෙළේ තනතුරක් ජයසූරිය මහතාට පිරිනැමීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද සාකච්ඡා වී ඇති බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් එම ආරංචි මාර්ග චෝදනා කළේ දිසානායකට හෝ ප්‍රනාන්දුට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ප්‍රේමදාස අවසර ලබා දී නොමැති බවයි. ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පසුව එවකට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය හා වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රමුඛ රජයේ අමාත්‍ය ධූරයක් භාර ගැනීමට එක හේතුවක් වූ බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි. ඒ වන විට ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජයසූරිය මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීමට අවස්ථාව ලබා දුන්නේ නම්, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරයට සියලු පක්ෂවල එකඟතාව ඇතිව ජයසූරිය මහතා පත් කිරීමට ඉඩ තිබූ බව එම ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පුරප්පාඩු වූ පුරප්පාඩුවකි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, The Morning පුවත්පත විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ඇමතූ විට ඔහු එම ප්‍රකාශය තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ද මෝනිං පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේ රටේ පවතින ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන පිහිටුවනු ලබන අන්තර්කාලීන සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක ප්‍රමුඛ තනතුරක් ජයසූරියට ලබාදීමට ඉඩ ඇති බවයි. එවන් අවස්ථාවක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) ප්‍රමුඛ රජයෙන් ඉවත් වී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ කණ්ඩායම් ඇතුළු පාර්ශව කිහිපයක් සහ විපක්ෂය ඔහුට පහසුකම් සැලසීමට එකඟ වනු ඇතැයි එකල ආරංචි මාර්ග පැවසීය. ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ලෙස පත්වීම.",
        "එකල එවැනි වාර්තා ගැන විමසීමට කළ විමසීමකදී ජයසූරිය පැවසුවේ “මම කිසිම තනතුරක් සඳහා ඉල්ලුම් කර නැත, නමුත් එවැනි කාරණයක් ගැන මිනිසුන් කතා කරන බව මම දනිමි. ඉතින් එහෙම ආරාධනාවක් ලැබුණොත් අපි ඒ ගැන සලකා බලමු. රට ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා ඕනෑම කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කිරීමට අපි සූදානම්.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කරු ජයසූරිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මයන්ත දිසානායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තු විපක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය සඳහා වූ ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරු ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුල් දවස්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයන්ත දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மயந்த திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோர் கரு ஜயசூரியவை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் பிரவேசிப்பதை தடை செய்ததாக கூறப்படும் குற்றச்சாட்டை சஜித் மறுத்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரும் தற்போதைய சமூக நீதிக்கான தேசிய இயக்கத்தின் தலைவருமான கரு ஜயசூரியவிற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரவேசிக்கும் வாய்ப்பை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொடுப்பதற்காக இரண்டு சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) தேசிய பட்டியல் எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் தமது எம்.பி பதவிகளை இராஜினாமா செய்ய விருப்பம் தெரிவித்திருந்த போதிலும், SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச இந்த நடவடிக்கையை வீட்டோ செய்ததாக தி மார்னிங் கற்றுத்தந்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை அடுத்து, இடைக்கால சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பான பேச்சுக்களின் ஆரம்ப நாட்களில், ஜயசூரியவுக்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்குவது தொடர்பில் SJB க்குள் பேச்சுக்கள் இடம்பெற்றதாக பிரேமதாசவுக்கு நெருக்கமான வட்டாரங்கள் The Morning இடம் பேசியுள்ளன. பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நுழைய.",
        "இந்த கலந்துரையாடலின் போது, ​​ஜயசூரியவுடன் தொடர்புடைய மயந்த திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் தற்போதைய அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகிய இரண்டு தேசியப்பட்டியல் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும், ஜயசூரியவிற்கு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்து, ஜயசூரியவிற்குள் நுழைவதற்கான வாய்ப்பை வழங்க சம்மதம் தெரிவித்ததாக அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் மேலும் தெரிவித்தன. பாராளுமன்றம். அந்தத் திட்டத்தின்படி அமைக்கப்படவுள்ள இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தில் ஜயசூரியவுக்கு உயர்மட்ட பதவியை வழங்குவது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாக அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், திஸாநாயக்க அல்லது பெர்னாண்டோ பதவி விலகுவதற்கு பிரேமதாச அனுமதி வழங்கவில்லை என அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளன. அன்றைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் அப்போதைய பிரதமரும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தில் பெர்னாண்டோ அமைச்சுப் பதவியை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதும் ஒரு காரணம் என்று அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. அப்போது பிரேமதாச, ஜயசூரியவுக்கு நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் பிரவேசிக்கும் வாய்ப்பை வழங்கியிருந்தால், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமாவால் வெற்றிடமான ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு, அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளின் இணக்கப்பாட்டுடன் ஜயசூரியவை நியமித்திருக்க முடியும் என அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. ஒரு வெற்றிடம் விக்கிரமசிங்கவால் நிரப்பப்பட்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தி மோர்னிங் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரைத் தொடர்பு கொண்டபோது, ​​அவர் அந்தக் கோரிக்கையை கடுமையாக நிராகரித்தார்.",
        "ஏப்ரல், 2022 இல், தி மார்னிங், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடி நிலையைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இடைக்கால சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில், ஜெயசூர்யாவுக்கு முன்னணி பதவி வழங்கப்பட வாய்ப்புள்ளது என்று செய்தி வெளியிட்டது. அவ்வாறான சந்தர்ப்பத்தில், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்து வெளியேறிய குழுக்கள் உட்பட பல கட்சிகள் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தம்மை சுயாதீனமாக அறிவித்துக் கொண்ட குழுக்கள் உட்பட பல கட்சிகள் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் அவருக்கு வசதிகளை வழங்க இணங்கியிருக்கும் என்று அந்த நேரத்தில் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. தேசிய பட்டியலிலிருந்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமனம்.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில் இதுபோன்ற செய்திகள் குறித்து விசாரிக்க ஜெயசூர்யாவைத் தொடர்பு கொண்டபோது, ​​​​\"நான் எந்தப் பதவிக்கும் விண்ணப்பிக்கவில்லை, ஆனால் இதுபோன்ற விஷயத்தைப் பற்றி மக்கள் பேசுகிறார்கள் என்பது எனக்குத் தெரியும். எனவே அப்படி ஒரு அழைப்பு வந்தால் அதை பரிசீலிப்போம். நாட்டைக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கு நாம் எந்தப் பங்கையும் செய்யத் தயாராக இருக்கிறோம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கரு ஜயசூரிய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மயந்த திசாநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ராஜினாமா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியப் பட்டியல் எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக நீதிக்கான தேசிய இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரு ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரம்ப நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மயந்த திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}