{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-colombo-port-container-volumes-down-9-3-pct-in-june-2022-98856/",
  "time_ut": 1661151840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s Colombo port container volumes down 9.3-pct in June 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Colombo port container volumes down 9.3-pct in June 2022",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s container transshipment volumes fell 4.5 percent from a year ago to 483,070 twenty foot equivalent units in June 2022 as domestic imports also fell, data shows, as the economy was contracted to stabilize a soft-peg which collapsed due to earlier money printing.",
        "Domestic container volumes fell 25 percent from a year ago to 80,386 TEUs in June.",
        "Total containers handled in June fell 9.3 percent to 577,082.",
        "In the six months to June total container volumes in Sri Lanka were down 0.6 percent to 3.554 million TEUs.",
        "Colombo’s container transshipment is linked to Indian external trade and global trade though domestic conditions like strikes or unrest may affect port activity in some months.",
        "Sri Lanka’s domestic container volumes started to fall steadily after March after Central Bank Governor Nandalal Weerasinghe allowed interest rates to go up to limit money printing and credit.",
        "Sri Lanka’s soft-peg with the US dollar collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar in a failed float with a surrender requirement (forced dollar sales to the central bank) and low rates.",
        "Global economic activity is also moderating as the Federal Reserve and other central bank try to allow rates to go up after printing money into a healthy banking system during the Coronavirus crisis to boost growth driving commodity prices and overall inflation to high levels. (Colombo/Aug22/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9.3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "June 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "483,070 twenty foot",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,386",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.3 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "577,082",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the six months to June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.554 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "some months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Federal Reserve",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coronavirus",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොළඹ වරායේ බහාලුම් පරිමාව 2022 ජුනි මාසයේදී සියයට 9.3 කින් අඩු විය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බහාලුම් ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත පරිමාව වසරකට පෙර සිට සියයට 4.5 කින් පහත වැටී 2022 ජූනි මාසයේදී අඩි විස්සක් සමාන ඒකක 483,070 ක් දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇති අතර, දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙන්නේ, කලින් මුදල් මුද්‍රණය හේතුවෙන් කඩා වැටුණු මෘදු-පෙග් එකක් ස්ථාවර කිරීමට ආර්ථිකය හැකිලීමත් සමඟ දේශීය ආනයන ද පහත වැටුණු බැවිනි. .",
        "දේශීය බහාලුම් පරිමාව ජුනි මාසයේදී TEU 80,386 දක්වා වසරකට පෙර සිට සියයට 25 කින් පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ජුනි මාසයේදී හසුරුවන ලද මුළු බහාලුම් 577,082 දක්වා සියයට 9.3 කින් පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ජූනි සිට ජුනි දක්වා මාස හය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුළු බහාලුම් පරිමාව TEU මිලියන 3.554 දක්වා සියයට 0.6 කින් අඩු විය.",
        "වැඩ වර්ජන හෝ නොසන්සුන්තා වැනි දේශීය තත්ත්වයන් සමහර මාසවලදී වරාය ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට බලපෑ හැකි වුවද කොළඹ බහාලුම් ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත කිරීම ඉන්දියානු විදේශ වෙළෙඳාම හා ගෝලීය වෙළෙඳාමට සම්බන්ධ වේ.",
        "මුදල් මුද්‍රණය සහ ණය සීමා කිරීම සඳහා මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ පොලී අනුපාත ඉහළ යාමට ඉඩ දීමෙන් පසු මාර්තු මාසයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශීය බහාලුම් පරිමාව ක්‍රමයෙන් පහත වැටීමට පටන් ගත්තේය.",
        "යටත් වීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය (මහ බැංකුවට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඩොලර් විකිණීම) සහ අඩු අනුපාත සමඟ අසාර්ථක වූ පාවීමකදී එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරය සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සොෆ්ට්-පෙග් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා කඩා වැටුණි.",
        "ෆෙඩරල් සංචිතය සහ අනෙකුත් මහ බැංකුව විසින් කොරොන වයිරස් අර්බුදය තුළ සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න බැංකු පද්ධතියකට මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමෙන් පසු අනුපාත ඉහළ යාමට ඉඩ දීමට උත්සාහ කරන බැවින් ගෝලීය ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ද මධ්‍යස්ථ වෙමින් පවතී. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 22/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9.3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022 ජූනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 4.5 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "483,070 අඩි විස්සක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 25 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,386 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 9.3 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "577,082 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි සිට මාස හය දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.554 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමහර මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල් සංචිතය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනාවයිරසය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் கொழும்பு துறைமுக கொள்கலன் அளவு ஜூன் 2022 இல் 9.3% குறைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – உள்நாட்டு இறக்குமதிகளும் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்ததால், இலங்கையின் கொள்கலன் பரிமாற்ற அளவுகள் ஒரு வருடத்திற்கு முன்பு இருந்ததை விட 4.5 சதவீதம் சரிந்து 2022 ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 483,070 இருபது அடிக்கு சமமான அலகுகளாக சரிந்தன, பொருளாதாரம் முந்தைய பண அச்சடிப்பு காரணமாக சரிந்த மென்மையான-பெக்கை உறுதிப்படுத்த ஒப்பந்தம் செய்யப்பட்டதால், தரவு காட்டுகிறது. .",
        "உள்நாட்டு கொள்கலன் அளவுகள் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 80,386 TEU களாக ஒரு வருடத்திற்கு முன்பு இருந்து 25 சதவீதம் சரிந்தன.",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் கையாளப்பட்ட மொத்த கொள்கலன்கள் 9.3 சதவீதம் சரிந்து 577,082 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "ஜூன் முதல் ஜூன் வரையிலான ஆறு மாதங்களில் இலங்கையில் மொத்த கொள்கலன் அளவு 0.6 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 3.554 மில்லியன் TEU ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "வேலைநிறுத்தங்கள் அல்லது அமைதியின்மை போன்ற உள்நாட்டு நிலைமைகள் சில மாதங்களில் துறைமுக நடவடிக்கைகளை பாதிக்கலாம் என்றாலும் கொழும்பின் கொள்கலன் பரிமாற்றமானது இந்திய வெளி வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உலகளாவிய வர்த்தகத்துடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, பணம் அச்சிடுதல் மற்றும் கடனைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த வட்டி விகிதங்களை அதிகரிக்க அனுமதித்ததன் பின்னர், இலங்கையின் உள்நாட்டு கொள்கலன் அளவுகள் மார்ச் மாதத்திற்குப் பின்னர் சீராக வீழ்ச்சியடையத் தொடங்கின.",
        "சரணடைதல் தேவை (மத்திய வங்கிக்கு கட்டாயப்படுத்தப்பட்ட டாலர் விற்பனை) மற்றும் குறைந்த விகிதங்களுடன் தோல்வியுற்ற மிதவையில் அமெரிக்க டாலருடன் இலங்கையின் சாஃப்ட்-பெக் அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு 200 முதல் 360 வரை சரிந்தது.",
        "பெடரல் ரிசர்வ் மற்றும் பிற மத்திய வங்கிகள் கொரோனா வைரஸ் நெருக்கடியின் போது ஆரோக்கியமான வங்கி அமைப்பில் பணத்தை அச்சடித்த பிறகு விகிதங்களை அதிகரிக்க அனுமதிக்க முயற்சிப்பதால், உலகளாவிய பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கை மிதமானது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்22/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9.3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "483,070 இருபது அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,386",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.3 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "577,082",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் முதல் ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.554 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெடரல் ரிசர்வ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா வைரஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}