{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Govt-to-present-revised-Budget-next-month/56-737946",
  "time_ut": 1658875380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Govt. to present revised Budget next month",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Govt. to present revised Budget next month",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Cabinet Spokesman Bandula Gunawardena yesterday confirmed that the Government will present the revised Budget next month for the remainder of the year.",
        "“The alterations to the numbers relating to the ministries have now been completed. The revised budget proposal will be presented for the remaining months of this year in August,” he said in response to a query posed at the post-Cabinet meeting media briefing yesterday.",
        "Earlier this month, former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa-led Cabinet of Ministers approved to present a bill to Parliament to amend Appropriation Act No. 30 of 2021 for the year 2022, to revise the original Budget estimates for the rest of the months, as a result of the ongoing worst economic crisis.",
        "The proposal to this effect was submitted by then Prime Minister and current President Ranil Wickremesinghe, in his capacity as the Finance, Economic Stabilisation, and National Policies Minister.",
        "As per the original budget estimates, the revenue was expected at Rs. 2.3 trillion and the expenditure at Rs. 3.3 trillion.",
        "However, given the worsening economic conditions, the Finance Ministry estimates the actual revenue to fall to Rs.1.6 trillion and expenditure to increase to Rs. 4 trillion, causing an additional budget deficit of Rs. 0.8 trillion.",
        "Experts claimed that sharp tax cuts introduced by former President Rajapaksa Government in 2019 were responsible for the fiscal policy mismanagement.",
        "At present, the authorities are trying to take a U-turn and get back to the same tax framework which existed before December 2019."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Budget",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "next month",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Budget",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the remaining months of this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Budget",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.3 trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3 trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.8 trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa Government",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "December 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය ලබන මාසයේ සංශෝධිත අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසරේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා රජය සංශෝධිත අයවැය ලබන මාසයේදී ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ඊයේ තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "“අමාත්‍යාංශවලට අදාළ අංකවල වෙනස්කම් දැන් අවසන්. මේ වසරේ ඉතිරි මාස සඳහා සංශෝධිත අයවැය යෝජනාව අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී ඉදිරිපත් කරනවා” යැයි ඊයේ කැබිනට් රැස්වීමෙන් පසු පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී අසන ලද ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ඉතිරි මාස සඳහා මුල් අයවැය ඇස්තමේන්තු සංශෝධනය කිරීම සඳහා 2022 වසර සඳහා 2021 අංක 30 දරන විසර්ජන පනත සංශෝධනය කිරීමේ පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ප්‍රමුඛ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය මේ මස මුලදී අනුමැතිය ලබා දුන්නේය. පවතින නරකම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ගැන.",
        "මේ සඳහා වූ යෝජනාව ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලැබුවේ මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය හා වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසිනි.",
        "මුල් අයවැය ඇස්තමේන්තුවලට අනුව ආදායම රු. ට්‍රිලියන 2.3 ක් සහ වියදම රු. ට්‍රිලියන 3.3 කි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය හමුවේ, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය ඇස්තමේන්තු කරන්නේ සැබෑ ආදායම රුපියල් ට්‍රිලියන 1.6 දක්වා පහත වැටෙනු ඇති අතර වියදම් රු. ටි‍්‍රලියන 4 ක අතිරේක අයවැය හිඟයක් ඇති කරයි. ට්‍රිලියන 0.8 කි.",
        "2019 දී හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ රජය විසින් හඳුන්වා දුන් තියුණු බදු කප්පාදු මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්ති වැරදි කළමනාකරණයට වගකිව යුතු බව විශේෂඥයින් ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "මේ වන විට බලධාරීන් උත්සාහ කරන්නේ U-turn එකක් ගෙන 2019 දෙසැම්බර් මාසයට පෙර පැවති බදු රාමුවටම නැවත පැමිණීමටය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අයවැය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයවැය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම වසරේ ඉතිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයවැය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 2.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 3.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 0.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ රජය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு அடுத்த மாதம் திருத்தப்பட்ட பட்ஜெட் தாக்கல் செய்ய வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வருடத்தின் எஞ்சிய காலப்பகுதிக்கான திருத்தப்பட்ட வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை அரசாங்கம் அடுத்த மாதம் சமர்ப்பிக்கும் என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன நேற்று உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "“அமைச்சகங்கள் தொடர்பான எண்களில் மாற்றங்கள் தற்போது நிறைவடைந்துள்ளன. இந்த வருடத்தின் எஞ்சிய மாதங்களுக்கான திருத்தப்பட்ட வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும்” என நேற்று நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்திற்குப் பின்னரான ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் எழுப்பப்பட்ட கேள்விக்கு அவர் பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான அமைச்சரவை, 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 30 ஆம் இலக்க ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டத்தை திருத்துவதற்கான சட்டமூலத்தை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்க ஒப்புதல் அளித்தது. தற்போதைய மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி.",
        "நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் அப்போதைய பிரதமரும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் இதற்கான பிரேரணை சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அசல் பட்ஜெட் மதிப்பீடுகளின்படி, வருவாய் ரூ. 2.3 டிரில்லியன் மற்றும் செலவு ரூ. 3.3 டிரில்லியன்.",
        "இருப்பினும், மோசமான பொருளாதார நிலைமைகளைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, நிதி அமைச்சகம் உண்மையான வருவாய் ரூ.1.6 டிரில்லியனாகக் குறையும் என்றும், செலவு ரூ. 4 டிரில்லியன், கூடுதல் பட்ஜெட் பற்றாக்குறை ரூ. 0.8 டிரில்லியன்.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சே அரசாங்கத்தால் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட கடுமையான வரிக் குறைப்புக்கள் நிதிக் கொள்கை தவறான நிர்வாகத்திற்குக் காரணம் என்று நிபுணர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "தற்போது, ​​அதிகாரிகள் யு-டர்ன் எடுத்து, டிசம்பர் 2019 க்கு முன்பு இருந்த அதே வரி கட்டமைப்பிற்கு திரும்ப முயற்சிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பட்ஜெட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் மீதமுள்ள மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.3 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.3 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.8 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே அரசு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}