{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-interim-budget-on-aug-30-followed-by-four-day-debate-98964/",
  "time_ut": 1661336100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka interim budget on Aug 30, followed by four-day debate",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka interim budget on Aug 30, followed by four-day debate",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s parliament will debate an interim budget, to be presented by President Ranil Wickremesinghe on Tuesday August 30, from Tuesday to Friday that week, a government MP said.",
        "Ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) general secretary MP Sagara Kariyawasam told reporters on Wednesday August 24 that a vote on the interim budget will be taken in parliament next Friday September 02.",
        "The MP said the interim budget will likely focus on economic recovery while also providing relief to the public as much as possible.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through its worst economic crisis since independence and high inflation have hit the public hard.",
        "“Note that this is only an interim budget. The budget proper for 2023 will be presented in November,” said Kariyawasam. (Colombo/Aug24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "four-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday to Friday that week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday August 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Friday September 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අතුරු අයවැය අගෝස්තු 30, ඉන් අනතුරුව දින හතරක විවාදය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා, එම සතියේ අඟහරුවාදා සිට සිකුරාදා දක්වා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත අතුරු අයවැයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විවාදයට ගන්නා බව රජයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "ලබන සිකුරාදා සැප්තැම්බර් 02 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අතුරු අයවැය පිළිබඳ ඡන්ද විමසීමක් පවත්වන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා අගෝස්තු 24 බදාදා මාධ්‍යවේදීන් හමුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "අතුරු අයවැයෙන් ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිමත් වීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන අතරම හැකිතාක් මහජනතාවට සහන සැලසීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන බව මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර ඉහළ උද්ධමනය මහජනතාවට දැඩි ලෙස බලපා ඇත.",
        "“මෙය අතුරු අයවැයක් පමණක් බව සලකන්න. 2023 වසරට නියමිත අයවැය නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී ඉදිරිපත් කරනවා” කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින හතරක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම සතියේ අඟහරුවාදා සිට සිකුරාදා දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සිකුරාදා සැප්තැම්බර් 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் ஆகஸ்ட் 30ஆம் தேதி, அதைத் தொடர்ந்து நான்கு நாள் விவாதம்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை, செவ்வாய் முதல் வெள்ளி வரை அந்த வாரத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் பற்றி விவாதிக்கப்படும் என்று அரசாங்க எம்.பி.",
        "எதிர்வரும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை செப்டம்பர் 02 ஆம் திகதி இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் மீதான வாக்கெடுப்பு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடத்தப்படும் என ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பொதுச் செயலாளர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சாகர காரியவசம் ஆகஸ்ட் 24 புதன்கிழமை செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டம் பொருளாதார மீட்சியில் கவனம் செலுத்தும் அதே வேளையில் பொதுமக்களுக்கு இயன்றளவு நிவாரணம் வழங்கும் என எம்.பி.",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சந்தித்து வருகிறது மற்றும் உயர் பணவீக்கம் பொதுமக்களை கடுமையாக பாதித்துள்ளது.",
        "“இது ஒரு இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் மட்டுமே என்பதை நினைவில் கொள்ளவும். 2023ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் நவம்பரில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும்” என்று காரியவசம் தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த வாரம் செவ்வாய் முதல் வெள்ளி வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை செப்டம்பர் 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}