{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අලුත්-වන-රක්ෂිතයක්-නම්-කරයි/1-617046",
  "time_ut": 1658816865,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අලුත් වන රක්ෂිතයක් නම් කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Designates a new forest reserve",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation has decided to designate the area around Sampalativu Lagoon in Trincomalee district as a sensitive ecological zone as well as a natural forest reserve.",
        "This decision was taken in a discussion held at the Ministry of Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation with the participation of the Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera.",
        "The surrounding area of ​​the sampling area is also an area with a large mangrove population. But it was revealed in this discussion that the mangrove ecosystem in Trincomalee which was 2043 hectares in the last few years has reduced to 1491 hectares.",
        "Accordingly, it was decided to designate this area of ​​239.58 hectares as a sensitive ecological zone and a natural forest reserve around the Sampalativu lagoon belonging to the areas of Sanli, Iluppaikulam, Varodhaya Nagar and Uppuveli Grama Niladhari. The minister instructed the secretary of the ministry, Chandra Herath, to prepare a related cabinet paper."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampalativu Lagoon",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Wildlife",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2043",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last few years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1491",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "​​239.58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampalativu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iluppaikulam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Varodhaya Nagar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uppuveli Grama Niladhari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අලුත් වන රක්ෂිතයක් නම් කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ සාම්පලතිව් කලපුව අවට ප්‍රදේශය සංවේදී පරිසර කලාපයක් මෙන්ම ස්වභාවික වන රක්ෂිතයක් ලෙස නම් කිරීමට කෘෂිකර්ම, වනජීවී හා වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍යාංශය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම, වනජීවී හා වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් වනජීවී හා වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මෙම තීරණය ගනු ලැබීය.",
        "සාම්පලතිව් කලාපය අවට ප්‍රදේශය විශාල කඩොලාන ගහනයකින් ද සමන්විත ප්‍රදේශයකි. නමුත් පසුගිය වසර කිහිපයේ හෙක්ටයාර් 2043ක් වූ ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ කඩොලාන පරිසර පද්ධතිය හෙක්ටයාර් 1491 දක්වා අඩු වී ඇති බව මෙම සාකච්ඡාවෙිදී අනාවරණය විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව සාම්පලතිව් කලපුව අවට සල්ලි, ඉලුප්පයිකුළම්, වරෝධය නගර් හා උප්පුවේලි ග්‍රාම නිලධාරී වසම්වලට අයත් හෙක්ටයාර් 239.58ක භූමි ප්‍රමාණයකින් සමන්විත මෙම ප්‍රදේශය සංවේදී පරිසර කලාපයක් මෙන්ම ස්වභාවික වන රක්ෂිතයක් ලෙස නම් කිරීමට තීරණය කරනු ලැබීය. මීට අදාළ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල පත්‍රිකාවක් සකසන ලෙස අමාත්‍යවරයා ව අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් චන්ද්‍රා හේරත් මහත්මියට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පලතිව් කලපුව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2043",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1491",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "239.58 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පලතිව්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලුප්පායිකුලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරෝධය නගර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උප්පුවේලි ග්‍රාම නිලධාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய வன காப்பகத்தை நியமிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "திருகோணமலை மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள சம்பலாதீவுக் குளத்தைச் சூழவுள்ள பிரதேசத்தை உணர்திறன் மிக்க சூழலியல் வலயமாகவும், இயற்கை வனப் பிரதேசமாகவும் நியமிக்க விவசாயம், வனவிலங்கு மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சில் விவசாய, வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீரவின் பங்குபற்றுதலுடன் நடைபெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் இந்தத் தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மாதிரிப் பகுதியைச் சுற்றியுள்ள பகுதியும் ஒரு பெரிய சதுப்புநில மக்களைக் கொண்ட ஒரு பகுதியாகும். ஆனால் திருகோணமலையில் கடந்த சில வருடங்களில் 2043 ஹெக்டேயராக இருந்த சதுப்புநில சூழல் 1491 ஹெக்டேராக குறைந்துள்ளது இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, 239.58 ஹெக்டேர் பரப்பளவைக் கொண்ட இப்பிரதேசம் சான்லி, இலுப்பைக்குளம், வரோதயா நகர், உப்புவெளி கிராம அலுவலர் ஆகிய பிரதேசங்களுக்கு உட்பட்ட சம்பலாதீவுக் குளத்தைச் சுற்றிலும் உணர்திறன் மிக்க சூழலியல் வலயமாகவும், இயற்கை வனப் பிரதேசமாகவும் நியமிக்கத் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது. இது தொடர்பான அமைச்சரவை பத்திரத்தை தயாரிக்குமாறு அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் சந்திர ஹேரத்துக்கு அமைச்சர் பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பலாதீவு தடாகம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2043",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1491",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "239.58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பலாதீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்லி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலுப்பைக்குளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரோதயா நகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உப்புவெளி கிராம உத்தியோகத்தர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திர ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}