{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/columns/Why-has-PM-Wickremesinghe-not-broached-Gulf-States-to-help-solve-fuel-crisis/4-736484",
  "time_ut": 1655856998,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Why has PM Wickremesinghe not broached Gulf States  to help solve fuel crisis?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Why has PM Wickremesinghe not broached Gulf States  to help solve fuel crisis?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Given the dire struggle for fuel and gas worsening by the day across the country and the serious multi-facetted ominous impact on food supplies cum transport caused by the woefully irregular and paltry supply of fuel, the question arises as to why Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe had not directly broached Sri Lanka’s humanitarian crisis with the Saudi government or any of the other oil exporting Gulf states for assistance to obtain essential fuel on humanitarian terms or credit basis, during his more than one month in the current term in that office.",
        "Instead of employing foreign agents, the Prime Minister ought to have supplemented India’s continued and timely assistance, by promptly speaking to his counterparts in the Middle East, the world’s major producers and exporters of ‘quality fuel’, who would certainly assist Sri Lanka by providing long-term credit as well as investment packages that the country badly needs, if duly handled.",
        "The experienced PM who took up the country’s complicated challenges by accepting office on 13 May for the sixth time, does not need 40 days to call on the Middle East leaders and seek their help to wipe the tears off the ever increasing number of hungry angry people.",
        "Needless to say that Wickremesinghe must watch, in addition to the print media, the daily news bulletins in the electronic media specially Siyatha and its ‘Tele-Vakiya’, Sirasa and its ‘Davasa’ plus ‘Newsline’ and Ada Derana to comprehend the enormity of the suffering from the peoples’ perspective as well as the imminent collapse of existential life within almost every family in the country!",
        "The apparent reason for the unprecedented sufferings of the innocent families is the Government’s failure to ensure an un-broken supply of fuel and gas. All other problems revolve around the fuel crisis! Constitutional and political problems follow closely thereafter. This Government including the President may not survive, if the fuel and consequential food problems are not effectively tackled!",
        "Until 2021, 95% of the country’s highest source of foreign exchange earnings came from the Sri Lankans employed in the Middle East, averaging $ 7 billion each year. Quality fuel and gas also come mainly from the Middle East. But successive governments inexcusably failed to keep close and friendly ties with any of these countries!",
        "The Cabinet has a knowledgeable man in the field, Minister of Environment Naseer Ahmed, an engineer by profession who is an honours graduate of the King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals of Saudi Arabia. The alumni of this university dedicated to petroleum and mineral resources reportedly hold key positions in the petroleum industry in most Gulf countries. Why didn’t Wickremesinghe within days of his assuming office send the only Arabic conversant Cabinet Minister Naseer Ahmed to the Gulf countries?",
        "Instead of giving him the ‘petroleum supplies’ portfolio at the minimum, Naseer Ahmed had been given ‘Environment’! And worse, in order to raise dollars for Sri Lanka from the Gulf countries, Wickremesinghe inappropriately appointed a foreigner, Maldivian politician Nasheed Ahmed, holding office as Maldives Speaker and distanced himself from the oil producing countries at a time when Sri Lanka needed to get closer and directly!",
        "Parliament Speaker Nasheed, who has many friends in Sri Lanka, resigned as President of Maldives in February 2012, on account of unceasing public protests following the arrest of a senior criminal court judge of Maldives allegedly at the instance of the then Maldives President Nasheed. Later on Nasheed claimed that he was forced to resign by the Maldivian police and the armed forces! The claim was investigated by a Commonwealth-backed Commission which held that Nasheed resigned voluntarily following unceasing public protests over the top Maldivian judge’s arrest and incarceration. The Commission rejected Nasheed’s claim that he was forced to resign at gun point!",
        "The question as to why pro-Western Maldivian Speaker Nasheed Ahmed, who is yet to give his performance report to PM Wickremesinghe, though he leaked out a later contradicted report to a Sri Lankan Opposition MP, was picked up from the blues in preference to pro-Middle Eastern Sri Lankan Minister Naseer Ahmed to alleviate Sri Lanka’s dollar crisis, is fraught with more questions than answers!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gulf States",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tele-Vakiya’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 7 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "each year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals of Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arabic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "pro-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Sri Lankan Opposition MP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "pro-Middle Eastern Sri Lankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා ගල්ෆ් රාජ්‍යයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා නොකළේ මන්ද?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට පුරා දිනෙන් දින නරක අතට හැරෙන ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් සඳහා වන දරුණු අරගලය සහ දුක්ඛිත ලෙස අක්‍රමවත් හා සොච්චම් ඉන්ධන සැපයීම හේතුවෙන් ආහාර සැපයුම් සහ ප්‍රවාහනයට ඇති වූ බරපතල බහුවිධ අශුභ බලපෑම් සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන, අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට එසේ වූයේ මන්දැයි ප්‍රශ්නය මතු වේ. ඔහුගේ වත්මන් නිල කාලය තුළ මාසයකට වැඩි කාලයක් මානුෂීය කොන්දේසි මත හෝ ණය පදනම මත අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා සහය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා සෞදි රජය හෝ වෙනත් තෙල් අපනයනය කරන ගල්ෆ් රාජ්‍යයන් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානුෂීය අර්බුදය සෘජුවම ඉදිරිපත් කර නැත.",
        "විදේශ නියෝජිතයන් යොදවා ගැනීම වෙනුවට, අගමැතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නිසැකවම සහය වන ලොව ප්‍රධාන නිෂ්පාදකයින් සහ අපනයනකරුවන් වන මැදපෙරදිග සිටින තම සගයන් සමඟ වහා කතා කිරීමෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ අඛණ්ඩ සහ කාලෝචිත ආධාර අතිරේකයක් කළ යුතුව තිබුණි. නිසි ලෙස හසුරුවන්නේ නම්, දිගුකාලීන ණය මෙන්ම රටට නරක ලෙස අවශ්‍ය ආයෝජන පැකේජ.",
        "මැයි 13 වෙනිදා හයවැනි වරටත් සිය ධුරය භාර ගනිමින් රටේ සංකීර්ණ අභියෝග භාරගත් පළපුරුදු අගමැතිවරයාට දින 40ක් අවශ්‍ය නොවේ මැදපෙරදිග නායකයන් අමතා දිනෙන් දින වැඩිවන කුසගින්නෙන් පෙළෙන මිනිසුන්ගේ කඳුළු පිස දමන්නට. .",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මුද්‍රිත මාධ්‍යවලට අමතරව සියත සහ එහි ‘ටෙලි වාකිය’, සිරස සහ එහි ‘දවස’ ප්ලස් ‘නිව්ස්ලයින්’ සහ අද දෙරණ යන විද්‍යුත් මාධ්‍යවල දෛනික ප්‍රවෘත්ති ප්‍රකාශන ද දැවැන්ත බව අවබෝධ කර ගැනීම සඳහා නැරඹිය යුතු බව අමුතුවෙන් කිව යුතු නැත. ජනතාවගේ දෘෂ්ටිකෝණයෙන් දුක් විඳීම මෙන්ම රටේ සෑම පවුලක් තුළම පැවැත්මේ ජීවිතයේ ආසන්න බිඳවැටීම!",
        "අහිංසක පවුල්වල පෙර නොවූ විරූ දුක් වේදනාවලට පැහැදිලි හේතුව වන්නේ ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් අඛණ්ඩව සැපයීම සහතික කිරීමට රජය අසමත් වීමයි. අනෙක් සියලුම ගැටලු ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය වටා කැරකෙයි! ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාමය සහ දේශපාලන ගැටලු ඉන් පසුව සමීපව අනුගමනය කරයි. ඉන්ධන සහ ප්‍රතිවිපාක ආහාර ප්‍රශ්න ඵලදායී ලෙස විසඳා නොගතහොත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඇතුළු මේ රජයට පැවැත්මක් නැත!",
        "2021 වන තෙක්, රටේ ඉහළම විදේශ විනිමය ඉපැයීම් මූලාශ්‍රයෙන් 95%ක් මැදපෙරදිග සේවයේ නියුතු ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගෙන් ලැබුණු අතර, එය සෑම වසරකම සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 7කි. ගුණාත්මක ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් ද ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් මැද පෙරදිගින් පැමිණේ. නමුත් මේ කිසිම රටක් සමඟ සමීප සහ මිත්‍රශීලී සබඳතා පවත්වා ගැනීමට අනුප්‍රාප්තික රජයන් සමාව දිය නොහැකි ලෙස අසමත් විය!",
        "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ දැනුමැති පුද්ගලයෙක්, පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ්, වෘත්තියෙන් ඉංජිනේරුවෙකු වන ඔහු සෞදි අරාබියේ කිං ෆාඩ් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් සහ ඛනිජ විද්‍යාලයේ ගෞරව උපාධිධාරියෙකි. ඛනිජ තෙල් සහ ඛනිජ සම්පත් සඳහා කැප වූ මෙම විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ආදි සිසුන් බොහෝ ගල්ෆ් රටවල ඛනිජ තෙල් කර්මාන්තයේ ප්‍රධාන තනතුරු දරන බව වාර්තා වේ. වික්‍රමසිංහ සිය ධූරයට පත්වී දින කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත එකම අරාබි භාෂාව කතා කරන කැබිනට් අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් ගල්ෆ් රටවලට නොයැව්වේ ඇයි?",
        "ඔහුට අවම වශයෙන් ‘පෙට්‍රෝලියම් සැපයුම්’ කළඹ දෙනවා වෙනුවට නසීර් අහමඩ්ට ‘පරිසරය’ දී තිබුණා! ඊටත් වඩා නරකම දෙය නම් ගල්ෆ් රටවලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් එකතු කිරීම සඳහා වික්‍රමසිංහ නුසුදුසු ලෙස විදේශිකයෙකු වන මාලදිවයින් දේශපාලඥ නෂීඩ් අහමඩ් මාලදිවයිනේ කථානායක ධුරය දරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සමීප වීමට අවශ්‍ය වූ අවස්ථාවක තෙල් නිපදවන රටවලින් ඈත්ව සිටීමයි. සහ සෘජුවම!",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බොහෝ මිතුරන් සිටින පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක නෂීඩ් 2012 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී මාලදිවයිනේ ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූයේ එවකට මාලදිවයිනේ ජනාධිපති නෂීඩ්ගේ ආදර්ශය මත මාලදිවයිනේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ අපරාධ අධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමත් සමඟ ඇති වූ නොනවතින මහජන විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන්. පසුව නෂීඩ් කියා සිටියේ මාලදිවයින් පොලිසිය සහ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව විසින් තමාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බල කළ බවයි! මෙම ප්‍රකාශය පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය පිටුබලය ලත් කොමිසමක් විසින් විමර්ශනය කරන ලද අතර එහි ප්‍රකාශය වූයේ මාලදිවයිනේ ඉහළම විනිසුරුවරයා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සිරගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් නොනවතින මහජන විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් නෂීඩ් ස්වේච්ඡාවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වූ බවයි. තුවක්කුවක් පෙන්වා තමාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බල කළ බවට නෂීඩ් කළ ප්‍රකාශය කොමිසම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය!",
        "බටහිර ගැති මාලදිවයිනේ කතානායක නෂීඩ් අහමඩ්, අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහට තම කාර්ය සාධන වාර්තාව ලබා නොදී, පසුව පරස්පර විරෝධී වාර්තාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුට කාන්දු කළද, ඔහු පක්ෂපාතීට මනාපයෙන් බ්ලූස් වෙතින් උදුරා ගත්තේ මන්ද යන ප්‍රශ්නය -ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඩොලර් අර්බුදය සමනය කිරීමට මැදපෙරදිග ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඇමති නසීර් අහමඩ්, පිළිතුරු වලට වඩා ප්‍රශ්න වලින් පිරී ඇත!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගල්ෆ් රාජ්යයන්",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 40 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙලි වාකිය'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි අරාබියේ කිං ෆාඩ් ඛනිජ තෙල් සහ ඛනිජ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරාබි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ගැති",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදපෙරදිග ශ්‍රී ලාංකික හිතවාදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஏன் வளைகுடா நாடுகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்க உதவவில்லை?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடு முழுவதும் நாளுக்கு நாள் மோசமடைந்து வரும் எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயுவுக்கான கடுமையான போராட்டம் மற்றும் மோசமான ஒழுங்கற்ற மற்றும் அற்ப எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தால் உணவு விநியோகம் மற்றும் போக்குவரத்தில் கடுமையான பன்முக அச்சுறுத்தும் தாக்கம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஏன் இவ்வாறு செய்தார் என்ற கேள்வி எழுகிறது. இலங்கையின் மனிதாபிமான நெருக்கடியை சவூதி அரசாங்கத்துடனும் அல்லது வேறு எந்த எண்ணெய் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யும் வளைகுடா நாடுகளுடனும் மனிதாபிமான அடிப்படையில் அல்லது கடன் அடிப்படையில் அத்தியாவசிய எரிபொருளைப் பெறுவதற்கான உதவிக்காக, அந்த அலுவலகத்தில் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கும் மேலாக தனது பதவிக்காலத்தில் நேரடியாகப் பேசவில்லை.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு முகவர்களை வேலைக்கு அமர்த்துவதற்குப் பதிலாக, பிரதமர், மத்திய கிழக்கில் உள்ள தனது சகாக்களுடன் உடனடியாகப் பேசி, உலகின் முக்கிய 'தரமான எரிபொருள்' உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களிடம், இந்தியாவின் தொடர்ச்சியான மற்றும் சரியான நேரத்தில் உதவிகளை வழங்க வேண்டும். முறையாகக் கையாளப்பட்டால், நீண்ட கால கடன் மற்றும் நாட்டிற்கு மோசமாகத் தேவைப்படும் முதலீட்டுப் பொதிகள்.",
        "மே 13 அன்று ஆறாவது முறையாக பதவி ஏற்று நாட்டின் சிக்கலான சவால்களை ஏற்றுக்கொண்ட அனுபவம் வாய்ந்த பிரதமர், மத்திய கிழக்கு தலைவர்களை அழைத்து அவர்களின் உதவியை நாடுவதற்கு 40 நாட்கள் தேவையில்லை. .",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க அச்சு ஊடகங்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக, இலத்திரனியல் ஊடகங்களில் குறிப்பாக சியத மற்றும் அதன் 'டெலி-வாகிய', சிரச மற்றும் அதன் 'தவச' பிளஸ் 'நியூஸ்லைன்' மற்றும் அதா தெரண ஆகியவற்றின் தினசரி செய்தித் தொகுப்புகளை பார்க்க வேண்டும் என்று சொல்லத் தேவையில்லை. மக்கள் பார்வையில் இருந்து வரும் துன்பம் மற்றும் நாட்டில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு குடும்பத்திற்கும் உள்ள இருத்தலியல் வாழ்க்கையின் உடனடி சரிவு!",
        "அப்பாவி குடும்பங்களின் முன்னோடியில்லாத துன்பங்களுக்கு வெளிப்படையான காரணம், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயு விநியோகத்தை உடைக்காததை உறுதி செய்ய அரசாங்கம் தவறியதே ஆகும். மற்ற அனைத்து பிரச்சனைகளும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியைச் சுற்றியே! அரசியலமைப்பு மற்றும் அரசியல் பிரச்சனைகள் பின்னர் நெருக்கமாகப் பின்பற்றப்படுகின்றன. எரிபொருள் மற்றும் அதனால் ஏற்படும் உணவுப் பிரச்சினைகளைத் திறம்படச் சமாளிக்காவிட்டால், ஜனாதிபதி உட்பட இந்த அரசாங்கம் பிழைக்காமல் போகலாம்!",
        "2021 வரை, நாட்டின் அதிக அந்நியச் செலாவணி வருவாயில் 95% மத்திய கிழக்கில் பணிபுரியும் இலங்கையர்களிடமிருந்து வந்தது, ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் சராசரியாக $7 பில்லியன். தரமான எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயுவும் முக்கியமாக மத்திய கிழக்கில் இருந்து வருகின்றன. ஆனால் அடுத்தடுத்து வந்த அரசாங்கங்கள் மன்னிக்கமுடியாமல் இந்த நாடுகளுடன் நெருங்கிய நட்புறவை வைத்திருக்க தவறிவிட்டன!",
        "கேபினட்டில் ஒரு அறிவாளி, சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அகமது, தொழிலில் ஒரு பொறியியலாளர், சவுதி அரேபியாவின் கிங் ஃபஹத் பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் மினரல் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் கௌரவ பட்டதாரி ஆவார். பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் கனிம வளங்களுக்கு அர்ப்பணிக்கப்பட்ட இந்தப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் முன்னாள் மாணவர்கள் பெரும்பாலான வளைகுடா நாடுகளில் பெட்ரோலியத் துறையில் முக்கிய பதவிகளை வகிக்கின்றனர். விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்ற சில நாட்களிலேயே அரபு மொழி தெரிந்த ஒரேயொரு கேபினட் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட்டை ஏன் வளைகுடா நாடுகளுக்கு அனுப்பவில்லை?",
        "அவருக்கு குறைந்தபட்சம் ‘பெட்ரோலியம் சப்ளைஸ்’ போர்ட்ஃபோலியோ கொடுக்காமல், நசீர் அகமதுவுக்கு ‘சுற்றுச்சூழல்’ கொடுக்கப்பட்டது! மேலும் மோசமானது, வளைகுடா நாடுகளில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு டாலர்களை திரட்டுவதற்காக, விக்கிரமசிங்க தகாத முறையில் மாலத்தீவு அரசியல்வாதி நஷீத் அஹமட் ஒரு வெளிநாட்டவரை நியமித்து, மாலத்தீவு சபாநாயகராக பதவி வகித்து, இலங்கையை நெருங்க வேண்டிய நேரத்தில் எண்ணெய் உற்பத்தி செய்யும் நாடுகளில் இருந்து தன்னை விலக்கிக் கொண்டார். மற்றும் நேரடியாக!",
        "இலங்கையில் பல நண்பர்களைக் கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் நஷீத், மாலத்தீவு அதிபர் நஷீத் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் மாலத்தீவின் மூத்த குற்றவியல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி கைது செய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, இடைவிடாத பொதுப் போராட்டங்கள் காரணமாக, பிப்ரவரி 2012 இல் மாலத்தீவு அதிபர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார். மாலத்தீவு காவல்துறை மற்றும் ஆயுதப் படைகளால் தான் ராஜினாமா செய்ய நிர்ப்பந்திக்கப்பட்டதாக பின்னர் நஷீத் கூறினார்! இந்த கூற்றை காமன்வெல்த் ஆதரவு ஆணையம் விசாரித்தது, இது மாலத்தீவின் உயர்மட்ட நீதிபதியின் கைது மற்றும் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டதற்கு இடைவிடாத பொது எதிர்ப்புகளைத் தொடர்ந்து நஷீத் தானாக முன்வந்து ராஜினாமா செய்ததாகக் கூறியது. துப்பாக்கி முனையில் தான் ராஜினாமா செய்ய நிர்ப்பந்திக்கப்பட்டதாக நஷீத் கூறியதை ஆணையம் நிராகரித்தது!",
        "மேற்குலக சார்பு மாலத்தீவு சபாநாயகர் நஷீத் அஹமட், பி.எம். விக்ரமசிங்கவிடம் தனது செயற்பாட்டு அறிக்கையை வழங்காதது ஏன் என்ற கேள்வி, பின்னர் முரண்பட்ட அறிக்கையை இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.யிடம் கசியவிட்டாலும், சார்புக்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கும் வகையில் ப்ளூஸில் இருந்து எடுக்கப்பட்டது. -இலங்கையின் டொலர் நெருக்கடியைத் தணிக்க மத்திய கிழக்கு இலங்கை அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட், பதில்களை விட கேள்விகளால் நிரம்பியிருக்கிறார்!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வளைகுடா நாடுகள்",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெலி-வாகியா’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 7 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி அரேபியாவின் பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் கனிமங்களின் கிங் ஃபஹ்த் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரபு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரகு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கத்திய சார்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு இலங்கை சார்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}