{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83740/ghana-battles-highly-infectious-marburg-virus-as-outbreak-is-declared",
  "time_ut": 1658228280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ghana battles highly infectious Marburg virus as outbreak is declared",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ghana battles highly infectious Marburg virus as outbreak is declared",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two people in Ghana have died after they tested positive for a highly infectious disease, prompting global health officials to declare an outbreak.",
        "On Tuesday, the World Health Organisation declared the country’s first outbreak of the Marburg virus, a disease similar to Ebola.",
        "Earlier this month, two people died from the virus and the WHO has since confirmed the results of their tests.",
        "The first case was a 26-year-old male who checked into a hospital on June 26 and died on June 27.",
        "The second was a 51-year-old male who went to the hospital on June 28 and died the same day, WHO said, adding that both men sought treatment at the same hospital.",
        "Both men were from Ghana’s southern Ashanti region and were unrelated.",
        "Marburg virus comes from the same family as Ebola and is a very infectious hemorrhagic fever, spread by fruit bats.",
        "It is transmitted among people through direct contact with the bodily fluids of infected people and surfaces.",
        "There have been several major outbreaks of the virus since 1967, mainly in southern and eastern Africa, however, this is the second outbreak of Marburg in West Africa.",
        "The first case in West Africa was detected in Guinea last year and there were no further infections after that first case.",
        "Fatality rates have varied from 24 per cent to 88 per cent in past outbreaks depending on the virus strain and case management, according to the WHO.",
        "The WHO will support local and national health authorities in Ghana to help with disease surveillance, testing, contact tracing and educating communities.",
        "“Health authorities have responded swiftly, getting a head start preparing for a possible outbreak,” Dr Matshidiso Moeti, WHO Regional Director for Africa said in a statement.",
        "“This is good because, without immediate and decisive action, Marburg can easily get out of hand.",
        "“WHO is on the ground supporting health authorities and now that the outbreak is declared, we are marshalling more resources for the response.”",
        "There are now 90 contacts related to the two men who died, including health workers and community members, that are being monitored.",
        "The WHO said there are no vaccines or antiviral treatments that are approved to treat the Marburg virus.",
        "However, supportive care, like rehydration with oral or intravenous fluids and treatment for specific symptoms can improve the chance of survival."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ghana",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Marburg",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ghana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ghana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guinea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "88 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ghana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dr Matshidiso Moeti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පුපුරා යාම ප්‍රකාශයට පත් වන විට ඝානාව ඉතා බෝවන මාර්බර්ග් වෛරසය සමඟ සටන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඝානාවේ පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු අධික බෝවන රෝගයක් සඳහා ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කිරීමෙන් පසු මිය ගොස් ඇති අතර, එය පුපුරා යාමක් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ගෝලීය සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් පොළඹවා ඇත.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා, ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය ඉබෝලා රෝගයට සමාන රෝගයක් වන මාර්බර්ග් වෛරසය රටේ පළමු පුපුරා යාම ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය.",
        "මෙම මස මුලදී, වෛරසයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු මිය ගිය අතර WHO විසින් ඔවුන්ගේ පරීක්ෂණවල ප්‍රතිඵල තහවුරු කර ඇත.",
        "පළමු නඩුව ජුනි 26 වන දින රෝහලකට ගොස් ජුනි 27 වන දින මිය ගිය 26 හැවිරිදි පිරිමියෙකි.",
        "දෙවැන්නා ජූනි 28 වැනි දින රෝහලට ගොස් එදිනම මිය ගිය 51 හැවිරිදි පිරිමි අයෙකි, දෙදෙනාම එකම රෝහලකින් ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා ගත් බව ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය පවසයි.",
        "දෙදෙනාම ඝානාවේ දකුණු අශාන්ති ප්‍රදේශයෙන් පැමිණි අය වූ අතර ඔවුන් අතර සම්බන්ධයක් නැත.",
        "Marburg වයිරසය Ebola වැනි එකම පවුලෙන් පැමිණෙන අතර පලතුරු වවුලන් විසින් බෝවන ඉතා බෝවන රක්තපාත උණකි.",
        "ආසාදිත පුද්ගලයින්ගේ සහ මතුපිට ශරීර තරල සමඟ සෘජු සම්බන්ධතා හරහා මිනිසුන් අතර සම්ප්රේෂණය වේ.",
        "1967 සිට ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දකුණු සහ නැගෙනහිර අප්‍රිකාවේ වෛරසයේ ප්‍රධාන පිපිරීම් කිහිපයක් සිදුවී ඇත, කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙය බටහිර අප්‍රිකාවේ මාර්බර්ග් හි දෙවන පුපුරා යාමයි.",
        "බටහිර අප්‍රිකාවේ පළමු රෝගියා පසුගිය වසරේ ගිනියාවෙන් අනාවරණය වූ අතර එම පළමු සිද්ධියෙන් පසුව තවත් ආසාදන කිසිවක් නොතිබුණි.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයට අනුව, වෛරස් වික්‍රියාව සහ සිද්ධි කළමනාකරණය මත පදනම්ව පසුගිය පුපුරා යාමේදී මරණ අනුපාතය සියයට 24 සිට සියයට 88 දක්වා වෙනස් වී ඇත.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය ඝානාවේ ප්‍රාදේශීය සහ ජාතික සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන්ට රෝග නිරීක්ෂණ, පරීක්ෂණ, සම්බන්ධතා සොයා ගැනීම සහ ප්‍රජාවන් දැනුවත් කිරීම සඳහා සහාය වනු ඇත.",
        "අප්‍රිකාවේ WHO කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෛද්‍ය Matshidiso Moeti ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ “සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන් ඉක්මනින් ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වා ඇති අතර, ඇතිවිය හැකි පිපිරීමක් සඳහා සූදානම් වීමට පටන් ගැනීමයි.",
        "“මෙය හොඳයි, මන්ද, ක්ෂණික හා තීරණාත්මක ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයකින් තොරව, Marburg හට පහසුවෙන් අත නොතැබිය හැකිය.",
        "“WHO සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන්ට සහාය දෙන බිමේ සිටින අතර දැන් පුපුරා යාම ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති හෙයින්, අපි ප්‍රතිචාරය සඳහා තවත් සම්පත් එකතු කරන්නෙමු.”",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින් සහ ප්‍රජා සාමාජිකයින් ඇතුළුව මියගිය පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනාට සම්බන්ධ සම්බන්ධතා 90 ක් දැන් නිරීක්ෂණය වෙමින් පවතී.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය පවසන්නේ Marburg වෛරසයට ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම සඳහා අනුමත කරන ලද එන්නත් හෝ ප්‍රතිවෛරස් ප්‍රතිකාර නොමැති බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, වාචික හෝ අභ්‍යන්තර තරල සමඟ නැවත සජලනය කිරීම සහ විශේෂිත රෝග ලක්ෂණ සඳහා ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම වැනි ආධාරක සත්කාර පැවැත්මේ අවස්ථාව වැඩි දියුණු කළ හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඝානාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Marburg",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඝානාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඝානාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 24 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 88 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඝානාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය Matshidiso Moeti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெடிப்பு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதால் கானா மிகவும் தொற்றுநோயான மார்பர்க் வைரஸை எதிர்த்துப் போராடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கானாவில் இரண்டு பேர் அதிக தொற்று நோய்க்கு நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்த பின்னர் இறந்துள்ளனர், இது உலகளாவிய சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளை வெடித்ததாக அறிவிக்க தூண்டியது.",
        "செவ்வாயன்று, உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம் எபோலாவைப் போன்ற ஒரு நோயான மார்பர்க் வைரஸின் நாட்டின் முதல் வெடிப்பை அறிவித்தது.",
        "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில், இரண்டு பேர் வைரஸால் இறந்தனர் மற்றும் WHO அவர்களின் சோதனைகளின் முடிவுகளை உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "முதல் வழக்கு 26 வயதான ஆண், ஜூன் 26 அன்று ஒரு மருத்துவமனைக்குச் சென்று ஜூன் 27 அன்று இறந்தார்.",
        "இரண்டாவதாக 51 வயதான ஆண் ஒருவர் ஜூன் 28 அன்று மருத்துவமனைக்குச் சென்று அதே நாளில் இறந்தார், இருவரும் ஒரே மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்றதாக WHO கூறியது.",
        "இருவரும் கானாவின் தெற்கு அஷாந்தி பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் மற்றும் தொடர்பில்லாதவர்கள்.",
        "மார்பர்க் வைரஸ் எபோலாவின் அதே குடும்பத்தில் இருந்து வருகிறது மற்றும் பழம் வெளவால்களால் பரவும் மிகவும் தொற்றும் ரத்தக்கசிவு காய்ச்சலாகும்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மக்கள் மற்றும் மேற்பரப்புகளின் உடல் திரவங்களுடன் நேரடி தொடர்பு மூலம் இது மக்களிடையே பரவுகிறது.",
        "1967 ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து, முக்கியமாக தெற்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு ஆபிரிக்காவில் வைரஸ் பல பெரிய வெடிப்புகள் உள்ளன, இருப்பினும், இது மேற்கு ஆபிரிக்காவில் மார்பர்க்கில் இரண்டாவது வெடிப்பு ஆகும்.",
        "மேற்கு ஆபிரிக்காவில் முதல் வழக்கு கடந்த ஆண்டு கினியாவில் கண்டறியப்பட்டது மற்றும் அந்த முதல் வழக்குக்குப் பிறகு மேலும் நோய்த்தொற்றுகள் எதுவும் இல்லை.",
        "உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் கூற்றுப்படி, வைரஸ் திரிபு மற்றும் கேஸ் நிர்வாகத்தைப் பொறுத்து இறப்பு விகிதங்கள் கடந்தகால வெடிப்புகளில் 24 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 88 சதவீதமாக வேறுபடுகின்றன.",
        "கானாவில் உள்ள உள்ளூர் மற்றும் தேசிய சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளுக்கு WHO, நோய் கண்காணிப்பு, பரிசோதனை, தொடர்புத் தடமறிதல் மற்றும் சமூகங்களுக்குக் கல்வி அளிப்பது போன்றவற்றுக்கு உதவும்.",
        "\"சுகாதார அதிகாரிகள் விரைவாக பதிலளித்துள்ளனர், சாத்தியமான வெடிப்புக்கு தயாராகி வருகின்றனர்\" என்று ஆப்பிரிக்காவிற்கான WHO பிராந்திய இயக்குனர் டாக்டர் மட்ஷிடிசோ மொய்ட்டி ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இது நல்லது, ஏனென்றால், உடனடி மற்றும் தீர்க்கமான நடவடிக்கை இல்லாமல், மார்பர்க் எளிதில் கையை விட்டு வெளியேற முடியும்.",
        "\"WHO சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளை ஆதரிக்கும் நிலையில் உள்ளது, இப்போது வெடிப்பு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதால், பதிலுக்கான கூடுதல் ஆதாரங்களை நாங்கள் மார்ஷல் செய்கிறோம்.\"",
        "சுகாதாரப் பணியாளர்கள் மற்றும் சமூக உறுப்பினர்கள் உட்பட இறந்த இருவர் தொடர்பான 90 தொடர்புகள் இப்போது கண்காணிக்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.",
        "மார்பர்க் வைரஸுக்கு சிகிச்சையளிக்க அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட தடுப்பூசிகள் அல்லது வைரஸ் தடுப்பு சிகிச்சைகள் எதுவும் இல்லை என்று WHO கூறியது.",
        "இருப்பினும், வாய்வழி அல்லது நரம்புவழி திரவங்களுடன் மறுநீரேற்றம் மற்றும் குறிப்பிட்ட அறிகுறிகளுக்கான சிகிச்சை போன்ற ஆதரவான கவனிப்பு உயிர்வாழ்வதற்கான வாய்ப்பை மேம்படுத்தலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கானா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மார்பர்க்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்பர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்பர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்பர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஆப்ரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஆப்ரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கினியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "88 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டாக்டர் மாட்ஷிடிசோ மொய்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்பர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்பர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}