{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/විදුලි-බිලේ-විවාදය-අද/1-618900",
  "time_ut": 1661743041,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විදුලි බිලේ විවාදය අද",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Electricity bill debate today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The debate regarding the government's decision to increase the electricity bill will be held in Parliament today (29) when the House is adjourned.",
        "The Parliament is scheduled to meet today (29) at 9:30 in the morning under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.",
        "The proposal for the debate is presented by the People's Power Party.",
        "The speaker's office said that the debate will be held from 9:30 am to 4:30 pm.",
        "The government has already decided to increase the electricity bill by 70 percent. Various parties including political parties and mass organizations have already protested the government in this regard.",
        "Meanwhile, the second reading debate on the Budget Appropriation Bill is scheduled to be held tomorrow (30), tomorrow (31), next 1st and 2nd.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe will present the budget proposals (budget speech) tomorrow (30) morning.",
        "After the President presents the budget speech, Parliament will be adjourned until the following day (31). Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena recently presented the Budget Appropriation (Amendment) Bill for the next four months to the Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9:30 in the morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the People's Power Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9:30 am to 4:30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Budget Appropriation Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the following day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Budget Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදුලි බිලේ විවාදය අද",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීමට රජය ගෙන ඇති තීරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සභාව කල්තබන අවස්ථාවේ විවාදය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අද(29) පැවැත්වේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද(29) උදේ 9:30 ට රැස්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "විවාදය සඳහා යෝජනාව ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලබන්නේ සමග ජන බලවේගය පක්ෂය විසිනි.",
        "විවාදය උදේ 9.30 සිට පස්වරු 4:30 දක්වා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බව කතානායක කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "විදුලි බිල සියයට සියයට 70 කින් වැඩි කිරීමට රජය දැනටමත් තීරණය කර ඇත. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් දේශපාලන පක්ෂ, බහුජන සංවිධාන ඇතුළු විවිධ පාර්ශව දැනටමත් රජයට විරෝධය පළ කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර අයවැය විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත පිළිබඳ දෙවන වර කියවීමේ විවාදය හෙට (30) ,අනිද්දා(31) , ලබන 1 වෙනිදා සහ 2 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් අයවැය යෝජනා( අයවැය කතාව) ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලබන්නේ හෙට(30) පෙරවරුවේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා අයවැය කතාව ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඊට පසු දින(31) දක්වා කල් තැබෙනු ඇත. ඉදිරි මාස හතරේ රජය වියදම් සඳහා අයවැය විසර්ජන ( සංශෝධන)පනත් කෙටුම්පත අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පසුගියදා ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදේ 9:30 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා බලය පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9:30 සිට සවස 4:30 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයවැය විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීළඟ 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයවැය විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மின்சார மசோதா மீதான விவாதம் இன்று",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சாரக் கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான அரசாங்கத்தின் தீர்மானம் தொடர்பான விவாதம் இன்று (29) பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் போது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (29) காலை 9.30 மணிக்கு சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "விவாதத்துக்கான பிரேரணையை மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சி முன்வைக்கிறது.",
        "காலை 9.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4.30 மணி வரை விவாதம் நடைபெறும் என சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மின் கட்டணத்தை 70 சதவீதம் உயர்த்த அரசு ஏற்கனவே முடிவு செய்துள்ளது. இது தொடர்பாக அரசியல் கட்சிகள், வெகுஜன அமைப்புகள் உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு கட்சிகள் அரசுக்கு ஏற்கனவே எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "இதேவேளை, வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலம் மீதான இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு விவாதம் நாளை (30), நாளை (31), எதிர்வரும் 1ஆம் மற்றும் 2ஆம் திகதிகளில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாளை (30) காலை வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட முன்மொழிவுகளை (வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரை) சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையை சமர்ப்பித்த பின்னர், பாராளுமன்றம் நாளை மறுதினம் (31) வரை ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும். அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கான வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தை பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன அண்மையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9:30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 9:30 முதல் மாலை 4:30 மணி வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட் ஒதுக்கீட்டு மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 1 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட் ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}