{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83254/high-level-sri-lankan-australian-delegates-discuss-prevention-of-transnational-crimes",
  "time_ut": 1656156180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "High-level Sri Lankan, Australian delegates discuss prevention of transnational crimes",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "High-level Sri Lankan, Australian delegates discuss prevention of transnational crimes",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A delegation led by Australia’s Minister for Home Affairs Clare O’Neill met the Sri Lankan delegation headed by Defence Secretary General Kamal Gunaratne at the Defence Headquarters Complex at Sri Jayewardenepura, Kotte recently.",
        "The Defence Secretary warmly received the visiting delegation accompanied by Australian High Commissioner for Sri Lanka David Holly, on their arrival and a round table discussion commenced afterwards where matters relating to strengthening the existing bilateral ties between the two countries were taken up.",
        "The deepening of bilateral cooperation for prevention of transnational crime including human smuggling and maritime threats were among the concerned areas of the discussion over the round table.",
        "Visiting delegation also included Australian Border Force Commissioner Michael Outram APM, Commander of the Joint Agency Task Force Rear Admiral Justin Jones, Commander of Transnational Operations of Australian Federal Police Richard Chin, Ambassador and Assistant Secretary of People Smuggling and Human Trafficking Branch Lucienne Manton and Several Australian High Commission based officials including the Deputy HC Amanda Jewell.",
        "Chief of Defence Staff General Shavendra Silva, Army Commander Lieutenant General Vikum Liyanage, Navy Commander Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne, Air Force Commander Air Marshal Sudarshana Pathirana, Director General of Sri Lanka Coast Guard Rear Admiral Anura Ekanayake, Chief of National Intelligence Major General Ruwan Kulathunga (Retd), Director of State Intelligence Service Major General Suresh Salley and Military Liaison Officer of the Defence Ministry were also present representing the Sri Lankan side."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Australian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defence Headquarters Complex",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "David Holly",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian Border Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Outram APM",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Joint Agency Task Force Rear",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justin Jones",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Transnational Operations of Australian Federal Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Richard Chin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People Smuggling and Human Trafficking",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lucienne Manton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Several Australian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amanda Jewell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikum Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Marshal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudarshana Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard Rear",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Intelligence Major",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwan Kulathunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Intelligence Service Major",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suresh Salley",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉහළ මට්ටමේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු නියෝජිතයින් ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ වැළැක්වීම ගැන සාකච්ඡා කරති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය Clare O’Neill ප්‍රමුඛ දූත පිරිසක් ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් ජනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත පිරිස පසුගියදා කෝට්ටේ ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර ආරක්ෂක මූලස්ථාන සංකීර්ණයේදී හමුවිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් ඩේවිඩ් හොලි මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිස ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්වරයා විසින් ඉතා උණුසුම් ලෙස පිළිගත් අතර, දෙරට අතර පවතින ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට අදාළ කරුණු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරන ලද වටමේස සාකච්ඡාවකින් අනතුරුව වට මේස සාකච්ඡාවක් ද ආරම්භ විය.",
        "මිනිස් ජාවාරම් සහ සමුද්‍රීය තර්ජන ඇතුළු අන්තර්ජාතික අපරාධ වැළැක්වීම සඳහා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව ගැඹුරු කිරීම වටමේස සාකච්ඡාවේ අවධානයට ලක් වූ ක්ෂේත්‍ර අතර විය.",
        "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු දේශසීමා බලකා කොමසාරිස් මයිකල් අවුට්‍රම් ඒපීඑම්, ඒකාබද්ධ නියෝජිතායතන කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ අණදෙන නිලධාරී රියර් අද්මිරාල් ජස්ටින් ජෝන්ස්, ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු ෆෙඩරල් පොලිසියේ අන්තර්ජාතික මෙහෙයුම් අණදෙන නිලධාරී රිචඩ් චින්, තානාපති සහ සහකාර ලේකම් රිචඩ් චින් සහ මිනිස් ජාවාරම් සහ මිනිස් ජාවාරම් පිළිබඳ මැන්ටන් බ්‍රැන්ටන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ද සංචාරයට පැමිණි දූත පිරිසට ඇතුළත් විය. නියෝජ්‍ය HC Amanda Jewell ඇතුළු ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය පදනම් කරගත් නිලධාරීන්.",
        "ආරක්‍ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා, යුද හමුදාපති ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලියනගේ, නාවික හමුදාපති වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න, ගුවන් හමුදාපති එයාර් මාර්ෂල් සුදර්ශන පතිරණ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් රියර් අද්මිරාල් අනුර ඒකනායක, ජාතික බුද්ධි ප්‍රධානී කුලජ් ජෙනරාල් රුවන්ගුරු ජාතික බුද්ධි ප්‍රධානී. (විශ්‍රාමික), රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි සේවයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මේජර් ජෙනරාල් සුරේෂ් සාලි සහ ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ හමුදා සම්බන්ධීකරණ නිලධාරියා ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කරමින් පැමිණ සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මූලස්ථාන සංකීර්ණය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් හොලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු දේශසීමා බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් අවුට්‍රම් ඒපීඑම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒකාබද්ධ නියෝජිතායතන කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය පසුපස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජස්ටින් ජෝන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ෆෙඩරල් පොලිසියේ අන්තර් ජාතික මෙහෙයුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් චින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුද්ගල ජාවාරම් සහ මිනිස් ජාවාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුසීන් මැන්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස්වරු කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමන්දා ජුවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් මාර්ෂල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදර්ශන පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය පසුපස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික බුද්ධි අංශ මේජර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන් කුලතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය බුද්ධි සේවයේ මේජර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේෂ් සාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடுகடந்த குற்றங்களைத் தடுப்பது குறித்து இலங்கை, அவுஸ்திரேலிய உயர்மட்ட பிரதிநிதிகள் கலந்துரையாடுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள் அமைச்சர் கிளேர் ஓ நீல் தலைமையிலான குழுவொன்று அண்மையில் கோட்டே ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுரவில் உள்ள பாதுகாப்பு தலைமையக வளாகத்தில் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் நாயகம் கமல் குணரத்ன தலைமையிலான இலங்கைக் குழுவைச் சந்தித்தது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அவுஸ்திரேலிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் டேவிட் ஹோலியுடன் வருகை தந்திருந்த தூதுக்குழுவை பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் அன்புடன் வரவேற்றதுடன், இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையில் தற்போதுள்ள இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது தொடர்பான விடயங்கள் எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட வட்டமேசை கலந்துரையாடல் ஆரம்பமானது.",
        "மனித கடத்தல் மற்றும் கடல்சார் அச்சுறுத்தல்கள் உள்ளிட்ட நாடுகடந்த குற்றங்களை தடுப்பதற்கான இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை ஆழப்படுத்துவது ஆகியவை வட்டமேசையின் மீதான விவாதத்தின் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பகுதிகளாகும்.",
        "வருகை தந்த தூதுக்குழுவில் ஆஸ்திரேலிய எல்லைப் படை ஆணையர் மைக்கேல் அவுட்ராம் ஏபிஎம், கூட்டு ஏஜென்சி பணிப் படையின் தளபதி ரியர் அட்மிரல் ஜஸ்டின் ஜோன்ஸ், ஆஸ்திரேலிய ஃபெடரல் காவல்துறையின் நாடுகடந்த நடவடிக்கைகளின் தளபதி ரிச்சர்ட் சின், தூதுவர் மற்றும் ஆட்கடத்தல் மற்றும் மனித கடத்தல் மன்டன் மற்றும் மான்டன் பலரின் உதவிச் செயலர் ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர். துணை HC அமண்டா ஜூவல் உட்பட ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் சார்ந்த அதிகாரிகள்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா, இராணுவத் தளபதி லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் விக்கும் லியனகே, கடற்படைத் தளபதி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகேதென்ன, விமானப்படைத் தளபதி எயார் மார்ஷல் சுதர்சன பத்திரன, இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் ரியர் அட்மிரல் அனுர ஏக்கநாயக்க, குலாத் தேசிய புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் தலைவர் மலாஜ் தேசிய புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் பிரதம அதிதி. (ஓய்வு), அரச புலனாய்வு சேவையின் பணிப்பாளர் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் சுரேஷ் சாலி மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் இராணுவ இணைப்பு அதிகாரி ஆகியோரும் இலங்கை தரப்பை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தியிருந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு தலைமையக வளாகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் ஹோலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய எல்லைப் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் அவுட்ராம் ஏபிஎம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டு ஏஜென்சி பணிக்குழு பின்புறம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜஸ்டின் ஜோன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய ஃபெடரல் காவல்துறையின் நாடுகடந்த நடவடிக்கைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் சின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் கடத்தல் மற்றும் மனித கடத்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூசியன் மாண்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமண்டா ஜூவல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர் மார்ஷல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதர்சன பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை பின்புறம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய புலனாய்வு மேஜர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவன் குலதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில புலனாய்வு சேவை மேஜர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேஷ் சாலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}