{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/600-000MT-of-substandard-rice-imported-due-to-chemical-fertilizer-ban-Amaraweera/108-244135",
  "time_ut": 1662020179,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "600,000MT of substandard rice imported due to chemical fertilizer ban: Amaraweera",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "600,000MT of substandard rice imported due to chemical fertilizer ban: Amaraweera",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka has had to import nearly 600,000 metric tons of substandard and poisonous rice as a result of the failed decision to promote organic farming, Agricultural Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said today.",
        "He told Parliament that Sri Lanka has imported nearly 600,000 MT of rice from countries where harmful chemicals such as Monocrotophos and glyphosate, which were banned in Sri Lanka, are used for paddy cultivation.",
        "\"This imported rice is more harmful than rice grown in Sri Lanka. Chemicals such as Monocrotophos, glyphosate are not used for paddy cultivation in Sri Lanka. However, just because we wanted to promote organic farming based on impractical advice from certain parties, we have to import substandard and harmful rice from other countries to meet the shortfall of paddy harvest,\" he said.",
        "Responding to a question raised by parliamentarian Ven. Athuraliye Rathana, the Minister said those so called themselves experts and doctors who provided wrong and impractical advice on organic farming are silent today.",
        "He said the ban on chemical fertilizer was the main cause of the debacle the country is facing today. (Ajith Siriwardana and Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "600,000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Amaraweera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 600,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monocrotophos",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monocrotophos",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "parliamentarian Ven",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athuraliye Rathana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රසායනික පොහොර තහනම නිසා බාල සහල් මෙ.ටොන් 600,000ක් ආනයනය කළා: අමරවීර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කාබනික ගොවිතැන ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ අසාර්ථක තීරණය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රමිතියෙන් තොර සහ විෂ සහිත සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 600,000කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ආනයනය කිරීමට සිදුව ඇති බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තහනම් කර තිබූ මොනොක්‍රොටෝෆෝස්, ග්ලයිෆොසේට් වැනි අහිතකර රසායන ද්‍රව්‍ය වී වගාව සඳහා භාවිත කරන රටවලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් හයලක්ෂයකට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ආනයනය කර ඇති බව ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“මේ ආනයනික සහල් ලංකාවේ වගා කරන සහල්වලට වඩා හානිකරයි. ලංකාවේ වී වගාවට මොනොක්‍රොටෝෆෝස්, ග්ලයිෆොසේට් වැනි රසායනික ද්‍රව්‍ය භාවිත කරන්නේ නැහැ. නමුත් යම් යම් පාර්ශ්වයන්ගේ ප්‍රායෝගික උපදෙස් මත කාබනික ගොවිතැන ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය වූ නිසාම, වී අස්වැන්නේ හිඟය පියවා ගැනීම සඳහා වෙනත් රටවලින් බාල හා හානිකර සහල් ආනයනය කිරීමට\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත‍්‍රී පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියන් නැගූ ප‍්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු ලබාදෙමින්. කාබනික ගොවිතැන සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැරදි සහ ප්‍රායෝගික නොවන උපදෙස් ලබාදුන් ඊනියා විද්වතුන් සහ වෛද්‍යවරුන් අද නිහඬ බව අමාත්‍ය අතුරලියේ රතන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අද රට මුහුණ දී සිටින විනාශයට ප්‍රධානතම හේතුව රසායනික පොහොර තහනම බව ඔහු පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන සහ යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "600,000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අමරවීර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 600,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනොක්‍රොටෝෆොස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනොක්‍රොටෝෆොස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරලියේ රතන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரசாயன உர தடை காரணமாக 600,000MT தரமற்ற அரிசி இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது: அமரவீர",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இயற்கை விவசாயத்தை ஊக்குவிப்பதற்காக எடுக்கப்பட்ட தோல்வியின் விளைவாக, இலங்கையில் சுமார் 600,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் தரமற்ற மற்றும் நச்சு அரிசியை இறக்குமதி செய்ய வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தடை செய்யப்பட்ட மோனோகுரோடோபோஸ் மற்றும் கிளைபோசேட் போன்ற தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் இரசாயனங்கள் நெல் பயிர்ச்செய்கைக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படும் நாடுகளில் இருந்து இலங்கை கிட்டத்தட்ட 600,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசியை இறக்குமதி செய்துள்ளதாக அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையில் பயிரிடப்படும் அரிசியை விட இந்த இறக்குமதி அரிசி மிகவும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கக்கூடியது. இலங்கையில் நெல் சாகுபடிக்கு Monocrotophos, glyphosate போன்ற இரசாயனங்கள் பயன்படுத்தப்படுவதில்லை. எனினும், சில தரப்பினரின் நடைமுறைச் சாத்தியமற்ற ஆலோசனையின் அடிப்படையில் இயற்கை விவசாயத்தை ஊக்குவிக்க விரும்பினோம். நெல் அறுவடையின் பற்றாக்குறையை சமாளிக்க தரமற்ற மற்றும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் அரிசியை பிற நாடுகளில் இருந்து இறக்குமதி செய்ய வேண்டும்,\" என்றார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வணக்கம் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்தார். இயற்கை விவசாயம் தொடர்பில் தவறான மற்றும் நடைமுறைக்கு மாறான ஆலோசனைகளை வழங்கிய நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் வைத்தியர்கள் என அழைக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் இன்று மௌனமாக இருப்பதாக அமைச்சர் அத்துரலியே இரத்தின தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ரசாயன உரங்களுக்கு விதிக்கப்பட்ட தடையே இன்று நாடு எதிர்நோக்கும் அழிவுக்கு முக்கிய காரணம் என்றார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன மற்றும் யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "600,000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமரவீர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 600,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோனோகுரோட்டோபாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோனோகுரோட்டோபாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வண",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுரலியே ரத்தனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}