{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/31/motorcycle-murderers-strike-again-51-year-old-man-gunned-down-in-colombo-15/",
  "time_ut": 1659239760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Motorcycle murderers strike again: 51-year-old man gunned down in Colombo 15",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Motorcycle murderers strike again: 51-year-old man gunned down in Colombo 15",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Motorcycle gunmen have struck once again in Sri Lanka following the brutaly gunning down of 51-year-old man in Vivekananda Road, Colombo 15 on Saturday (30) night.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said that two men in full-faced helments on a motorcycle had opened fire at the victim while he was with several others.",
        "The motive for the shooting remains unknown and CCTV footage seen by News 1st showed one of the gunmen getting off the bike after firing three shots at the victim, and then walking towards his to fire a final round to finish the job.",
        "The Office of the Police Spokesperson said further investigations are underway.",
        "Since the 30th of May 2022, motorcycle murders have killed numerous people across the country especially in the Western and Southern provinces.",
        "The killings started with Bastian Mawatha, Colombo shooting when one person was killed and another was injured in a shooting near the Private Bus Terminal at Bastian Mawatha, Colombo. Another man was unharmed.",
        "The three men who were targeted had once served in the Commando Regiment of the Sri Lanka Army, and after leaving service they had joined a club in Cinnamon Gardens as bouncers.",
        "Since then muliple shootings had taken place and according to police reports, most of the targest were linked to criminal activity, including drug peddling.",
        "Reports also suggested that he was connected to notorious underworld criminal 'Kuu Kudu Kanna'.",
        "Motorcycle murderers strike again: 51-year-old man gunned down in Colombo 15",
        "Sri Lanka’s Economic Crisis: Did the Island-nation miss the warning signs?",
        "Protests and debates will not resolve the crisis – President",
        "Does the President seek to misuse idea of All-party Govt? – Ven. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Motorcycle",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "brutaly",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vivekananda Road",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Office of the Police Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 30th of May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bastian Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Private Bus Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bastian Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commando Regiment of the Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cinnamon Gardens",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuu Kudu Kanna'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Protests",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යතුරුපැදි මිනීමරුවන් යළිත් වැඩවර්ජනයක්: කොළඹ 15දී 51 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙක් වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සෙනසුරාදා (30) රාත්‍රියේ කොළඹ 15, විවේකානන්ද පාරේදී 51 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකුට අමානුෂික ලෙස වෙඩි තබා මරා දැමීමෙන් පසු යතුරුපැදි තුවක්කුකරුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නැවත වරක් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර තිබේ.",
        "තුවාල ලැබූ පුද්ගලයා තවත් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සමඟ සිටියදී යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි ෆුල්ෆේස් හිස්වැසුම් පැළඳ සිටි පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු ඔහුට වෙඩි තබා ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීමේ චේතනාව තවමත් නොදන්නා අතර News 1st විසින් දැක ඇති CCTV දර්ශනවල දැක්වෙන්නේ එක් තුවක්කුකරුවෙකු වින්දිතයාට වෙඩි තුනක් එල්ල කිරීමෙන් පසු බයිසිකලයෙන් බැස අවසන් වටයක් වෙඩි තැබීමට ඔහු දෙසට ගමන් කරන ආකාරයයි.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන ක්‍රියාත්මක බවයි.",
        "2022 මැයි 30 වැනිදා සිට රටපුරා විශේෂයෙන්ම බස්නාහිර සහ දකුණු පළාත්වල යතුරුපැදි ඝාතනවලින් විශාල පිරිසක් මිය ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මෙම ඝාතන ආරම්භ වූයේ කොළඹ බැස්ටියන් මාවතේ පෞද්ගලික බස් නැවතුම්පොළ අසල සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් එක් අයෙකු මිය ගොස් තවත් අයෙකු තුවාල ලැබීමත් සමඟ කොළඹ බැස්ටියන් මාවතට වෙඩි තැබීමත් සමඟයි. තවත් පුද්ගලයෙකුට හානියක් සිදු නොවීය.",
        "ප්‍රහාරයට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනා වරක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාවේ කමාන්ඩෝ රෙජිමේන්තුවේ සේවය කර ඇති අතර, සේවයෙන් ඉවත්වීමෙන් පසු ඔවුන් කුරුඳුවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ බවුන්සර් ක්‍රීඩා සමාජයකට සම්බන්ධ වී ඇත.",
        "එතැන් සිට බහුවිධ වෙඩි තැබීම් සිදුවී ඇති අතර, පොලිස් වාර්තාවලට අනුව, ඉලක්කවලින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම ඇතුළු අපරාධ ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට සම්බන්ධ ඒවා විය.",
        "ඔහු කුප්‍රකට පාතාල අපරාධකරුවෙකු වන 'කූ කුඩු කන්න'ට සම්බන්ධ බවට ද වාර්තා පළ විය.",
        "යතුරුපැදි මිනීමරුවන් යළිත් වැඩවර්ජනයක්: කොළඹ 15දී 51 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙක් වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය: දිවයිනේ ජාතියට අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ සංඥා මග හැරී ගියේද?",
        "විරෝධතා සහ වාද විවාදවලින් අර්බුදය විසඳෙන්නේ නැහැ - ජනපති",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව පිළිබඳ අදහස අවභාවිත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරනවාද? – හාමුදුරුවනේ. ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51 හැවිරිදිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යතුරුපැදිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෲර ලෙස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විවේකානන්ද පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 30 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික බස් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාවේ කමාන්ඩෝ රෙජිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුකුඩු කන්නා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරෝධතා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் கொலைகாரர்கள் மீண்டும் வேலைநிறுத்தம்: கொழும்பு 15 இல் 51 வயது நபர் துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பு 15, விவேகானந்தா வீதியில் சனிக்கிழமை (30) இரவு 51 வயதுடைய நபர் கொடூரமான முறையில் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் துப்பாக்கிதாரிகள் இலங்கையில் மீண்டும் ஒருமுறை தாக்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர் மேலும் பலருடன் இருந்த வேளையில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இருவர் முழு முகத் தலைக்கவசம் அணிந்து அவர் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதாக இலங்கை காவல்துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதற்கான நோக்கம் தெரியவில்லை மற்றும் நியூஸ் 1ஸ்ட் பார்த்த சிசிடிவி காட்சிகளில், துப்பாக்கி ஏந்தியவர்களில் ஒருவர் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரை மூன்று முறை துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்ட பிறகு பைக்கை விட்டு இறங்கி, இறுதிச் சுற்றில் சுடுவதற்காக அவரை நோக்கி நடந்து செல்வதைக் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "மேலதிக விசாரணைகள் இடம்பெற்று வருவதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மே 30, 2022 முதல், மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் கொலைகள் நாடு முழுவதும் குறிப்பாக மேற்கு மற்றும் தெற்கு மாகாணங்களில் ஏராளமான மக்களைக் கொன்றுள்ளன.",
        "கொழும்பு பஸ்டியன் மாவத்தையில் தனியார் பஸ் நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் கொல்லப்பட்டதுடன் மற்றுமொருவர் காயமடைந்த நிலையில் கொழும்பு பஸ்டியன் மாவத்தையில் துப்பாக்கிச்சூடு ஆரம்பமானது. மற்றொருவர் காயமின்றி இருந்தார்.",
        "குறிவைக்கப்பட்ட மூவரும் இலங்கை இராணுவத்தின் கொமாண்டோ படைப்பிரிவில் ஒருமுறை பணியாற்றியவர்கள், சேவையை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பின்னர் அவர்கள் கறுவாத்தோட்டத்தில் உள்ள கிளப் ஒன்றில் பவுன்சர்களாக சேர்ந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அப்போதிருந்து, பல துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சம்பவங்கள் நடந்தன மற்றும் பொலிஸ் அறிக்கைகளின்படி, பெரும்பாலான இலக்குகள் போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தல் உட்பட குற்றச் செயல்களுடன் தொடர்புடையவை.",
        "அவர் பிரபல பாதாள உலகக் குற்றவாளியான 'கு குடு கண்ணா'வுடன் தொடர்புடையவர் என்றும் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் கொலைகாரர்கள் மீண்டும் வேலைநிறுத்தம்: கொழும்பு 15 இல் 51 வயது நபர் துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி: எச்சரிக்கை அறிகுறிகளை தீவு நாடு தவறவிட்டதா?",
        "போராட்டங்கள் மற்றும் விவாதங்கள் நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்காது - ஜனாதிபதி",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் யோசனையை ஜனாதிபதி தவறாக பயன்படுத்த முற்படுகிறாரா? – வண. ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடூரமான",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவேகானந்தா சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவல்துறை செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 30, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் பேருந்து முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவத்தின் கொமாண்டோ படைப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலவங்கப்பட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கு குடு கண்ணா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்புகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}