{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අරගලකරුවෝ-සටන-අත්-නොහරිති/1-616753",
  "time_ut": 1658314605,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අරගලකරුවෝ සටන අත් නොහරිති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The fighters do not give up the fight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Galle Mouth activists say that the appointment of Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe to the office of President is against the public opinion and they will continue the struggle to remove him from office.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who was defeated by the people of the country and came to parliament from the national list, cannot be accepted as the president, said Mr. Wasantha Mudalige, convener of the inter-university student body, representing the Galle Mudoora strugglers.",
        "He said this while attending a press conference held today at Gota Go Village, Aragal Bhoomi.",
        "Mr. Mudalige stated that it was the people who made Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, who got 69 lakh votes, flee to the Maldives by jet, and that the struggle cannot be ended by being beaten and chased away or arrested.",
        "Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa appointed Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe as the Prime Minister to protect his family and fraud, Mr. Mudalige said that he is a person who did nothing for the people after being the Prime Minister for 6 times, looted the central bank, and was unable to enter the Parliament through a vote, and said that Mr. Mudalige will continue the struggle to oust him. . He said that the people's opinion is not represented in the parliament, and if they go outside the action plan given by the activists, the government can see what happens in the next two or three weeks.",
        "Sugathananda Thero of Tampitiya, Father Jeevantha Peiris, lawyer Nuwan Bopage, Lahiru Weerasekera, actor Jagath Manuvarna, Dumindu Hettiarachchi and others participated in this press conference representing the strugglers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Mudoora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gota Go Village",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragal Bhoomi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two or three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sugathananda Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeevantha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jagath Manuvarna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dumindu Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලකරුවෝ සටන අත් නොහරිති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිධූරයට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කරගැනීම මහජන මතයට විරුද්ධ බවත්, ඔහු ධූරයෙන් ඉවත්කිරීම සඳහා අරගලය අඛණ්ඩව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යන බවත් ගාලු මුවදොර අරගලකරුවෝ පවසති.",
        "රටේ ජනතාව විසින් පරාජය කර ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පිළිගැනීමට නොහැකි බව ගාලු මුවදොර අරගලකරුවන් නියෝජනය කරමින් අන්තර් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයීය ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු, වසන්ත මුදලිගේ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව පැවසුවේ ගාලුමුව‍දොර ගෝඨා ගෝ ගම අරගලභූමියේ දී අද පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමිනි.",
        "ලක්‍ෂ 69ක් ඡන්ද ගත් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා ජෙට් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පැන යන තත්වයට තරමට පත්කළේ මහජනතාව බවත්, පහරදී පන්නා දමා හෝ අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් මගින් අරගලය අවසන් කළ නොහැකි බවත් මුදලිගේ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගමැති ධූරයට පත්කළේ තමන්ගේ පවුල, හොරවැඩ ආරක්‍ෂා කරගැනීමට බවත්, ඔහු අවස්ථා 6ක් අගමැති වී ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් කිසිත් නොකළ, මහබැංකුව කොල්ල කෑ, ඡන්දයකින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට එන්නට නොහැකි වූ අයකු බවත් කී මුදලිගේ මහතා අරගලය ඔහු එලවීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව ඉදිරියට ගෙනයන බවත් පැවසීය. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ජනතා මතය නියෝජනය නොවන බවත්, අරගලකරුවන් විසින් ලබාදුන් ක්‍රියාකාරී සැලැස්මට පිටින් ගියොත් ඉදිරි සති දෙක තුන තුළ ආණ්ඩුවට වන දේ බලාගත හැකි බවත් ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "අරගලකරුවන් නියෝජනය කරමින් ටැම්පිටියේ සුගතානන්ද හිමියන්, ජීවන්ත පීරිස් පියතුමා, නීතීඥ නුවන් බෝපගේ, ළහිරු වීරසේකර, රංගන ශිල්පී ජගත් මනුවර්ණ, දුමිඳු හෙට්ටිආරච්චි ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම මාධ්‍ය හමුවට සහභාගී වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල මුදූර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝටා ගෝ ගම්මානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගල් භූමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුගතානන්ද හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්ත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජගත් මනුවර්ණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමිඳු හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராளிகள் போராட்டத்தை கைவிடுவதில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு நியமித்தமை மக்களின் கருத்துக்கு எதிரானது எனவும், அவரை பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்கும் போராட்டத்தை தொடர்ந்தும் முன்னெடுக்கவுள்ளதாக காலி மவுத் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்களால் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்டு தேசியப்பட்டியலில் இருந்து பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாது என காலி மூதூரை போராட்டக்காரர்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் அமைப்பின் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார். .",
        "ஆறகல் பூமி கோட்டகோ கிராமத்தில் இன்று நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "69 இலட்சம் வாக்குகளைப் பெற்ற திரு.கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவை ஜெட் விமானம் மூலம் மாலைதீவுக்குத் தப்பிச் செல்லச் செய்தவர்கள் மக்களே என்றும், அடித்து விரட்டியோ அல்லது கைது செய்வதன் மூலமோ போராட்டத்தை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டு வர முடியாது எனவும் திரு.முதலிகே குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக நியமித்த கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தனது குடும்பத்தையும், மோசடிகளையும் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக, 6 தடவைகள் பிரதமராக இருந்தும், மத்திய வங்கியை கொள்ளையடித்து மக்களுக்கு எதுவும் செய்யாதவர் என முதலிகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார். வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் பிரவேசிக்க முடியவில்லை, மேலும் அவரை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்வதற்கான போராட்டத்தை திரு. முதலிகே தொடருவார் என்றும் கூறினார். மக்கள் கருத்துக்கு நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவம் இல்லை என்றும், செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கொடுக்கும் செயல்திட்டத்திற்கு புறம்பாக சென்றால் இன்னும் இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று வாரங்களில் என்ன நடக்கும் என்பதை அரசு பார்க்கலாம் என்றார்.",
        "இந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தம்பிட்டிய சுகதானந்த தேரர், தந்தை ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ், சட்டத்தரணி நுவான் போபகே, லஹிரு வீரசேகர, நடிகர் ஜகத் மனுவர்ண, துமிந்து ஹெட்டியாராச்சி உள்ளிட்டோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முதூரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோதா கோ கிராமம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகல் பூமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகதானந்த தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜகத் மனுவர்ணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்து ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}