{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/උයන්වත්ත-වැවේ-මළ-සිරුරක්/1-619256",
  "time_ut": 1662272294,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "උයන්වත්ත වැවේ මළ සිරුරක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A dead body in the garden pond",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bandaragama Police say that the dead body of the missing person who fell into the Uyanwatta Lake in Bandaragama was found yesterday (4) while floating in the Rajagama Ferry area of ​​the Uyanwatta Lake.",
        "The dead body was found during investigations after a group of youths who came to bathe in Uyan Vattha lake saw a pair of dress shoes and an empty liquor bottle of a man and informed the police.",
        "The police suspect that the man may have drowned after drinking alcohol",
        "Horana Coroner Mr. Sumedha Gunawardena came to the place where the body was and conducted preliminary investigations",
        "Panadura division crime lab officials also came and conducted investigations",
        "After identifying the identity of the deceased, the coroner ordered the body to be deposited at the Horana Base Hospital for post-mortem examination."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bandaragama Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Uyanwatta Lake in Bandaragama",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagama Ferry",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​the Uyanwatta Lake",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uyan Vattha",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Horana Coroner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumedha Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Horana Base Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "උයන්වත්ත වැවේ මළ සිරුරක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බණ්ඩාරගම උයන් වත්ත වැවට වැටී අතුරුදන් පුද්ගලයාගේ මළ සිරුර උයන්වත්ත වැවේ රාජගම තොටුපොළ ප්‍රදේශයේ පාවෙමින් තිබියදී ඊයේ (4) හමුවූ බව බණ්ඩාරගම පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "උයන් වත්ත වැවේ දිය නෑමට පැමිණි තරුණයන් පිරිසක් විසින් පිරිමි පුද්ගලයකු ගේ ඇඳුම් පැළඳුම් පාවහන් යුගලක් සහ හිස් මත්පැන් බෝතලයක් දැක පොලිසියට දැනුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව සිදු කළ විමර්ශන වලදී මෙම මළ සිරුර හමුවී ඇත",
        "මෙම පුද්ගලයා මත්පැන් පානය කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව දියනෑමට ගොස් දියේ ගිලෙන්නට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය සැක කරයි",
        "සිරුර තිබෙන ස්ථානයට හොරණ හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂක සුමේධ ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැමිණ මූලික විමර්ශන සිදු කළේය",
        "පාණදුර කොට්ඨාස අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණාගාර නිලධාරීන් ද පැමිණ පරීක්ෂණ සිදු කළේය",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා කාගේ කවුදැයි හඳුනා ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය පැවැත්වීම සඳහා මෘත ශරීරය හොරණ මූලික රෝහලේ තැන්පත් කරන ලෙස හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂකවරයා නියෝග කළේය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරගම උයන්වත්ත වැව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජගම තොටුපළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උයන්වත්ත වැව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උයන් වත්ත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හොරණ හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේධා ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හොරණ මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தோட்டக் குளத்தில் ஒரு சடலம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பண்டாரகம, உயன்வத்த ஏரியில் விழுந்து காணாமல் போனவரின் சடலம் உயன்வத்தை ஏரியின் ராஜாகம படகுப் பகுதியில் மிதந்து கொண்டிருந்த போது நேற்று (4) கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டதாக பண்டாரகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயன் வத்த ஏரியில் குளிக்க வந்த இளைஞர்கள் குழுவொன்று ஆண் ஒருவரின் ஜோடி ஆடை காலணிகள் மற்றும் காலி மதுபான போத்தலைக் கண்டு பொலிஸாருக்கு அறிவித்ததையடுத்து விசாரணைகளின் போது சடலம் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குறித்த நபர் மது அருந்திவிட்டு நீரில் மூழ்கி உயிரிழந்திருக்கலாம் என பொலிஸார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்",
        "ஹொரணை மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி திரு.சுமேத குணவர்தன சடலம் இருந்த இடத்திற்கு வந்து முதற்கட்ட விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டார்.",
        "பாணந்துறை குற்றவியல் ஆய்வக அதிகாரிகளும் வந்து விசாரணை நடத்தினர்",
        "உயிரிழந்தவரின் அடையாளத்தை அடையாளம் கண்ட மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி சடலத்தை பிரேத பரிசோதனைக்காக ஹொரணை ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் வைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரகம காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரகம உயன்வத்த குளம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜாகம படகு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயன்வத்த ஏரி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயன் வத்த",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹொரண மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேதா குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹொரண ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}