{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Urgent-medicinal-supplies-from-US-to-the-people-of-Sri-Lanka/56-737776",
  "time_ut": 1658445789,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Urgent medicinal supplies from US to the people of Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Urgent medicinal supplies from US to the people of Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Washington, D.C. and Heart to Heart International United States",
        "Consequent to the request of the Embassy of Sri Lanka in Washington, D.C., and under the guidance of Ambassador Mahinda Samarasinghe, Heart to Heart International, a renowned global humanitarian organisation in the United States made a generous in-kind donation of urgent medicinal supplies worth $ 908,547 (i.e., Rs. 326,077,518.30) to the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "In coordination with the Ministry of Health and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Sri Lanka, this first consignment of medicinal supplies, at the expense of Heart to Heart International, reached Colombo via air on 13 July 2022. The Ministry of Health will receive the consignment for immediate distribution at no cost to the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "At a time that international aid and medicinal supplies are imperative for the island nation, the people of Sri Lanka and this Embassy express our sincere appreciation and gratitude to Heart to Heart International in their continuous efforts and commitment to assist Sri Lanka.",
        "Headquartered in Lenexa, Kansas, Heart to Heart International (HHI) is a global humanitarian organisation focused on improving access to health. Since its inception in 1992, HHI has delivered medical aid and supplies worth $ 2.4 billion to more than 130 countries, including within the United States.",
        "HHI responds to natural disasters both domestically and internationally by supplying medical relief and mobilising volunteers. The organisation is a 4-star Charity Navigator charity, a BBB Accredited charity and is on the “Philanthropy 400”.",
        "Heart to Heart International hopes to provide more humanitarian assistance to the Government of Sri Lanka to ensure that the best care is provided to its people. This Embassy and Heart to Heart International shall continue to work in collaboration with the Ministry of Health to procure further medicinal consignments to Sri Lanka in the coming months."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.C.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Embassy of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.C.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "908,547",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Embassy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lenexa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kansas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 2.4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBB Accredited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට එක්සත් ජනපදයෙන් හදිසි ඖෂධ සැපයුම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වොෂින්ටන්, ඩී.සී සහ හාට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් එක්සත් ජනපදය",
        "Washington, D.C. හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි සහ තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ මහතාගේ මඟපෙන්වීම මත ඇමරිකාවේ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ගෝලීය මානුෂීය සංවිධානයක් වන Heart to Heart International වෙත වටිනා හදිසි ඖෂධ ද්‍රව්‍ය නොමසුරුව පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලදී. ඩොලර් 908,547 (එනම් රු. 326,077,518.30) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණයෙන්, හාට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් හි වියදමින් මෙම ප්‍රථම ඖෂධ සැපයුම් තොගය 2022 ජූලි 13 වැනි දින ගුවනින් කොළඹට ළඟා විය. සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයට තොගය ලැබෙනු ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට කිසිදු වියදමකින් තොරව වහාම බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර ආධාර සහ ඖෂධීය සැපයුම් දිවයින ජාතියට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන මොහොතක, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසී ජනතාව සහ මෙම තානාපති කාර්යාලය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට දරන අඛණ්ඩ උත්සාහය සහ කැපවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් Heart to Heart International වෙත අපගේ අවංක කෘතඥතාව සහ කෘතඥතාව පළකරමු.",
        "Heart to Heart International (HHI) යනු කන්සාස් හි ලෙනෙක්සා හි මූලස්ථානය, සෞඛ්‍යයට ප්‍රවේශය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන ගෝලීය මානුෂීය සංවිධානයකි. 1992 හි ආරම්භයේ සිට, HHI විසින් එක්සත් ජනපදය ඇතුළුව රටවල් 130 කට වැඩි ගණනකට ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.4 ක් වටිනා වෛද්‍ය ආධාර සහ සැපයුම් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "දේශීය හා ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් ස්වභාවික විපත්වලට HHI ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වන්නේ වෛද්‍ය සහන සැපයීමෙන් සහ ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන් බලමුලු ගැන්වීමෙනි. සංවිධානය තරු 4 පුණ්‍යායතන Navigator පුණ්‍යායතනයක් වන අතර, BBB ප්‍රතීතනය ලත් පුණ්‍යායතනයක් වන අතර එය \"Philanthropy 400\" හි ඇත.",
        "හාර්ට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් ආයතනය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට වඩාත් මානුෂීය ආධාර සැපයීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන්නේ එහි ජනතාවට හොඳම රැකවරණය සැලසීම සහතික කිරීමයි. මෙම තානාපති කාර්යාලය සහ හාට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් ආයතනය සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් ඉදිරි මාසවලදී තවදුරටත් ඖෂධ තොග ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා ගැනීමට අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.සී.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.සී.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "908,547 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෙනෙක්සා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැන්සාස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "130 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBB ප්‍රතීතනය කර ඇත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு அமெரிக்காவிலிருந்து அவசர மருத்துவப் பொருட்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை வாஷிங்டன், டி.சி மற்றும் ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் யுனைடெட் ஸ்டேட்ஸ்",
        "வாஷிங்டனில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகத்தின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க, தூதுவர் மஹிந்த சமரசிங்கவின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் பேரில், அமெரிக்காவின் புகழ்பெற்ற உலகளாவிய மனிதாபிமான அமைப்பான ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல், பெறுமதியான அவசர மருந்துப் பொருட்களை தாராளமாக நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியது. $ 908,547 (அதாவது, ரூ. 326,077,518.30) இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு.",
        "இலங்கையில் சுகாதார அமைச்சு மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் ஒருங்கிணைப்புடன், ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் செலவில், இந்த முதல் மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் 2022 ஜூலை 13 அன்று விமானம் மூலம் கொழும்பை அடைந்தது. சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் சரக்குகளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும். இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எவ்வித கட்டணமும் இன்றி உடனடி விநியோகத்திற்காக.",
        "தீவு தேசத்திற்கு சர்வதேச உதவி மற்றும் மருந்து பொருட்கள் இன்றியமையாததாக இருக்கும் இந்த நேரத்தில், இலங்கை மக்களும் இந்த தூதரகமும் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதற்கான அவர்களின் தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கு ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் நிறுவனத்திற்கு எங்களது மனமார்ந்த பாராட்டுகளையும் நன்றியையும் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறது.",
        "ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் (HHI) என்பது லெனெக்சா, கன்சாஸில் தலைமையிடமாக உள்ளது, இது ஆரோக்கியத்திற்கான அணுகலை மேம்படுத்துவதில் கவனம் செலுத்தும் ஒரு உலகளாவிய மனிதாபிமான அமைப்பாகும். 1992 இல் தொடங்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து, HHI, அமெரிக்கா உட்பட 130க்கும் மேற்பட்ட நாடுகளுக்கு $2.4 பில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள மருத்துவ உதவி மற்றும் பொருட்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "HHI மருத்துவ நிவாரணம் மற்றும் தன்னார்வலர்களை அணிதிரட்டுவதன் மூலம் உள்நாட்டிலும் சர்வதேச அளவிலும் இயற்கை பேரழிவுகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கிறது. இந்த அமைப்பு 4-நட்சத்திர தொண்டு நேவிகேட்டர் தொண்டு நிறுவனம், BBB அங்கீகாரம் பெற்ற தொண்டு மற்றும் \"பரோபகாரம் 400\" இல் உள்ளது.",
        "ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் தனது மக்களுக்கு சிறந்த பராமரிப்பு வழங்கப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு மேலும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை வழங்க நம்புகிறது. இந்த தூதரகம் மற்றும் ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஆகியவை, எதிர்வரும் மாதங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு மேலதிக மருந்துப் பொருட்களை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு சுகாதார அமைச்சுடன் இணைந்து தொடர்ந்து பணியாற்றும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.சி.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.சி.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "908,547",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூதரகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லெனெக்சா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 2.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "130க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBB அங்கீகாரம் பெற்றது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}