{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130717",
  "time_ut": 1656866559,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யாழில் டீசலை பதுக்கி வைத்து அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்த ஒருவர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A man was arrested for hoarding diesel and selling it at a high price in Yali",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Jaffna. Thellipappa police have arrested a man who was selling diesel at a high price by storing it in a measuring stick.",
        "Based on the information received by the police that diesel was being stored and sold in a shop in the area under the Tellipapa police division, the police conducted raids.",
        "During this, 291 liters of diesel and equipment used for sale were seized by the police and the police also arrested the 42-year-old shop owner on the charge of hoarding the diesel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yali",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thellipappa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tellipapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "291",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාලි ප්‍රදේශයේ ඩීසල් ගොඩගසා වැඩි මිලට අලෙවි කළ පුද්ගලයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය. ඩීසල් මිණුම් දණ්ඩක ගබඩා කර අධික මිලකට අලෙවි කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු තෙල්ලිපාප්පා පොලීසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "තෙලිපාපා පොලිස් වසමට අයත් ප්‍රදේශයේ වෙළඳසැලක ඩීසල් ගබඩා කර අලෙවි කරන බවට පොලිසියට ලැබුණු තොරතුරක් මත පොලිසිය වැටලීම් සිදු කළා.",
        "මේ අතරතුර ඩීසල් ලීටර් 291ක් සහ අලෙවි කිරීමට යොදාගත් උපකරණ පොලිස් භාරයට ගෙන ඇති අතර ඩීසල් ගබඩා කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත 42 හැවිරිදි වෙළෙඳසැල් හිමියාද ​​පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යාලි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙල්ලිපප්පා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙලිපපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "291",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழில் டீசலை பதுக்கி வைத்து அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்த ஒருவர் கைது",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ். அளவெட்டியில் டீசலை பதுக்கி வைத்திருந்து அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனை செய்த ஒருவரை நேற்று மாலை தெல்லிப்பழை பொலிசார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தெல்லிப்பழை பொலிஸ் பிரிவிற்குட்பட்ட அளவெட்டி பகுதியில் உள்ள கடை ஒன்றில் டீசலை பதுக்கி வைத்து விற்பனை செய்வதாக பொலிசாருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் பொலிசார் சோதனை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "இதன்போது 291 லீற்றர் டீசல் மற்றும் விற்பனைக்கு பயன்படுத்திய உபகரணங்கள் என்பன பொலிசாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டதோடு டீசலை பதுக்கி வைத்திருந்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் 42 வயதுடைய கடை உரிமையாளரையும் பொலிசார் கைது செய்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யாளி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெல்லிபாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெல்லிபாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "291",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}