{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-debt-advisors-looking-at-local-debt-president-98230/",
  "time_ut": 1659674880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka debt advisors looking at local debt: President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka debt advisors looking at local debt: President",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s debt advisors are looking at local debt as a re-structuring plan to negotiate with creditors is being developed as part of efforts to make the debt sustainable, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said.",
        "He said agreement has to be reached with official creditors to go to the London Club (of private creditors).",
        "“Second, and the more important issue is have you got to look at the local debt?,” President Wickremesinghe told an economic forum organized by Advocata Institute, a Colombo-based think tank.",
        "“Certainly it will have far reaching consequences. Lazard, the financial advisors are looking at both.”",
        "Central Bank Governor Nandalal Weerasinghe has said that the government’s position on debt restructuring is as declared in April 2022, where there is no re-structuring of rupee debt.",
        "Local debt has already been hit by a real hair cut with the steep currency depreciation and inflation.",
        "When the currency collapses and inflation go up, revenues eventually inflate over time making it easier to service them.",
        "Most local debt is sold at low rates to the Employment Provident Fund of private sector workers. Others are held at banks.",
        "If local debt is re-structured, it will be even more difficult for the government to fund the deficit. (Colombo/Aug05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the London Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocata Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lazard",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Employment Provident Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය උපදේශකයන් දේශීය ණය දෙස බලයි: ජනපති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ණය තිරසාර කිරීමට දරන ප්‍රයත්නයේ කොටසක් ලෙස ණයහිමියන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සැලැස්මක් සකස් වෙමින් පවතින බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය උපදේශකයින් දේශීය ණය දෙස බලා සිටින බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලන්ඩන් ක්ලබ් (පෞද්ගලික ණය හිමියන්ගේ) වෙත යාමට නිල ණය හිමියන් සමඟ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණිය යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"දෙවනුව සහ වඩාත් වැදගත් ප්‍රශ්නය වන්නේ ඔබ දේශීය ණය ගැන සොයාබැලීමද?\" ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කොළඹ පදනම් වූ චින්තන ටැංකියක් වන Advocata ආයතනය විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද ආර්ථික සංසදයකට පැවසීය.",
        "“නිසැකවම එය දුරදිග යන ප්‍රතිවිපාක ඇති කරයි. ලාසාර්ඩ්, මූල්‍ය උපදේශකයෝ දෙකම බලනවා.”",
        "මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසා ඇත්තේ රුපියලේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමක් සිදු නොවන 2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ ස්ථාවරය ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි බවයි.",
        "දැඩි මුදල් අවප්‍රමාණය සහ උද්ධමනය සමඟ සැබෑ හිසකෙස් කැපීමකින් දේශීය ණය දැනටමත් පහර දී ඇත.",
        "මුදල් ඒකකය කඩා වැටෙන විට සහ උද්ධමනය ඉහළ යන විට, ආදායම අවසානයේ දී ඔවුන් සේවය කිරීම පහසු කරයි.",
        "බොහෝ දේශීය ණය අඩු මිලට පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ සේවකයන්ගේ රැකියා අර්ථසාධක අරමුදලට විකුණනු ලැබේ. අනෙක් ඒවා බැංකු වල රඳවා ඇත.",
        "දේශීය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කළහොත් හිඟය පියවීම රජයට තවත් අපහසු වනු ඇත. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocata ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lazard",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රැකියා අර්ථසාධක අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடன் ஆலோசகர்கள் உள்ளூர் கடனைப் பார்க்கிறார்கள்: ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - கடனை நிலையானதாக மாற்றுவதற்கான முயற்சிகளின் ஒரு பகுதியாக கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவதற்கான மறுகட்டமைப்பு திட்டம் உருவாக்கப்பட்டு வருவதால், இலங்கையின் கடன் ஆலோசகர்கள் உள்ளூர் கடனைப் பார்க்கிறார்கள் என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "லண்டன் கிளப்புக்கு (தனியார் கடனாளிகளின்) செல்ல உத்தியோகபூர்வ கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "\"இரண்டாவது, மிக முக்கியமான பிரச்சினை நீங்கள் உள்ளூர் கடனைப் பார்க்க வேண்டுமா?\" என்று கொழும்பைத் தளமாகக் கொண்ட சிந்தனைக் குழுவான அட்வகேட்டா இன்ஸ்டிட்யூட் ஏற்பாடு செய்த பொருளாதார மன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "\"நிச்சயமாக இது தொலைநோக்கு விளைவுகளை ஏற்படுத்தும். லசார்ட், நிதி ஆலோசகர்கள் இருவரையும் பார்க்கிறார்கள்.",
        "கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான அரசாங்கத்தின் நிலைப்பாடு 2022 ஏப்ரலில் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், அங்கு ரூபா கடனை மீள்கட்டமைப்பு செய்யவில்லை எனவும் மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "செங்குத்தான நாணயத் தேய்மானம் மற்றும் பணவீக்கத்தால் உள்ளூர் கடன் ஏற்கனவே ஒரு உண்மையான முடி வெட்டப்பட்டதால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாணயம் சரிந்து, பணவீக்கம் அதிகரிக்கும் போது, ​​வருவாய்கள் காலப்போக்கில் அதிகரித்து, அவர்களுக்கு சேவை செய்வதை எளிதாக்குகிறது.",
        "பெரும்பாலான உள்ளூர் கடன்கள் தனியார் துறை ஊழியர்களின் வேலைவாய்ப்பு வருங்கால வைப்பு நிதிக்கு குறைந்த விலையில் விற்கப்படுகின்றன. மற்றவை வங்கிகளில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "உள்ளூர் கடன் மறுகட்டமைக்கப்பட்டால், பற்றாக்குறையை நிதியளிப்பது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இன்னும் கடினமாக இருக்கும். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லண்டன் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வக்கீல் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லசார்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேலைவாய்ப்பு வருங்கால வைப்பு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}