{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/President-never-ordered-British-woman-to-be-deported/108-243512",
  "time_ut": 1661186285,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President never ordered British woman to be deported",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President never ordered British woman to be deported",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President office today denied reports that said an order has been given by President Ranil Wickremesinghe to deport the British women who has allegedly supported the Galle Face protesters by spreading falsehoods.",
        "When contacted by Daily Mirror, Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry said the matter is handled by the Department of Immigration and Emigration.",
        "It was reported earlier that the Immigration and Emigration Department has taken action to cancel the visa of the said person.",
        "She has been informed to leave the country on or before August 15 as she had violated her visa conditions. Department sources said that the British woman in question had a medical visa.",
        "The Department has issued this order following an inquiry conducted by the Department officials based on a complaint. As part of this investigation, her British passport was held by the officials on August 2. She had been ordered to be present at the department premises within seven days. Investigations have also revealed that she had come to Sri Lanka under the medical resident visa category and has been staying in Negombo and Malabe areas since August 14, 2019 as a therapist."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "British",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Immigration and Emigration Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 14, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ජාතික කාන්තාව රටින් පිටුවහල් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා කිසිවිටෙක නියෝග කළේ නැත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අසත්‍ය ප්‍රචාර පතුරවමින් ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට සහය දැක්වූ බව කියන බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කාන්තාවන් පිටුවහල් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නියෝගයක් ලබාදී ඇති බවට පළවන වාර්තා ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි.",
        "ඩේලි මිරර් කළ විමසීමකදී විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි පැවසුවේ මෙම කාරණය ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් හසුරුවන බවයි.",
        "එම පුද්ගලයාගේ වීසා බලපත්‍රය අවලංගු කිරීමට ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව කටයුතු කර ඇති බව මීට පෙර වාර්තා විය.",
        "වීසා කොන්දේසි උල්ලංඝණය කර ඇති බැවින් අගෝස්තු 15 වැනිදා හෝ ඊට පෙර රටින් පිටවන ලෙස ඇයට දන්වා ඇත. දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග පැවසුවේ අදාළ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ජාතික කාන්තාවට වෛද්‍ය වීසා බලපත්‍රයක් තිබූ බවයි.",
        "පැමිණිල්ලක් මත දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නිලධාරීන් විසින් කරන ලද පරීක්ෂණයකින් අනතුරුව දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත. මෙම විමර්ශනයේ කොටසක් ලෙස ඇයගේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රය පසුගිය අගෝස්තු 2 වැනි දින නිලධාරීන් සතුව තිබී ඇත. දින හතක් ඇතුළත දෙපාර්තමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයේ පෙනී සිටින ලෙස ඇයට නියෝග කර තිබුණි. වෛද්‍ය නේවාසික වීසා කාණ්ඩය යටතේ ඇය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ 2019 අගෝස්තු 14 වැනිදා සිට මීගමුව සහ මාලඹේ ප්‍රදේශවල චිකිත්සකවරියක ලෙස රැඳී සිට ඇති බවද විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 අගෝස්තු 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரித்தானிய பெண்ணை நாடு கடத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ஒருபோதும் உத்தரவிடவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலிமுகத்திடல் போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு ஆதரவாக பொய்யான தகவல்களை பரப்பிய பிரித்தானிய பெண்களை நாடு கடத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவினால் உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெளியான தகவலை ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் இன்று மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "டெய்லி மிரர் தொடர்பு கொண்ட போது, ​​வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி, இந்த விடயத்தை குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம் கையாள்வதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குறித்த நபரின் வீசாவை ரத்து செய்ய குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளதாக முன்னர் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "அவர் தனது விசா நிபந்தனைகளை மீறியதால் ஆகஸ்ட் 15 அல்லது அதற்கு முன் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுமாறு அவருக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. குறித்த பிரித்தானிய பெண்ணுக்கு மருத்துவ விசா இருந்ததாக திணைக்கள வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "புகாரின் அடிப்படையில் துறை அதிகாரிகள் நடத்திய விசாரணையை அடுத்து இந்த உத்தரவை திணைக்களம் பிறப்பித்துள்ளது. இந்த விசாரணையின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, ஆகஸ்ட் 2 ஆம் தேதி அவரது பிரிட்டிஷ் பாஸ்போர்ட்டை அதிகாரிகள் வைத்திருந்தனர். அவர் ஏழு நாட்களுக்குள் துறை வளாகத்தில் ஆஜராக வேண்டும் என்று உத்தரவிடப்பட்டது. அவர் மருத்துவ வதிவிட விசா பிரிவின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கு வந்து சிகிச்சையாளராக 2019 ஆகஸ்ட் 14 முதல் நீர்கொழும்பு மற்றும் மாலபே பகுதிகளில் தங்கியிருந்ததாகவும் விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 14, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}