{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-to-resign-on-july-13-speaker-97202/",
  "time_ut": 1657385880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka president to resign on July 13: Speaker",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka president to resign on July 13: Speaker",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will resign on Wednesday July 13, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena said, after protestors stormed Rajapaksa’s official residence demanding his resignation.",
        "In a statement issued to the media Saturday July 09 night, Abeywardena urged the public to remain calm and advised state officials to ensure the smooth functioning of day to day life.",
        "The Speaker said he had informed Rajapaksa of a decision reached at a party leaders’ meeting earlier in the evening that the president and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe must step down.",
        "The president has expressed his agreement to the decision and said he will resign on Wednesday, to allow a smooth transition.",
        "Calling for calm, Speaker Abeywardena noted that a group of people had set fire to Prime Minister Wickremesinghe’s private residence in Colombo.",
        "“I urge everyone not to further engage in such acts and to please return to your homes,” said Abeywardena. (Colombo/Jul09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier in the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති ජුලි 13 ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි: කතානායක",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජුලි 13 බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ, ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කරමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ජුලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා රාත්‍රියේ මාධ්‍ය වෙත නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් අබේවර්ධන මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ සන්සුන්ව සිටින ලෙස සහ එදිනෙදා ජීවිතය සුමටව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් දෙන ලෙසයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට මීට පෙර සවස පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ගත් තීරණයක් පිළිබඳව තමන් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට දැනුම් දුන් බව කථානායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා එම තීරණයට සිය එකඟතාවය ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති අතර සුමට සංක්‍රමණයකට ඉඩ දීම සඳහා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව පැවසීය.",
        "සන්සුන් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි කථානායක අබේවර්ධන සඳහන් කළේ කිසියම් පිරිසක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තබා ඇති බවයි.",
        "තවදුරටත් මෙවැනි ක්‍රියාවල නොයෙදෙන ලෙසත් කරුණාකර නැවත ඔබේ නිවෙස් වෙත පැමිණෙන ලෙසත් මම සියලු දෙනාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමි,” අබේවර්ධන පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාත්‍රී 09",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලින් සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அதிபர் ஜூலை 13ல் ராஜினாமா: சபாநாயகர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச, ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவார் என்று சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன கூறினார், எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் ராஜபக்சவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து, அவர் பதவி விலகக் கோரி.",
        "ஜூலை 09 சனிக்கிழமை இரவு ஊடகங்களுக்கு வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கையில், அபேவர்தன, பொதுமக்கள் அமைதியாக இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொண்டதுடன், அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையை சுமூகமாகச் செயல்படுவதை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறு அரச அதிகாரிகளுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என நேற்று மாலை நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானத்தை ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு தெரிவித்ததாக சபாநாயகர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இந்த தீர்மானத்திற்கு தனது உடன்பாட்டை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார் மற்றும் சுமூகமான மாற்றத்திற்கு அனுமதிக்கும் வகையில் புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "அமைதி காக்குமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்த சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன, கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு சிலர் தீ வைத்துள்ளதாக குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மேலும் இதுபோன்ற செயல்களில் ஈடுபட வேண்டாம் என்றும் தயவு செய்து உங்கள் வீடுகளுக்கு திரும்புமாறும் அனைவரையும் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன் என அபேவர்தன கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 09",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}