{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Eastern-Brokers-sets-all-time-record-price-for-Luckyland-Estate/34-738509",
  "time_ut": 1660088721,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Eastern Brokers sets all-time record price for Luckyland Estate",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Eastern Brokers sets all-time record price for Luckyland Estate",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At the Colombo Tea Auctions held yesterday, Luckyland Estate achieved an all-time record price of Rs. 1,750 per kg for two invoices of BOPF Grade in the Uda Pusellawa Planting District. These lines of tea were purchased by M/s. Unilever Lipton Ceylon Ltd.",
        "Luckyland Estate was initially planted by Fred Whittall, a Scion of the Great British and Turkish Mercantile family.",
        "Luckyland Estate is situated at an elevation of 1,523 m above mean sea level in the Uda Pussellawa Planting District with an annual production of 500,000 kg. The estate currently comes under the stewardship of Deputy General Manager Sahan Aluwihare. Luckyland Estate is reputed for manufacturing high quality teas and is an ISO 22,000, and Rainforest Alliance certified facility.",
        "Luckyland Estate comes under the management of Kegalle Plantation PLC and owned by the Richard Peiris Group of Companies.",
        "Eastern Brokers Ltd. are the brokers associated in selling and Marketing of Luckyland Estate Teas."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Eastern Brokers",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Luckyland Estate",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Tea Auctions",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Luckyland Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,750 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPF Grade",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Uda Pusellawa Planting District",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Unilever Lipton Ceylon Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luckyland Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fred Whittall",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkish Mercantile",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luckyland Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,523",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Uda Pussellawa Planting District",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sahan Aluwihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Luckyland Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rainforest Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle Plantation PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Richard Peiris Group of Companies",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eastern Brokers Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marketing of Luckyland Estate Teas",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඊස්ටර්න් බ්‍රෝකර්ස් ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය සඳහා සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිලක් නියම කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ පැවති කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය විසින් මෙතෙක් වාර්තා වූ රු. උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ BOPF ශ්‍රේණියේ ඉන්වොයිසි දෙකක් සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 1,750 කි. මෙම තේ පේළි M/s විසින් මිලදී ගන්නා ලදී. සීමාසහිත යුනිලීවර් ලිප්ටන් සිලෝන් සමාගම",
        "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය මුලින් රෝපණය කරන ලද්දේ මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය සහ තුර්කි වෙළඳ පවුලට අයත් ෆ්‍රෙඩ් විටල් විසිනි.",
        "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මධ්‍යන්‍ය මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට මීටර් 1,523 ක උන්නතාංශයක පිහිටා ඇති අතර වාර්ෂික නිෂ්පාදනය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 500,000 කි. වතුයාය දැනට නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී සහන් අලුවිහාරේ මහතාගේ භාරකාරත්වය යටතේ පවතී. ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය උසස් තත්ත්වයේ තේ නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා කීර්තිමත් වන අතර එය ISO 22,000 සහ Rainforest Alliance සහතික ලත් පහසුකමකි.",
        "ලකීලන්ඩ් වත්ත කෑගල්ල ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී හි කළමනාකාරිත්වය යටතේ වන අතර රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමාගම් සමූහයට අයත් වේ.",
        "East Brokers Ltd යනු Luckyland Estate Teas විකිණීම සහ අලෙවි කිරීම සම්බන්ධ තැරැව්කරුවන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නැගෙනහිර තැරැව්කරුවන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,750 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPF ශ්‍රේණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත යුනිලීවර් ලිප්ටන් සිලෝන් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්‍රෙඩ් විටල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි වෙළඳ සේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,523 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහන් අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැසි වනාන්තර සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමාගම් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊස්ටර්න් බ්‍රෝකර්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලකීලන්ඩ් වතුයායේ තේ අලෙවි කිරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லக்கிலேண்ட் தோட்டத்திற்கான அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலையை ஈஸ்டர்ன் புரோக்கர்ஸ் அமைத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று நடைபெற்ற கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் லக்கிலாண்ட் தோட்டம் இதுவரை இல்லாத வகையில் ரூ. உடா புசெல்லாவ நடவு மாவட்டத்தில் BOPF தரத்தின் இரண்டு விலைப்பட்டியல்களுக்கு கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 1,750. இந்த தேநீர் வரிசைகள் M/s ஆல் வாங்கப்பட்டது. யுனிலீவர் லிப்டன் சிலோன் லிமிடெட்.",
        "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட் ஆரம்பத்தில் கிரேட் பிரிட்டிஷ் மற்றும் துருக்கிய வணிகக் குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஃபிரெட் விட்டால் என்பவரால் நடப்பட்டது.",
        "லக்கிலேண்ட் தோட்டமானது உடா புஸ்ஸல்லாவ நாற்று மாவட்டத்தில் சராசரி கடல் மட்டத்திலிருந்து 1,523 மீ உயரத்தில் 500,000 கிலோ வருடாந்த உற்பத்தியுடன் அமைந்துள்ளது. இந்த தோட்டம் தற்போது பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் சஹான் அலுவிஹாரேவின் பொறுப்பில் உள்ளது. லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட் உயர்தர தேயிலைகளை தயாரிப்பதில் புகழ்பெற்றது மற்றும் ISO 22,000 மற்றும் ரெயின்ஃபாரெஸ்ட் அலையன்ஸ் சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட வசதியாகும்.",
        "லக்கிலேண்ட் தோட்டம் கேகாலை பிளான்டேஷன் பிஎல்சியின் நிர்வாகத்தின் கீழ் வருகிறது மற்றும் ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழும நிறுவனங்களுக்கு சொந்தமானது.",
        "ஈஸ்டர்ன் புரோக்கர்ஸ் லிமிடெட் என்பது லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட் டீஸ் விற்பனை மற்றும் சந்தைப்படுத்துதலில் தொடர்புடைய தரகர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கிழக்கு தரகர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிலோ 1,750",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPF தரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடா புசெல்லாவ நடவு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனிலீவர் லிப்டன் சிலோன் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரெட் விட்டல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கிய வணிகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,523",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடா புஸ்ஸல்லாவ நடவு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹான் அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மழைக்காடு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை பிளான்டேஷன் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழும நிறுவனங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்ன் புரோக்கர்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்கிலேண்ட் எஸ்டேட் டீஸின் சந்தைப்படுத்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}