{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/18/china-to-participate-in-russia-military-drills-says-india-will-join-too/",
  "time_ut": 1660808400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China To Participate In Russia Military Drills, Says India Will Join Too",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China To Participate In Russia Military Drills, Says India Will Join Too",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "NDTV; China's defence ministry said Wednesday its participation in the annual \"Vostok\" exercises is part of a bilateral cooperation agreement with Russia.",
        "Chinese troops will travel to Russia to take part in joint military drills, Beijing's defence ministry said.",
        "Beijing and Moscow have close defence links and China has said it wants to push bilateral relations \"to a higher level,\" even as Moscow faces international sanctions and widespread condemnation over its war in Ukraine.",
        "China's defence ministry said Wednesday its participation in the annual \"Vostok\" exercises – which Moscow has said will take place from August 30 to September 5 – is part of a bilateral cooperation agreement with Russia.",
        "\"The aim is to deepen practical and friendly cooperation with the armies of participating countries, enhance the level of strategic collaboration among the participating parties, and strengthen the ability to respond to various security threats,\" the Chinese defence ministry said in a statement.",
        "India, Belarus, Mongolia, Tajikistan, and other countries will also participate, it said.",
        "China and India have been accused of providing diplomatic cover for Russia throughout its months-long war in Ukraine by opposing Western sanctions and arms sales to Kyiv.",
        "But Beijing insisted its participation in the joint exercises was \"unrelated to the current international and regional situation.\"",
        "It is the second joint military exercise conducted by Chinese and Russian troops this year.",
        "Bombers from the two countries conducted a 13-hour drill close to Japan and South Korea in May, forcing those countries to scramble jet fighters, as US President Joe Biden was visiting Tokyo.",
        "State Department spokesperson Ned Price said that while warming ties between China and Russia undermined global security, Washington didn't \"read anything\" into the drills.",
        "China To Participate In Russia Military Drills, Says India Will Join Too"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "defence ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "defence ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "defence ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30 to September 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belarus",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mongolia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tajikistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kyiv",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ned Price",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියාවේ හමුදා අභ්‍යාසවලට චීනය සහභාගී වීමට ඉන්දියාව ද එක්වන බව කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "NDTV; චීනයේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය බදාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ වාර්ෂික “වොස්ටොක්” අභ්‍යාසවලට සහභාගී වීම රුසියාව සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතා ගිවිසුමක කොටසක් බවයි.",
        "ඒකාබද්ධ හමුදා අභ්‍යාසවලට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා චීන හමුදා රුසියාවට යන බව බීජිං ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "බීජිං සහ මොස්කව් සමීප ආරක්ෂක සබඳතා ඇති අතර, යුක්රේනයේ යුද්ධය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මොස්කව් ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්බාධකවලට සහ පුලුල්ව හෙලා දැකීමට මුහුන දී සිටියත්, ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා \"ඉහළ තලයකට\" තල්ලු කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය බව චීනය පවසා තිබේ.",
        "චීනයේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය බදාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ වාර්ෂික \"වොස්ටොක්\" අභ්‍යාස සඳහා සහභාගී වීම - මොස්කව් අගෝස්තු 30 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 5 දක්වා පැවැත්වෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති අතර එය රුසියාව සමඟ ඇති ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතා ගිවිසුමේ කොටසකි.",
        "\"සහභාගී වන රටවල හමුදාවන් සමඟ ප්‍රායෝගික සහ මිත්‍රශීලී සහයෝගීතාව ගැඹුරු කිරීම, සහභාගී වන පාර්ශ්ව අතර උපායමාර්ගික සහයෝගීතාවයේ මට්ටම ඉහළ නැංවීම සහ විවිධ ආරක්ෂක තර්ජනවලට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමේ හැකියාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීම මෙහි අරමුණයි\" යනුවෙන් චීන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව, බෙලාරුස්, මොංගෝලියාව, ටජිකිස්තානය සහ අනෙකුත් රටවල් ද සහභාගී වන බව එහි සඳහන් වේ.",
        "බටහිර සම්බාධක සහ කියෙව් වෙත ආයුධ විකිණීමට විරුද්ධ වීමෙන් යුක්රේනයේ මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති යුද්ධය පුරාවට රුසියාවට රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආවරණයක් සැපයීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාවට චෝදනා එල්ල වී තිබේ.",
        "එහෙත් බෙයිජිං අවධාරනය කලේ, ඒකාබද්ධ අභ්‍යාස වලට තම සහභාගීත්වය \"වර්තමාන ජාත්‍යන්තර හා කලාපීය තත්වයට සම්බන්ධ නැති\" බවයි.",
        "එය මේ වසරේ චීන සහ රුසියානු හමුදා විසින් පවත්වනු ලබන දෙවන ඒකාබද්ධ යුද අභ්‍යාසයයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති ජෝ බිඩෙන් ටෝකියෝවේ සංචාරයක යෙදී සිටියදී, දෙරටේ බෝම්බකරුවන් මැයි මාසයේදී ජපානයට සහ දකුණු කොරියාවට ආසන්නව පැය 13 ක අභ්‍යාසයක් පැවැත්වූ අතර, එම රටවලට ජෙට් ප්‍රහාරක යානා පොරබැදීමට බල කෙරුනි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ප්‍රකාශක නෙඩ් ප්‍රයිස් පැවසුවේ, චීනය සහ රුසියාව අතර උණුසුම් සබඳතා ගෝලීය ආරක්ෂාවට වල කපන අතර, වොෂින්ටනය අභ්‍යාසවලට \"කිසිවක් කියවා\" නැති බවයි.",
        "රුසියාවේ හමුදා අභ්‍යාසවලට චීනය සහභාගී වීමට ඉන්දියාව ද එක්වන බව කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 5 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලාරුස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොංගෝලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටජිකිස්තානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කියෙව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13-පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙඩ් මිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்யாவின் ராணுவப் பயிற்சியில் பங்கேற்கும் சீனா, இந்தியாவும் இணையும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "என்டிடிவி; வருடாந்திர \"வோஸ்டாக்\" பயிற்சிகளில் பங்கேற்பது ரஷ்யாவுடனான இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பு ஒப்பந்தத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும் என்று சீனாவின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் புதன்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சீனப் படைகள் கூட்டு ராணுவப் பயிற்சியில் பங்கேற்பதற்காக ரஷ்யாவுக்குச் செல்லும் என்று பெய்ஜிங்கின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பெய்ஜிங்கும் மாஸ்கோவும் நெருங்கிய பாதுகாப்புத் தொடர்புகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளன, மேலும் மாஸ்கோ உக்ரைனில் அதன் போர் தொடர்பாக சர்வதேசத் தடைகள் மற்றும் பரவலான கண்டனங்களை எதிர்கொண்டாலும், இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை \"உயர் நிலைக்கு\" தள்ள விரும்புவதாக சீனா கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "ரஷ்யாவுடனான இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பு ஒப்பந்தத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாக ஆகஸ்ட் 30 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 5 வரை நடைபெறும் என்று மாஸ்கோ கூறியுள்ள வருடாந்திர \"வோஸ்டாக்\" பயிற்சிகளில் பங்கேற்பது புதன்கிழமை என்று சீனாவின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"பங்கேற்கும் நாடுகளின் ராணுவங்களுடனான நடைமுறை மற்றும் நட்புரீதியான ஒத்துழைப்பை ஆழமாக்குவது, பங்கேற்பாளர்களிடையே மூலோபாய ஒத்துழைப்பின் அளவை மேம்படுத்துவது மற்றும் பல்வேறு பாதுகாப்பு அச்சுறுத்தல்களுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் திறனை வலுப்படுத்துவது இதன் நோக்கமாகும்\" என்று சீன பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியா, பெலாரஸ், ​​மங்கோலியா, தஜிகிஸ்தான் மற்றும் பிற நாடுகளும் பங்கேற்கும் என்று அது கூறியது.",
        "சீனாவும் இந்தியாவும் ரஷ்யாவின் உக்ரைனில் பல மாதங்கள் நீடித்த போர் முழுவதும், மேற்கத்திய பொருளாதாரத் தடைகள் மற்றும் கைவ் மீதான ஆயுத விற்பனையை எதிர்ப்பதன் மூலம் ரஷ்யாவிற்கு இராஜதந்திர பாதுகாப்பு அளித்ததாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஆனால் பெய்ஜிங் கூட்டுப் பயிற்சிகளில் பங்கேற்பது \"தற்போதைய சர்வதேச மற்றும் பிராந்திய சூழ்நிலையுடன் தொடர்பில்லாதது\" என்று வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு சீன மற்றும் ரஷ்ய துருப்புக்கள் நடத்தும் இரண்டாவது கூட்டு ராணுவ பயிற்சி இதுவாகும்.",
        "அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடன் டோக்கியோவிற்கு விஜயம் செய்திருந்த நிலையில், இரு நாடுகளின் குண்டுவீச்சுக்காரர்கள் ஜப்பான் மற்றும் தென் கொரியாவிற்கு அருகில் 13 மணி நேர பயிற்சியை மேற்கொண்டனர்.",
        "வெளியுறவுத்துறை செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் நெட் பிரைஸ் கூறுகையில், சீனாவிற்கும் ரஷ்யாவிற்கும் இடையிலான வெப்பமயமாதல் உறவுகள் உலகளாவிய பாதுகாப்பைக் குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தும் அதே வேளையில், வாஷிங்டன் பயிற்சியில் \"எதையும் படிக்கவில்லை\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "ரஷ்யாவின் ராணுவப் பயிற்சியில் பங்கேற்கும் சீனா, இந்தியாவும் இணையும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "என்டிடிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 5 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலாரஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மங்கோலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தஜிகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீவ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெட் விலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}