{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84421/hirunika-records-statement-with-cid",
  "time_ut": 1660982340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hirunika records statement with CID",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika records statement with CID",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former parliamentarian Hirunika Premachandra arrived at the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) at around 11.00 a.m. this morning to record a statement with regard to an ongoing probe.",
        "Speaking to the media, Premachandra said she was not informed of the nature of the investigation.",
        "She alleged that President Ranil Wickremesinghe is now attempting to arrest and interrogate those who were involved in the Aragalaya movement.",
        "It was Ranil Wickremesinghe who reaped benefits from the mass protests and became the president of the country, Premachandra said further.",
        "“Ranil Rajapaksa” is more of a dictator than Rajapaksas ever were, Premachandra added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 11.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිරුණිකා රහස් පොලිසියට ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීනී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර අද පෙරවරු 11.00 ට පමණ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වෙත පැමිණ සිටියේ සිදුකෙරෙන විමර්ශනයකට අදාළව ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහායි.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර කියා සිටියේ විමර්ශනයේ ස්වභාවය පිළිබඳව තමන් දැනුවත් නොකළ බවයි.",
        "අරගලය ව්‍යාපාරයට සම්බන්ධ වූවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දැන් උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින බව ඇය චෝදනා කළාය.",
        "ජනතා විරෝධයේ ඵල නෙළා රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත්වූයේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බවද ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "“රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ” යනු රාජපක්ෂලාට වඩා ඒකාධිපතියෙකු බව ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.00 පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிஐடியிடம் ஹிருணிகா வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர இன்று காலை 11.00 மணியளவில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்திற்கு வருகை தந்தார், இது தொடர்பிலான விசாரணைகள் தொடர்பில் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஊடகங்களிடம் பேசிய பிரேமச்சந்திர, விசாரணையின் தன்மை குறித்து தமக்கு தெரிவிக்கப்படவில்லை என்றார்.",
        "அரகலய இயக்கத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களை கைது செய்து விசாரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தற்போது முயற்சித்து வருவதாக அவர் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவே மக்கள் போராட்டங்களின் பலனைப் பெற்று நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதியானார் என்றும் பிரேமச்சந்திர மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"ரணில் ராஜபக்ச\" ராஜபக்ஷவை விட சர்வாதிகாரி என்றும் பிரேமச்சந்திர மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 11.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}