{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කබ්රාල්ට-එරෙහි-නඩුව-නොවැම්බර්වලට-කල්-යයි/101-618598",
  "time_ut": 1661235053,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කබ්රාල්ට එරෙහි නඩුව නොවැම්බර්වලට කල් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The case against Cabral is adjourned until November",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage has adjourned the case until November (11th) next month to submit an amended complaint against the former Central Bank Governor Mr. Ajith Nivard Cabral regarding an alleged misappropriation of US$ 65 million belonging to the Government of Sri Lanka. Ordered today (23).",
        "Former Central Bank Governor Mr. Ajith Nivard Cabral appeared in court today (23) on bail in connection with this incident.",
        "President's lawyer Mr. Sampath Mendis, who appeared in court on behalf of former Central Bank governor Mr. Ajith Nivard Cabral, stated that he hopes to file preliminary objections related to this incident.",
        "Nugegoda Nalandaramadhipati Thiniawala Palitha Thero has submitted a complaint related to this incident.",
        "In his complaint, the complainant submitted that in the year 2014, an amount of US$ 6.5 million belonging to the Central Bank of Sri Lanka was paid to Ahmed Sbriri, who was working for the American CIA spy service, under the guise of improving the image of Sri Lanka. has been ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "November",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "November (11th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 65 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sampath Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiniawala Palitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year 2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 6.5 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahmed Sbriri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කබ්රාල්ට එරෙහි නඩුව නොවැම්බර්වලට කල් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට අයත් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 65 ක මුදලක් සාවද්‍ය පරිහරණය කළැයි කියන සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතාට එරෙහි නඩුවේ සංශෝධිත පැමිණිල්ලක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා ලබන මස නොවැම්බර් මාස (11) වැනිදා තෙක් එම නඩුව කල් තැබීමට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිලිණ ගමගේ මහතා අද (23) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතා මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇප මත සිටිමින් අද (23) අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටියේය.",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතා වෙනුවෙන් අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සම්පත් මෙන්ඩිස් මහතා සඳහන් කර සිටියේ මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළව මූලික විරෝධතා ගොනු කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බැවය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළව පැමිණිල්ලක් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබෙනේ නුගේගොඩ නාලන්දාරාමාධිපති තීනියාවල පාලිත හිමියන් ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිරූපය ගොඩ නැංවීමේ අරමුණ ට මුවා වී එවකට ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපතිවරයා ව කරමින් 2014 වර්ෂයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවට අයත් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.5 ක මුදලක් ඇමරිකානු සී අයි ඒ ඔත්තු සේවයේ නියුතුව සිටි අහම්ඩ් ස්බ්‍රිරි යන අයට ගෙවා ඇති බව පැමිණිලිකරු සිය පැමිණිල්ලෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් (11 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 65 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සම්පත් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිනියාවල පාලිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහමඩ් ස්බ්රිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඅයිඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கப்ராலுக்கு எதிரான வழக்கு நவம்பர் மாதத்துக்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்குச் சொந்தமான 65 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை முறைகேடாகப் பயன்படுத்தியதாகக் கூறப்படும் மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் திரு.அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ராலுக்கு எதிரான திருத்தப்பட்ட முறைப்பாட்டைச் சமர்பிப்பதற்கான வழக்கை அடுத்த மாதம் (11)ஆம் திகதிக்கு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே ஒத்திவைத்தார். இன்று (23)",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் திரு.அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் பிணையில் இன்று (23) நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராகியிருந்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் சார்பில் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதியின் சட்டத்தரணி சம்பத் மெண்டிஸ், இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பான பூர்வாங்க ஆட்சேபனைகளை தாக்கல் செய்ய எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் நுகேகொட நாளந்தராமாதிபதி தினியாவல பாலித தேரர் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "2014 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கிக்கு சொந்தமான 6.5 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் அமெரிக்க சிஐஏ உளவு சேவையில் பணியாற்றிய அஹமட் ஸ்ப்ரிரிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக முறைப்பாட்டாளர் தனது முறைப்பாட்டில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இலங்கையின் படம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நவம்பர்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் (11ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சம்பத் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினியாவல பாலித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர் 6.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகமது ஸ்ப்ரிரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}