{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/17/lanka-premier-league-2022-postponed/",
  "time_ut": 1658059320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lanka Premier League 2022 postponed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lanka Premier League 2022 postponed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Cricket (SLC) has announced that the Lanka Premier League 2022 has been postponed.",
        "Accordingly, the Lanka Premir League, which was scheduled to be held from 1st to 21st August, 2022 will be postponed, with immediate effect.",
        "This decision was taken by the SLC, following a request made by the Innovative Production Group FZE (IPG), the Rights Holder of the tournament, which cited the current ‘economic situation,’ in the country, as not conducive to hosting the tournament.",
        "Indian Govt calls for all-party meeting over Sri Lankan crisis",
        "Japan engages in high level talks with CBSL & Treasury officials"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premir League",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Innovative Production Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL & Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකා ප්‍රිමියර් ලීග් 2022 කල් යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ලංකා ප්‍රිමියර් ලීග් තරගාවලිය කල් දැමූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව 2022 අගෝස්තු 01 වැනිදා සිට 21 වැනිදා දක්වා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ ලංකා ප්‍රිමිර් ලීගය වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි කල් දමනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත්තේ තරඟාවලියේ හිමිකම් දරන්නා වන Innovative Production Group FZE (IPG) විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව, රටෙහි වත්මන් 'ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය,' තරඟාවලිය පැවැත්වීම සඳහා හිතකර නොවන බව සඳහන් කරමිනි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය රජය සර්ව පාක්ෂික හමුවක් කැඳවයි",
        "ජපානය CBSL සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premir League",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවෝත්පාදන නිෂ්පාදන සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL සහ භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லங்கா பிரீமியர் லீக் 2022 ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); லங்கா பிரீமியர் லீக் 2022 ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் (எஸ்எல்சி) அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 1 ஆம் திகதி முதல் 21 ஆம் திகதி வரை நடைபெறவிருந்த லங்கா பிரீமிர் லீக் உடனடியாக அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய ‘பொருளாதார சூழ்நிலையை’ மேற்கோள் காட்டி, போட்டியை நடத்துவதற்கு ஏற்றதாக இல்லை என, போட்டியின் உரிமையாளரான Innovative Production Group FZE (IPG) விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து, SLC இந்த முடிவை எடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை பிரச்சனை தொடர்பாக அனைத்து கட்சி கூட்டத்திற்கு இந்திய அரசு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
        "CBSL மற்றும் கருவூல அதிகாரிகளுடன் ஜப்பான் உயர்மட்ட பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரீமிர் லீக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதுமையான தயாரிப்பு குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL & கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}