{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Veteran-Trotskyist-and-SEP-Chairman-Wije-Dias-dies-aged-80/56-738103",
  "time_ut": 1659124685,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Veteran Trotskyist and SEP Chairman Wije Dias dies aged 80",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Veteran Trotskyist and SEP Chairman Wije Dias dies aged 80",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Socialist Equality Party (SEP), the Sri Lankan section of the International Committee of the Fourth International (ICFI), announces with great sorrow the loss of party chairman and veteran Trotskyist, comrade Wije Dias. He was a leader of the ICFI and a member of the International Editorial Board of the World Socialist Web Site. He died in Jayewardenepura Hospital after being rushed there following a massive heart attack. He would have celebrated his 81st birthday on 27 August.",
        "The death of comrade Wije is a great loss for the SEP in particular, the ICFI as a whole and the working class in Sri Lanka, South Asia and internationally. He was an intransigent fighter for more than half a century for the Trotskyist principles of international socialism that embody the interests of the working class in Sri Lanka and around the world.",
        "Comrade Wije was a founding member of the Revolutionary Communist League (RCL), the predecessor the SEP, established in June 1968 to take up the fight for Trotskyism in the wake of the Lanka Sama Samaja’s (LSSP) betrayal in 1964 when it entered the bourgeois government of Prime Minister Sirima Bandaranaike.",
        "Comrade Wije, then a young member of the LSSP, was a leading figure in the group of youth who opposed the betrayal and, under the ICFI’s guidance, drew the necessary political lessons and laid the RCL’s firm political foundations.",
        "After the tragic and untimely death of the RCL’s founding general secretary Keerthi Balasuriya in December 1987, comrade Wije was elected to fill the post. He was general secretary of the RCL then SEP right up until the latest congress in May when he was elected party chairman.  Comrade Wije Dias led the party in fighting for the political independence of the working class from all the parties of political establishment, its pseudo-left hangers-on and trade union agencies. Despite his age and weakened health, he played a key role in charting a revolutionary socialist course for the working class and rural toilers amid the current popular uprising against the Rajapaksa and Wickremesinghe governments and their agenda of austerity and repression.",
        "His loss is particularly felt amid this unprecedented economic, political and social crisis in Sri Lanka, the sharpest expression of the global crisis of capitalism. However, his powerful political legacy lives on in the cadre of the SEP and political work of the ICFI which continue his lifelong struggle for a socialist future for humanity.",
        "Remains of late comrade Wije Dias lie at ‘Jayaratne Respect Home’, Kanatta Road, Borella for final respect from 9 a.m. on Thursday, 28 July to Saturday, 30 July. The cortege leaves Jayaratne Respect Home at 2:30 p.m. Saturday for Borella Cemetery for the funeral meeting at 3 p.m. and cremation at 5 p.m."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Veteran Trotskyist",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SEP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wije Dias",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Socialist Equality Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Committee of the Fourth International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trotskyist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wije Dias",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Editorial Board of the World Socialist Web Site",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayewardenepura Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "81st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than half a century",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trotskyist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Revolutionary Communist League",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trotskyism",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lanka",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1964",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirima Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keerthi Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 July to Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayaratne Respect Home",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella Cemetery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රවීණ ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී සහ සසප සභාපති විජේ ඩයස් වයස අවුරුදු 80 දී මිය යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හතරවන ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ (හජාජාක) ශ්‍රී ලංකා ශාඛාව වන සමාජවාදී සමානතා පක්ෂය (සසප) පක්ෂයේ සභාපති සහ ප්‍රවීණ ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී විජේ ඩයස් සහෝදරයාගේ වියෝව ගැන මහත් ශෝකයෙන් නිවේදනය කරයි. ඔහු හජාජාක නායකයෙකු වූ අතර ලෝක සමාජවාදී වෙබ් අඩවියේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කර්තෘ මණ්ඩලයේ සාමාජිකයෙකි. දරුණු හෘදයාබාධයකින් ජයවර්ධනපුර රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසු ඔහු මිය ගියේය. ඔහු අගෝස්තු 27 වන දින ඔහුගේ 81 වන උපන්දිනය සමරනු ඇත.",
        "විජේ සහෝදරයාගේ මරණය විශේෂයෙන්ම සසපට, සමස්තයක් ලෙස හජාජාකයට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ, දකුනු ආසියාවේ හා ජාත්‍යන්තරව කම්කරු පන්තියට විශාල පාඩුවකි. ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ ලොව පුරා කම්කරු පන්තියේ අවශ්‍යතා මූර්තිමත් කරන ජාත්‍යන්තර සමාජවාදයේ ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී මූලධර්ම සඳහා අඩ සියවසකට වැඩි කාලයක් තිස්සේ අනවරත සටන්කරුවෙක් විය.",
        "විජේ සහෝදරයා 1964 දී ලංකා සම සමාජය (ලසසප) ධනේශ්වරයට ඇතුළු වූ විට ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදයේ පාවාදීමෙන් ඉක්බිත්තෙන් ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදය සඳහා සටන ගෙන ඒම සඳහා 1968 ජූනි මාසයේ පිහිටුවන ලද සසප පූර්වගාමියා වූ විප්ලවවාදී කොමියුනිස්ට් සංගමයේ (විකොස) ආරම්භක සාමාජිකයෙකි. අගමැතිනි සිරිමා බණ්ඩාරනායකගේ රජය.",
        "එවකට ලසසපයේ තරුණ සාමාජිකයෙකු වූ විජේ සහෝදරයා, පාවාදීමට විරුද්ධ වූ සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ මගපෙන්වීම යටතේ, අවශ්‍ය දේශපාලන පාඩම් උකහාගත් සහ විකොස ස්ථීර දේශපාලන අත්තිවාරම් දැමූ තරුන කණ්ඩායමේ ප්‍රමුඛ චරිතයක් විය.",
        "1987 දෙසැම්බරයේ විකොස ආරම්භක ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් කීර්ති බාලසූරියගේ ඛේදනීය සහ අකල් මරණයෙන් පසුව, විජේ සහෝදරයා එම තනතුර පිරවීමට තේරී පත් විය. ඔහු පක්ෂයේ සභාපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ මැයි මාසයේ නවතම සම්මේලනය දක්වාම එවකට විකොස සසප ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් විය. විජේ ඩයස් සහෝදරයා, දේශපාලන සංස්ථාපිතයේ, එහි ව්‍යාජ-වාම එල්ලී සිටින සහ වෘත්තීය සමිති ආයතනවල සියලු පක්ෂවලින් කම්කරු පන්තියේ දේශපාලන ස්වාධීනත්වය සඳහා අරගලයේ දී පක්ෂයට නායකත්වය දුන්නේ ය. ඔහුගේ වයස සහ දුර්වල සෞඛ්‍යය නොතකා, රාජපක්ෂ හා වික්‍රමසිංහ ආන්ඩුවලට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ කප්පාදු හා මර්දනයේ න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට එරෙහිව වත්මන් මහජන නැගිටීම මධ්‍යයේ කම්කරු පන්තිය සහ ග්‍රාමීය කම්කරුවන් සඳහා විප්ලවවාදී සමාජවාදී මාවතක් ප්‍රස්ථාරගත කිරීමේ දී ඔහු ප්‍රධාන භූමිකාවක් ඉටු කළේය.",
        "ධනවාදයේ ගෝලීය අර්බුදයේ තියුනුම ප්‍රකාශනය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජ අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ඔහුගේ පාඩුව විශේෂයෙන් දැනේ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහුගේ බලගතු දේශපාලන උරුමය සසපයේ කේඩරය සහ මානව වර්ගයා සඳහා සමාජවාදී අනාගතයක් සඳහා ඔහුගේ ජීවිත කාලය පුරාම අරගලය අඛන්ඩව ගෙන යන ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ දේශපාලන වැඩ කොටස තුල පවතී.",
        "අභාවප්‍රාප්ත විජේ ඩයස් සහෝදරයාගේ දේහය ජූලි 28 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා උදේ 9 සිට ජූලි 30 සෙනසුරාදා දක්වා අවසන් ගෞරව දැක්වීම සඳහා බොරැල්ල කනත්ත පාරේ ‘ජයරත්න රෙස්පෙක්ට් හෝම්’ හි තැන්පත් කර ඇත. 2:30 ට cortege ජයරත්න රෙස්පෙක්ට් හෝම් වෙතින් පිටත් වේ. බොරැල්ල කනත්තට සෙනසුරාදා සවස 3 ට අවමංගල්‍ය රැස්වීම සඳහා. සහ ආදාහනය සවස 5 ට."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රවීණ ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදියෙක්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සසප",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විජේ ඩයස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමාජවාදී සමානතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේ ඩයස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හජාජාක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සමාජවාදී වෙබ් අඩවියේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කර්තෘ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධනපුර රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "81 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩ සියවසකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විප්ලවවාදී කොමියුනිස්ට් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකොස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1968 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1964",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිමා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකොස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකොස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කීර්ති බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකොස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 28 සිට සෙනසුරාදා දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයරත්න රෙස්පෙක්ට් හෝම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:30 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල කනත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மூத்த ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிசவாதியும் சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சியின் தலைவருமான விஜே டயஸ் 80 வயதில் காலமானார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் (ICFI) இலங்கைப் பிரிவான சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி (SEP), கட்சியின் தலைவரும் மூத்த ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிசவாதியுமான தோழர் விஜே டயஸின் இழப்பை மிகுந்த வருத்தத்துடன் அறிவிக்கிறது. அவர் ICFI இன் தலைவராகவும், உலக சோசலிச வலைத் தளத்தின் சர்வதேச ஆசிரியர் குழுவின் உறுப்பினராகவும் இருந்தார். அவருக்கு பாரிய மாரடைப்பு ஏற்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜயவர்தனபுர வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் அவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார். ஆகஸ்ட் 27 அன்று அவர் தனது 81வது பிறந்தநாளைக் கொண்டாடியிருப்பார்.",
        "தோழர் விஜேவின் மரணம், குறிப்பாக சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சிக்கு, ஒட்டுமொத்த நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவிற்கும் மற்றும் இலங்கை, தெற்காசியா மற்றும் சர்வதேச அளவில் உள்ள தொழிலாள வர்க்கத்திற்கும் பெரும் இழப்பாகும். அவர் இலங்கையிலும் உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள தொழிலாள வர்க்கத்தின் நலன்களை உள்ளடக்கிய சர்வதேச சோசலிசத்தின் ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிச கொள்கைகளுக்காக அரை நூற்றாண்டுக்கும் மேலாக ஒரு சளைக்காத போராளியாக இருந்தார்.",
        "தோழர் விஜே, சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சியின் முன்னோடியான புரட்சிக் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகத்தின் (RCL) ஸ்தாபக உறுப்பினராக இருந்தார். பிரதமர் சிறிமா பண்டாரநாயக்கவின் அரசாங்கம்.",
        "அப்போது லங்கா சமசமாஜக் கட்சியின் இளம் உறுப்பினராக இருந்த தோழர் விஜே, காட்டிக்கொடுப்பை எதிர்த்த இளைஞர் குழுவில் ஒரு முன்னணி நபராக இருந்தார், மேலும் நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ், தேவையான அரசியல் படிப்பினைகளைப் பெற்று, புரட்சிக் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகத்தின் உறுதியான அரசியல் அடித்தளங்களை அமைத்தார்.",
        "1987 டிசம்பரில் புரட்சிக் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகத்தின் ஸ்தாபக பொதுச் செயலாளர் கீர்த்தி பாலசூரியவின் துயரமான மற்றும் அகால மரணத்திற்குப் பிறகு, தோழர் விஜே அந்தப் பதவிக்கு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். அவர் புரட்சிக் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளராக இருந்தார், பின்னர் சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி மே மாதம் சமீபத்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியின் தலைவராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டது வரை. தோழர் விஜே டயஸ், அரசியல் ஸ்தாபனத்தின் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகள், அதன் போலி-இடது தொங்கும் மற்றும் தொழிற்சங்க ஏஜென்சிகள் ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து தொழிலாள வர்க்கத்தின் அரசியல் சுதந்திரத்திற்காகப் போராடுவதில் கட்சியை வழிநடத்தினார். அவரது வயது மற்றும் பலவீனமான உடல்நலம் இருந்தபோதிலும், ராஜபக்சே மற்றும் விக்கிரமசிங்க அரசாங்கங்களுக்கு எதிரான தற்போதைய மக்கள் எழுச்சி மற்றும் அவர்களின் சிக்கன மற்றும் அடக்குமுறையின் செயல்திட்டங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் தொழிலாள வர்க்கம் மற்றும் கிராமப்புற உழைப்பாளர்களுக்கு ஒரு புரட்சிகர சோசலிசப் போக்கை வகுப்பதில் அவர் முக்கிய பங்கு வகித்தார்.",
        "முதலாளித்துவத்தின் உலகளாவிய நெருக்கடியின் கூர்மையான வெளிப்பாடான இலங்கையின் இந்த முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக நெருக்கடியின் மத்தியில் அவரது இழப்பு குறிப்பாக உணரப்படுகிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், அவரது சக்திவாய்ந்த அரசியல் மரபு சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி மற்றும் நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் அரசியல் பணிகளில் வாழ்கிறது, இது மனிதகுலத்திற்கான சோசலிச எதிர்காலத்திற்கான அவரது வாழ்நாள் போராட்டத்தைத் தொடர்கிறது.",
        "மறைந்த தோழர் விஜே டயஸின் பூதவுடல், பொரளை கனத்த வீதியில் உள்ள ‘ஜயரத்ன மரியாதை இல்லத்தில்’ ஜூலை 28 வியாழன் காலை 9 மணி முதல் ஜூலை 30 சனிக்கிழமை வரை இறுதி அஞ்சலிக்காக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பகல் 2:30 மணிக்கு ஜெயரத்ன மரியாதை இல்லத்திலிருந்து புறப்படுகிறது. பொரளை மயானத்திற்கு சனிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் 3 மணிக்கு இறுதிச் சடங்கு கூட்டம். மற்றும் மாலை 5 மணிக்கு தகனம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூத்த ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிஸ்ட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சோ.ச.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விஜே டயஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜே டயஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICFI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சோசலிச வலைத் தளத்தின் சர்வதேச ஆசிரியர் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயவர்தனபுர வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "81வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரை நூற்றாண்டுக்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புரட்சிகர கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிசம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1964",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிமா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீர்த்தி பாலசூரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28 முதல் சனிக்கிழமை வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயரத்ன மரியாதை இல்லம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2:30",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை மயானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 3 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 5 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}