{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/sri-lanka-want-to-increase-visitors-from-china/",
  "time_ut": 1661499780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka want to increase visitors from China",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka want to increase visitors from China",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Asian Mountain Tourism Alliance held its sixth summit in Guiyang, Guizhou, China, on 17 -18 August 2022.",
        "The summit showcased a range of products especially handicrafts from the province and was graced by high-level officials from the central, provincial, and city Governments and diplomatic and business representatives.",
        "In his presentation, the Ambassador of Sri Lanka to China, Dr.Palitha Kohona, stated that while Sri Lanka lacked snow-covered peaks, it possessed perhaps the only high peak in the world sacred to three of the key religions of the world, Sri Paada to Buddhists and Adam's Peak to Christians and Muslims.",
        "Thousands climbed the mountain to express their religious fervor and to experience the incomparable sense of freedom and serenity.",
        "Ambassador Dr. Kohona spoke of the beautiful lush greenery, the aroma of fresh tea engulfing the ranges, and the gushing rivulets and waterfalls of the tea country of Sri Lanka.",
        "He stated that with the increasing numbers of visitors, bungalows, now converted to boutique hotels, were beginning to fill up.",
        "The Greeks called the island “Serendip”. This word gave rise to the English word serendipity – a pleasant surprise around every corner. In Chinese, it is Yuan Feng.",
        "Dr. Kohona invited the audience for a 'yuanfeng' experience in Sri Lanka.",
        "Military should be ready for technological knowledge for cyber warfare – President",
        "Is Sri Lanka’s economic crisis spiraling into a humanitarian one?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Asian Mountain Tourism Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guiyang",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guizhou",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Paada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhists",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Christians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Greeks",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Serendip",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Feng",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ චීනයෙන් පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයින් වැඩි කර ගැනීමටයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Asian Mountain Tourism Alliance සිය හයවන සමුළුව 2022 අගෝස්තු 17-18 දිනවල චීනයේ Guizhou හි Guiyang හිදී පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "මෙම සමුළුවේදී විශේෂයෙන් පළාතේ අත්කම් භාණ්ඩ රැසක් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන ලද අතර මධ්‍යම, පළාත් සහ නගර ආණ්‌ඩුවල ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් සහ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සහ ව්‍යාපාරික නියෝජිතයන් විසින් එය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන ලදී.",
        "චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති ආචාර්ය පාලිත කොහොන සිය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමේ දී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හිමෙන් වැසී ගිය කඳු මුදුන් නොමැති වුවද, ලෝකයේ ප්‍රධාන ආගම් තුනකට පූජනීය වූ ලොව එකම උස් කඳු මුදුන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සතු බව ය. බෞද්ධයන්ට පාදා සහ ක්‍රිස්තියානුවන්ට සහ මුස්ලිම්වරුන්ට ආදම්ගේ මුදුන.",
        "දහස් ගණනක් තම ආගමික උද්යෝගය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමටත්, නිදහසේ සහ සන්සුන් භාවයේ අසමසම හැඟීමක් අත්විඳීමටත් කන්ද තරණය කළහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තේ රටෙහි සුන්දර සශ්‍රීක ගහකොළ, කඳු වැටි ගිලගත් නැවුම් තේවල සුවඳ, ගලා බසින දිය ඇලි සහ දිය ඇලි ගැන තානාපති ආචාර්ය කොහොන කතා කළේය.",
        "නරඹන්නන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩි වීමත් සමඟ දැන් බුටික් හෝටල් බවට පරිවර්තනය කර ඇති බංගලා පිරී යාමට පටන් ගෙන ඇති බව ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ග්‍රීකයන් එම දූපත හැඳින්වූයේ \"සෙරන්ඩිප්\" යනුවෙනි. මෙම වචනය ඉංග්රීසි වචනය serendipity - සෑම අස්සක් මුල්ලක් නෑරම ප්රසන්න පුදුමයට හේතු විය. චීන භාෂාවෙන් එය Yuan Feng වේ.",
        "ආචාර්ය කොහොන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 'යුවාන්ෆෙන්ග්' අත්දැකීමක් සඳහා ප්‍රේක්ෂකයන්ට ආරාධනා කළේය.",
        "සයිබර් යුද්ධයට අවශ්‍ය තාක්ෂණික දැනුම සඳහා හමුදාව සූදානම් විය යුතුයි – ජනපති",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මානුෂීය අර්බුදයක් බවට පත්වෙමින් තිබේද?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian Mountain Tourism Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුයියං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guizhou",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී පාදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිතුනුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ග්රීකයන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙරන්ඩිප්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Feng",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனாவில் இருந்து வருபவர்களை அதிகரிக்க இலங்கை விரும்புகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஆசிய மவுண்டன் டூரிஸம் அலையன்ஸ் அதன் ஆறாவது உச்சி மாநாட்டை 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 17-18 அன்று சீனாவின் குய்சோவில் உள்ள குயாங்கில் நடத்தியது.",
        "இந்த உச்சிமாநாட்டில் மாகாணத்தில் இருந்து குறிப்பாக கைவினைப் பொருட்கள் பலவற்றை காட்சிப்படுத்தியது மற்றும் மத்திய, மாகாண மற்றும் நகர அரசாங்கங்களின் உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் இராஜதந்திர மற்றும் வணிக பிரதிநிதிகளால் அலங்கரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சீனாவுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் கலாநிதி பாலித கொஹொன தனது விளக்கக்காட்சியில், இலங்கையில் பனி மூடிய சிகரங்கள் இல்லாத நிலையில், உலகின் மூன்று முக்கிய மதங்களான ஸ்ரீ புனிதமான உலகின் ஒரே உயரமான சிகரம் இலங்கையில் இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்தார். பௌத்தர்களுக்கு பாடா மற்றும் கிறிஸ்தவர்களுக்கும் முஸ்லிம்களுக்கும் ஆதாமின் சிகரம்.",
        "ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோர் தங்கள் மத ஆர்வத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தவும், சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் அமைதியின் ஒப்பற்ற உணர்வை அனுபவிக்கவும் மலையில் ஏறினர்.",
        "தூதுவர் கலாநிதி கொஹொனா, அழகிய பசுமையான பசுமை, புதிய தேயிலையின் நறுமணம், எல்லைகளை சூழ்ந்து கொள்ளும், மற்றும் தேயிலை நாடான இலங்கையின் சிற்றோடைகள் மற்றும் நீர்வீழ்ச்சிகள் பற்றி பேசினார்.",
        "பார்வையாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்து வருவதால், தற்போது பூட்டிக் ஹோட்டல்களாக மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ள பங்களாக்கள் நிரம்பத் தொடங்கியுள்ளன என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கிரேக்கர்கள் தீவை \"செரண்டிப்\" என்று அழைத்தனர். இந்த வார்த்தை ஆங்கில வார்த்தையான serendipity ஐ உருவாக்கியது - ஒவ்வொரு மூலையிலும் ஒரு இன்ப அதிர்ச்சி. சீன மொழியில் இது யுவான் ஃபெங்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஒரு 'யுவான்ஃபெங்' அனுபவத்திற்காக பார்வையாளர்களை டாக்டர் கொஹோனா அழைத்தார்.",
        "சைபர் போருக்கான தொழில்நுட்ப அறிவுக்கு ராணுவம் தயாராக இருக்க வேண்டும் - ஜனாதிபதி",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மனிதாபிமானமாக மாறுகிறதா?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய மலை சுற்றுலா கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குய்யாங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guizhou",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித கொஹோன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ பாத",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்தர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்தவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹோனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரேக்கர்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "செரண்டிப்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Feng",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹோனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}