{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84542/ranjan-ramanayake-to-be-released-tomorrow",
  "time_ut": 1661434560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranjan Ramanayake to be released tomorrow?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranjan Ramanayake to be released tomorrow?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister Harin Fernando says that former MP Ranjan Ramanayake is expected to be released either tomorrow (26) or Monday (29).",
        "In a Twitter message, he mentioned that Ramanayake will be released following the request made by him and Minister Manusha Nanayakkara along with many others to President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Fernando also expressed his gratitude to the Minister of Justice Wijeyadasa Rajapakse, who he says worked tirelessly to make this happen.",
        "The minister stated that he is ‘ecstatic’ about the release of former deputy minister Ranjan Ramanayake.",
        "“Expecting dear brother Ranjan Ramanayake to be released tomorrow (26) or Monday (29) on the request that Manusha Nanayakkara and I made along with many others to HE President Ranil Wickremesinghe. I would like to thank Wijeyadasa Rajapakse who worked tirelessly to make it happen. Ecstatic about his release,” he tweeted.",
        "On August 13, it was reported that the incarcerated former parliamentarian had signed the letter seeking a presidential pardon and that it will be directed to President Wickremesinghe.",
        "Ramanayake is currently serving a prison sentence over contempt of court.",
        "The actor-turned-politician was sentenced to four years’ rigorous imprisonment by the Supreme Court on January 12, 2021, over contempt of court charges, in connection with disparaging remarks he had made about the judiciary in August 2017.",
        "Justice Minister Wijedasa Rajapakse had recently stated that necessary measures will be taken to pardon and release Mr. Ramanayake, as per the instructions of President Ranil Wickramasinghe, under a Presidential Pardon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijedasa Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Presidential Pardon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක හෙට නිදහස් වෙයි?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක හෙට (26) හෝ සඳුදා (29) නිදහස් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේ තමන් සහ මනූෂ නානායක්කාර අමාත්‍යවරයා ඇතුළු තවත් බොහෝ පිරිසක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීමට අනුව රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කරන බවයි.",
        "මෙය සිදු කිරීම සඳහා වෙහෙස නොබලා කටයුතු කළ බව පවසන අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ද ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා සිය කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය.",
        "හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් සතුටට පත්වන බවයි අමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ.",
        "“මනුෂ නානායක්කාර සහ මම තවත් බොහෝ දෙනෙක් සමඟ අතිගරු ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීම මත ආදරණීය රන්ජන් රාමනායක සොහොයුරා හෙට (26) හෝ සඳුදා (29) නිදහස් කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරනවා. එය ඉටු කිරීමට වෙහෙස නොබලා කටයුතු කළ විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට මම ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා. ඔහුගේ නිදහස් කිරීම ගැන ප්‍රීති වන්න, ”ඔහු ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "සිරගතව සිටින හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ජනාධිපති සමාව ඉල්ලා එම ලිපියට අත්සන් තබා ඇති බවත් එය ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත යොමු කිරීමට නියමිත බවත් අගෝස්තු 13 වැනිදා වාර්තා විය.",
        "රාමනායක මේ වන විට අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාවකට සිර දඬුවම් විඳිමින් සිටියි.",
        "2017 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී අධිකරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු විසින් කරන ලද අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත 2021 ජනවාරි 12 වන දින ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් වසර හතරක බරපතල සිරදඬුවම් නියම කරන ලදී.",
        "රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව යටතේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි සමාව දී නිදහස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගියදා ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති සමාවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நாளை விடுதலை?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நாளை (26) அல்லது திங்கட்கிழமை (29) விடுதலை செய்யப்படுவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தாம் மற்றும் அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார மற்றும் பலர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து ராமநாயக்க விடுதலை செய்யப்படவுள்ளதாக அவர் டுவிட்டர் செய்தியில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதனை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு அயராது உழைத்ததாக அவர் கூறும் நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கும் பெர்னாண்டோ தனது நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதியமைச்சர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலை குறித்து தாம் மகிழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "“மனுஷ நாணயக்காரவும் நானும் பலருடன் சேர்ந்து அதிமேதகு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் விடுத்த வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் அன்புச் சகோதரர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நாளை (26) அல்லது திங்கட்கிழமை (29) விடுதலை செய்யப்படுவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கிறோம். அதனை நனவாக்க அயராது உழைத்த விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன். அவரது விடுதலை குறித்து பரவசம்” என்று ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 13ஆம் தேதி, சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், ஜனாதிபதியின் மன்னிப்புக் கோரி கடிதத்தில் கையொப்பமிட்டுள்ளதாகவும், அது ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு அனுப்பி வைக்கப்படும் எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ராமநாயக்க தற்போது நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்கில் சிறைத்தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வருகிறார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 2017 இல் நீதித்துறையைப் பற்றி அவமதிக்கும் கருத்துக்கள் தொடர்பாக, நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்புக் குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில், நடிகராக மாறிய அரசியல்வாதிக்கு உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தால் ஜனவரி 12, 2021 அன்று நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பணிப்புரைக்கு அமைய, ஜனாதிபதியின் பொது மன்னிப்பின் கீழ் திரு ராமநாயக்கவை மன்னித்து விடுதலை செய்ய தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும் என நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ அண்மையில் தெரிவித்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}