{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132330",
  "time_ut": 1658900655,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவின் விசாவை நீடித்தது சிங்கப்பூர்-",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Singapore extends Gotabaya Rajapaksa's visa",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya will continue to stay in Singapore as his visa has been extended, the country's Straits Times reported.",
        "The Straits Times reported that Singapore has further extended the short-term permit granted to Gotabaya Rajapaksa when he visited Singapore on the 14th.",
        "This information has come out as Cabinet Speaker Bandula Gunawardena said on Tuesday that Gotabaya Rajapaksa is coming back to Sri Lanka.",
        "The cabinet spokesperson said that it was not known when the former president would return to the country but he was not absconding.",
        "On the 14th, he was issued 14 visa when he arrived in Gothapaya from Maldives to Changi Airport by Saudia flight.",
        "He fled the country amid a deepening economic crisis and widespread protests against his government as rising inflation drove up the prices of essential commodities, including food and fuel.",
        "After arriving in Singapore, he announced his resignation, which was officially announced to the Sri Lankan Parliament on the 15th.",
        "His colleague Prime Minister Ranilwickramasinghe was elected as the new President by members of Parliament.",
        "It is known that the new visa granted to Gotabaya Rajapaksa will expire on the 11th.",
        "It is known that Rajapaksa initially stayed in a hotel in the city center and is currently staying in a private house.",
        "When he arrived in Singapore on the 14th, an official of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Singapore made a personal visit to him."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gothapaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changi Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudia",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 15th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranilwickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 11th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Singapore",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිංගප්පූරුව ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ වීසා කාලය දීර්ඝ කරයි",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභයගේ වීසා බලපත්‍රය දීර්ඝ කර ඇති බැවින් ඔහු තවදුරටත් සිංගප්පූරුවේ රැඳී සිටින බව එරට ස්ට්‍රේට් ටයිම්ස් වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිංගප්පූරුවට ගිය අවස්ථාවේදී සිංගප්පූරුව විසින් ලබාදී තිබූ කෙටිකාලීන බලපත්‍රය තවදුරටත් දීර්ඝ කර ඇති බව ස්ට්‍රේට් ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ යළි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බව කැබිනට් කථානායක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමත් සමඟ මෙම තොරතුරු අනාවරණය වී තිබේ.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා කවදා මෙරටට පැමිණෙයිද යන්න නොදන්නා නමුත් ඔහු සැඟවී නොසිටින බවද කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා ඔහු මාලදිවයිනේ සිට චංගි ගුවන් තොටුපළට සෞදි ගුවන් යානයකින් ගෝඨාපායට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේදී ඔහුට වීසා 14ක් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "උද්ධමනය වැඩිවීම නිසා ආහාර සහ ඉන්ධන ඇතුළු අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල මිල ඉහල යාමත් සමග ඔහුගේ ආන්ඩුවට එරෙහිව පැතිරුනු ගැඹුරු වන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් සහ පුලුල් විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ඔහු රට හැර ගියේය.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඔහු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පසුගිය 15 වැනිදාය.",
        "ඔහුගේ සගයා වූ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ලබාදී ඇති නව වීසා බලපත්‍රය ලබන 11 වැනිදායින් අවසන් වන බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මුලින් නගර මධ්‍යයේ හෝටලයක නැවතී සිටි අතර මේ වන විට නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටින්නේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසක බව දන්නා කරුණකි.",
        "පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේදී සිංගප්පූරු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරියෙක් පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක නිරත විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද ස්ට්‍රේට්ස් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝතාපාය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැංගි ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவின் விசாவை நீடித்தது சிங்கப்பூர்-",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தபாய சிங்கப்பூரில் தொடர்ந்து தங்கியிருப்பார் அவரது விசா நீடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது அந்த நாட்டின் ஸ்டிரெய்ட் டைம்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச சிங்கப்பூரிற்கு 14 ம் திகதி சென்றவேளை அவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட குறுகிய கால அனுமதியை சிங்கப்பூர் மேலும் நீடித்துள்ளது என தெரியவந்துள்ளதாக ஸ்டிரெய்ட் டைம்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கைக்கு திரும்பிவரவுள்ளார் என அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்த்தன செவ்வாய்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ள நிலையிலேயே இந்த தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி எப்போது நாடு திரும்புவார் என்பது தெரியாது ஆனால் அவர் தலைமறைவாக இருக்கவில்லை என அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "14 ம் திகதி  சவுதியா விமானத்தில் மாலைதீவிலிருந்து சங்கி விமானநிலையத்திற்குகோத்தபாய வந்தவேளை அவருக்கு 14 விசா வழங்கப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "அதிகரித்துவரும் பணவீக்கம் உணவு மற்றும் எரிபொருள் உட்பட அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களின் விலைகளை அதிகரித்ததால் அவரதுஅரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக உருவான பரந்துபட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் மற்றும் தீவிரமடைந்துவரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகளின் மத்தியில் அவர் நாட்டிலிருந்து வெளியேறினார்.",
        "சிங்கப்பூரிற்கு வந்த பின்னர் அவர் தனது பதவி விலகலை அறிவித்தார்,அது குறித்து இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு 15 ம் திகதி உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அவரது சகாவான பிரதமர் ரணில்விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்தனர்.",
        "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவிற்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள புதிய விசா 11ம் திகதி முடிவடையும் என தெரியவருகின்றது.",
        "ராஜபக்ச ஆரம்பத்தில் சிட்டிசென்டரில் உள்ள ஹோட்டலில் தங்கியிருந்தார்,தற்போது தனியார் வீடொன்றில் தங்கியுள்ளார் என தெரியவருகின்றது.",
        "14ம் திகதி அவர் சிங்கப்பூர் வந்தவேளை சிங்கப்பூர் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் அதிகாரியொருவர் தனிப்பட்ட விஜயத்தை மேற்கொண்டு வந்த அவருக்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது அவர் புகலிடம் கோரவில்லை என அவருக்கு புகலிடம் வழங்கவில்லை என தெரிவித்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ட்ரெய்ட்ஸ் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி ஸ்ட்ரெய்ட்ஸ் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோதாபய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}