{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78509",
  "time_ut": 1657394100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three Youths Aged  19, 21 and 24 Arrested for Alleged Involvement in the Arson Attack on Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s  Private Residence are Remanded Until July 20 by Fort Magistrate",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three Youths Aged  19, 21 and 24 Arrested for Alleged Involvement in the Arson Attack on Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s  Private Residence are Remanded Until July 20 by Fort Magistrate",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Three youths were arrested in connection to the fire at Premier Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence at 5th Lane last Saturday (9) night and have been remanded until 20 July by the Fort Magistrate’s Court.",
        "“Three people were arrested yesterday – one is 19 years old, the other 21 years, and the third 24 years,” Police Spokesperson Senior Superintendent of Police (SSP) and Attorney-at-Law Nihal Thalduwa told The Morning yesterday (10).",
        "SSP Thalduwa said that the three were arrested at the property of Wickremesinghe.",
        "Last Saturday (9), hundreds of thousands of people descended upon the “GotaGoGama” protest site at Galle Face Green, where they ultimately took over the Presidential Secretariat, the official residence of the President, and Temple Trees – the official residence of the Prime Minister. The three buildings remain occupied, with key protestors stating that they would remain occupied until President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s official resignation, which Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena has stated will happen on Wednesday (13).",
        "Later that night, protestors were tear-gassed outside the private residence of Wickremesinghe at Fifth Lane, while four journalists attached to a private media organisation were also assaulted by the Special Task Forces (STF). The fire started shortly afterwards.",
        "Meanwhile, the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) said yesterday that the investigations will be conducted to find out why power was unavailable at Fifth Lane during the time of the incident.",
        "“No power cuts were scheduled after 6 p.m. islandwide and therefore proper investigation will be conducted by PUCSL to reveal the truth behind the non-availability of power during the event,” said PUCSL Chairman Janaka Rathnayake.",
        "A protestor occupying the official residence of the President told the media yesterday that they are part of a peaceful struggle and that they had no reason to set fire to Wickremesinghe’s house.",
        "“Even now, petrol comes inside and goes out from this residence too. That is why we have to be extra vigilant. This is our property and we do not want it to be destroyed. We did not win this struggle to destroy these things,” he said.",
        "Wickremesinghe has issued a statement expressing regret over the assault on journalists outside his residence.",
        "Meanwhile, Opposition and Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) Leader Sajith Premadasa said that he strongly condemns the attack on Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe’s residence.",
        "He said that everyone involved in the incident should be punished through a fair investigation regardless of their positions.",
        "Issuing a statement yesterday, Premadasa said that he unconditionally opposes the destruction of property and disturbances caused to people’s lives by a certain group of saboteurs hiding behind the peaceful struggle.",
        "The Opposition Leader requested the people to be aware of the external forces that are trying to “add a black stain” to the citizen’s struggle that has been carried out carefully for a peaceful country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Arson Attack",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fort Magistrate",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th Lane",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the other 21 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the third 24 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Thalduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GotaGoGama",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fifth Lane",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Rathnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ බවට සැකපිට අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් වයස අවුරුදු 19, 21 සහ 24 යන වයස්වල පසුවන තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකු ජුලි 20 දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය නියෝග කර තිබේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය සෙනසුරාදා (9) රාත්‍රියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ 5 වන පටුමගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අතර කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින් ජුලි 20 දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර තිබේ.",
        "ඊයේ (10) දිනයේදී පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත - එක් අයෙකු වයස අවුරුදු 19 යි, අනෙක් පුද්ගලයා අවුරුදු 21 යි, සහ තුන්වන පුද්ගලයා අවුරුදු 24 යි,\" පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී (එස්එස්පී) සහ නීතීඥ නිහාල් තල්දූව ඊයේ (10) උදෑසන පැවසීය.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී තල්දූව මහතා පැවසුවේ, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ දේපොළේදී තිදෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ය.",
        "පසුගිය සෙනසුරාදා (9) ලක්ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත ජනකායක් ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ \"ගෝඨාගෝගම\" විරෝධතා භූමියට බැස, අවසානයේ ඔවුන් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය, ජනාධිපති නිල නිවස සහ අගමැති නිල නිවස වන අරලියගහ මන්දිරය අත්පත් කර ගත්හ. ඇමැති. මෙම ගොඩනැඟිලි තුන තවදුරටත් රැඳී සිටින අතර, ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතාකරුවන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන තෙක් ඒවා රැඳී සිටින බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බව බදාදා (13) ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පසුව එදින රාත්‍රියේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පස්වන පටුමගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර ඇති අතර, පෞද්ගලික මාධ්‍ය සංවිධානයකට අනුයුක්ත මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සිව් දෙනෙකුටද විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය (STF) විසින් පහර දී ඇත. ටික වේලාවකට පසු ගින්න ආරම්භ විය.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සිද්ධිය වූ අවස්ථාවේ පස්වන පටුමගට විදුලිය නොලැබුණේ මන්දැයි සොයා බැලීම සඳහා මෙම පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වන බවයි.",
        "“සවස 6න් පසු විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර නැහැ. දිවයින පුරා, එබැවින් උත්සවය අතරතුර බලය නොලැබීම පිටුපස ඇති සත්‍යය හෙළි කිරීම සඳහා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව මගින් නිසි පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වනු ඇත.",
        "තමන් සාමකාමී අරගලයක කොටස්කරුවන් බවත්, වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමට කිසිදු හේතුවක් නොමැති බවත් ජනාධිපති නිල නිවසේ වාඩිලාගෙන සිටි විරෝධතාකරුවෙකු ඊයේ මාධ්‍ය වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "“දැන් මේ නවාතැනෙනුත් පෙට්‍රල් ඇතුළට එනවා එළියට යනවා. ඒ නිසා අපි වඩාත් විමසිලිමත් විය යුතුයි. මෙය අපගේ දේපළ වන අතර එය විනාශ කිරීමට අපට අවශ්‍ය නැත. අපි මේ අරගලය දිනුවේ මේ දේවල් විනාශ කරන්න නෙවෙයි.”",
        "තම නිවසින් පිටතදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කණගාටුව පළකරමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවසට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරය තරයේ හෙළා දකින බව විපක්ෂයේ සහ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "තරාතිරම නොබලා සාධාරණ පරීක්ෂණයක් මගින් සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ සියලු දෙනාට දඩුවම් ලබාදිය යුතු බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා.",
        "ඊයේ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ සාමකාමී අරගලය පිටුපස සැඟවී සිටින කඩාකප්පල්කාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් දේපළ විනාශ කිරීමට සහ ජන ජීවිතයට බාධා ඇති කිරීමට තමන් කොන්දේසි විරහිතව විරුද්ධ වන බවයි.",
        "සාමකාමී රටක් වෙනුවෙන් කල්පනාකාරීව ගෙන යන පුරවැසි අරගලයට කළු පැල්ලමක් එක් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බාහිර බලවේග පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙස විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගිනි තැබීමේ ප්‍රහාරය",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වන පටුමග",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනෙක් අවුරුදු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්වන වසර 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාගෝගම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන පටුමග",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வாசஸ்தலத்திற்கு தீவைப்புத் தாக்குதலில் ஈடுபட்ட குற்றச்சாட்டில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 19, 21 மற்றும் 24 வயதுடைய மூன்று இளைஞர்கள் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் 5வது லேனில் உள்ள தனியார் இல்லத்தில் கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை (9) இரவு தீ வைத்தமை தொடர்பில் மூன்று இளைஞர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு, கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றினால் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "\"மூன்று பேர் நேற்று கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர் - ஒருவருக்கு 19 வயது, மற்றவருக்கு 21 வயது, மற்றும் மூன்றாவது 24 வயது\" என்று பொலிஸ் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகரும் (SSP) சட்டத்தரணியான நிஹால் தல்துவா நேற்று (10) காலை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் சொத்தில் வைத்து மூவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக எஸ்.எஸ்.பி தல்துவா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை (9) இலட்சக்கணக்கான மக்கள் காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள “கொட்டகோகம” போராட்ட தளத்தில் இறங்கி, அங்கு இறுதியில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம், ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் மற்றும் பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமான அலரிமாளிகையை கைப்பற்றினர். அமைச்சர். மூன்று கட்டிடங்களும் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை அவை ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்படும் என்று முக்கிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர், இது புதன்கிழமை (13) நடக்கும் என்று சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அன்றிரவு, ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஐந்தாவது லேனில் உள்ள விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே கண்ணீர்ப்புகைக் குண்டுகளை வீசினர், அதே நேரத்தில் தனியார் ஊடக அமைப்பு ஒன்றின் நான்கு ஊடகவியலாளர்களும் சிறப்பு அதிரடிப் படையினரால் (STF) தாக்கப்பட்டனர். சிறிது நேரத்தில் தீ பரவியது.",
        "இதேவேளை, சம்பவம் இடம்பெற்ற போது ஐந்தாவது பாதையில் மின்சாரம் ஏன் கிடைக்காமல் போனது என்பது தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகள் நடத்தப்படும் என இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு நேற்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“மாலை 6 மணிக்குப் பிறகு மின்வெட்டு எதுவும் திட்டமிடப்படவில்லை. நாடளாவிய ரீதியில், எனவே நிகழ்வின் போது மின்சாரம் கிடைக்காமையின் பின்னணியில் உள்ள உண்மையை வெளிப்படுத்த PUCSL ஆல் முறையான விசாரணை நடத்தப்படும்” என PUCSL தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ள ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர் ஒருவர் நேற்று ஊடகங்களுக்குத் தெரிவித்ததாவது, தாங்கள் அமைதிப் போராட்டத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியினர் என்றும், விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வீட்டிற்குத் தீ வைப்பதற்கு எந்த காரணமும் இல்லை என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "“இப்போது கூட, இந்த குடியிருப்பில் இருந்தும் பெட்ரோல் உள்ளே வருகிறது, வெளியே செல்கிறது. அதனால்தான் நாம் கூடுதல் விழிப்புடன் இருக்க வேண்டும். இது எங்களின் சொத்து, இது அழிக்கப்படுவதை நாங்கள் விரும்பவில்லை. இவற்றை அழிப்பதற்காக நடந்த இந்தப் போராட்டத்தில் நாங்கள் வெற்றி பெறவில்லை,'' என்றார்.",
        "தனது இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் தாக்கப்பட்டமைக்கு வருத்தம் தெரிவித்து விக்கிரமசிங்க அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வீடு மீது நடத்தப்பட்ட தாக்குதலை வன்மையாகக் கண்டிப்பதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும், சமகி ஜன பலவேகய கட்சியின் தலைவருமான சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இச்சம்பவத்தில் தொடர்புடைய அனைவரும் எந்த பதவியில் இருந்தாலும் நியாயமான விசாரணை மூலம் தண்டிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "நேற்றைய தினம் அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்ட பிரேமதாச, அமைதிப் போராட்டத்தின் பின்னால் மறைந்திருந்து சில நாசகாரர்களால் சொத்துக்கள் அழிக்கப்படுவதையும் மக்களின் வாழ்வில் இடையூறுகளை ஏற்படுத்துவதையும் நிபந்தனையின்றி எதிர்ப்பதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "அமைதியான நாட்டிற்காக கவனமுடன் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட பிரஜைகளின் போராட்டத்திற்கு கறுப்புக் கறையை சேர்க்க முயலும் வெளிச் சக்திகள் தொடர்பில் மக்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தீக்குளிப்பு தாக்குதல்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டை மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது லேன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்ற 21 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது 24 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டகோகாமா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப் படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது பாதை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை 6 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}