{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/05/flight-training-academy-at-batti-airport/",
  "time_ut": 1657034880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Flight training academy at Batti airport ?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Flight training academy at Batti airport ?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Although Sri Lanka Air Force and the Road Development Authority developed the Batticaloa airport as a local air tours destination in the year 2018, the airport does not generate any revenue at present since it is toll-free of landing and parking charges.",
        "It has been observed that the airport space is suitable to be utilized for other productive purposes considering the above fact.",
        "Accordingly, the Cabinet of Ministers approved the proposal submitted by the Minister of Ports, Naval and Civil Aviation for the invitation of competitive resolutions to establish a flight training academy in the airport of Batticaloa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Batti airport",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Road Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Batti ගුවන් තොටුපලේ ගුවන් ගමන් පුහුණු ඇකඩමිය ?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2018 වර්ෂයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව සහ මාර්ග සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය විසින් මඩකලපුව ගුවන් තොටුපළ දේශීය ගුවන් සංචාර ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස සංවර්ධනය කළද, ගොඩබෑමේ සහ වාහන නැවැත්වීමේ ගාස්තු රහිත බැවින් දැනට ගුවන්තොටුපළ කිසිදු ආදායමක් උපයා නොගනී.",
        "ඉහත කරුණ සලකා බැලීමේදී ගුවන් තොටුපළ අවකාශය වෙනත් නිෂ්පාදන කටයුතු සඳහා යොදා ගැනීමට සුදුසු බව නිරීක්ෂණය වී ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව මඩකලපුව ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ගුවන් ගමන් පුහුණු ඇකඩමියක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා වන තරඟකාරී යෝජනා සඳහා ආරාධනා කිරීම සඳහා වරාය, නාවික සහ සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉදිරිපත් කළ යෝජනාව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බට්ටි ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්ග සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பட்டி விமான நிலையத்தில் விமான பயிற்சி அகாடமி ?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை விமானப்படை மற்றும் வீதி அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு மட்டக்களப்பு விமான நிலையத்தை உள்ளூர் விமான சுற்றுலாத் தளமாக அபிவிருத்தி செய்த போதிலும், தரையிறங்கும் மற்றும் பார்க்கிங் கட்டணங்கள் இல்லாததால், விமான நிலையம் தற்போது எந்தவொரு வருமானத்தையும் ஈட்டவில்லை.",
        "மேற்கூறிய உண்மையைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு விமான நிலைய இடம் வேறு உற்பத்தி நோக்கங்களுக்காகப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு ஏற்றதாக இருப்பது அவதானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, மட்டக்களப்பு விமான நிலையத்தில் விமானப் பயிற்சி அகாடமி ஒன்றை நிறுவுவதற்கான போட்டித் தீர்மானங்களை அழைப்பதற்காக துறைமுகங்கள், கடற்படை மற்றும் சிவில் விமான சேவைகள் அமைச்சரினால் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட யோசனைக்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பட்டி விமான நிலையம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீதி அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}