{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/navy-commander-meets-maldives-delegation/",
  "time_ut": 1662111420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy commander meets Maldives delegation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy commander meets Maldives delegation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Defence Advisor designate at the High Commission of the Republic of Maldives in Colombo, Lieutenant Colonel Hassan Amir and the incumbent Maldivian Defence Advisor, Colonel Ismail Naseer called on Commander of the Navy, Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne at the Navy Headquarters on Friday (02nd September 2022).",
        "During this official interaction, Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne warmly welcomed Lieutenant Colonel Hassan Amir, the incoming Maldivian Defence Advisor and also expressed his gratitude and best wishes to Colonel Ismail Naseer, who is on the verge of his termination of duty in Sri Lanka.",
        "The cordial interaction drew to a close with an exchange of mementoes, signifying goodwill and cooperation.",
        "Suspect arrested after failed assassination attempt on Argentine vice president"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hassan Amir",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Advisor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ismail Naseer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Navy Headquarters",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday (02nd September 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hassan Amir",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ismail Naseer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Argentine",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාවික හමුදාපති මාලදිවයින් දූත පිරිස හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කොළඹ මාලදිවයින් ජනරජයේ මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ ආරක්ෂක උපදේශක ලුතිනන් කර්නල් හසන් අමීර් සහ වත්මන් මාලදිවයින් ආරක්ෂක උපදේශක කර්නල් ඉස්මයිල් නසීර් සිකුරාදා (02) නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේදී නාවික හමුදාධිපති, වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න හමුවිය. 2022).",
        "මෙම නිල සංවාදයේදී වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න මහතා මාලදිවයිනේ පැමිණෙන මාලදිවයින් ආරක්ෂක උපදේශක ලුතිනන් කර්නල් හසන් අමීර් මහතා උණුසුම් ලෙස පිළිගත් අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජකාරි අවසන් කිරීමට ආසන්නව සිටින කර්නල් ඉස්මයිල් නසීර් මහතා වෙත සිය කෘතඥතාව සහ සුබ පැතුම් පළ කළේය.",
        "සුහදතාවය සහ සහයෝගීතාවය සනිටුහන් කරමින් සමරු තිළිණ හුවමාරුවක් සමඟින් සුහද අන්තර් ක්‍රියාව අවසන් විය.",
        "ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ උප ජනාධිපති ඝාතන තැත අසාර්ථක වීමෙන් පසු සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසන් අමීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක උපදේශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්මයිල් නසීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා (02 සැප්තැම්බර් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසන් අමීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්මයිල් නසීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடற்படை தளபதி மாலைதீவு தூதுக்குழுவை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பில் உள்ள மாலைதீவு உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர் லெப்டினன்ட் கேணல் ஹசன் அமீர் மற்றும் தற்போதைய மாலைதீவின் பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர் கேணல் இஸ்மாயில் நசீர் ஆகியோர் கடற்படைத் தளபதி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகேதென்ன அவர்களை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (02) கடற்படைத் தலைமையகத்தில் சந்தித்தனர். 2022)",
        "இந்த உத்தியோகபூர்வ கலந்துரையாடலின் போது, ​​வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன, மாலத்தீவுக்கு வரவிருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர் லெப்டினன்ட் கேணல் ஹசன் அமீரை அன்புடன் வரவேற்றதுடன், இலங்கையில் தனது கடமையை முடிக்கும் தருவாயில் இருக்கும் கேணல் இஸ்மாயில் நசீருக்கு தனது நன்றியையும் வாழ்த்துக்களையும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நல்லெண்ணம் மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்பைக் குறிக்கும் நினைவுச் சின்னங்களின் பரிமாற்றத்துடன் சுமுகமான தொடர்பு முடிவுக்கு வந்தது.",
        "அர்ஜென்டினாவின் துணை ஜனாதிபதியை படுகொலை செய்ய முயற்சி தோல்வியடைந்ததை அடுத்து சந்தேக நபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசன் அமீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்மாயில் நசீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (02 செப்டம்பர் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசன் அமீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்மாயில் நசீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}