{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/மலையகம்/மாணவனின்-சடலம்-4-நாட்களின்-பின்னர்-மீட்பு/76-303322",
  "time_ut": 1661936853,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மாணவனின் சடலம்  4 நாட்களின் பின்னர் மீட்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The body of the student was recovered after 4 days",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The body of a student of Peradanai University, who committed suicide by jumping into the Mahavali River from the Peradanai Bridge, was recovered today (31) during the day.",
        "The 24-year-old from Belmadulla, who was studying in the 3rd year of the Faculty of Engineering of Peradanai University, jumped into the river from the Peradanai bridge on the evening of the 27th.",
        "The cause of death of the deceased student is yet to be ascertained and the Peradana police have said that investigations are being carried out in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Peradanai University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mahavali River",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Peradanai Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belmadulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 3rd year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Faculty of Engineering of Peradanai University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening of the 27th",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peradana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දින 4කට පසු සිසුවාගේ මළ සිරුර ගොඩ ගෙන ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පේරාදාන පාලමෙන් මහවලි ගඟට පැන සියදිවි හානිකරගත් පේරාදාන විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ සිසුවෙකුගේ මළ සිරුර අද (31) දිවා කාලයේදී ගොඩගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "පේරාදාන විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ඉංජිනේරු පීඨයේ 3 වැනි වසරේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන 24 හැවිරිදි බෙල්මඩුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි මෙම තරුණයා පෙරේදා (27) සවස පේරාදාන පාලමෙන් ගඟට පැන ඇත.",
        "මියගිය සිසුවාගේ මරණයට හේතුව මෙතෙක් අනාවරණ වී නොමැති අතර මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වන බව පේරාදාන පොලිසිය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දින 4 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පේරාදානයි විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහවලි ගඟ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදාන පාලම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල්මඩුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදානයි විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ඉංජිනේරු පීඨය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වැනිදා සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේරදාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாணவனின் சடலம்  4 நாட்களின் பின்னர் மீட்பு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பேராதனை பாலத்திலிருந்து மஹாவலி ஆற்றில் பாய்ந்து தன்னுயிரை மாய்த்துக் கொண்ட பேராதனை பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவனின் சடலம், இன்று (31) பகல் மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பேராதனை பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் பொறியியல் பீடத்தின் 3ஆம் ஆண்டில் கல்வி கற்று வந்த, பெல்மடுல்ல பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 24 வயதான குறித்த இளைஞன், 27ஆம் திகதி மாலை பேராதனை பாலத்திலிருந்து ஆற்றிக்குள் பாய்ந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த மாணவனின் மரணத்துக்கான காரணம் இதுவரை தெரியவரவில்லை என்றும் இது தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை முன்னெடுத்து வருவதாக பேராதனை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாவலி ஆறு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்மதுல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் பொறியியல் பீடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27ம் தேதி மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேரடானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}