{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ලූලා--බොල්සොනාරෝ-නිල-වශයෙන්-මැතිවරණ-සටනට/3-396369",
  "time_ut": 1660714874,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලූලා, බොල්සොනාරෝ නිල වශයෙන් මැතිවරණ සටනට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lula, Bolsonaro officially in the election battle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Jair Bolsonaro and his front-runner challenger Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva have officially kicked off Brazil's hottest October election in decades.",
        "\"Our country no longer needs corruption, it needs order and prosperity,\" Bolsonaro, a former army captain, told a crowd at Juís de Fora on Tuesday afternoon, recalling his stab at the 2018 campaign that swept him to power and fueled anti-Lula sentiment. having done",
        "His supporters were said to have chanted \"Lula the thief\" during his speech.",
        "Nine years older than his opponent, Lula, 76, began his campaign by stopping at the gates of the Volkswagen car factory outside Sao Paulo amid repression under the military dictatorship.",
        "In a video posted on social media Tuesday morning, Lula said hunger has returned to Brazil under Bolsonaro and inflation is hitting families who cannot survive on the minimum wage.",
        "\"We have a lot of work to do to get this country back together,\" he said as he launched his bid to return to office. \"I want to be president again to change people's lives, because nobody can take it the way it is anymore.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jair Bolsonaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brazil",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "October",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bolsonaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Juís de Fora",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nine years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lula",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Volkswagen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sao Paulo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lula",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brazil",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bolsonaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලූලා, බොල්සොනාරෝ නිල වශයෙන් මැතිවරණ සටනට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ජෙයාර් බොල්සොනාරෝ සහ ඔහුගේ පෙරටුගාමී අභියෝගකරු ලුයිස් ඉනාසියෝ ලූලා ද සිල්වා දශක කිහිපයකින් ඔක්තෝබර් මාසයේ බ්‍රසීලයේ පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත උණුසුම් මැතිවරණයේ ඡන්ද සටන නිල වශයෙන් ආරම්භ කළහ.",
        "“අපේ රටට තවදුරටත් දූෂණය අවශ්‍ය නැහැ, එයට පිළිවෙල සහ සමෘද්ධිය අවශ්‍යයි,” හිටපු හමුදා කපිතාන්වරයෙකු වන බොල්සොනාරෝ, අඟහරුවාදා දහවල් ජුයිස් ද ෆෝරා හි රැස්ව සිටි පිරිසකට පැවසුවේ, ඔහු බලයට ගෙන ගිය 2018 ව්‍යාපාරයේදී ඔහුට එල්ල කළ පිහි ඇණුම සිහිපත් කර, ලූලා විරෝධී හැඟීම් මතු කරමිනි.",
        "ඔහුගේ ආධාරකරුවෝ \"ලූලා හොරා\" කියමින් ඔහුගේ දේශනය අතරතුර කෑ ගසමින් සිටි බව පැවසෙයි.",
        "ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිවාදියාට වඩා අවුරුදු නවයක් වැඩිමල්, 76 හැවිරිදි ලූලා, සාඕ පවුලෝ නගරයෙන් පිටත වොක්ස්වැගන් මෝටර් රථ කම්හලේ ගේට්ටු අසල නතර කරමින් සිය ව්‍යාපාරය ආරම්භ කළේ හමුදා ආඥාදායකත්වය යටතේ පවතින මර්දනය මධ්‍යයේය.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා උදේ සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල පළ කරන ලද වීඩියෝවක ලූලා කියා සිටියේ බොල්සොනාරෝ යටතේ කුසගින්න නැවත බ්‍රසීලයට පැමිණ ඇති බවත් උද්ධමනය අවම වැටුපෙන් ජීවත් විය නොහැකි පවුල්වලට පහර දෙන බවත්ය.",
        "\"මේ රට ගොඩගන්න අපිට ගොඩක් වැඩ තියෙනවා\" ඔහු නැවත කාර්යාලයට පැමිණීමේ උත්සාහය දියත් කළේය. \"මිනිසුන්ගේ ජීවිත වෙනස් කිරීමට මට නැවත ජනාධිපති වීමට අවශ්‍යයි, මන්ද එය පවතින ආකාරයටම කිසිවෙකුට එය තවදුරටත් ගත නොහැකියි.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෙයාර් බොල්සොනාරෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොල්සොනාරෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුයිස් ද ෆෝරා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු නවයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලූලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Volkswagen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාඕ පවුලෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලූලා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොල්සොනාරෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லூலா, போல்சனாரோ அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக தேர்தல் போரில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ஜெய்ர் போல்சனாரோ மற்றும் அவரது முன்னோடி போட்டியாளர் லூயிஸ் இனாசியோ லுலா டா சில்வா ஆகியோர் பிரேசிலின் பல தசாப்தங்களில் வெப்பமான அக்டோபர் தேர்தலை அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக தொடங்கினர்.",
        "\"எங்கள் நாட்டிற்கு இனி ஊழல் தேவையில்லை, அதற்கு ஒழுங்கு மற்றும் செழிப்பு தேவை\" என்று முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தலைவர் போல்சனாரோ செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை பிற்பகல் ஜூஸ் டி ஃபோராவில் ஒரு கூட்டத்தில் கூறினார், 2018 பிரச்சாரத்தில் அவர் குத்தியதை நினைவு கூர்ந்தார் மற்றும் லூலாவுக்கு எதிராக எரியூட்டினார். உணர்வு",
        "அவரது உரையின் போது அவரது ஆதரவாளர்கள் \"லூலா திருடன்\" என்று கோஷமிட்டதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "அவரது எதிரியை விட ஒன்பது வயது மூத்தவர், 76 வயதான லூலா, இராணுவ சர்வாதிகாரத்தின் கீழ் அடக்குமுறைக்கு மத்தியில் சாவ் பாலோவிற்கு வெளியே உள்ள வோக்ஸ்வேகன் கார் தொழிற்சாலையின் வாயில்களில் நின்று தனது பிரச்சாரத்தைத் தொடங்கினார்.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை காலை சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட ஒரு வீடியோவில், போல்சனாரோவின் கீழ் பிரேசிலுக்கு பசி திரும்பியுள்ளது என்றும் பணவீக்கம் குறைந்தபட்ச ஊதியத்தில் வாழ முடியாத குடும்பங்களைத் தாக்குகிறது என்றும் லூலா கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்த நாட்டை மீண்டும் ஒன்றிணைக்க எங்களுக்கு நிறைய வேலைகள் உள்ளன,\" என்று அவர் அலுவலகத்திற்குத் திரும்புவதற்கான முயற்சியைத் தொடங்கினார். \"மக்களின் வாழ்க்கையை மாற்றுவதற்கு நான் மீண்டும் ஜனாதிபதியாக இருக்க விரும்புகிறேன், ஏனென்றால் அதை இனி யாராலும் எடுக்க முடியாது.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்ர் போல்சனாரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேசில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போல்சனாரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூஸ் டி ஃபோரா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வோக்ஸ்வேகன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸா பாலோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேசில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போல்சனாரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}