{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79254",
  "time_ut": 1661711940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera  defends decision to increase electricity tariffs, citing spendthrift generation plans and unsuitable policies adopted by successive governments pushed for the inevitable upward adjustments.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera  defends decision to increase electricity tariffs, citing spendthrift generation plans and unsuitable policies adopted by successive governments pushed for the inevitable upward adjustments.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera yesterday in Parliament defended the decision to increase electricity tariffs, citing spendthrift generation plans and unsuitable policies adopted by successive governments pushed for the inevitable upward adjustments.",
        "Speaking during an adjournment debate on electricity tariff hike, he pointed out that electricity users would not have been shocked if timely revisions were implemented from time to time, whilst diversifying the power generation mix with cost-effective and renewable sources.",
        "“Tariff hike was inevitable. It has been implemented with the maximum possible subsidies for groups utilising least electricity,” he said.",
        "The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka approved the Ceylon Electricity Board’s (CEB) request to increase electricity tariffs by 75% on average for all categories from 10 August. This cost-reflective price revision was implemented after nine years.",
        "Minister Wijesekera pointed out that despite the CEB’s request for projected revenue of Rs. 869 billion from the tariff hikes, the electricity regulator had only approved over Rs. 500 billion.",
        "“The CEB needs to pay Rs. 76.8 billion to private power plants and Rs. 29 billion for renewables including rooftop solar. It also owes Ceylon Petroleum Corporation Rs. 31 billion,” he revealed.",
        "Sri Lanka’s total electricity users at present are 7.8 million, 6.7 million of which are domestic users, 1.1 million are general purpose users, and 1.4 million use below 30 units per month. A total of 1.7 million using 90 units, while 4.8 million use below 90 units each month.",
        "As per the tariff revision, for the least usage of up to 30 units, the CEB has been allowed to increase by 264%, whilst for the usage of 31- 60 units was increased by 211%.",
        "“Though the price hike percentage seems a lot, in terms of value it is not that high. Electricity users who utilised 30 units a month earlier spent Rs. 105, with the tariff hike it went up to Rs. 360. But is there anyone who cannot pay Rs. 360 for monthly electricity bill? Even for a loaf of bread we pay Rs. 200 on a daily basis now,” he argued, noting that to supply at Rs. 360, the Government spends around Rs. 1,500.",
        "Minister Wijesekera pointed out that the tariff hikes for religious places were also raised despite the heavy criticism from the clergy.",
        "“Of 46,682 religious places, only 15,195 consume below 30 units. Up until the tariff hike, they have only spent Rs. 87 for electricity per month. However, with the tariff hike, they will have to pay Rs. 330 monthly,” he said.",
        "He also justified the 900 MW Norochcholai coal power plant despite the breakdowns encountered since it was commissioned in 2011. “If the Norochcholai coal power plant was not built then the country would have faced the worst issues today,” he said.",
        "The Power and Energy Minister also proposed setting up a new Parliamentary Select Committee to monitor irregularities in the fuel procurement processes. He said the Committee should be chaired by a member of the Opposition, whilst nominating Independent MP Champika Ranawaka as the best suited for the post.",
        "“MP Ranawaka continues to make statements that he has contacts who can bring in sufficient fuel capacities at a lower price range. I will extend my fullest support as the subject Minister for it,” Wijesekera said.",
        "On 18 August, the Power and Energy Minister complained to the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) to investigate irregularities in the CPC and CPSTL activities.",
        "He requested the CID to investigate the procurement of fuel, evaluation of proposals, non-placement of orders, investigations into the selection of suppliers, delays in payments, irregularities in distribution, and various allegations levelled by individuals."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Energy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "869 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76.8 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "each month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "up to 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "264%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "211%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46,682",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 15,195",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "330",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MW Norochcholai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochcholai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentary Select Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independent MP Champika Ranawaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය ආරක්ෂා කරමින්, වියදම් සකසුරුවම් උත්පාදන සැලසුම් සහ නොවැලැක්විය හැකි ඉහලට ගැලපීම් සඳහා තල්ලු කරන ලද අනුප්‍රාප්තික රජයන් විසින් අනුගමනය කරන ලද නුසුදුසු ප්‍රතිපත්ති උපුටා දක්වයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීමේ තීරණය ආරක්ෂා කළේ වියදම් උත්පාදන සැලසුම් සහ නොවැළැක්විය හැකි ඉහළට ගැලපීම් සඳහා තල්ලු කරන ලද අනුප්‍රාප්තික රජයන් විසින් අනුගමනය කරන ලද නුසුදුසු ප්‍රතිපත්ති උපුටා දක්වමින්.",
        "විදුලි බිල ඉහළ නැංවීම පිළිබඳ සභාව කල්තබන අවස්ථාවේ විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේ වියදම් අඩු සහ පුනර්ජනනීය ප්‍රභවයන් සමඟ විදුලි ජනන මිශ්‍රණය විවිධාංගීකරණය කරමින් කාලානුරූපී සංශෝධන ක්‍රියාත්මක කළේ නම් විදුලි පාරිභෝගිකයන් කම්පා නොවන බවයි.",
        "“ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීම නොවැළැක්විය හැකිය. අවම වශයෙන් විදුලිය භාවිත කරන කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා ලබාදිය හැකි උපරිම සහනාධාර සහිතව එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "අගෝස්තු 10 වැනිදා සිට සියලුම කාණ්ඩ සඳහා සාමාන්‍යයෙන් 75%කින් විදුලි ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීමට ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (CEB) ඉල්ලීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් අනුමත කරන ලදී. මෙම පිරිවැය පරාවර්තක මිල සංශෝධනය වසර නවයකට පසුව ක්‍රියාත්මක විය.",
        "රුපියල් කෝටි 100 ක ප්‍රක්ෂේපිත ආදායමක් ලබා දෙන ලෙස විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය ඉල්ලීමක් කළද, එම ප්‍රතිලාභය ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. ගාස්තු වැඩිකිරීම් වලින් රුපියල් බිලියන 869 ක්, විදුලි නියාමකයා අනුමත කර තිබුණේ රු. බිලියන 500 කි.",
        "“ලංවිමට රු. බිලියන 76.8 ක් සහ පෞද්ගලික බලාගාර සඳහා රු. වහල සූර්ය බලය ඇතුළු පුනර්ජනනීය ද්‍රව්‍ය සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 29ක්. එය ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට රු. බිලියන 31ක්,” ඔහු හෙළි කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දැනට මුළු විදුලිය භාවිතා කරන්නන් මිලියන 7.8 ක් වන අතර, ඉන් මිලියන 6.7 ක් ගෘහස්ත පරිශීලකයන් වන අතර මිලියන 1.1 ක් සාමාන්‍ය කාර්ය භාවිතා කරන්නන් වන අතර මිලියන 1.4 ක් මසකට ඒකක 30 ට අඩු ප්‍රමාණයක් භාවිතා කරයි. මිලියන 1.7 ක් ඒකක 90 ක් භාවිතා කරන අතර මිලියන 4.8 ක් සෑම මසකම ඒකක 90 ට වඩා අඩු ප්‍රමාණයක් භාවිතා කරයි.",
        "ගාස්තු සංශෝධනයට අනුව අවම වශයෙන් ඒකක 30ක් දක්වා භාවිතය සඳහා 264%කින් වැඩි කිරීමට විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට අවසර දී ඇති අතර, ඒකක 31-60 අතර භාවිතය සඳහා 211%කින් වැඩි කර ඇත.",
        "“මිල ඉහළ යාමේ ප්‍රතිශතය බොහෝ සෙයින් පෙනුනද වටිනාකම අනුව එය එතරම් ඉහළ මට්ටමක නැත. මාසයකට පෙර ඒකක 30ක් භාවිත කළ විදුලි පාරිභෝගිකයන් සඳහා රු. 105, ගාස්තු වැඩිවීමත් සමඟ එය රු. 360. නමුත් රුපියල ගෙවිය නොහැකි අය සිටීද? මාසික විදුලි බිලට 360ක්? පාන් ගෙඩියකටත් අපි රු. දැන් දෛනික පදනමින් රුපියල් 200යි,” ඔහු තර්ක කළේ, රු. 360, රජය රු. 1,500 කි.",
        "පූජ්‍ය පක්‍ෂවල දැඩි විවේචන නොතකා ආගමික ස්ථාන සඳහාද ගාස්තු ඉහළ දැමීම සිදුකළ බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර පෙන්වා දුන්නා.",
        "“ආගමික ස්ථාන 46,682 න් ඒකක 30 ට අඩු පරිභෝජනය කරන්නේ 15,195 ක් පමණි. ගාස්තු වැඩි කරන තෙක් ඔවුන් වියදම් කර ඇත්තේ රු. මසකට විදුලිය සඳහා 87 කි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ගාස්තු වැඩිවීමත් සමඟ ඔවුන්ට රු. 330 මාසිකව, ”ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙගාවොට් 900ක නොරොච්චෝලේ ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරය 2011 වසරේ ආරම්භ කළ දා සිට බිඳවැටීම් තිබියදී එය සාධාරණීකරණය කළ ඔහු “නොරොච්චෝලේ ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරය එදා ඉදි නොකළේ නම් අද රට බරපතළම ප්‍රශ්නවලට මුහුණ පාන්නට ඉඩ තිබුණා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ප්‍රසම්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලියේ අක්‍රමිකතා නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා නව පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාවක් පිහිටුවීමට ද විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා යෝජනා කළේය. එම කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිත්වය විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුට හිමිවිය යුතු බවත් ඒ සඳහා සුදුසුම පුද්ගලයා ලෙස ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රී චම්පික රණවක මහතා නම් කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රණවක මන්ත්‍රීවරයා දිගින් දිගටම ප්‍රකාශ කරනවා අඩු මිලට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ධාරිතාවක් ගෙන්වා ගත හැකි සම්බන්ධතා තමන්ට ඇති බවට. ඒ සඳහා විෂය භාර අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස මගේ උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දෙනවා” විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "CPC සහ CPSTL ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල අක්‍රමිකතා විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා අගෝස්තු 18 වන දින විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (CID) පැමිණිලි කළේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම, යෝජනා ඇගයීම, ඇණවුම් ලබා නොදීම, සැපයුම්කරුවන් තෝරාගැනීමේ පරීක්ෂණ, ගෙවීම් ප්‍රමාදය, බෙදා හැරීමේ අක්‍රමිකතා සහ පුද්ගලයන්ගෙන් එල්ල වන විවිධ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කරන ලෙස ඔහු අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශක්තිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු නවයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 869 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 76.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 29 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 31 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 7.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම මාසයකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "264%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "211%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46,682 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,195 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "330",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රී චම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, தவிர்க்க முடியாத மேல்நோக்கிச் சரிசெய்தல்களுக்குத் தள்ளப்பட்ட செலவின உற்பத்தித் திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் பொருத்தமற்ற கொள்கைகள் ஆகியவற்றை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, மின்சார கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான முடிவை ஆதரித்தார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் மின்சார கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான முடிவை ஆதரித்தார், தவிர்க்க முடியாத மேல்நோக்கி மாற்றங்களுக்கு தள்ளப்பட்ட செலவின உற்பத்தித் திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் அடுத்தடுத்த அரசாங்கங்களால் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட பொருத்தமற்ற கொள்கைகளை மேற்கோள் காட்டினார்.",
        "மின்கட்டண உயர்வு மீதான ஒத்திவைப்பு விவாதத்தின் போது பேசிய அவர், மின் உற்பத்தியை செலவு குறைந்த மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆதாரங்களுடன் பன்முகப்படுத்துவதுடன், அவ்வப்போது திருத்தங்களைச் செயல்படுத்தினால், மின்சாரம் பயன்படுத்துவோர் அதிர்ச்சியடைந்திருக்க மாட்டார்கள் என்று சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "“கட்டண உயர்வு தவிர்க்க முடியாதது. குறைந்த மின்சாரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தும் குழுக்களுக்கு அதிகபட்ச மானியத்துடன் இது செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 10 முதல் அனைத்து பிரிவினருக்கும் சராசரியாக 75% மின்சார கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிக்க வேண்டும் என்ற இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின் (CEB) கோரிக்கைக்கு இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது. ஒன்பது ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு இந்த விலைத் திருத்தம் அமல்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின் உத்தேச வருமானம் ரூ.50000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000 00000000000000000000000000000000000000000000373விஜேசேகர கட்டண உயர்விலிருந்து 869 பில்லியன் ரூபாய், மின்சார ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம் ரூ. 500 பில்லியன்.",
        "“CEB ரூ. தனியார் மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்களுக்கு 76.8 பில்லியன் மற்றும் ரூ. கூரை சோலார் உட்பட புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க பொருட்களுக்கு 29 பில்லியன். மேலும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு ரூ. 31 பில்லியன்,” என்று அவர் வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "தற்போது இலங்கையின் மொத்த மின்சாரப் பாவனையாளர்கள் 7.8 மில்லியன், அவர்களில் 6.7 மில்லியன் உள்நாட்டுப் பாவனையாளர்கள், 1.1 மில்லியன் பொது நோக்கத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துபவர்கள் மற்றும் 1.4 மில்லியன் பேர் மாதாந்தம் 30 அலகுகளுக்குக் குறைவாகப் பயன்படுத்துகின்றனர். மொத்தம் 1.7 மில்லியன் பேர் 90 யூனிட்களைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறார்கள், அதே நேரத்தில் 4.8 மில்லியன் பேர் ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும் 90 யூனிட்டுகளுக்குக் கீழே பயன்படுத்துகிறார்கள்.",
        "கட்டண திருத்தத்தின்படி, குறைந்தபட்சமாக 30 யூனிட்கள் வரை பயன்படுத்தினால், CEB 264% அதிகரிக்க அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில் 31- 60 அலகுகளின் பயன்பாடு 211% ஆக அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“விலை உயர்வு சதவீதம் அதிகமாகத் தோன்றினாலும், மதிப்பின் அடிப்படையில் அது அவ்வளவு அதிகமாக இல்லை. ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்பு 30 யூனிட்களைப் பயன்படுத்திய மின்சார பயனர்கள் ரூ. 105 ஆகவும், கட்டண உயர்வால் ரூ. 360. ஆனால் ரூ. கொடுக்க முடியாதவர்கள் யாராவது இருக்கிறார்களா? மாதாந்திர மின்கட்டணத்திற்கு 360? ஒரு ரொட்டிக்கு கூட ரூ. இப்போது தினசரி அடிப்படையில் 200 ரூபாய்” என்று வாதிட்டார். 360, அரசாங்கம் சுமார் ரூ. 1,500.",
        "மதத் தலங்களுக்கான கட்டண உயர்வு, மதகுருமார்களின் கடும் விமர்சனங்களுக்கு மத்தியிலும் உயர்த்தப்பட்டதாக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "“46,682 வழிபாட்டுத் தலங்களில், 15,195 மட்டுமே 30 யூனிட்டுகளுக்குக் கீழே பயன்படுத்துகின்றன. கட்டண உயர்வு வரை அவர்கள் ரூ. மாதம் மின்சாரத்திற்கு 87 ரூபாய். ஆனால், கட்டண உயர்வால் அவர்கள் ரூ. 330 மாதாந்திரம்,” என்றார்.",
        "900 மெகாவாட் திறன் கொண்ட நொரோச்சோலை நிலக்கரி அனல்மின் நிலையம் 2011 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து முறிவுகளை எதிர்கொண்ட போதிலும் அதனை நியாயப்படுத்தினார். \"நொரோச்சோலை நிலக்கரி மின்நிலையம் அமைக்கப்படாவிட்டால் இன்று நாடு மிக மோசமான பிரச்சினைகளை எதிர்கொண்டிருக்கும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவு செயற்பாடுகளில் முறைகேடுகளை கண்காணிக்க புதிய பாராளுமன்ற தெரிவுக்குழுவை அமைக்கவும் மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் முன்மொழிந்தார். இந்த குழுவிற்கு எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் தலைமை தாங்க வேண்டும் எனவும், அதேவேளையில் சுயேச்சை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சம்பிக்க ரணவக்கவை அப்பதவிக்கு மிகவும் பொருத்தமானவர் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "“குறைந்த விலை வரம்பில் போதுமான எரிபொருள் கொள்ளளவைக் கொண்டுவரக்கூடிய தொடர்புகள் தனக்கு இருப்பதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரணவக்க தொடர்ந்து அறிக்கைகளை வெளியிட்டு வருகிறார். அதற்கு அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் எனது பூரண ஆதரவை வழங்குவேன் என விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 18 அன்று, மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் CPC மற்றும் CPSTL நடவடிக்கைகளில் உள்ள முறைகேடுகளை விசாரிக்க குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறைக்கு (CID) புகார் அளித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவு, முன்மொழிவுகளை மதிப்பீடு செய்தல், ஆர்டர்கள் வழங்கப்படாமை, சப்ளையர்களைத் தெரிவு செய்தமை தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள், கொடுப்பனவுகளில் தாமதம், விநியோகத்தில் முறைகேடுகள், தனிநபர்கள் சுமத்தியுள்ள பல்வேறு குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் தொடர்பாக விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு அவர் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரிடம் கோரியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆற்றல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "869 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "264%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "211%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46,682",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,195 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "330",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MW நொரோச்சோலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத் தெரிவுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயேச்சை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}