{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/headline/Vidyartha-shock-fancied-St-Peters-11-07/419-240255",
  "time_ut": 1656858811,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Vidyartha shock fancied St. Peter’s 11-07",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vidyartha shock fancied St. Peter’s 11-07",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Vidyartha College Kandy, a name strongly linked with inter-school rugby over the years dished out a giant killing performance at the Nittawela Stadium last evening to stun the much-fancied St. Peter’s College by 11 points (1 try, 2 penalties) to 7 points (1 try, 1 conversion) in their Dialog inter schools rugby league 2022 encounter.",
        "The game was played under wet conditions, which made ball handling that much more difficult and the boys from Bambalapitiya were guilty of a number of handling errors. Vidyartha too had their share of mistakes, but not to the extent of the visiting team. Whenever the home team got opportunities, they capitalized on same and essentially put the Peterites under pressure.",
        "Kalana Premaratne, the hooker scored the only try (unconverted) for Vidyartha through a forward’s rush very early in the game. In the second half Vidyartha put over a couple of penalties through full back, Menuka Thilakaratne. For the losers their only try was scored by Vishwa Silva with Emith Jayaweera adding the extras late in the game with the clock running down on them. Vidyartha were perched deep in Peterite territory, when referee Gihan Yatawara brought the game to an end signaling a famous Vidyartha win. Vidyartha is coached by Nalin Wijesinghe with Ananda Kasturiarachchi as their Rugby Director.",
        "The last Vidyartha win against St. Peter’s was at Bambalapitiya in 2012 under Jason Dissanayake."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "St. Peter’s",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "11-07",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vidyartha College Kandy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nittawela Stadium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "St. Peter’s College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bambalapitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peterites",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalana Premaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidyartha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Menuka Thilakaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vishwa Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emith Jayaweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gihan Yatawara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidyartha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidyartha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananda Kasturiarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vidyartha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "St. Peter’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bambalapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jason Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විද්‍යාර්ථ විසින් ලකුණු 11-07ක් ලෙස ශාන්ත පීතර විදුහල පරාජය කළේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා අන්තර් පාසල් රග්බි ක්‍රීඩාවට තදින්ම සම්බන්ධ නාමයක් වූ මහනුවර විද්‍යාර්ථ විද්‍යාලය ඊයේ සවස නිත්තවෙල ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදී දැවැන්ත ඝාතන සංදර්ශනයක් පවත්වමින් ලකුණු 11 කින් (උත්සාහක 1 යි දඩුවම් පහර 2 යි) ලකුණු 7 කින් විස්මයට පත් කළේය. ඔවුන්ගේ Dialog අන්තර් පාසල් රග්බි ලීග් 2022 තරගයේදී ලකුණු (1 උත්සාහක දිනුමක්, 1 පරිවර්තනයක්)",
        "මෙම තරගය තෙත් තත්ත්‍වයක් යටතේ ක්‍රීඩා කළ අතර එමඟින් පන්දු රැකීම වඩාත් දුෂ්කර වූ අතර බම්බලපිටියේ පිරිමි ළමයින් හැසිරවීමේ දෝෂ රැසකට වරදකරුවන් විය. විද්‍යාර්ථගෙත් වැරදි තිබුණත් ආගන්තුක කණ්ඩායමට වැරදුණා. ගෘහස්ථ කණ්ඩායමට අවස්ථා ලැබුණු සෑම විටම, ඔවුන් එය ප්‍රයෝජනයට ගත් අතර අත්‍යවශ්‍යයෙන්ම පීතරයින් පීඩනයට පත් කළහ.",
        "විද්‍යාර්ථ වෙනුවෙන් එකම උත්සාහක දිනුම (ප‍්‍රවර්තනය නොවූ) කලණ පේ‍්‍රමරත්න විසින් වාර්තා කරන ලදී. දෙවන අර්ධයේදී විද්‍යාර්ථ විසින් ෆුල් බැක් ක්‍රීඩක මෙනුක තිලකරත්න දඩුවම් පහර කිහිපයක් සාර්ථක කර ගැනීමට සමත් විය. පරාජිතයින් වෙනුවෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ එකම උත්සාහක දිනුම විශ්ව සිල්වා විසින් වාර්තා කරන ලද අතර එමිත් ජයවීර විසින් තරගයේ ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති ඔරලෝසුව ඔවුන් වෙත ක්‍රියාත්මක වන විට අමතර ලකුණු එක් කළේය. ප්‍රසිද්ධ විද්‍යාර්ථ ජයග්‍රහණයක් සනිටුහන් කරමින් විනිසුරු ගිහාන් යටවර තරගය අවසන් කරන විට විද්‍යාර්ථ පීතර භූමියේ ගැඹුරට රැඳී සිටියේය. ආනන්ද කස්තුරිආරච්චි ඔවුන්ගේ රග්බි අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා ලෙසින් විද්‍යාර්ථ පුහුණු කරනු ලබන්නේ නලින් විජේසිංහ විසිනි.",
        "2012 වසරේ ජේසන් දිසානායක යටතේ බම්බලපිටියේදී ශාන්ත පීතර පිලට එරෙහිව විද්‍යාර්ථ අවසන් ජයග්‍රහණය වාර්තා විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශාන්ත පීතර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "11-07",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර විද්‍යාර්ථ විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිත්තවෙල ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත පීතර විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයලොග්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බම්බලපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීතරයිට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළණ ප්‍රේමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විද්යාර්ථ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේනුකා තිලකරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්ව සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිත් ජයවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිහාන් යටවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විද්යාර්ථ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විද්යාර්ථ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද කස්තුරිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විද්යාර්ථ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත පීතර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බම්බලපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේසන් දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வித்யார்தா 11-07 என்ற கணக்கில் செயின்ட் பீட்டர்ஸை வீழ்த்தினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கண்டி வித்யார்த்த கல்லூரி, பல வருடங்களாக பாடசாலைகளுக்கு இடையிலான ரக்பி விளையாட்டுடன் வலுவாக இணைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த நித்தவெல விளையாட்டரங்கில் நேற்று மாலை மாபெரும் கொலு ஆட்டத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தி 11 புள்ளிகள் (1 முயற்சி, 2 பெனால்டிகள்) 7 என மிகவும் விரும்பப்பட்ட புனித பீற்றர் கல்லூரியை திகைக்க வைத்தது. அவர்களின் டயலொக் இன்டர் ஸ்கூல் ரக்பி லீக் 2022 என்கவுண்டரில் புள்ளிகள் (1 முயற்சி, 1 மாற்றம்).",
        "இந்த விளையாட்டு ஈரமான சூழ்நிலையில் விளையாடப்பட்டது, இது பந்தைக் கையாள்வதை மிகவும் கடினமாக்கியது மற்றும் பம்பலப்பிட்டியைச் சேர்ந்த சிறுவர்கள் பல கையாளுதல் பிழைகளில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். வித்யார்தாவுக்கும் அவர்களின் பங்குத் தவறுகள் இருந்தன, ஆனால் வருகை தரும் அணி அளவுக்கு இல்லை. சொந்த அணிக்கு வாய்ப்புகள் கிடைக்கும்போதெல்லாம், அவர்கள் அதையே பயன்படுத்தினர் மற்றும் அடிப்படையில் பீட்டரைட்ஸை அழுத்தத்திற்கு உள்ளாக்கினர்.",
        "ஹூக்கர் ஆட்டத்தின் ஆரம்பத்திலேயே முன்னோக்கி வேகத்தில் வித்யார்த்தவிற்காக ஒரே ட்ரையை (மாற்றப்படாமல்) அடித்தார் கலன பிரேமரத்ன. இரண்டாவது பாதியில் வித்யார்த்த ஃபுல் பேக், மெனுகா திலகரத்னே மூலம் இரண்டு பெனால்டிகளை வைத்தார். தோல்வியுற்றவர்களுக்கு அவர்களின் ஒரே ட்ரை விஷ்வா சில்வாவினால் அடிக்கப்பட்டது, எமித் ஜெயவீர ஆட்டத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில் கூடுதல் வீரர்களைச் சேர்த்தார். நடுவர் கிஹான் யாதவாரா ஒரு பிரபலமான வித்யார்த்தாவின் வெற்றியைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில் ஆட்டத்தை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டு வந்தபோது, ​​வித்யார்தா பீட்டரைட் பிரதேசத்தில் ஆழமாக அமர்ந்திருந்தார். ஆனந்த கஸ்தூரியாராச்சி அவர்களின் ரக்பி இயக்குனராக நளின் விஜேசிங்கவினால் வித்யார்த்த பயிற்றுவிக்கப்படுகிறார்.",
        "கடந்த 2012 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜேசன் திஸாநாயக்கவின் தலைமையில் பம்பலப்பிட்டியில் சென் பீற்றர்ஸ் அணிக்கு எதிராக வித்யார்த்த வெற்றி பெற்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "செயின்ட் பீட்டர்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "11-07",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்டி வித்யார்தா கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நித்தவெல மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித பீட்டர் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரையாடல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பம்பலப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டரைட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கலன பிரேமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வித்யார்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெனுகா திலகரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஷ்வ சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமித் ஜயவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிஹான் யாதவரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வித்யார்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வித்யார்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த கஸ்தூரியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வித்யார்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயின்ட் பீட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பம்பலப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேசன் திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}