{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/13/accusations-against-scottish-tourist-kayleigh-fraser-unjustified-slyof/",
  "time_ut": 1660385520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Accusations against Scottish tourist Kayleigh Fraser ‘unjustified’ – SLYOF",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Accusations against Scottish tourist Kayleigh Fraser ‘unjustified’ – SLYOF",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lanka Youth Overseas Federation (SLYOF) has raised concern regarding the 'mistreatment' of Scottish tourist Kayleigh Fraser by Sri Lankan Authorities.",
        "Issuing a statement, SLYOF says the accusations and investigations placed against Fraser, and intimidation tactics used by immigration authorities raises several concerns, and are unjustified.",
        "Moreover, the Sri Lanka Youth Overseas Federation has urged the Scottish Government to work on this case and urge the Sri Lankan Government to ensure her safety.",
        "It also urges the Sri Lankan Government to uphold the rule of law and democratic principals.",
        "Sri Lanka Youth Overseas Federation announced that it will launch a legal campaign in the UK, endorsed by Deena Tissera, the Scottish labour party councillor for Aberdeen, to bring this matter before the attention of the UK Parliament and to help restore justice to Kayleigh Fraser.",
        "On August 10th, the Department of Immigration and Emigration  decided to terminate the visa issued to Scottish tourist Kayleigh Fraser, who posted content with regard to the Aragalaya protest on Social Media.",
        "The Department informed her to leave Sri Lanka before the 15th",
        "On 12th August, the Scottish tourist filed a writ application with the Court of Appeal seeking an order to invalidate the decision taken by the Department of Immigration and Emigration to deport her from Sri Lanka.",
        "Will support from Opposition until Tamil people are satisfied: C.V. Wigneswaran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Scottish",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Authorities",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLYOF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Scottish Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Youth Overseas Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deena Tissera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aberdeen",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 10th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Social Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත සංචාරක Kayleigh Fraser ට එරෙහි චෝදනා 'අසාධාරණ' - SLYOF",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා තරුණ විදේශීය සම්මේලනය (SLYOF) ස්කොට්ලන්ත සංචාරක කේලී ෆ්‍රේසර්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් විසින් 'අහිතකර සැලකීම' සම්බන්ධයෙන් කනස්සල්ල පළ කර ඇත.",
        "ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් SLYOF පවසන්නේ ෆ්‍රේසර්ට එරෙහිව එල්ල වී ඇති චෝදනා සහ විමර්ශන සහ ආගමන බලධාරීන් විසින් භාවිතා කරන බිය ගැන්වීමේ උපක්‍රම ගැටළු කිහිපයක් මතු කරන අතර ඒවා සාධාරණ නොවන බවයි.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, මෙම නඩුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙසත් ඇයගේ ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින ලෙසත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ තරුණ සම්මේලනය ස්කොට්ලන්ත රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මූලධර්ම ආරක්ෂා කරන ලෙස ද එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "මෙම කාරණය එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අවධානයට යොමු කර කේලී ෆ්‍රේසර්ට යුක්තිය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට සහය වීම සඳහා ඇබර්ඩීන් හි ස්කොට්ලන්ත කම්කරු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රී ඩීනා තිසේරා විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද නීතිමය ව්‍යාපාරයක් එක්සත් රාජධානියේ දියත් කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා තරුණ විදේශ සම්මේලනය නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "අගෝස්තු 10 වන දින, ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව  සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල අරගලයා විරෝධතාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් අන්තර්ගතය පළ කළ ස්කොට්ලන්ත සංචාරක කේලී ෆ්‍රේසර් වෙත නිකුත් කර ඇති වීසා බලපත්‍රය අවසන් කිරීමට තීරණය කළේය.",
        "ලබන 15 වැනිදාට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටව යන ලෙස දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඇයට දැනුම් දුන්නා",
        "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටුවහල් කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය බලරහිත කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ස්කොට්ලන්ත ජාතික සංචාරක කාන්තාව අභියාචනාධිකරණයට රිට් අයදුම්පතක් ගොනු කළේ අගෝස්තු 12 වැනිදාය.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව තෘප්තිමත් වන තුරු විපක්ෂයේ සහය දෙනවා: සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLYOF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රේසර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තරුණ විදේශීය සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දීනා තිසේරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇබර්ඩීන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 10 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ் சுற்றுலாப் பயணி கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர் மீதான குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் 'நியாயமற்றவை' - SLYOF",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஸ்காட்லாந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணி கெய்லி பிரேசரை இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் 'தவறாக நடத்துவது' குறித்து இலங்கை இளைஞர் வெளிநாட்டு சம்மேளனம் (SLYOF) கவலை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டு, SLYOF ஃப்ரேசருக்கு எதிராக வைக்கப்படும் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் மற்றும் விசாரணைகள் மற்றும் குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகளால் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் மிரட்டல் தந்திரங்கள் பல கவலைகளை எழுப்புகின்றன, மேலும் அவை நியாயமற்றவை என்று கூறுகிறது.",
        "மேலும், இலங்கை இளைஞர் வெளிநாட்டு சம்மேளனம் ஸ்கொட்லாந்து அரசாங்கத்தை இந்த வழக்கை விசாரித்து அவரது பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறு இலங்கை அரசை வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி மற்றும் ஜனநாயகக் கோட்பாடுகளை நிலைநாட்டுமாறு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "இந்த விடயத்தை ஐக்கிய இராச்சிய பாராளுமன்றத்தின் கவனத்திற்கு கொண்டு வந்து கெய்லி பிரேசருக்கு நீதியை நிலைநாட்ட உதவுவதற்காக அபெர்டீனின் ஸ்காட்லாந்து தொழிலாளர் கட்சியின் கவுன்சிலரான தீனா திசேராவால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட சட்டப் பிரச்சாரத்தை இங்கிலாந்தில் முன்னெடுக்கவுள்ளதாக இலங்கை இளைஞர் வெளிநாட்டு சம்மேளனம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 10 ஆம் தேதி, குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வுத் திணைக்களம்  சமூக ஊடகங்களில் அரகலயா எதிர்ப்பு தொடர்பான உள்ளடக்கத்தை வெளியிட்ட ஸ்காட்டிஷ் சுற்றுலாப் பயணி கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட விசாவை நிறுத்த முடிவு செய்தது.",
        "எதிர்வரும் 15ஆம் திகதிக்கு முன்னர் இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறுமாறு திணைக்களம் அறிவித்துள்ளது",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 12 ஆம் தேதி, ஸ்காட்லாந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணி மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தில் தன்னை இலங்கையில் இருந்து நாடு கடத்துவதற்கு குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம் எடுத்த தீர்மானத்தை செல்லுபடியாக்க உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரி மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தில் மனு தாக்கல் செய்தார்.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் திருப்தி அடையும் வரை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு: சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLYOF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு இளைஞர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீனா திசேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபெர்டீன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}