{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/indian-media-and-travel-influencers-take-lead-in-supporting-sri-lankan-tourism/",
  "time_ut": 1660672620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian media and travel influencers take lead in supporting Sri Lankan tourism",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian media and travel influencers take lead in supporting Sri Lankan tourism",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Under the Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau’s Visiting Journalists & Blogger Programs, a group of high-profile Indian media personnel was invited to Sri Lanka from July 3 to July 11, to re-discover Indo-Sri Lanka historical relationships.",
        "Eight media personnel representing several key states & cities of India, including Delhi, Mumbai, Pune, Kolkata, Bangalore and Hyderabad were present. The Indian audience expected to be reached via this media promotion will be approximately 104 million across India, covering key outbound regions.",
        "Some of the key Indian national & regional publications that participated in this destination exploration were, Lokmat (Print – daily), Daily Sagar (Language – Marathi), India Blooms News Service (indiablooms.com), Mumbai Messenger (Language- Hindi), India Tribune (Language – English), Daily Do baje Dopaha (Language Hindi).",
        "Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau (SLTPB), the national government agency for International tourism promotions undertook this timely initiative to generate a positive destination brand image about Sri Lanka, while showcasing the welcoming approach of tourism stakeholders in Sri Lanka.",
        "With the current economic downturn the country is facing, neighboring Indian tourists will be the first adventurous traveler segment to visit Sri Lanka on holidays and other tourism & leisure purposes. Yet, they are expecting real-life updates from Sri Lanka to know how travel is feasible. SLTPB invited the above mainstream Indian publications as well as a group of well-established travel influencers to have a naked-eye look at the island mainly through travel and to show them how important it is for tourism to be kept alive for the betterment of well over 2 million Sri Lankans who are involved in it. Also, this promotional exercise is expected to provide an assurance about hassle-free travel in Sri Lanka and update tourism stakeholders on recent policy actions taken by the Ministry of Tourism to offer uninterrupted tourism services (eg: fuel).",
        "For fellow Indian travelers, there are hundreds of reasons to select Sri Lanka as the best holiday getaway out of all regional destinations. With the currency variance, traveling to Sri Lanka right now makes ‘’The Read Deal’’ for Indian tourists. Also, with less cultural shock and more familiar things (food, weather, culture) just like back in India, Sri Lanka is like a perfect holiday home located within a very short distance with frequent flights covering many states.",
        "Visiting Indian media & influencers delegation expects to further promote Sri Lanka as one of the best tourist destinations in the region for potential Indian travel segments, including family travelers, honeymooners, business travel & weekend quick break holiday seekers, wedding & MICE, young solo travel and pilgrims – Ramayana & Buddhist Trail.",
        "To welcome this high-profile Indian media delegation, SLTPB together with Galle Face Hotel Colombo and Walkers Tours organized an evening welcoming event on July 4.",
        "Together with Minister of Tourism Harin Fernado, chairman SLTPB Chalaka Gajabahu, Managing Director SLTPB Ms. Padma Siriwardena, Director Public Relations STPB Ms. Madubhani Perera, Assistant Director Public Relations Chaminda Munasinghe warmly welcomed the Indian media delegation to Sri Lanka.",
        "Officials from the Indian High Commission of Sri Lanka, members of the Sri Lanka Association of Inbound Tour Operators Association (SLAITO) and key Indian entrepreneurs in Sri Lanka also participated in this event. During the event, they shared positive views about the tourism industry in Sri Lanka and the support they seek from India’s outbound tourism industry for a speedy recovery.",
        "The Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka also welcomed the media delegation and Eldos Mathew Punnoose – First Secretary for Press and Information, Development Corporation shared the High Commission’s views on supporting the Sri Lankan tourism industry and on improving trade and social developments in Sri Lanka.",
        "Hela Apparel Holdings marks an impressive start to FY 2022/23",
        "Nations Trust Bank records steady performance in 1st half 2022 amidst challenging market conditions",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau’s Visiting Journalists & Blogger Programs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 3 to July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indo-Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pune, Kolkata",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hyderabad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 104 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lokmat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Print",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Sagar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India Blooms News Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai Messenger",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Language- Hindi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India Tribune",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dopaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Language Hindi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTPB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the national government agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Tourism",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "& weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramayana & Buddhist Trail",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Hotel Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walkers Tours",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tourism Harin Fernado",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTPB Chalaka Gajabahu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Padma Siriwardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madubhani Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Munasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Association of Inbound Tour Operators Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mathew Punnoose",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Press and Information, Development Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hela Apparel Holdings marks",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nations Trust Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st half 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියානු මාධ්‍ය සහ සංචාරක බලපෑම් කරන්නන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයට සහාය වීම සඳහා පෙරමුණ ගනී",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau’s Visiting Journalists & Blogger Programs යටතේ, ඉන්දු-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඓතිහාසික සබඳතා යළි සොයාගැනීම සඳහා ඉහළ පෙළේ ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පිරිසකට ජූලි 3 සිට ජූලි 11 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආරාධනා කරන ලදී.",
        "දිල්ලි, මුම්බායි, පූනේ, කොල්කටා, බැංගලෝර් සහ හයිද්‍රාබාද් ඇතුළු ඉන්දියාවේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රාන්ත සහ නගර කිහිපයක් නියෝජනය කරමින් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අට දෙනෙක් පැමිණ සිටියහ. මෙම මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රවර්ධනය හරහා ළඟා වීමට අපේක්ෂිත ඉන්දියානු ප්‍රේක්ෂකයින් ප්‍රධාන පිටතට යන ප්‍රදේශ ආවරණය කරමින් ඉන්දියාව පුරා දළ වශයෙන් මිලියන 104 ක් වනු ඇත.",
        "මෙම ගමනාන්ත ගවේෂණයට සහභාගී වූ ප්‍රධාන ඉන්දියානු ජාතික සහ කලාපීය ප්‍රකාශන සමහරක් වූයේ, Lokmat (මුද්‍රණය - දිනපතා), Daily Sagar (භාෂාව - මරාති), India Blooms News Service (indiablooms.com), මුම්බායි මැසෙන්ජර් (භාෂාව- හින්දි), ඉන්දියා ට්‍රිබියුන් (භාෂාව - ඉංග්‍රීසි), ඩේලි දෝ බජේ ඩොපහා (භාෂා හින්දි).",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන ජාතික රාජ්‍ය ආයතනය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය (SLTPB) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ පිළිගැනීමේ ප්‍රවේශය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ ධනාත්මක ගමනාන්ත සන්නාම ප්‍රතිරූපයක් ජනනය කිරීම සඳහා මෙම කාලෝචිත මුලපිරීම සිදු කළේය.",
        "රට මුහුණ දී සිටින වත්මන් ආර්ථික අවපාතයත් සමඟ අසල්වැසි ඉන්දියානු සංචාරකයින් නිවාඩු දින සහ වෙනත් සංචාරක සහ විවේක කටයුතු සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන පළමු වික්‍රමාන්විත සංචාරක අංශය වනු ඇත. එහෙත්, ඔවුන් සංචාරය කළ හැකි ආකාරය දැන ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් සැබෑ ජීවිතයේ යාවත්කාලීන බලාපොරොත්තු වේ. SLTPB ඉහත ප්‍රධාන ධාරාවේ ඉන්දියානු ප්‍රකාශනවලට මෙන්ම හොඳින් ස්ථාපිත සංචාරක බලපෑම්කරුවන් පිරිසකට ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් සංචාර හරහා දිවයින දෙස පියවි ඇසින් බැලීමට සහ ළිඳේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය ජීවමානව තබා ගැනීම කොතරම් වැදගත්ද යන්න පෙන්වීමට ආරාධනා කළේය. මිලියන 2කට අධික ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෝ ඊට සම්බන්ධ වෙති. එසේම, මෙම ප්‍රවර්ධන අභ්‍යාසය මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කරදරයකින් තොරව ගමන් කිරීම පිළිබඳ සහතිකයක් ලබා දීමටත් සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් අඛණ්ඩ සංචාරක සේවා (උදා: ඉන්ධන) ලබා දීම සඳහා මෑතකාලීන ප්‍රතිපත්ති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව සංචාරක පාර්ශවකරුවන් යාවත්කාලීන කිරීමටත් අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "සෙසු ඉන්දියානු සංචාරකයින් සඳහා, සියලුම කලාපීය ගමනාන්තයන් අතරින් හොඳම නිවාඩු නිකේතනය ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තෝරා ගැනීමට හේතු සිය ගණනක් ඇත. මුදල් විචලනයත් සමඟ, දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගමන් කිරීම ඉන්දියානු සංචාරකයින් සඳහා ‘‘The Read Deal’’ බවට පත් කරයි. එසේම, අඩු සංස්කෘතික කම්පනයක් සහ වඩාත් හුරුපුරුදු දේවල් (ආහාර, කාලගුණය, සංස්කෘතිය) සමඟින්, ඉන්දියාවේ මෙන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බොහෝ ප්‍රාන්ත ආවරණය වන නිරන්තර ගුවන් ගමන් සමඟ ඉතා කෙටි දුරක් තුළ පිහිටා ඇති පරිපූර්ණ නිවාඩු නිකේතනයක් වැනි ය.",
        "සංචාරය කරන ඉන්දියානු මාධ්‍ය සහ බලපෑම් දූත පිරිස, පවුලේ සංචාරකයින්, මධුසමය ගත කරන්නන්, ව්‍යාපාරික සංචාර සහ සති අන්ත ඉක්මන් විවේක නිවාඩු සොයන්නන්, විවාහ මංගල්‍යය සහ MICE, තරුණ ඒකල සංචාර ඇතුළු විභව ඉන්දියානු සංචාර කොටස් සඳහා කලාපයේ හොඳම සංචාරක ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තවදුරටත් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරයි. සහ වන්දනාකරුවන් - රාමායනය සහ බෞද්ධ මාවත.",
        "මෙම ඉහළ පෙළේ ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය දූත පිරිස පිළිගැනීම සඳහා, SLTPB Galle Face Hotel Colombo සහ Walkers Tours සමඟ එක්ව ජූලි 4 වැනිදා සවස පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයක් සංවිධානය කළේය.",
        "සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, SLTPB සභාපති චලක ගජබාහු, SLTPB කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ පද්මා සිරිවර්ධන, මහජන සම්බන්ධතා STPB අධ්‍යක්ෂ මධුභානි පෙරේරා, සහකාර මහජන සම්බන්ධතා අධ්‍යක්ෂ චමින්ද මුණසිංහ යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් සමඟ ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය දූත පිරිස උණුසුම් අයුරින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ නිලධාරීන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමයේ (SLAITO) සාමාජිකයින් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින ප්‍රධාන ඉන්දීය ව්‍යවසායකයින් ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගී වූහ. මෙම අවස්ථාවෙහිදී, ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය සහ ඉක්මන් ප්‍රකෘතියක් සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ පිටතට යන සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයෙන් අපේක්ෂා කරන සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව ධනාත්මක අදහස් බෙදාහදා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ද මාධ්‍ය දූත පිරිස සාදරයෙන් පිළිගත් අතර සංවර්ධන සංස්ථාවේ පුවත්පත් සහ තොරතුරු පිළිබඳ ප්‍රථම ලේකම් එල්ඩෝස් මැතිව් පුන්නූස් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයට සහය වීම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙළෙඳ සහ සමාජ ප්‍රවර්ධන වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම පිළිබඳ මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයාගේ අදහස් බෙදා ගත්තේය.",
        "Hela Apparel Holdings 2022/23 FY සඳහා ආකර්ෂණීය ආරම්භයක් සනිටුහන් කරයි",
        "නේෂන්ස් ට්‍රස්ට් බැංකුව අභියෝගාත්මක වෙළෙඳපොළ තත්ත්වයන් මධ්‍යයේ 2022 පළමු භාගයේදී ස්ථාවර කාර්ය සාධනයක් වාර්තා කරයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශයේ ආගන්තුක මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සහ Blogger වැඩසටහන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 3 සිට ජූලි 11 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දු-ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූනේ, කොල්කටා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හයිද්රාබාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 104 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක්මාත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුද්‍රණය කරන්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි සාගර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියා බ්ලූම්ස් පුවත් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි මැසෙන්ජර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාෂාව - හින්දි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියා ට්‍රිබියුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොපහා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාෂාව හින්දි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTPB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රාජ්ය ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහ සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමායනය සහ බෞද්ධ මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ගාලු මුවදොර හෝටලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝකර්ස් චාරිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tourism Harin Fernado",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTPB චාලක ගජබාහු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පද්මා සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධුභානි පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද මුණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිව් පුන්නූස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුවත්පත් සහ තොරතුරු, සංවර්ධන සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙළ ඇපරල් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් ලකුණු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නේෂන්ස් ට්‍රස්ට් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் பயண செல்வாக்கு செலுத்துபவர்கள் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாவை ஆதரிப்பதில் முன்னணியில் உள்ளனர்",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகத்தின் வருகை தரும் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் பிளாகர் நிகழ்ச்சிகளின் கீழ், இந்திய-இலங்கை வரலாற்று உறவுகளை மீண்டும் கண்டறிய ஜூலை 3 முதல் ஜூலை 11 வரை உயர்மட்ட இந்திய ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் குழு ஒன்று இலங்கைக்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "டெல்லி, மும்பை, புனே, கொல்கத்தா, பெங்களூர் மற்றும் ஹைதராபாத் உட்பட இந்தியாவின் பல முக்கிய மாநிலங்கள் மற்றும் நகரங்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் எட்டு ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் கலந்து கொண்டனர். இந்த மீடியா விளம்பரத்தின் மூலம் இந்திய பார்வையாளர்களை சென்றடைவார்கள் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் இந்திய பார்வையாளர்கள், வெளிச்செல்லும் முக்கிய பகுதிகளை உள்ளடக்கி, இந்தியா முழுவதும் சுமார் 104 மில்லியனாக இருப்பார்கள்.",
        "இந்த இலக்கு ஆய்வில் பங்கேற்ற சில முக்கிய இந்திய தேசிய மற்றும் பிராந்திய வெளியீடுகள், லோக்மத் (அச்சு - தினசரி), டெய்லி சாகர் (மொழி - மராத்தி), இந்தியா ப்ளூம்ஸ் செய்தி சேவை (indiablooms.com), மும்பை மெசஞ்சர் (மொழி- இந்தி), இந்தியா ட்ரிப்யூன் (மொழி - ஆங்கிலம்), டெய்லி டோ பஜே டோபஹா (மொழி இந்தி).",
        "சர்வதேச சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்புக்கான தேசிய அரசாங்க நிறுவனமான இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகம் (SLTPB) இலங்கையில் உள்ள சுற்றுலாப் பங்குதாரர்களின் வரவேற்பு அணுகுமுறையை வெளிப்படுத்தும் அதேவேளை, இலங்கையைப் பற்றிய நேர்மறையான இலக்கு வர்த்தக முத்திரையை உருவாக்குவதற்கான இந்த சரியான நேரத்தில் முயற்சியை மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியுடன், அண்டை இந்திய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் விடுமுறை மற்றும் பிற சுற்றுலா மற்றும் ஓய்வு நோக்கங்களுக்காக இலங்கைக்கு வரும் முதல் சாகசப் பயணிகள் பிரிவாக இருப்பார்கள். ஆயினும்கூட, பயணம் எவ்வாறு சாத்தியமாகும் என்பதை அறிய இலங்கையிலிருந்து நிஜ வாழ்க்கை புதுப்பிப்புகளை அவர்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கின்றனர். SLTPB மேற்கூறிய முக்கிய இந்திய வெளியீடுகளையும் நன்கு நிறுவப்பட்ட பயண செல்வாக்கு செலுத்துபவர்களின் குழுவையும் முக்கியமாக பயணத்தின் மூலம் தீவை நிர்வாணக் கண்ணால் பார்க்கவும், சுற்றுலாவை நன்றாக மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு உயிருடன் வைத்திருப்பது எவ்வளவு முக்கியம் என்பதைக் காட்டவும் அழைத்தது. 2 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான இலங்கையர்கள் இதில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். மேலும், இந்த ஊக்குவிப்புப் பயிற்சியானது இலங்கையில் தொந்தரவில்லாத பயணம் பற்றிய உத்தரவாதத்தை அளிக்கும் என்றும், தடையற்ற சுற்றுலா சேவைகளை (எ.கா: எரிபொருள்) வழங்குவதற்கு சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகத்தால் எடுக்கப்பட்ட சமீபத்திய கொள்கை நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து சுற்றுலாப் பங்குதாரர்களுக்குப் புதுப்பிப்பதற்கும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சக இந்தியப் பயணிகளுக்கு, அனைத்து பிராந்திய இடங்களிலிருந்தும் இலங்கையை சிறந்த விடுமுறை இடமாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கு நூற்றுக்கணக்கான காரணங்கள் உள்ளன. நாணய மாறுபாட்டுடன், இப்போது இலங்கைக்கு பயணம் செய்வது இந்திய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளுக்கு ‘’தி ரீட் டீல்’’ செய்கிறது. மேலும், இந்தியாவைப் போலவே குறைவான கலாச்சார அதிர்ச்சி மற்றும் மிகவும் பழக்கமான விஷயங்களுடன் (உணவு, வானிலை, கலாச்சாரம்) இலங்கை, பல மாநிலங்களை உள்ளடக்கிய அடிக்கடி விமானங்களுடன் மிகக் குறுகிய தூரத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள ஒரு சரியான விடுமுறை இல்லம் போன்றது.",
        "வருகை தரும் இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் செல்வாக்கு மிக்க பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு, குடும்பப் பயணிகள், தேனிலவு, வணிகப் பயணம் மற்றும் வார இறுதி விரைவு இடைவேளை விடுமுறை தேடுபவர்கள், திருமணம் மற்றும் MICE, இளம் தனிப் பயணம் உள்ளிட்ட இந்தியப் பயணப் பிரிவுகளுக்கான சிறந்த சுற்றுலாத் தலங்களில் ஒன்றாக இலங்கையை மேலும் மேம்படுத்த எதிர்பார்க்கிறது. மற்றும் யாத்ரீகர்கள் - ராமாயணம் & புத்த பாதை.",
        "இந்த உயர்மட்ட இந்திய ஊடகக் குழுவை வரவேற்பதற்காக, SLTPB Galle Face Hotel Colombo மற்றும் Walkers Tours உடன் இணைந்து ஜூலை 4 அன்று மாலை வரவேற்பு நிகழ்வை ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தது.",
        "சுற்றுலா அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாடோ, SLTPB தலைவர் சாலக கஜபாஹு, SLTPB முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் திருமதி பத்மா சிறிவர்தன, மக்கள் தொடர்பு பணிப்பாளர் திருமதி மதுபானி பெரேரா, உதவிப் பணிப்பாளர் மக்கள் தொடர்புகள் சமிந்த முனசிங்க ஆகியோர் இலங்கை வந்துள்ள இந்திய ஊடகக் குழுவை அன்புடன் வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் இலங்கையின் இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் அதிகாரிகள், இலங்கை உள்வரும் சுற்றுலா செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் (SLAITO) உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் இலங்கையிலுள்ள முக்கிய இந்திய தொழில்முனைவோர்களும் கலந்துகொண்டனர். இந்த நிகழ்வின் போது, ​​இலங்கையில் உள்ள சுற்றுலாத் துறை மற்றும் விரைவான மீட்சிக்காக இந்தியாவின் வெளிச்செல்லும் சுற்றுலாத் துறையின் ஆதரவைப் பற்றி அவர்கள் நேர்மறையான கருத்துக்களைப் பகிர்ந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ஊடகக் குழுவை வரவேற்றதுடன், பத்திரிகை மற்றும் தகவல், அபிவிருத்திக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் முதன்மைச் செயலாளர் எல்டோஸ் மேத்யூ புன்னூஸ், இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத் துறைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது மற்றும் இலங்கையில் வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் சமூக அபிவிருத்திகளை மேம்படுத்துவது தொடர்பான உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் கருத்துக்களைப் பகிர்ந்துகொண்டார்.",
        "ஹெலா அப்பேரல் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் 2022/23 நிதியாண்டில் சிறப்பான தொடக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கிறது",
        "நேஷன்ஸ் டிரஸ்ட் வங்கி சவாலான சந்தை நிலைமைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் 2022 முதல் பாதியில் நிலையான செயல்திறனை பதிவு செய்கிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகத்தின் வருகை தரும் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் பிளாகர் நிகழ்ச்சிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 3 முதல் ஜூலை 11 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய-இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனே, கொல்கத்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹைதராபாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 104 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோக்மத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அச்சிடுக",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி சாகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா ப்ளூம்ஸ் செய்தி சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை தூதுவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொழி - இந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா ட்ரிப்யூன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோபஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொழி இந்தி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTPB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அரசு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "& வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமாயணம் & புத்த பாதை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Hotel Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாக்கர்ஸ் டூர்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tourism Harin Fernado",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTPB சாலக கஜபாஹு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்மா சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுபானி பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த முனசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்வரும் சுற்றுலா நடத்துநர்கள் சங்கத்தின் இலங்கை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேத்யூ புன்னூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரிக்கை மற்றும் தகவல், வளர்ச்சிக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hela Apparel Holdings மதிப்பெண்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேஷன்ஸ் டிரஸ்ட் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}