{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සජිත්--බුද්ධිකට-ලොකු-වැඩක්-පවරයි/101-615643",
  "time_ut": 1656574938,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත්, බුද්ධිකට ලොකු වැඩක් පවරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith assigns a big task to Buddhi",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Matara District Parliamentarian Buddhika Pathirana has been appointed as the General Secretary of the Secretariat, which has been set up by the Leader of the Opposition's National Program to implement the social reforms demanded by the people.",
        "The appointment was made by Leader of the Opposition Sajith Primadasa.",
        "MP Buddhika Pathirana said that this Secretariat was established to create a modern Sri Lanka with the aim of finding solutions to the severe economic, political and social crisis facing Sri Lanka today.",
        "The purpose of this Secretariat is to reach an agreement for the social transformation demanded by the people and to establish a national program for social reform, said Mr. Buddhika Pathirana."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Buddhi",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhika Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Primadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddhika Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhika Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත්, බුද්ධිකට ලොකු වැඩක් පවරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතාව ඉල්ලන සමාජ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ඉටුකිරීම සඳහා විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයෙන් පිහිටවූ ජාතික වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සැකසීමේ මහලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ලෙස මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී බුද්ධික පතිරණ මහතා පත්කර තිබේ.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් මෙම පත් කිරීම සිදු කර තිබේ.",
        "වර්තමානයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දෙන දරුණු ආර්ථික දේශපාලන හා සමාජය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීමේ අරමුණ ඇතිව නුතනවාදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක් බිහි කිරීම සඳහා මෙම මහලේකම් කාර්යාලය පිහිටුවා ඇතැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී බුද්ධික පතිරණ මහතා පැවසීය .",
        "ජනතාව විසින් ඉල්ලා සිටින  සමාජ පරිවර්තනය උදෙසා එකඟතාවයක් ඇතිකර ගැනීම සහ සමාජ  ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා ජාතික වැඩපිළිවෙළ ස්ථාපිත කිරීම මෙම  මහලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ අරමුණ බව ද බුද්ධික පතිරණ මහතා සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බුද්ධි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධික පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රිමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධික පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධික පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித் புத்திகாவுக்கு பெரிய வேலை கொடுக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்கள் கோரும் சமூக சீர்திருத்தங்களை நிறைவேற்றும் வகையில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தினால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட தேசிய வேலைத்திட்டத்தை தயாரிப்பதற்காக மாத்தறை மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.புத்திக பத்திரன அவர்கள் செயலாளர் நாயகத்தின் பிரதம செயலாளராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிறமதாசவினால் இந்த நியமனம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை இன்று எதிர்நோக்கும் கடுமையான பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் நோக்கில் நவீன இலங்கையை உருவாக்கும் நோக்கில் இந்த செயலகம் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் புத்திக பத்திரன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மக்கள் கோரும் சமூக மாற்றத்துக்கான இணக்கப்பாடு மற்றும் சமூக சீர்திருத்தத்திற்கான தேசிய வேலைத்திட்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவதே இந்த செயலகத்தின் நோக்கமாகும் என திரு.புத்திக பத்திரன தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புத்தி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்திக பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்திக பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்திக பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}