{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/21/egg-distribution-suspended/",
  "time_ut": 1661057160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Egg distribution suspended",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Egg distribution suspended",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's Association says that the distribution of eggs has been suspended in protest against the imposition of a maximum retail price for eggs.",
        "Its Chairman, Ajith Gunasekara said that it is not possible to distribute eggs at a loss.",
        "He further stated that it costs around Rs. 2/- to transport a single egg, which has not been factored into the MRP, and the businessmen cannot distribute at a loss.",
        "Gunasekara alleged that the imposition of the MRP was done without much investigations into egg sales, as the gazette notification stipulates for eggs within cartons too to be sold at the MRP.",
        "He added that further discussions with authorities are necessary on the matter.",
        "A maximum retail price of Rs 43/- was imposed for a white egg with effect from midnight yesterday (20).",
        "The maximum retail price of a brown and red eggs are Rs. 45/-.",
        "NTC to take action against over 100 buses for overcharging passengers"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Egg",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "midnight yesterday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිත්තර බෙදා හැරීම අත්හිටුවා ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බිත්තර සඳහා උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලක් පැනවීමට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් බිත්තර බෙදා හැරීම අත්හිටුවා ඇති බව සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "එහි සභාපති අජිත් ගුණසේකර කියා සිටියේ පාඩු පිට බිත්තර බෙදා හැරීමේ හැකියාවක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ඒ සඳහා රු. 2/- MRP වලට සාදක කර නොමැති තනි බිත්තරයක් ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට සහ ව්‍යාපාරිකයින්ට පාඩු පිට බෙදා හැරිය නොහැක.",
        "පෙට්ටි තුළ ඇති බිත්තර ද එම්ආර්පී මිලට අලෙවි කළ යුතු බවට ගැසට් නිවේදනයේ දක්වා ඇති බැවින් බිත්තර අලෙවිය පිළිබඳ වැඩි විමර්ශනයකින් තොරව එම්ආර්පී පැනවීම සිදු කළ බවට ගුණසේකර චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් බලධාරීන් සමඟ තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම අවශ්‍ය බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඊයේ (20) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි සුදු බිත්තරයක් සඳහා රුපියල් 43/- ක උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලක් පනවා තිබේ.",
        "දුඹුරු සහ රතු බිත්තරයක උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල රු. 45/-කි.",
        "මගීන්ගෙන් අධික ගාස්තු අයකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බස් රථ 100කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවකට එරෙහිව පියවර ගැනීමට NTC"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බිත්තරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MRP",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முட்டை விநியோகம் நிறுத்தப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முட்டைக்கு அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை விதிக்கப்பட்டதற்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து முட்டை விநியோகம் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை கோழிப்பண்ணை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நஷ்டத்தில் முட்டைகளை விநியோகிக்க முடியாது என அதன் தலைவர் அஜித் குணசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், இதற்கு சுமார் ரூ. 2/- ஒரு முட்டையை கொண்டு செல்ல, MRP யில் காரணியாக இல்லை, மற்றும் வணிகர்கள் நஷ்டத்தில் விநியோகிக்க முடியாது.",
        "வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பில் அட்டைப்பெட்டிகளுக்குள் முட்டைகளை எம்ஆர்பி விலையில் விற்க வேண்டும் என்று குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதால், முட்டை விற்பனை குறித்து அதிக விசாரணைகள் இல்லாமல், எம்ஆர்பி விதித்துள்ளதாக குணசேகர குற்றம்சாட்டினார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பாக அதிகாரிகளுடன் மேலும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவது அவசியம் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "நேற்று (20) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் வெள்ளை முட்டை ஒன்றின் அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை 43 ரூபாவாக நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு பழுப்பு மற்றும் சிவப்பு முட்டையின் அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை ரூ. 45/-.",
        "பயணிகளிடம் அதிக கட்டணம் வசூலித்த 100க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பேருந்துகள் மீது என்டிசி நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "முட்டை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் குணசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஆர்.பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஆர்.பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஆர்.பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}