{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83391/sri-lankan-national-held-with-gold-in-chennai-airport",
  "time_ut": 1656786300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan national held with gold in Chennai airport",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan national held with gold in Chennai airport",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Over two kilograms of gold worth 9.85 million Indian rupees was seized at the domestic airport in Chennai and a Sri Lankan national was arrested in this connection, the Customs department of India said on Saturday.",
        "Acting on specific inputs, the officials intercepted the passenger who arrived in Chennai from Mumbai on Friday and recovered 11 bundles of foreign-origin gold paste concealed in his baggage, an official release said.",
        "The gold weighed 2.13 kilograms worth INR 98.55 lakh and was seized under relevant sections of the Customs Act, 1962 of India. The passenger was arrested, Indian media reported."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two kilograms",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.85 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.13 kilograms",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "98.55",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Customs Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1962",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චෙන්නායි ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී රන් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය රුපියල් මිලියන 9.85ක් වටිනා රත්‍රං කිලෝග්‍රෑම් දෙකකට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් චෙන්නායි හි අභ්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ඉන්දීය රේගු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සෙනසුරාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "නිශ්චිත යෙදවුම් මත ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ නිලධාරීන් සිකුරාදා මුම්බායි සිට චෙන්නායි වෙත පැමිණි මගියා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අතර ඔහුගේ ගමන් මලුවල සඟවා තිබූ විදේශීය සම්භවයක් ඇති රන් පේස්ට් මිටි 11 ක් සොයා ගත් බව නිල නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "ඉන්දීය රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 98.55ක් වටිනා මෙම රත්‍රන් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 2.13ක් බරැති අතර 1962 ඉන්දියාවේ රේගු පනතේ අදාළ වගන්ති යටතේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. මගියා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "චෙන්නායි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් දෙකක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9.85 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 2.13 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "98.55 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1962",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சென்னை விமான நிலையத்தில் தங்கத்துடன் இலங்கை பிரஜை கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சென்னையில் உள்ள உள்நாட்டு விமான நிலையத்தில் 9.85 மில்லியன் இந்திய ரூபா பெறுமதியான இரண்டு கிலோகிராம் தங்கம் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், இது தொடர்பாக இலங்கை பிரஜை ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இந்திய சுங்கத் திணைக்களம் சனிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குறிப்பிட்ட உள்ளீடுகளின் அடிப்படையில், மும்பையில் இருந்து வெள்ளிக்கிழமை சென்னை வந்த பயணியை அதிகாரிகள் தடுத்து நிறுத்தி, அவரது சாமான்களில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 11 மூட்டை வெளிநாட்டு தங்க பேஸ்ட்டை மீட்டனர்.",
        "98.55 லட்சம் மதிப்பிலான 2.13 கிலோ எடையுள்ள தங்கம், இந்திய சுங்கச் சட்டம், 1962ன் தொடர்புடைய பிரிவுகளின் கீழ் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டது. பயணி கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "சென்னை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு கிலோகிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.85 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.13 கிலோகிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "98.55",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1962",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}