{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බෙම්මුල්ලේ-වෙඩි-තැබීමකින්-කොළඹ-වෙඩික්කරු-මරුට/101-615807",
  "time_ut": 1656902129,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බෙම්මුල්ලේ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් කොළඹ වෙඩික්කරු මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo shooter killed in Bemmulla shooting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Thilakaratne Dissanayake and Ananda Jayakodi and Bimal Shyaman Jayasinghe)",
        "Police say that an underworld member who is said to be the shooter in the incident of shooting and killing two people at Bastion Mawatha in Colombo has been shot dead in Gampaha Bemmulla area.",
        "According to the police, a 41-year-old man named Joseph Kumara, a resident of Alpitiya area, has died.",
        "According to the information received by the Colombo Crime Division that the deceased shooter is in the Gampaha area, during the search operation in the area this morning, the police found the suspect while traveling on a motorcycle and at the same time, a police officer said that the T-56 firearm that the suspect was hiding had been shot at the van the police were traveling in.",
        "The police said that the suspect was seriously injured in the attack by the police and died after being admitted to the Gampaha hospital."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bemmulla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thilakaratne Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananda Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bimal Shyaman Jayasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bastion Mawatha in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha Bemmulla",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alpitiya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බෙම්මුල්ලේ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් කොළඹ වෙඩික්කරු මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "( තිලකරත්න දිසානායක සහ ආනන්ද ජයකොඩි සහ බිමල් ශ්‍යාමන් ජයසිංහ)",
        "කොළඹ බැස්ටියන් මාවතේ දී පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙකුට වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කිරීමේ සිද්ධියේ වෙඩික්කරු  බව කියන පාතාල සාමාජිකයකු ගම්පහ බෙම්මුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් මියගොස් ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ මියගොස්ටි ඇත්තේ ඇල්පිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු වන ඉහළ විතානගේ ජෝශප් කුමාර නමැති 41 හැවිරිදි අයෙකු මිය ගොස් ඇති බවද පොලීසිය සදහන් කරයි.",
        "මියගිය වෙඩිකරු ගම්පහ ප්‍රදේශයේ සිටින බවට කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශයට ලද තොරතුරක් අනුව අද අළුයම එම ප්‍රදේශයේ කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමේදී සැකකරු යතුරුපැදියකින් ගමන් කරමින් සිටියදී පොලිසියට හමුවී ඇති අතර ඒ සමඟම සැකකරු සඟවාගෙන සිටි ටී 56 ගිනි අවියෙන් පොලිසිය ගමන්ගත් ගමන් ගත් වෑන් රථයට වෙඩි තබා ඇතැයි පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙක් පැවැසීය.",
        "පෙරළා පොලීසිය සිදුකළ ප්‍රහාරයේදී සැකකරු බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා ගම්පහ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව මියගොස් බවත් සැකකරු කළ වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසයේ  නිලධාරීන් ගමන් ගත් වෑන් රථයට අලාභ සිදු වී ඇති බවත් පොලිසිය කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බෙම්මුල්ල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තිලකරත්න දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිමල් ශ් යාමන් ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ බෙම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝශප් කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්පිටිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெமுல்ல துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் கொழும்பு துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு வீரர் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(திலகரத்ன திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் ஆனந்த ஜெயக்கொடி மற்றும் பிமல் ஷியமன் ஜயசிங்க)",
        "கொழும்பு, பஸ்டன் மாவத்தையில் இருவரை சுட்டுக் கொன்ற சம்பவத்தில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் எனக் கூறப்படும் பாதாள உலக உறுப்பினர் கம்பஹா பெம்முல்ல பிரதேசத்தில் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அல்பிட்டிய பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த ஜோசப் குமார என்ற 41 வயதுடைய நபரே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சுட்டுக்கொல்லப்பட்டவர் கம்பஹா பிரதேசத்தில் இருப்பதாக கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் பிரகாரம், இன்று காலை அப்பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​சந்தேக நபர் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் பயணித்த போது, ​​பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர் ஒருவரும் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். சந்தேகநபர் மறைத்து வைத்திருந்த T-56 துப்பாக்கியால் பொலிஸார் பயணித்த வேன் மீது சுடப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பொலிஸாரின் தாக்குதலில் சந்தேக நபர் பலத்த காயமடைந்து கம்பஹா வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பெம்முல்லா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திலகரத்ன திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிமல் ஷியமன் ஜெயசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பஸ்டன் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா பெமுல்ல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}