{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Pfizer-vaccination-centres-at-CMC-today/108-241407",
  "time_ut": 1658287748,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pfizer vaccination centres at CMC today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pfizer vaccination centres at CMC today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Regional Epidemiologist Dr. Dinu Guruge today requested those who are over 20 years of age to get the COVID-19 vaccine dose against the virus from the CMC Vaccination Centres today.",
        "She said the people who are eligible to get the vaccine should be over 20 years of age and should have completed three months since their last COVID jab.",
        "The people are advised to visit the MOH Office at Ginthupitiya, MCH and MOH office at Deans Road, New Bazaar Maternity Home, MOH office at Wellawatte, Campbell Park and MOH Office at Kirula Road to get their first, second, third and fourth Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine doses from 9:00 am to 1:00 pm today.",
        "However, the health ministry said the fourth dose is recommended for people between 20 and 60 years of age and for those with immunodeficiency and chronic disorders. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CMC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the MOH Office at Ginthupitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MCH",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deans Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawatte",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Campbell Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "MOH Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirula Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9:00 am to 1:00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the health ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 20 and 60 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද CMC හි Pfizer එන්නත් මධ්‍යස්ථාන",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ ප්‍රාදේශීය වසංගත රෝග විද්‍යාඥ වෛද්‍ය දිනු ගුරුගේ මහතා වයස අවුරුදු 20ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින්ගෙන් වෛරසයට එරෙහි COVID-19 එන්නත් මාත්‍රාව අද CMC එන්නත් මධ්‍යස්ථානවලින් ලබා ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "එන්නත ලබා ගැනීමට සුදුසුකම් ලබන පුද්ගලයින් වයස අවුරුදු 20 ට වැඩි විය යුතු අතර ඔවුන්ගේ අවසන් කොවිඩ් රෝගයෙන් මාස තුනක් සම්පූර්ණ කර තිබිය යුතු බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "පළමු, දෙවන, තෙවන සහ සිව්වන ෆයිසර් කොවිඩ් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ගින්තුපිටියේ MOH කාර්යාලය, MCH සහ ඩීන්ස් පාරේ MOH කාර්යාලය, නව බසාර් මාතෘ නිවාසය, වැල්ලවත්තේ MOH කාර්යාලය, කැම්බල් පාර්ක් සහ කිරුළ පාරේ MOH කාර්යාලය වෙත පැමිණෙන ලෙස ජනතාවට උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ. -19 එන්නත් මාත්‍රා අද පෙරවරු 9.00 සිට පස්වරු 1.00 දක්වා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය පැවසුවේ සිව්වන මාත්‍රාව වයස අවුරුදු 20 ත් 60 ත් අතර පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා සහ ප්‍රතිශක්ති ඌනතා සහ නිදන්ගත ආබාධ සහිත පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා නිර්දේශ කරන බවයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CMC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 20 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 20 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිංතුපිටිය MOH කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MCH",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීන්ස් පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැම්බල් උද්‍යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "MOH කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරුළ පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9:00 සිට 1:00 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 20 සහ 60 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று CMC இல் ஃபைசர் தடுப்பூசி மையங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்கள் கோவிட்-19 தடுப்பூசி மருந்தை CMC தடுப்பூசி மையங்களில் இருந்து பெற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறு கொழும்பு பிராந்திய தொற்றுநோய் நிபுணர் டாக்டர் டினு குருகே இன்று வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "தடுப்பூசியைப் பெறத் தகுதியுடையவர்கள் 20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்களாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும், அவர்களின் கடைசி கோவிட் ஜப் முதல் மூன்று மாதங்கள் முடிந்திருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மக்கள் தங்களின் முதல், இரண்டாவது, மூன்றாவது மற்றும் நான்காவது Pfizer கோவிட் பெறுவதற்கு Ginthupitiya வில் உள்ள MOH அலுவலகம், MCH அலுவலகம், டீன்ஸ் வீதியில் உள்ள MCH மற்றும் MOH அலுவலகம், New Bazaar மகப்பேறு இல்லம், வெள்ளவத்தையில் உள்ள MOH அலுவலகம், Campbell Park மற்றும் கிருல வீதியிலுள்ள MOH அலுவலகம் ஆகியவற்றுக்குச் செல்லுமாறு மக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. - இன்று காலை 9:00 மணி முதல் மதியம் 1:00 மணி வரை 19 தடுப்பூசிகள்.",
        "இருப்பினும், நான்காவது டோஸ் 20 முதல் 60 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்களுக்கும், நோயெதிர்ப்பு குறைபாடு மற்றும் நாள்பட்ட கோளாறுகள் உள்ளவர்களுக்கும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுவதாக சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.எம்.சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிந்துபிட்டியவில் உள்ள MOH அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MCH",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீன்ஸ் சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காம்ப்பெல் பூங்கா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "MOH அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருளா சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9:00 முதல் மதியம் 1:00 மணி வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 முதல் 60 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}