{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-seizes-postal-meth-98022/",
  "time_ut": 1659093180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka seizes postal Meth",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka seizes postal Meth",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s Customs said methamphetamine tablets with a street value of 29.7 million rupees that had come from through post from the Netherlands had been seized",
        "The Central Postal Division of the Sri Lanka Postal Department, the Narcotics Control Division of the Sri Lanka Customs, and the Narcotics Bureau of the Sri Lanka Police worked in detecting the drugs.",
        "The package was said to contain a foot massager, but when inspected was found to contain 2,973 methamphetamine tablets weighing 1.1 kilograms.",
        "The drugs were handed over to the Narcotics Bureau of the Sri Lanka Police for further investigation. (Colombo/Jul29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Meth",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Central Postal Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Postal Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Narcotics Control Division of the Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Narcotics Bureau of the Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,973",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 kilograms",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Narcotics Bureau of the Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාව තැපැල් මෙත් අල්ලයි",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නෙදර්ලන්තයේ සිට තැපැල් මාර්ගයෙන් පැමිණි රුපියල් මිලියන 29.7ක වීදි වටිනාකමකින් යුත් මෙතම්ෆෙටමින් පෙති අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ මධ්‍යම තැපැල් අංශය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක අංශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය මෙම මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය හඳුනාගැනීම සඳහා කටයුතු කරන ලදී.",
        "එම පැකේජයේ පාද මසාජරයක් තිබූ බව පැවසුවත් පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේදී කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 1.1ක් බරැති මෙතම්ෆෙටමින් පෙති 2973ක් තිබී හමුවී ඇත.",
        "එම මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 29.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම තැපැල් අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පාලන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,973 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 1.1 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தபால் மெத்தை இலங்கை கைப்பற்றியது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெதர்லாந்தில் இருந்து தபால் மூலம் வந்த 29.7 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான மெத்தம்பெட்டமைன் மாத்திரைகள் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை சுங்கப் பிரிவினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை தபால் திணைக்களத்தின் மத்திய தபால் பிரிவு, இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு மற்றும் இலங்கை காவல்துறையின் போதைப்பொருள் பணியகம் ஆகியவை போதைப்பொருட்களைக் கண்டறியும் பணியில் ஈடுபட்டன.",
        "பொட்டலத்தில் கால் மசாஜர் இருந்ததாக கூறப்பட்டது, ஆனால் ஆய்வு செய்தபோது 1.1 கிலோகிராம் எடையுள்ள 2,973 மெத்தம்பேட்டமைன் மாத்திரைகள் இருப்பது கண்டறியப்பட்டது.",
        "மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக போதைப்பொருள் இலங்கை காவல்துறையின் போதைப்பொருள் தடுப்புப் பிரிவிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மெத்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய தபால் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஞ்சல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறையின் போதைப்பொருள் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,973",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 கிலோகிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறையின் போதைப்பொருள் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}