{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/එක්ස්ප්‍රස්-පර්ල්-රක්ෂණ-සමාගමෙන්-තවත්-ලක්ෂ-9110ක-වන්දියක්/11-396651",
  "time_ut": 1661580203,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් රක්ෂණ සමාගමෙන් තවත් ලක්ෂ 9110ක වන්දියක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another compensation of 9110 lakhs from Express Pearl Insurance Company",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The government of Sri Lanka has received an amount of 9110 lakh rupees from the ship's insurance company as the 3rd interim compensation amount to compensate the sailors who lost their lives due to the Express Pearl ship accident in 2021.",
        "Accordingly, Fisheries Minister Mr. Douglas Devananda instructed the officials including Ministry Secretary Mrs. Indu Ratnayake to distribute this amount among 15,032 identified fishermen in Gampaha, Colombo and Kalutara districts. Earlier also on two occasions Rs. 3480 lakhs and Rs. The Ministry of Fisheries arranged to distribute the interim compensation amounting to 3350 lakhs to these fishermen.",
        "As in the previous cases, the 3rd interim compensation amount is to be distributed through the Divisional Secretariat offices in the areas where the fishermen reside and with the payment of this 3rd interim compensation amount, all fishermen affected by the Express Pearl ship accident will be given Rs. . 80,000 to Rs. 240,000 in total has been awarded as compensation so far.",
        "After the Express Pearl shipwreck, a fishing ban was imposed in the area from Negombo to Panadura for the safety of fishermen, their gear and vessels and to prevent the possible effects of catching and consuming fish from the affected area. The number of fishermen who lost their livelihood due to this ban has been identified as 15,032."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9110",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Express Pearl Insurance Company",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9110",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indu Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,032",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3350",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divisional Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "240,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Express",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,032",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් රක්ෂණ සමාගමෙන් තවත් ලක්ෂ 9110ක වන්දියක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021 වසරේදී සිදු වු එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් නෞකා අනතුර හේතුවෙන් ජීවිකාව අහිමි වු ධිවර කාර්මිකයන්ට වන්දි ගෙවීම සදහා 3 වන අතුරු වන්දි මුදල වශයෙන් රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 9110ක මුදලක් නෞකාවේ රක්ෂණ ආයතනය වෙතින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය වෙත ලැබී ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම මුදල ගම්පහ, කොළඹ සහ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල හඳුනාගත් ධීවර කාර්මිකයින් 15,032 දෙනෙකු අතර බෙදාදීමට කටයුතු කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්දා මහතා අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම් ඉන්දු රත්නායක මහත්මිය ඇතුළු නිළධාරීන් වෙත උපදෙස් ලබා දෙන ලදි. මීට පෙරද අවස්ථා දෙකකදී රක්ෂණ ආයතනය වෙතින් ලද  රු. ලක්ෂ 3480 ක් සහ රු. ලක්ෂ 3350 ක් බැඟින් වු අතුරු වන්දි මුදල් මෙම ධීවර ජනතාව වෙත බෙදා දීමට ධීවර අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් කටයුතු කරන ලදි'",
        "පෙර අවස්ථාවල මෙන්ම 3 වන අතුරු වන්දි මුදලද ධීවරයින් පදිංචි ප්‍රදේශවල ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාල හරහා බෙදා හැරීමට නියමිත වන අතර මෙම 3 වන අතුරු වන්දි මුදල ගෙවීමත් සමඟ එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් නෞකා අනතුර හේතුවෙන් බලපෑමට ලක්වු සැම ධීවර කාර්මිකයෙකුටම ඔවුන්ගේ යාත්‍රා වර්ගය , පන්න ක්‍රමය හා අහිමි වු ආදායම අනුව රු. 80,000 සිට රු. 240,000 දක්වා මුළු මුදලක් වන්දි වශයෙන් මේ දක්වා හිමිව ඇත.",
        "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් නැව් අනතුරින් පසු ධීවර ජනතාවගේ,ඔවුන්ගේ ආම්පන්නවල සහ යාත්‍රාවල ආරක්ෂාව සඳහාත් බලපෑමට ලක්වූ ප්‍රදේශයෙන් මසුන් අල්ලා පාරිභෝජනය කිරීමෙන් ඇතිවිය හැකි බලපෑම් වැලැක්වීම සඳහාත් මීගමුව සිට පානදුර දක්වා ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවර කටයුතු තහනමක් පනවා තිබුණි. මෙම තහනම හේතුවෙන් ජීවිකාව අහිමිවූ ධීවර කාර්මිකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව 15,032 ක් වශයෙන් හඳුනාගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9110",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් රක්ෂණ සමාගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9110",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දු රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,032 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3350",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "240,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්ප්රස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,032 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் இன்சூரன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திடமிருந்து 9110 லட்சங்கள் இழப்பீடு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021ஆம் ஆண்டு எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் கப்பல் விபத்தினால் உயிரிழந்த மாலுமிகளுக்கு இழப்பீடு வழங்குவதற்காக 3வது இடைக்கால இழப்பீட்டுத் தொகையாக 9110 இலட்சம் ரூபாவை கப்பலின் காப்புறுதி நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, இத்தொகையை கம்பஹா, கொழும்பு மற்றும் களுத்துறை மாவட்டங்களில் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட 15,032 மீனவர்களுக்கு பகிர்ந்தளிக்குமாறு கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் திரு.டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் திருமதி இந்து ரத்நாயக்க உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார். இதற்கு முன்பும் இரண்டு முறை ரூ. 3480 லட்சம் மற்றும் ரூ. இந்த மீனவர்களுக்கு இடைக்கால இழப்பீடு தொகையான 3350 இலட்சம் வழங்க கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சு ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த முறை மீனவர்கள் வசிக்கும் பகுதிகளில் உள்ள பிரதேச செயலகங்களின் ஊடாக 3ஆம் இடைக்கால இழப்பீட்டுத் தொகை விநியோகிக்கப்படவுள்ளதுடன், இந்த 3ஆம் இடைக்கால இழப்பீட்டுத் தொகையுடன் விரைவு முத்து கப்பல் விபத்தினால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து மீனவர்களுக்கும் வழங்கப்படவுள்ளது. ரூ. 80,000 முதல் ரூ. மொத்தம் 240,000 இதுவரை இழப்பீடாக வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் கப்பல் விபத்திற்குப் பிறகு, மீனவர்கள், அவர்களின் உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் கப்பல்களின் பாதுகாப்பிற்காகவும், பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பகுதியிலிருந்து மீன்களைப் பிடித்து உட்கொள்வதால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய விளைவுகளைத் தடுக்கவும் நீர்கொழும்பிலிருந்து பாணந்துறை வரையிலான பகுதியில் மீன்பிடித் தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த தடையால் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை இழந்த மீனவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 15,032 ஆக அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9110",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் இன்சூரன்ஸ் நிறுவனம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9110",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,032",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3350",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "240,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,032",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}