{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/யாழ்ப்பாணம்/டிப்பரில்-கடத்திச்-செல்லப்பட்ட-மூன்று-இளைஞர்கள்/71-299833",
  "time_ut": 1657099484,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "டிப்பரில் கடத்திச் செல்லப்பட்ட மூன்று இளைஞர்கள்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three youths kidnapped in a tipper",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "There has been an incident where three youths belonging to Vallipunam and Teravill areas were attacked in Gomba under Pudukudiripu area of ​​Mullaitivu district and they were abducted in a tipper and severely assaulted.",
        "This has happened to three youths who were reported to have assaulted a youth from Kallaru area during a clash between youth groups last week.",
        "Yesterday evening, while a group of youths were abducting three youths in a tipper, the tipper's tire burst after hitting a bridge in Vishwamadu area.",
        "Following this, they left the tipper vehicle at the spot and abducted the youth.",
        "Subsequently, when the Pudukudiripu police went to the spot, the youths involved in the abduction incident escaped from the tipper vehicle and rescued the three abducted youths. They have been admitted to Mullaitivu District Hospital.",
        "Pudukudiripu police are conducting investigations regarding the owner of the vehicle and the driver. (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vallipunam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gomba",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pudukudiripu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kallaru",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vishwamadu",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pudukudiripu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu District Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pudukudiripu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ටිපර් රථයකින් තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකු පැහැරගෙන යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුලතිව් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පුදුකුඩිරිපු ප්‍රදේශය යටතේ ගොම්බා ප්‍රදේශයේදී වල්ලිපුනම් සහ තෙරවිල් ප්‍රදේශවල තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකුට පහරදී ඔවුන් ටිපර් රථයකින් පැහැරගෙන ගොස් බරපතල ලෙස පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියක් වාර්තා වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ තරුණ කණ්ඩායම් අතර ඇති වූ ගැටුමකදී කල්ලාරු ප්‍රදේශයේ තරුණයෙකුට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියක් වාර්තා වූ තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකුට මෙය සිදුව තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඊයේ සවස තරුණයින් පිරිසක් ටිපර් රථයකින් තරුණයින් තිදෙනෙකු පැහැරගෙන යමින් සිටියදී විශ්වමඩු ප්‍රදේශයේ පාලමක හැපී ටිපර් රථයේ ටයරය පුපුරා ගොස් තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔවුන් ටිපර් රථය එම ස්ථානයේ තබා තරුණයා පැහැරගෙන ගොස් තිබෙනවා.",
        "අනතුරුව පුදුකුඩිරිප්පු පොලිසිය එම ස්ථානයට යන විට පැහැරගැනීමේ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ තරුණයන් ටිපර් රථයෙන් පැන ගොස් පැහැරගත් තරුණයන් තිදෙනා බේරාගෙන තිබේ. ඔවුන් මුලතිව් දිසා රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත.",
        "රථයේ හිමිකරු සහ රියදුරු සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුදුකුඩිරිප්පු පොලිසිය පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි. (ආ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වල්ලිපුනම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොම්බා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුදුකුඩිරිපු",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කල්ලාරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්වමඩු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුදුකුඩිරිපු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව් දිසා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුදුකුඩිරිපු",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டிப்பரில் கடத்திச் செல்லப்பட்ட மூன்று இளைஞர்கள்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "முல்லைத்தீவு  மாவட்டத்தின்  புதுக்குடியிருப்பு பிரதேசத்திற்கு உட்பட்ட கோம்பாவில் , வள்ளிபுனம், தேரவில் பகுதிகளை சேர்ந்த மூன்று இளைஞர்கள் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்தி,  அவர்களை  டிப்பரில் கடத்திச் சென்று கடுமையாக தாக்குதல் நடத்திய சம்பவம் ஒன்று இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் இளைஞர் குழுக்களுக்கிடையில் ஏற்பட்ட மோதலின் போது கல்லாற்று பகுதியினை சேர்ந்த இளைஞன் ஒருவரை தாக்கியதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படும் மூன்று இளைஞர்களுக்கே இந்த நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நேற்று மாலை இளைஞர் குழு ஒன்று டிப்பரில் மூன்று இளைஞர்களையும் கடத்தி சென்ற வேளை விசுவமடு பகுதியில் பாலத்தில் மோதி டிப்பரின் டயர் வெடித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதைத் தொடர்ந்து  டிப்பர் வாகனத்தை அந்த இடத்திலேயே விட்டுவிட்டு இளைஞர்களை கடத்தி சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதையடுத்து சம்பவ இடத்திற்கு புதுக்குடியிருப்பு பொலிஸார்  சென்ற வேளை கடத்தல் சம்பவத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட இளைஞர்கள் டிப்பர் வாகனத்தினை விட்டு தப்பி சென்ற நிலையில், கடத்தப்பட்ட மூன்று இளைஞர்களையும் மீட்டுள்ளனர். அவர்களை முல்லைத்தீவு மாவட்ட மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதித்துள்ளார்கள்.",
        "வாகனத்தின் உரிமையாளர் தொடர்பிலும் வாகன சாரதி தொடர்பிலும் புதுக்குடியிருப்பு பொலிஸார்   விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர். (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வள்ளிபுனம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோம்பா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதுக்குடியிருப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்லாறு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஸ்வமடு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதுக்குடியிருப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு மாவட்ட வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதுக்குடியிருப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}