{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Lankan-nabbed-with-gold-jewellery-worth-Rs-55mn-at-airport/108-243857",
  "time_ut": 1661580413,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lankan nabbed with gold jewellery worth Rs.55mn at airport",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lankan nabbed with gold jewellery worth Rs.55mn at airport",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Sri Lankan passenger who was arrested this morning at the Katunayake International airport for illegally carrying gold jewelery to the value of around Rs.55 million by a team of customs officials at the arrival terminal.",
        "The suspect was a 38-year-old man from Malabe, who was returning after working in Paris, France for about 10 years.",
        "He arrived at the airport by SriLankan Airlines from Paris at 5.45 in the morning.",
        "He was wearing a neck chain weighing 586.8g, and other Jewellery were stealthily hidden in the suitcase he brought. (T.K.G. Kapila)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rs.55mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake International",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malabe",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 10 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "586.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jewellery",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T.K.G. Kapila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් මිලියන 55ක් වටිනා රන් ආභරණ සමඟ ලාංකිකයෙකු ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී මාට්ටු",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රුපියල් මිලියන 55ක් පමණ වටිනා රන් ආභරණ රැගෙන යමින් සිටි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ගුවන් මගියෙකු කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ පැමිණීමේ පර්යන්තයේදී රේගු නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් අද උදෑසන අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "මෙලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ වසර 10ක පමණ කාලයක් ප්‍රංශයේ පැරිස් නුවර සේවය කර ආපසු එමින් සිටි මාලඹේ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 38 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකි.",
        "ඔහු පැරීසියේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයෙන් අලුයම 5.45 ට ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණියේය.",
        "ග්‍රෑම් 586.8ක් බර බෙල්ලේ දම්වැලක් ඔහු පැළඳ සිටි අතර ඔහු රැගෙන ආ ගමන් මල්ලෙහි වෙනත් ස්වර්ණාභරණ හොර රහසේ සඟවා තිබුණි. (ටී.කේ.ජී. කපිල)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල් මිලියන 55ක්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලබේ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "586.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආභරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.කේ.ජී. කපිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "55 மில்லியன் பெறுமதியான தங்க நகைகளுடன் இலங்கையர் விமான நிலையத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் சுமார் 55 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான தங்க நகைகளை எடுத்துச் சென்ற இலங்கைப் பயணி ஒருவர் கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினால் இன்று காலை கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சுமார் 10 வருடங்களாக பிரான்சின் பாரிஸில் பணிபுரிந்துவிட்டு நாடு திரும்பிய மாலபே பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 38 வயதுடைய நபரே இவ்வாறு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் பாரிஸில் இருந்து ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் மூலம் அதிகாலை 5.45 மணியளவில் விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "அவர் 586.8 கிராம் எடையுள்ள கழுத்து சங்கிலியை அணிந்திருந்தார், மேலும் அவர் கொண்டு வந்த சூட்கேஸில் மற்ற நகைகள் திருட்டுத்தனமாக மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டன. (டி.கே.ஜி. கபிலா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூ.55 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேசம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலபே",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "586.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அணிகலன்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.கே.ஜி. கபிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}