{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78528",
  "time_ut": 1657609560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa  signs  resignation letter  dated for July 13 and  Submits it to the Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena   who is expected to  publicly announce it to the nation On Wednesday",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa  signs  resignation letter  dated for July 13 and  Submits it to the Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena   who is expected to  publicly announce it to the nation On Wednesday",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa yesterday signed his resignation letter, dated for July 13 and the Speaker of Parliament will publicly announce it to the nation tomorrow, the Daily Mirror learns.",
        "The resignation letter of the President was signed and handed over to a senior government official who will hand it over to the Parliament Speaker.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena who has been informed of the letter will then make a public announcement tomorrow ending Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s presidency.",
        "Speculation was rife yesterday that Rajapaksa had already left the island last afternoon, however, these reports were rejected by senior sources close to the President who confirmed to Daily Mirror that Rajapaksa was still in the country and was protected by the Armed Forces.",
        "Just before the July 9 riots, President Rajapaksa was evacuated from the President’s House in Fort by the security forces and was protected on a naval vessel within the territorial waters of the country for security reasons.",
        "However, sources close to him said that Rajapaksa physically met commanders of the tri forces yesterday morning at 9.30 am and thereafter remains in the country. His exact whereabouts in the country is unknown but he is likely to leave the country this week, paving way for a new President to be sworn in and an All Party government to be formed.",
        "On Wedneday Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe will for a temporary period be sworn in as the President till a new President is selected by Parliament on July 20. Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena in a statement said party leaders had decided to elect a new President on July 20 through a vote in Parliament in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution.",
        "Nominations for the presidency will be called for on July 19.",
        "So far the two confirmed candidates are the Prime Minister and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa who yesterday already informed that he is ready to rebuild Sri Lanka’s economy."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wednesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "All Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wedneday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියට අත්සන් තබා එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත භාරදෙනු ලබන අතර ඔහු එය බදාදා ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ජාතියට ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි 13 වැනි දිනට යෙදී තිබූ සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ අත්සන් තැබූ අතර එය හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයා විසින් ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ජාතියට ප්‍රකාශ කරනු ඇති බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියට අත්සන් තබා රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකුට භාරදුන් අතර ඔහු එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයා වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "එම ලිපිය පිළිබඳව දැනුම් දී ඇති කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය අවසන් කරමින් හෙට ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදු කරනු ඇත.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ වන විටත් ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ දිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇති බවට ඊයේ දිනයේදී අනුමාන කිරීම් පැතිර ගිය නමුත්, රාජපක්ෂ තවමත් මෙරට සිටින බවත්, ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවේ ආරක්ෂාවට ඔහු සිටින බවත්, ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත තහවුරු කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සමීප ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආරංචි මාර්ග මෙම වාර්තා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "ජුලි 9 කැරැල්ලට මොහොතකට පෙර, ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයෙන් ඉවත් කරන ලද අතර ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත මෙරට මුහුදු සීමාව තුළ නාවික යාත්‍රාවක ආරක්‍ෂා කරන ලදී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහුට සමීප ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේ, රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ උදෑසන 9.30 ට ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් ශාරීරිකව හමු වූ අතර, ඉන් අනතුරුව දිවයිනේ රැඳී සිටින බවයි. ඔහු මෙරට සිටින්නේ කොහේදැයි නිශ්චිතව නොදන්නා නමුත් ඔහු මේ සතියේ රට හැර යාමට ඉඩ ඇති අතර, නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු දිවුරුම් දීමට සහ සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට මග පාදයි.",
        "ජුලි 20 වනදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා ගන්නා තෙක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තාවකාලිකව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස බදාදා දිවුරුම් දෙන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ජුලි 20 වනදා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත්කිරීමට පක්ෂ නායකයින් තීරණය කර ඇති බවයි. ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධානවලට අනුකූලව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයක්.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීම ජූලි 19 වැනිදා සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "මේ වන විට තහවුරු කර ඇති අපේක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනා වන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය යළි ගොඩනැගීමට තමන් සූදානම් බව ඊයේ දැනටමත් දැනුම් දුන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතායි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බදාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියලු පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் கையொப்பமிட்டு, அதை பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவிடம் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளார், அவர் அதை புதன்கிழமை நாட்டுக்கு பகிரங்கமாக அறிவிப்பார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி நேற்று கையொப்பமிட்டதாகவும், அதனை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் நாளை பகிரங்கமாக நாட்டுக்கு அறிவிப்பார் என்றும் டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமா கடிதம் கையொப்பமிடப்பட்டு அரசாங்கத்தின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி ஒருவரிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது. அவர் அதனை பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரிடம் கையளிப்பார்.",
        "இந்த கடிதம் தொடர்பில் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை நாளை முடிவடையும் அறிவிப்பை வெளியிடுவார்.",
        "நேற்று பிற்பகல் ராஜபக்ச ஏற்கனவே தீவை விட்டு வெளியேறிவிட்டார் என்று ஊகங்கள் பரவியிருந்தன, ஆனால் இந்த செய்திகளை ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நெருக்கமான மூத்த வட்டாரங்கள் நிராகரித்து, ராஜபக்ச இன்னும் நாட்டில் இருப்பதாகவும், ஆயுதப்படையினரால் அவர் பாதுகாக்கப்படுகிறார் என்றும் டெய்லி மிரருக்கு உறுதிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "ஜூலை 9 கலவரத்திற்கு சற்று முன்பு, ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையிலிருந்து பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் வெளியேற்றப்பட்டார் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக நாட்டின் கடல் எல்லைக்குள் கடற்படைக் கப்பலில் பாதுகாக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நேற்று காலை 9.30 மணியளவில் முப்படைத் தளபதிகளை ராஜபக்சே உடல் ரீதியாக சந்தித்ததாகவும், அதன்பின்னர் அவர் நாட்டில் இருப்பதாகவும் அவருக்கு நெருக்கமான வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. அவர் நாட்டில் எங்கு இருக்கிறார் என்பது சரியாகத் தெரியவில்லை, ஆனால் அவர் இந்த வாரம் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற வாய்ப்புள்ளது, புதிய ஜனாதிபதி பதவியேற்கவும், அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கவும் வழி வகுக்கிறது.",
        "எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை மாதம் 20 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தினால் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் வரை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தற்காலிகமாக ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்வார் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளின்படி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஒரு வாக்கெடுப்பு.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் ஜூலை 19ஆம் தேதி நடைபெறும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்பத் தயாராக உள்ளதாக நேற்றைய தினம் ஏற்கனவே அறிவித்திருந்த பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஆகிய இரு வேட்பாளர்கள் இதுவரை உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}