{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83258/sri-lankan-ambassador-to-us-meets-president-joe-biden",
  "time_ut": 1656180900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan ambassador to U.S. meets President Joe Biden",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan ambassador to U.S. meets President Joe Biden",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan Ambassador to the United States Mahinda Samarasinghe called on U.S. President Joe Biden recently, to brief him on the current situation in the crisis-hit island nation.",
        "The meeting between the two parties took place at the White House Oval Office.",
        "The ambassador also hosted the high-level delegation representing the U.S. Department of the Treasury and the U.S. Department of State will be visiting Sri Lanka from June 26- 29.",
        "According to the Sri Lankan envoy, these officials too were briefed on the challenges faced by the island nation.",
        "The delegation members include Deputy Assistant Secretary of Treasury for Asia Robert Kaproth and Ambassador Kelly Keiderling, the Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia.",
        "The visitors will meet with various political representatives, economists, and international organizations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "U.S.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Joe Biden",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the White House Oval Office",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Department of the",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අමෙරිකාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහ මහතා පසුගියදා එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් හමුවී අර්බුදකාරී දිවයිනේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ඔහුව දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "දෙපාර්ශවය අතර හමුව ධවල මන්දිර ඕවල් කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිත පිරිසට ද තානාපතිවරයා සත්කාරකත්වය සැපයූ අතර ජූනි 26-29 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරය කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා පවසන පරිදි මෙම නිලධාරීන් ද දිවයින ජාතිය මුහුණ දෙන අභියෝග පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කරන ලදී.",
        "දූත පිරිසට ආසියානු භාණ්ඩාගාර නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් රොබට් කප්‍රෝත් සහ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් තානාපති කෙලී කීඩර්ලින් ද ඇතුළත් වෙති.",
        "අමුත්තන් විවිධ දේශපාලන නියෝජිතයන්, ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන හමුවනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Joe Biden",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය ඕවල් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனை சந்தித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் மகிந்த சமரசிங்க, அண்மையில் அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனை சந்தித்து, நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தீவு தேசத்தின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "வெள்ளை மாளிகை ஓவல் அலுவலகத்தில் இரு தரப்புக்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பு இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "அமெரிக்க கருவூலத் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களத்தைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் உயர்மட்டக் குழுவுக்கும் தூதுவர் விருந்தளித்து ஜூன் 26-29 வரை இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்யவுள்ளார்",
        "இலங்கைத் தூதுவரின் கூற்றுப்படி, இந்த அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் தீவு நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்கள் குறித்து விளக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தூதுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்களில் ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை கருவூலச் செயலர் ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை இராஜாங்கச் செயலாளரான தூதர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.",
        "பார்வையாளர்கள் பல்வேறு அரசியல் பிரதிநிதிகள், பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளைச் சந்திப்பார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Joe Biden",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை ஓவல் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைய ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}