{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84576/five-including-woman-arrested-over-gampaha-daylight-shooting",
  "time_ut": 1661605560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Five including woman arrested over Gampaha daylight shooting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Five including woman arrested over Gampaha daylight shooting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Five suspects including a woman have been arrested in connection with the brazen daylight shooting inside a hair salon in Gampaha earlier this month, in which a youth was murdered.",
        "The arrests were made in a raid carried out by the officers of Police Special Task Force at Gonahena camp.",
        "The suspects, aged between 23 and 29 years, were identified as residents of Pethiyagoda, Makewita and Kotugoda areas.",
        "Meanwhile, the revolver and the car used by the perpetrators in the shooting were also taken into custody.",
        "The suspects were slated to be produced before the Gampaha Magistrate’s Court today. Gampaha Police is conducting further investigations into the incident.",
        "The victim, a youth in his early 20s, was a resident of Udugampola area in Gampaha.",
        "It was revealed that the victim had no criminal record. The police suspect that he shot dead in a case of mistaken identity."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gampaha",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gonahena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 23 and 29 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pethiyagoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makewita",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotugoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "his early 20s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udugampola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගම්පහ දිවා කාලයේ වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියට කාන්තාවක් ඇතුළු 5ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ මස මුලදී ගම්පහ ප්‍රදේශයේ කොණ්ඩා මෝස්තර ශාලාවක් තුළ දිවා කාලයේ වෙඩි තබා තරුණයෙකු ඝාතනය කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කාන්තාවක් ඇතුළු සැකකරුවන් 5 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ නිලධාරීන් ගෝනහේන කඳවුරේ සිදු කළ වැටලීමකදී ඔවුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් අවුරුදු 23 ත් 29 ත් අතර වයස්වල පසුවන පෙතියාගොඩ, මාකේවිට සහ කොටුගොඩ ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන්.",
        "මේ අතර වෙඩි තැබීමට අපරාධකරුවන් භාවිත කළ රිවෝල්වරය සහ මෝටර් රථය ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "සැකකරුවන් අද ගම්පහ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි. සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගම්පහ පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්ව ඇත්තේ ගම්පහ උඩුගම්පොල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 20 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකි.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයාට අපරාධ වාර්තාවක් නොමැති බව අනාවරණය විය. වැරදි අනන්‍යතාවක් මත වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කරන්නට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය සැක කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගම්පහ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝනහේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 23 සහ 29 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙතියාගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකේවිට",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔහුගේ මුල් 20 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩුගම්පොල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கம்பஹா பகல் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் பெண் உட்பட ஐவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இம்மாதத் தொடக்கத்தில் கம்பஹாவில் சிகையலங்கார நிலையமொன்றிற்குள் பகலில் நடந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் இளைஞர் ஒருவர் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் பெண் உட்பட 5 சந்தேக நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கொனஹேன முகாமில் பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை அதிகாரிகள் மேற்கொண்ட சுற்றிவளைப்பில் இவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் 23 மற்றும் 29 வயதுடைய பெத்தியகொட, மகேவிட்ட மற்றும் கொடுகொட பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு குற்றவாளிகள் பயன்படுத்திய ரிவால்வர் மற்றும் காரும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் இன்று கம்பஹா நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளனர். சம்பவம் தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை கம்பஹா பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "கம்பஹா உடுகம்பொல பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் 20 வயதுடைய இளைஞன் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பெண்ணுக்கு எந்த குற்றப் பின்னணியும் இல்லை என்பது தெரியவந்தது. தவறான அடையாளம் காரணமாக அவர் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் என போலீசார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கம்பஹா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோனாஹேனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 மற்றும் 29 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெத்தியகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேவிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடுகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவரது ஆரம்ப 20கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடுகம்பொல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}