{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/04/criminal-gangster-shot-dead-in-shootout/",
  "time_ut": 1656905340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Criminal gangster shot dead in shootout",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Criminal gangster shot dead in shootout",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A Criminal Gangster was shot dead by police during a shootout in Yakkala.",
        "Police Spokesperson, Senior Superintendent of Police Nihal Talduwa said that a T56 firearm was also found in the possession of the deceased suspect.",
        "According to reports, the gunned-down gangster was identified as Ihala Vithanage Joseph Kumara alias Elpitiye Joseph (41).",
        "It is reported that he was a close associate of Underworld Gangster Ganemulla Sanjeewa, and is suspected to have carried out the shooting at Bastian Mawatha, Colombo on 30th May 2022.",
        "Yupun becomes first South Asian to finish 100m below 10 seconds & win"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "A Criminal Gangster",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yakkala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ihala Vithanage Joseph Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elpitiye Joseph",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Underworld Gangster Ganemulla Sanjeewa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bastian Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෙඩි හුවමාරුවකදී අපරාධ කල්ලියක් වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); යක්කල ප්‍රදේශයේ ඇති වූ වෙඩි හුවමාරුවකදී අපරාධ කල්ලියක් පොලිස් වෙඩි පහරින් මිය ගියේය.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල් තල්දූව පැවසුවේ මියගිය සැකකරු සතුව තිබී ටී 56 ගිනි අවියක් ද සොයාගත් බවයි.",
        "වාර්තා වන අන්දමට වෙඩි වැදුණු මැර කල්ලිය ඉහළ විතානගේ ජෝශප් කුමාර නොහොත් ඇල්පිටියේ ජෝශප් (41) ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "මොහු පාතාල කල්ලි නායක ගනේමුල්ල සංජීවගේ සමීපතමයෙකු බවත් 2022 මැයි 30 වැනිදා කොළඹ බැස්ටියන් මාවතේදී වෙඩි තැබීම සිදුකරන්නට ඇති බවට සැකකරන බවත් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "යුපුන් මීටර් 100 තත්පර 10 ට අඩුවෙන් අවසන් කර ජයග්‍රහණය කළ පළමු දකුණු ආසියානු ක්‍රීඩකයා බවට පත් වෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ මැරයෙක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යක්කල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ විතානගේ ජෝශප් කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්පිටියේ ජෝශප්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාතාල කල්ලි ගනේමුල්ල සංජීව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கிரிமினல் கும்பல் துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யக்கல பிரதேசத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச்சூட்டில் கிரிமினல் கும்பல் ஒருவர் பொலிஸாரால் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த சந்தேக நபரிடம் இருந்து T56 துப்பாக்கி ஒன்றும் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிஹால் தல்துவா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு இலக்கானவர் இஹல விதானகே ஜோசப் குமார எனப்படும் எல்பிட்டியே ஜோசப் (41) எனத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "அவர் பாதாள உலகக் கும்பல் கனேமுல்ல சஞ்சீவவின் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளி என்றும், 2022 மே 30 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு, பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தையில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டை நடத்தியிருக்கலாம் என்றும் சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "யூபுன் 100 மீ 10 வினாடிகளுக்கு கீழே முடித்து வெற்றி பெற்ற முதல் தெற்காசிய வீரர் ஆவார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிரிமினல் கேங்ஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யக்கலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இஹல விதானகே ஜோசப் குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்பிட்டி ஜோசப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதாள உலக கும்பல் கணேமுல்ல சஞ்சீவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வினாடிகள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}