{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගෝඨාභය-රාජපක්ෂ-ඇතුළු-රජය-වහාම-ඉවත්-විය-යුතුයි/1-615594",
  "time_ut": 1656486824,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඇතුළු රජය වහාම ඉවත් විය යුතුයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The government including Gotabhaya Rajapaksa should resign immediately",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The chief organizer of the opposition, MP Laxman Kiriella, said in Colombo that the government including Gotabhaya Rajapaksa should leave immediately to recover the country which has been completely disabled.",
        "Mr. Kiriella said the government, which came to power claiming to protect local resources, was selling off the country's resources one by one to cover up its incompetence and bankruptcy, trapping the country in another trap.",
        "Speaking at a media briefing held at the office of the Leader of the Opposition at Marcus Fernando Mawatha, Colombo, Lakshman Kiriella said,",
        "\"We have received assistance from India to carry out the daily life of the people. Within 24 hours of the Indian delegation's arrival, they announced their assistance, but this time the Indian delegation discussed various issues, but did not say a word about further assistance,\" the Monetary Board said. They also said that a decision should be taken in this regard and that they should give us a number of projects in return for the assistance we have given to Sri Lanka in the recent past. The most dangerous thing is to hand over the land around the Trincomalee port as an industrial development area, where the port will inevitably join in. This is a dangerous situation. It is very clear that a program to be taken is being implemented.",
        "In fact, this government came to power to protect local resources. But we know that if the Hambantota port is given to China and the Colombo port is given to China and India in two parts and the Kunamalai port is given to India, our country will face a big problem for our independence. All political parties, regardless of party affiliation, should express their views on this situation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Laxman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monetary Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kunamalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඇතුළු රජය වහාම ඉවත් විය යුතුයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම අකර්මණ්‍ය කර ඇති රට ගොඩ ගැනීම සඳහා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඇතුළු රජය වහාම  ඉවත් විය යුතු බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා කොළඹදී පැවසීය.",
        "දේශීය සම්පත් ආරක්ෂා කරනවා කියා බලයට පත්වූ රජය තම නොහැකියාව, බංකොලොත්භාවය වසා වසාගැනීම සඳහා රටේ සම්පත් එකිනෙක විකුණා රට තවත් උගුලක සිර කරමින් සිටින බවත් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා කීවේය.",
        "කොළඹ මාකස් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවතේ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේ දී කැදවූ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී තවදුරටත් අදහස් දැක් වූ ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා මෙසේද කීවේය.",
        "\"අපිට ඉන්දියාවෙන් එදිනෙදා ජන ජීවිතය ගෙන යන්න ආධාර ලැබුණා. ඉන්දියානු නියෝජිතවරු ආපු ගමන් පැය විසි 24ක් යන්න කලින් දෙන ආධාර ගැන ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළා. නමුත් මේ වතාවෙ ආපු ඉන්දියාවේ නියෝජිතයින් විවිධ දේ සාකච්ඡා කලත් ඉදිරියට දෙන ආධාර ගැන වචනයක්වත් නැහැ. මේ අවස්ථාව කිව්වේ මූල්‍ය මණ්ඩලය මේ සම්බන්ධව තීරණයක් දෙන්න ඕන කියලා. ඒ වගේම ඔවුන් කිව්වා අපි පසුගිය කාලයේ ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් ආධාර වලට මුදල් වලට අපට ව්‍යාපෘති ගණනාවක් ලබා දෙන්න කියලා. බලාගාර කිහිපයක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියාව අතර අධි බලති විදුලි ලබාදෙන කේබලයක් වගේම අලුත්  ඉල්ලීමක් කිහිපයක් කරල තිබුණා. මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණියේ තෙල් කලාප දෙකක් ලබා දෙන්න කියලා. භයානකම දේ තමයි ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය අවට ඉඩකඩම් කාර්මික සංවර්ධන ප්‍රදේශයක් හැටියට ලබාදෙන්න කියලා. එහිදී වරායත් අනිවාර්යෙන්ම ඒකට එකතු වෙනවා. මේක භයානක තත්ත්වයක්. මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණියේ තෙල් කැණීම් කරන්න කොටස් දෙකක් ඉල්ලා තියෙනවා. මේ අය ක්‍රමක් ක්‍රමයෙන් අපේ රටේ මරමස්ථාන ඒ අය සන්තක කර ගන්න වැඩපිළිවෙළක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙනවා කියන එක ඉතා පැහැදිලියි.",
        "ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම මේ රජය බලයට පත්වුණේ දේශීය සම්පත් ආරක්ෂා කරනවා කියලා. නමුත් අපි දන්නවා හම්බන්තොට වරාය චීනයට දීලා කොළඹ වරාය චීනයටයි ඉන්දියාවටයි කඩකඩ කොටස් දෙකකට දීලා කුණාමලය වරායත් ඉන්දියාවට දෙන්න යනවා නම් අපේ රටට ඇති වෙන්නේ අපේ ස්වාධීනත්වයට විශාල ප්‍රශ්නයක්. පක්ෂ භේදයකින් තොරව සියළු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ මේ තත්ත්වය ගැන තමන්ගේ මතය ප්‍රකාශ කරන්න ඕන."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kunamalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச உள்ளிட்ட அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முற்றாக முடக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நாட்டை மீட்பதற்கு கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச உள்ளிட்ட அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக வெளியேற வேண்டும் என எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் லக்ஸ்மன் கிரியெல்ல கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "உள்ளுர் வளங்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதாகக் கூறி ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த அரசாங்கம், தனது இயலாமை மற்றும் வங்குரோத்து நிலையை மறைப்பதற்காக நாட்டின் வளங்களை ஒவ்வொன்றாக விற்று நாட்டை இன்னொரு பொறிக்குள் சிக்க வைப்பதாக திரு.கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மார்கஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தையில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் மேலும் கருத்துத் தெரிவித்த திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல,",
        "\"மக்களின் அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையை நடத்துவதற்கு இந்தியாவிடம் இருந்து உதவிகள் கிடைத்துள்ளன. இந்தியக் குழு வந்த 24 மணி நேரத்திற்குள் அவர்கள் தங்கள் உதவியை அறிவித்தனர், ஆனால் இந்த முறை இந்திய பிரதிநிதிகள் பல்வேறு விஷயங்களைப் பற்றி விவாதித்தனர், ஆனால் மேலும் உதவி பற்றி ஒரு வார்த்தை கூட பேசவில்லை, நாணயச் சபை கூறியது. இது தொடர்பில் முடிவெடுக்க வேண்டும் எனவும், கடந்த காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு நாம் வழங்கிய உதவிகளுக்கு பிரதிபலனாக பல திட்டங்களை எமக்கு வழங்க வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். மிகவும் ஆபத்தான விடயம் திருகோணமலை துறைமுகத்தைச் சுற்றியுள்ள காணிகளை கைத்தொழில் அபிவிருத்திப் பிரதேசமாக கையளித்து, அங்கு துறைமுகம் தவிர்க்க முடியாமல் இணையும்.இது ஆபத்தான நிலை.எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டிய வேலைத்திட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்றமை மிகத் தெளிவாகத் தெரிகிறது.",
        "உண்மையில் இந்த அரசாங்கம் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்தது உள்ளூர் வளங்களை பாதுகாக்கவே. ஆனால் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை சீனாவிற்கும் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தை சீனாவிற்கும் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இரண்டாக பிரித்து குணமாலய துறைமுகத்தையும் இந்தியாவிற்கு வழங்கினால் எமது நாட்டு சுதந்திரத்திற்கு பெரும் பிரச்சினை ஏற்படும் என்பதை நாம் அறிவோம். இந்த நிலையில் அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் கட்சி வேறுபாடின்றி தங்களது கருத்தை தெரிவிக்க வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஸ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாணய வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kunamalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}