{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/14/reports-of-war-games-between-sl-pakistan-are-false-navy/",
  "time_ut": 1660466220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Reports of ‘war games’ between SL & Pakistan are false: Navy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Reports of ‘war games’ between SL & Pakistan are false: Navy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Pakistan Navy Ship (PNS) Taimur which arrived in Sri Lanka on a formal visit, is scheduled to conduct a Passage Exercise with SLNS Sindurala in seas off Colombo as she departs the island on 15th August 2022, upon completion of her visit. In this backdrop, certain media reports circulating about a ‘War Game’ between Sri Lanka Navy and Pakistan Navy are fallacious, says the Sri Lankan Navy.",
        "Sri Lanka Navy, with the concurrence of foreign navies, conducts Passage Exercises as a routine engagement when their visiting naval ships departing the island after making official port calls. The prime motive of these efforts is to enhance interoperability, partnerships and goodwill as well as exchange best practices with foreign navies.",
        "As part of this Passage Exercise, PNS Taimur and SLNS Sindurala are expected to conduct Maneuvering exercises and Search and Rescue exercise.",
        "Meanwhile, Sri Lanka Navy has conducted similar Passage Exercises with the navies of countries such as India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Japan, Germany, U.K., Russia and Australia on a number of previous occasions.",
        "Conducting similar naval exercises with regional and extra-regional navies will enable each partner to overcome common maritime challenges in the future, through enhanced cooperation. In addition, such engagements will also be vital for its own maritime operations of Sri Lanka Navy.",
        "Will support from Opposition until Tamil people are satisfied: C.V. Wigneswaran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL & Pakistan",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Pakistan Navy Ship",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Sindurala",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a ‘War Game’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Sindurala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Search and Rescue",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.K.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ පාකිස්තානය අතර ‘යුද ක්‍රීඩා’ පිළිබඳ වාර්තා අසත්‍ය: නාවික හමුදාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විධිමත් සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි පාකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාවට අයත් (PNS) Taimur නෞකාව 2022 අගෝස්තු 15 වන දින දිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව යන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සිඳුරළ සමඟ කොළඹට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදේදී ගමන් අභ්‍යාසයක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය. මෙම පසුබිම තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සහ පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව අතර ‘යුද්ධ ක්‍රීඩාවක්’ පිළිබඳව පැතිර යන ඇතැම් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා සාවද්‍ය බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව, විදේශීය නාවික හමුදාවල එකඟතාවය ඇතිව, ඔවුන්ගේ නරඹන නාවික නෞකා නිල වරාය ඇමතුම් ලබා දීමෙන් පසු දිවයිනෙන් පිටත් වන විට සාමාන්‍ය නියැලීමක් ලෙස පාසේජ් අභ්‍යාස පවත්වයි. මෙම ප්‍රයත්නවල මූලික අභිප්‍රාය වන්නේ අන්තර් ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය, හවුල්කාරිත්වය සහ සුහදතාවය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම මෙන්ම විදේශීය නාවික හමුදා සමඟ හොඳම භාවිතයන් හුවමාරු කර ගැනීමයි.",
        "මෙම ඡේද අභ්‍යාසයේ කොටසක් ලෙස, PNS Taimur සහ SLNS Sindurala උපාමාරු අභ්‍යාස සහ සෙවීම් සහ ගලවා ගැනීමේ අභ්‍යාස පැවැත්වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව මීට පෙර අවස්ථා ගණනාවකදී ඉන්දියාව, පකිස්ථානය, බංග්ලාදේශය, ජපානය, ජර්මනිය, එක්සත් රාජධානිය, රුසියාව සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව වැනි රටවල නාවික හමුදා සමඟ මෙවැනිම අභ්‍යාස අභ්‍යාස පවත්වා ඇත.",
        "කලාපීය සහ බාහිර කලාපීය නාවික හමුදාවන් සමඟ සමාන නාවික අභ්‍යාස පැවැත්වීම තුළින් සෑම හවුල්කරුවෙකුටම අනාගතයේ දී පොදු සමුද්‍රීය අභියෝග ජය ගැනීමට හැකි වනු ඇත. මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ ස්වකීය සමුද්‍ර මෙහෙයුම් සඳහා ද එවැනි කටයුතු ඉතා වැදගත් වනු ඇත.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව තෘප්තිමත් වන තුරු විපක්ෂයේ සහය දෙනවා: සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL & පාකිස්තානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාවට අයත් නෞකාවකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සිඳුරල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'යුද ක්‍රීඩාවක්'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සිඳුරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙවීම සහ ගැලවීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.K.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கும் பாகிஸ்தானுக்கும் இடையிலான ‘போர் விளையாட்டுகள்’ பற்றிய தகவல்கள் தவறானவை: கடற்படை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முறையான பயணமாக இலங்கை வந்துள்ள பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படைக் கப்பல் (பிஎன்எஸ்) தைமூர், தனது விஜயத்தை முடித்துக் கொண்டு 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 15 ஆம் தேதி தீவை விட்டுப் புறப்படும்போது, ​​கொழும்புக்கு அப்பால் உள்ள கடல் பகுதியில் எஸ்எல்என்எஸ் சிந்தூரலாவுடன் பயிற்சிப் பயிற்சியை நடத்த உள்ளது. இந்தப் பின்னணியில், இலங்கை கடற்படைக்கும் பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படைக்கும் இடையில் ‘போர் விளையாட்டு’ இடம்பெறுவதாக சில ஊடகங்களில் வெளியாகும் செய்திகள் பொய்யானவை என இலங்கை கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படை, வெளிநாட்டு கடற்படைகளின் இணக்கத்துடன், உத்தியோகபூர்வ துறைமுக அழைப்புகளை மேற்கொண்ட பின்னர், அவர்களின் வருகை தரும் கடற்படைக் கப்பல்கள் தீவை விட்டுப் புறப்படும் போது, ​​வழக்கமான ஈடுபாடாக கடவுப் பயிற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்கின்றன. இம்முயற்சிகளின் பிரதான நோக்கம், வெளிநாட்டு கடற்படைகளுடன் இணைந்து செயல்படுதல், கூட்டாண்மை மற்றும் நல்லெண்ணத்தை மேம்படுத்துவது மற்றும் சிறந்த நடைமுறைகளை பரிமாறிக்கொள்வதாகும்.",
        "இந்தப் பயிற்சிப் பயிற்சியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, PNS தைமூர் மற்றும் SLNS சிந்தூரலா ஆகியவை சூழ்ச்சிப் பயிற்சிகள் மற்றும் தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பயிற்சிகளை நடத்தும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, இலங்கை கடற்படை இதற்கு முன்னர் பல தடவைகள் இந்தியா, பாகிஸ்தான், பங்களாதேஷ், ஜப்பான், ஜேர்மனி, இங்கிலாந்து, ரஷ்யா மற்றும் அவுஸ்திரேலியா போன்ற நாடுகளின் கடற்படைகளுடன் இதேபோன்ற கடற்பயிற்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிராந்திய மற்றும் கூடுதல் பிராந்திய கடற்படைகளுடன் இதேபோன்ற கடற்படை பயிற்சிகளை நடத்துவது, ஒவ்வொரு கூட்டாளியும் எதிர்காலத்தில் பொதுவான கடல்சார் சவால்களை மேம்பட்ட ஒத்துழைப்பின் மூலம் சமாளிக்க உதவும். மேலும், இலங்கை கடற்படையின் சொந்த கடல் நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கும் இத்தகைய ஈடுபாடுகள் இன்றியமையாததாக இருக்கும்.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் திருப்தி அடையும் வரை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு: சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL & பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS சிந்தூரலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு 'போர் விளையாட்டு'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS சிந்தூரலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.கே.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}