{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ස්ථිර-පත්වීම්-නොලැබූ-උපාධිධාරීන්ගේ-ගැටලුව-විසඳනවා/11-396698",
  "time_ut": 1661756465,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ස්ථිර පත්වීම් නොලැබූ උපාධිධාරීන්ගේ ගැටලුව විසඳනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Solving the problem of graduates who did not get permanent appointments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena, as the Minister of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government, stated in the Parliament that he will work to provide a solution to the problem of the people who did not get appointments due to various problems while giving appointments to the graduates.",
        "Answering a question asked by the opposition leader that 461 people have not received appointments due to various deficiencies, the Prime Minister said that the Ministry Secretary has already started discussions in this regard.",
        "\"Mr. Deputy Speaker, the leader of the opposition mentioned the number of qualified persons who have not yet obtained tenure in the departments under the Ministry of Public Administration. The Ministry Secretary has already started discussions on this issue. I hope to work to find a solution to it.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "461",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deputy Speaker",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්ථිර පත්වීම් නොලැබූ උපාධිධාරීන්ගේ ගැටලුව විසඳනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "උපාධිධාරීන්ට පත්වීම් ලබාදීමේදී, විවිධ ගැටළු නිසා පත්වීම් නොලැබූ  පිරිසගේ ප්‍රශ්නයට විසඳුමක් ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කරන බව, රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විවිධ අඩුපාඩු නිසා 461 දෙනෙකුට පත්වීම් ලැබී නොමැති බවට, විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා විමසූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසුවේ, දැනටමත් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අමාත්‍යංශය ලේකම්වරයා සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවය.",
        "\" නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායකතුමනි, විපක්ෂ නායකතුමා විසින් රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යංශය යටතේ තිබෙන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවල, සුදුසුකම්ලාභී, තවමත් ස්ථීරත්වය ලබා නොමැති සංඛ්‍යාව පිළිබඳව සඳහන් කළා.  දැනටමත් මේ ප්‍රශ්නය ගැන අමාත්‍යංශ ලේකම්තුමා සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කරලා තියෙනවා. එයට විසඳුමක් ලබා දීමට කටයුතු කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා. \""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "461",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නියෝජ්‍ය කථානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிரந்தர நியமனம் கிடைக்காத பட்டதாரிகளின் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பல்வேறு பிரச்சினைகளால் நியமனம் வழங்கப்படாமல் தவிக்கும் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வொன்றை வழங்குவதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதாக பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன பொதுநிர்வாக, உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். பட்டதாரிகளுக்கான நியமனங்கள்.",
        "பல்வேறு குறைபாடுகள் காரணமாக 461 பேருக்கு நியமனம் கிடைக்கவில்லை என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கேட்ட கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த பிரதமர், அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் இது தொடர்பில் ஏற்கனவே கலந்துரையாடலை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பிரதி சபாநாயகர் அவர்களே, பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள திணைக்களங்களில் இதுவரை பதவிக்காலம் பெறாத தகுதியான நபர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை எதிர்கட்சித் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டார். அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் ஏற்கனவே கலந்துரையாடலை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளார். கண்டறியும் முயற்சியில் ஈடுபடுவேன் என நம்புகிறேன். அதற்கு ஒரு தீர்வு.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "461",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துணை சபாநாயகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}