{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132098",
  "time_ut": 1658567862,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஊர்காவற்துறையில் எரிபொருள் அட்டைக்கு காத்திருந்தவர் உயிரிழப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A man was killed while waiting for a fuel card at the police station",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "A person who was waiting to get a fuel card at the Jaffna Urban Police Divisional Secretariat has suddenly fainted and died.",
        "Nadarasa Premkumar (48 years old) from Velani Puliyangkudal area has died in this incident which took place on Friday.",
        "The person in question suddenly fainted while waiting to get his fuel card at the Home Police Divisional Secretariat.",
        "After that, the bystanders rescued him and admitted him to the local police hospital, but he succumbed to his injuries."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna Urban Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divisional Secretariat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nadarasa Premkumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velani Puliyangkudal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Home Police Divisional Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පතක් බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු ඝාතනය කර තිබේ",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය නාගරික පොලිස් ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පතක් ලබා ගැනීමට රැඳී සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු හදිසියේ ක්ලාන්ත වී මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "සිකුරාදා සිදුවූ මෙම සිද්ධියෙන් මියගොස් ඇත්තේ වේලනි පුලියන්කුඩල් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි නඩරාසා ප්‍රේම්කුමාර් (අවු:48)",
        "අදාළ පුද්ගලයා ස්වදේශ පොලිස් ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ඉන්ධන කාඩ්පත ලබා ගැනීමට රැඳී සිටියදී හදිසියේ ක්ලාන්ත වී ඇත.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව අසල සිටි පිරිස ඔහුව බේරාගෙන ප්‍රාදේශීය පොලිස් රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කළත් ඔහු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය නාගරික පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නඩරාසා ප්‍රේම්කුමාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 48 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේලනි පුලියංකුඩල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ පොලිස් ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊர்காவற்துறையில் எரிபொருள் அட்டைக்கு காத்திருந்தவர் உயிரிழப்பு",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் ஊர்காவற்துறை பிரதேச செயலகத்தில் எரிபொருள் அட்டையை பெற காத்திருந்தவர் திடீரென மயங்கி சரிந்து உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற இந்த சம்பவத்தில் வேலணை புளியங்கூடல் பகுதியை சேர்ந்த நடராசா பிரேம்குமார் (வயது 48) என்பவரே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "குறித்த நபர் தனக்கான எரிபொருள் அட்டையினை பெற்றுக்கொள்வதற்காக ஊர்காவற்துறை பிரதேச செயலகத்திற்கு சென்று காத்திருந்த வேளை திடீரென மயங்கி சரிந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதனை அடுத்து அங்கிருந்தவர்கள் அவரை மீட்டு ஊர்காவற்துறை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதித்த போதிலும் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் நகர காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச செயலகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நடராசா பிரேம்குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலனி புளியங்குடல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உள்துறை பொலிஸ் பிரதேச செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}