{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලංගම-සඳුදා-සිට-උපරිම-ධාරිතාවෙන්-ධාවනයේ/101-616813",
  "time_ut": 1658401606,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංගම සඳුදා සිට උපරිම ධාරිතාවෙන් ධාවනයේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Running at maximum capacity from Monday onwards",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A senior officer of the Ceylon Transport Board said that since the shortage of tires and batteries faced by the Ceylon Transport Board (Langama) is over, the buses will run at maximum capacity from next Monday.",
        "The official said that due to the lack of tires and batteries that Langama was facing, about 2,000 buses out of 5,000 buses were not able to run and thus about 80 percent of long-distance services had to be suspended.",
        "The official further said that the purchase was delayed due to a problem in the procurement process for the purchase of tires and batteries."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Monday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Langama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Langama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 80 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංගම සඳුදා සිට උපරිම ධාරිතාවෙන් ධාවනයේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ගමනා ගමන මණ්ඩලය (ලංගම) මුහුණදී සිටි ටයර් සහ බැටරි හිඟය අවසන් වීම නිසා ලබන සඳුදා සිට උපරිම ධාරිතාවෙන් බස් ධාවයන ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව ලංකා ගමනා ගමන මණ්ඩලයේ උසස් නිලධාරියකු පැවසීය.",
        "ලංගම මුහුණ දී සිටි ටයර් සහ බැටරි හිඟය හේතුවෙන් බස් රථ 5,000 න් බස් රථ 2000 ක් පමණ ධාවනය කිරීමට නොහැකිව තිබූ බවත් ඒ අනුව දුරගමන් සේවා සියයට 80 ක් පමණ අත්හිටුවීමට සිදුව තිබූ බවත් එම නිලධාරියා කීය.",
        "ටයර් සහ බැටරි මිලදීගැනීමේ ප්‍රසංපාදන ක්‍රියාවලියේ ගැටලුවක් හේතුවෙන් මිලදී ගැනීම ප්‍රමාද වූ බව ද එම නිලධාරියා වැඩි දුරටත් කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සඳුදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 80 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் அதிகபட்ச திறனில் இயங்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை (லங்காம) எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள டயர்கள் மற்றும் பேட்டரிகள் தட்டுப்பாடு நீங்கியுள்ளதால், எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் பஸ்கள் அதிகபட்ச கொள்ளளவில் இயங்கும் என இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "லங்காமா எதிர்கொள்ளும் டயர்கள் மற்றும் பேட்டரிகள் இல்லாததால், 5,000 பேருந்துகளில் சுமார் 2,000 பேருந்துகளை இயக்க முடியவில்லை, இதனால் சுமார் 80 சதவீத தொலைதூர சேவைகள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக அந்த அதிகாரி கூறினார்.",
        "டயர்கள் மற்றும் பேட்டரிகள் வாங்குவதற்கான கொள்முதல் நடவடிக்கையில் ஏற்பட்ட சிக்கல் காரணமாக கொள்முதல் செய்வதில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டதாக அந்த அதிகாரி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்காமா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 80 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}