{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84605/bandula-prasanna-and-wimal-called-before-hrcsl",
  "time_ut": 1661751960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bandula, Prasanna and Wimal called before HRCSL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bandula, Prasanna and Wimal called before HRCSL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ministers Bandula Gunawardena, Prasanna Ranathunga and MP Wimal Weerawansa have been called before the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka (HRCSL).",
        "The commission stated that they have been summoned in connection with the investigations into the violent incidents that occurred on May 09th and the after that day, including the torching of several MPs’ houses and damaging their properties.",
        "Accordingly, the commission is scheduled to note down the preliminary facts required for the probes today (29).",
        "The relevant MPs had filed a complaint with Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka that their houses were set on fire. The investigations are conducted in accordance with the complaints.",
        "Meanwhile, several local council Chairmen have also been summoned to the Human Rights Commission today for the investigations of the damage done to houses and property during the events that occurred on and after May 9.",
        "HRCSL mentioned that they will only record the basic facts from this group today (29)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bandula",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prasanna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wimal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "HRCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranathunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 09th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chairmen",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බන්දුල, ප්‍රසන්න සහ විමල් මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම හමුවට කැඳවූහ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව (HRCSL) වෙත කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුගේ නිවාසවලට ගිනි තැබීම් සහ දේපළවලට හානි කිරීම ඇතුළු මැයි 09 වැනිදා සහ ඉන් පසු දින සිදු වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සිදු කෙරෙන විමර්ශනවලට අදාළව ඔවුන් කැඳවා ඇති බව කොමිසම ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ඒ අනුව විමර්ශන සඳහා අවශ්‍ය මූලික කරුණු කොමිසම අද (29) සටහන් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "තම නිවාසවලට ගිනි තැබූ බවට අදාළ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවට පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කර තිබුණා. එම පැමිණිලිවලට අනුව විමර්ශන සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "මේ අතර, මැයි 9 වැනිදා සහ ඉන් පසුව සිදුවූ සිදුවීම්වලදී නිවාස සහ දේපළවලට සිදුවූ අලාභහානි පිළිබඳ පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා සභාපතිවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ද අද මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට කැඳවා තිබෙනවා.",
        "HRCSL සඳහන් කළේ ඔවුන් අද (29) මෙම කණ්ඩායමෙන් මූලික කරුණු පමණක් සටහන් කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බන්දුල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රසන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "විමල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "HRCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සභාපතිවරු",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பந்துல, பிரசன்னா மற்றும் விமல் ஆகியோர் HRCSL முன் அழைக்கப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமைச்சர்களான பந்துல குணவர்தன, பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்ச ஆகியோர் இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 09ஆம் திகதி மற்றும் அதற்குப் பின்னரான காலப்பகுதியில் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்கள், பல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வீடுகளுக்கு தீவைப்பு மற்றும் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தமை உள்ளிட்ட விசாரணைகள் தொடர்பிலேயே இவர்கள் அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஆணைக்குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, விசாரணைகளுக்குத் தேவையான முதற்கட்ட உண்மைகளை ஆணைக்குழு இன்று (29) பதிவு செய்ய உள்ளது.",
        "தமது வீடுகளுக்கு தீ வைக்கப்பட்டதாக சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவில் முறைப்பாடு செய்திருந்தனர். முறைப்பாடுகளுக்கு அமைய விசாரணைகள் நடத்தப்படுகின்றன.",
        "இதேவேளை, கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி மற்றும் அதற்குப் பின்னரான காலப்பகுதியில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வுகளின் போது வீடுகள் மற்றும் சொத்துக்களுக்கு ஏற்பட்ட சேதங்கள் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகளுக்காக பல உள்ளூராட்சி மன்ற தலைவர்களும் இன்று மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று (29) இந்தக் குழுவிடமிருந்து அடிப்படை உண்மைகளை மட்டுமே பதிவு செய்வார்கள் என்று HRCSL குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பந்துல",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிரசன்னா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "விமல்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "HRCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}