{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගෝඨා-දක්ෂ-දේශපාලකයෙක්-නොවේ/1-618278",
  "time_ut": 1660728131,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨා දක්ෂ දේශපාලකයෙක් නොවේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gota was not a skilled politician",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Udayanga Weeratunga, the former ambassador of Russia, said that former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa has said that he will come to Sri Lanka on the 24th.",
        "Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa is not a skilled politician. He also says that he is a competent administrative officer. He also says that Gotabaya is not as talented as Mahinda Rajapaksa as a politician.",
        "Mr. Weeratunga said this in a media inquiry while returning from the Criminal Investigation Department to give a statement regarding the alleged MiG aircraft fraud that took place during the war."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Udayanga Weeratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 24th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weeratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨා දක්ෂ දේශපාලකයෙක් නොවේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලබන 24 වැනි දා මෙරටට පැමිණනෙ බව පවසා ඇතැයි රුසියාවේ හිටපු තානාපති උදයංග වීරතුංග මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දක්ෂ දේශපාලනඥයකු නොවෙයි. ඔහු දක්ෂ පරිපාලන නිලධාරියකු බව ද ඔහු පවසයි. දේශපාලනඥයකු වශයෙන් මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ තරම් ගෝඨාභය දක්ෂයකු නොවන බව ද ඔහු පවසයි.",
        "යුද සමයේ සිදු වූ බව කියන මිග් ගුවන් යානා වංචාව  සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීමට අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පැමිණ ආපසු පිටව යද්දී මාධ්‍ය කළ විමසීමකදී වීරතුංග මහතා මේ බව කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "උදයංග වීරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டா திறமையான அரசியல்வாதி அல்ல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் 24ஆம் திகதி இலங்கை வரவுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக ரஷ்யாவின் முன்னாள் தூதுவர் திரு உதயங்க வீரதுங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "திரு.கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச திறமையான அரசியல்வாதி அல்ல. அவர் ஒரு திறமையான நிர்வாக அதிகாரி என்றும் கூறுகிறார். மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவை போல் கோட்டாபய ஒரு அரசியல்வாதி போல் திறமையானவர் அல்ல என்றும் அவர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "யுத்த காலத்தில் இடம்பெற்றதாகக் கூறப்படும் மிக் விமான மோசடி தொடர்பில் வாக்குமூலம் வழங்குவதற்காக குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தில் இருந்து நாடு திரும்பிய போது ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் விசாரனையில் திரு.வீரதுங்க மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உதயங்க வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}