{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/වරප්‍රසාද-ඇති-රාජ්‍ය-අමාත්‍යධුර-නැත්නම්-බැසිල්ගේ-කණ්ඩායම-ජනපතිගේ-අයවැයට-විරුද්ධයි-/11-396665",
  "time_ut": 1661666938,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වරප්‍රසාද ඇති රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යධුර නැත්නම් බැසිල්ගේ කණ්ඩායම ජනපතිගේ අයවැයට විරුද්ධයි?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Is Basil's group against the President's budget or the state ministries with privileges?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sunday Times reports that the group supporting Mr. Basil Rajapaksa of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has stated that if privileges are not granted to the ministers to be appointed in the future, they will vote against the budget to be presented by President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the Minister of Finance on the 30th.",
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna still has the majority in Parliament. Thus they have stated that the state ministers have a private secretary, a press secretary and three coordination secretaries and all five of them have separate vehicles.",
        "In addition, state ministers are entitled to five office staff members, three vehicles and other perks enjoyed by ministers. Also, their salaries will be equal to the salaries of ministers.",
        "The Sunday Time newspaper, which mentions that President Ranil Wickremesinghe is currently preparing the list of state ministers, has not yet made a final decision on how many state ministers will be appointed.",
        "Since the state ministers are to be appointed before the presentation of the interim budget and the appointment of an all-party government has become a bit of a problem, it has become complicated to appoint the new cabinet.",
        "The focus is on going forward by including the existing cabinet and several other parties and such inclusion will naturally lead to a rift between the government and the parties concerned."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Basil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Time",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වරප්‍රසාද ඇති රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යධුර නැත්නම් බැසිල්ගේ කණ්ඩායම ජනපතිගේ අයවැයට විරුද්ධයි?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉදිරියේදී පත්කිරීමට නියමිත රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් සඳහා වරප්‍රසාද හිමි නොවන්නේ නම් ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙසින් ලබන 30 දා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත අයවැයට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහාය පළ කරන කණ්ඩායම ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇතැයි සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පත වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ තවමත් බහුතරය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට පවතී. මේ අනුව ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තෙ , රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන්ට පෞද්ගලික ලේකම්වරයෙක්,  මාධ්‍ය ලේකම්වරයෙක් සහ සම්බන්ධීකරණ ලේකම්වරු තිදෙනෙක් හිමි වෙති ඔවුන් පස්දෙනාටම වෙනම වාහන හිමිවේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව, රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන්ට කාර්යාල කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින් පස් දෙනෙකු, වාහන තුනක් සහ අමාත්‍යවරුන් භුක්ති විඳින වෙනත් වරප්‍රසාද ද හිමිවේ. එසේම ඔවුන්ගේ වැටුප් ඇමැතිවරුන්ගේ වැටුපට සමාන වෙයි.",
        "ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ වන විට රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන්ගේ නාම ලේඛනය සකස් කරමින් සිටින බව සඳහන් කරන සන්ඩේ ටයිම් පුවත්පත රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් කොපමණ සංඛ්‍යාවක් පත්කරන්නේදැයි යන්න පිළිබඳව තවමත් අවසන් තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැත.",
        "අතුරු අයැවැය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට මත්තෙන් රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරන් පත්කිරීමට නියමිත බවත් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පත්කිරීම තරමක ගැටලුවක් බවට පත්ව ඇති හෙයින් නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය පත්කිරීමට සංකීර්ණ වී තිබේ.",
        "පවතින ඇමැති මණ්‌ඩලය සහ තවත් පක්‍ෂවලින් කිහිප දෙනකු ඇතුළත් කර ගනිමින් ඉදිරියට යාමට අවධානය යොමුකර ඇති අතර එසේ ඇතුළත් කිරීම ස්වභාවිකවම රජය සහ අදාළ පාර්ශ්ව අතර විරසකයකට තුඩු දෙනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැසිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பசில் குழு ஜனாதிபதியின் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்திற்கோ அல்லது அரச அமைச்சுக்களுக்கோ எதிரானதா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ள அமைச்சர்களுக்கு சலுகைகள் வழங்கப்படாவிட்டால் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்படும் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிப்போம் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பசில் ராஜபக்சவை ஆதரிக்கும் குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக சண்டே டைம்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. 30ஆம் தேதி நிதி அமைச்சர்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவுக்கு இன்னும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை உள்ளது. இதனால், மாநில அமைச்சர்களுக்கு தனிச் செயலாளர், செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், மூன்று ஒருங்கிணைப்புச் செயலாளர்கள் இருப்பதாகவும், அவர்கள் ஐவருக்கும் தனித்தனி வாகனங்கள் இருப்பதாகவும் அவர்கள் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும், மாநில அமைச்சர்கள் ஐந்து அலுவலக ஊழியர்கள், மூன்று வாகனங்கள் மற்றும் அமைச்சர்கள் அனுபவிக்கும் இதர சலுகைகளுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு. மேலும், அவர்களின் சம்பளம், அமைச்சர்களின் சம்பளத்துக்கு இணையாக இருக்கும்.",
        "இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்களின் பட்டியலை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தற்போது தயாரித்து வருவதாக குறிப்பிடும் சண்டே டைம் பத்திரிகை, எத்தனை இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் நியமிக்கப்படுவார்கள் என்பது குறித்து இன்னும் இறுதித் தீர்மானம் எடுக்கவில்லை.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னதாகவே அரச அமைச்சர்கள் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாலும், சர்வகட்சி ஆட்சியை நியமிப்பதிலும் சற்று சிக்கல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாலும், புதிய அமைச்சரவையை நியமிப்பதில் சிக்கல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள அமைச்சரவை மற்றும் பல கட்சிகளை உள்ளடக்கி முன்னோக்கி செல்வது குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துளசி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}