{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131337",
  "time_ut": 1657635454,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய இன்று பதவி விலகுகிறார்  ?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Gotabaya resigns today?",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is expected to step down on Wednesday. Speaker Mahinda Yaba Abeywardana had announced that the President would announce his resignation to the people on the 13th in order to peacefully hand over the administration of the country.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has announced his resignation following massive protests and violence in many parts of the country including the capital Colombo on the 9th. The President is expected to step down today as already announced.",
        "Regarding the unstable political situation in the country, a special party leader meeting was held on Monday under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yaba Abeywardhana.",
        "During this, it was decided to convene the parliament on the day after tomorrow, Friday after considering the ideas of all the parties, and after that on the 20th, to elect the interim president.",
        "According to the constitution, if a president resigns before the end of his term, the prime minister can take over as president, and after that, a qualified person can be elected by parliament as interim president for the remainder of the term, according to political experts.",
        "But now the protesting parties are insisting that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should also resign.",
        "It is also reported that if both the President and the Prime Minister have to resign, the Speaker can act as acting President until an interim President is elected.",
        "In this situation, many names have been put forward as the interim president from many sides. United People's Shakti has decided to propose the name of Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa as the Interim President.",
        "On the other hand JVP President Anurakumara Dissanayake has announced that he is ready to take over the government. While there are various differences of opinion, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has not directly announced any issue.",
        "In this situation, it is expected that he will resign today as he has already announced through the Speaker, and if he resigns, it will be recorded as an important event in Sri Lankan political history. It is noteworthy that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has said that he is ready to hand over power and resign if an all-party government is formed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yaba Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yaba Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day after tomorrow, Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "United People's Shakti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය අද ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි?",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. රටේ පාලනය සාමකාමීව භාරදීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලබන 13 වැනිදා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ජනතාවට ප්‍රකාශ කරන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාබ අබේවර්ධන ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණා.",
        "පසුගිය 09 වනදා කොළඹ අගනුවර ඇතුළු දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල දැවැන්ත විරෝධතා සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා හේතුවෙන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ. දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි ජනාධිපතිවරයා අද සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "රටේ පවතින අස්ථාවර දේශපාලන තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කථානායක මහින්ද යාබා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් විශේෂ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් සඳුදා පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මේ අතරවාරයේ සියලු පක්ෂවල අදහස් සලකා බලා අනිද්දා සිකුරාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීමටත්, ඉන් පසු 20 වැනිදා අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමටත් තීරණය විය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව, ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තම ධුර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත්, අගමැතිවරයාට ජනාධිපති ධුරය භාර ගත හැකි අතර, ඉන් පසුව, දේශපාලන අනුව, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අතුරු ජනාධිපති ලෙස සුදුසුකම් ලත් අයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගත හැකිය. විශේෂඥයන්.",
        "එහෙත් මේ වනවිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත පාර්ශව අවධාරණය කරන්නේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ අගමැතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සිදුවුවහොත් අතුරු ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත්කර ගන්නා තෙක් වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කථානායකවරයාට කටයුතු කළ හැකි බවද වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස බොහෝ පාර්ශ්වවලින් නම් රැසක් ඉදිරිපත්ව තිබේ. අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති පක්ෂය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "අනෙක් පැත්තෙන් ජ.වි.පෙ ජනාධිපති අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක මහතා ආණ්ඩුව භාර ගැනීමට සූදානම් බව ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ. විවිධ මතභේද පවතින අතර, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ කිසිදු කරුණක් සෘජුව ප්‍රකාශ කර නැත.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ කථානායකවරයා හරහා මේ වන විටත් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති පරිදි අද දිනයේදී ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරෙන අතර ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ වැදගත් සිදුවීමක් ලෙස සටහන් වනු ඇත. සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් බලය පවරා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සූදානම් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාබා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාබා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට අනිද්දා, සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய இன்று பதவி விலகுகிறார்  ?",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. அமைதியான முறையில் நாட்டு நிர்வாகத்தை ஒப்படைப்பதற்காக 13 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி தனது பதவி விலகலை நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு அறிவிப்பார் என்று சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாபா அபேவர்தன அறிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்களால் கடந்த 9 ஆம் திகதி தலைநகர் கொழும்பு உட்பட நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளிலும் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட பாரிய தன்னெழுச்சி போராட்டங்கள் மற்றும் வன்முறைகளை தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகுவதாக அறிவித்தார். அதற்கமைய ஏற்கனவே அறிவிக்கப்பட்டமைக்கு அமைய ஜனாதிபதி இன்று பதவி விலகுவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள அரசியல் ஸ்திரமற்ற நிலைமை தொடர்பில் நேற்றுமுன்தினம் திங்கட்கிழமை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாபா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் விசேட கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டம் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இதன் போது சகல கட்சிகளினதும் யோசனைகளைக் கருத்திற் கொண்டு நாளை மறுதினம் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தைதைக் கூட்டுவதற்கும் , அதன் பின்னர் 20 ஆம் திகதி இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செயவதற்கும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதியொருவர் தனது பதவி காலம் நிறைவடைவதற்கு முன்னர் பதவி விலகும் பட்சத்தில் பிரதமர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதிபதியாக பதவியேற்க முடியும் என்றும் , அதன் பின்னர் எஞ்சியுள்ள காலத்திற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தகுதியான ஒருவரை இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்ய முடியும் என்று அரசியல் நிபுணர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஆனால் தற்போது பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்றும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள தரப்பினர் வலியுறுத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இவ்வாறு ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் ஆகிய இருவருமே பதவி விலக வேண்டியேற்பட்டால் இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியொருவரை தெரிவு செய்யும் வரையில் சபநாயகரால் பதில் ஜனாதிபதிபதியாக செயற்பட முடியும் என்று அரசியலமைப்பில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இவ்வாறான நிலையில் பல தரப்பிலிருந்தும் இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக பலரது பெயர்களும் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவின் பெயரை முன்மொழிவதற்கு ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "மறுபுறம் ஜே.வி.பி. தலைவர் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆட்சியை பொறுப்பேற்ற தயார் என்று அறிவித்துள்ளார். இவ்வாறு பல்வேறுபட்ட கருத்து முரண்பாடுகள் நிலவுகின்ற நிலையிலும் , ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் நேரடியாக எந்தவொரு விடயம் தொடர்பிலும் அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "இந்நிலையிலேயே அவர் ஏற்கனவே சபாநாயகர் ஊடாக அறிவித்ததன் படி இன்று பதவி விலகுவார் என்றும் , அவ்வாறு விலகும் பட்சத்தில் அது இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் முக்கிய சம்பவமாகப் பதிவாகும் என்றும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட்டால் , ஆட்சியை ஒப்படைத்து பதவி விலகத் தயார் என்று பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாபா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யபா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை மறுநாள், வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}