{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කාලගුණයෙන්-රතු-නිවේදනයක්/11-396766",
  "time_ut": 1661912357,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කාලගුණයෙන් රතු නිවේදනයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A red notice from the weather",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Meteorological Department has issued a warning about heavy rains. This announcement issued at 7.00 am today will be valid until 7.00 am tomorrow.",
        "According to the Department of Meteorology, very heavy rains of more than 150 mm are expected in some places in the Bawan West, South, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces where there is a turbulent situation in the lower atmosphere.",
        "Also, the department adds that heavy rains of around 100 mm may occur in other areas."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Meteorological Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bawan West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාලගුණයෙන් රතු නිවේදනයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තද වැසි පිළිබඳව අවවාදාත්මක නිවේදනයක් කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නිකුත් කර තිබේ. අද පෙරවරු 7.00ට නිකුත් කළ මෙම නිවේදනය හෙට පෙරවරු 7.00 තෙක් වලංගු වෙයි.",
        "පහළ වායුගෝලයේ කැළඹිලි සහිත තත්ත්වයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසන්නයේ පවතින බැවැන් බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම හා ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලි මිටර් 150ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "එසේම සෙසු ප්‍ර දේශවලට මිලි මීටර් 100ක පමණ තද වැසි ඇතිවිය හැකි බවද එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වැඩිදුරටත් පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bawan බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வானிலையிலிருந்து சிவப்பு அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கனமழை பெய்யும் என வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம் எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது. இன்று காலை 7.00 மணிக்கு வெளியிடப்பட்ட இந்த அறிவிப்பு நாளை காலை 7.00 மணி வரை செல்லுபடியாகும்.",
        "வளிமண்டலத்தின் கீழ் வளிமண்டலத்தில் கொந்தளிப்பான சூழ்நிலை காணப்படும் பவான் மேற்கு, தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான கடும் மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களில் சுமார் 100 மில்லிமீற்றர் வரையான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என திணைக்களம் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 7.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 7.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவான் மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}