{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Ranil-and-the-134-backing-him-must-be-sent-home-AKD/56-738958",
  "time_ut": 1661115696,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil and the 134 backing him must be sent home: AKD",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil and the 134 backing him must be sent home: AKD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "National People’s Power (NPP) Leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake claimed the Rajapaksas have not been fully vanquished from Parliament. According to him, while the citizen’s protest managed to get rid of its ugly head, the torso remains in Parliament to this day. “If the country is to be revived then these remainders of the Rajapaksa regime must also be destroyed,” he said",
        "Dissanayake made these comments while addressing those gathered at the massive anti-Government rally held by the party on Saturday in Nugegoda. A protest march organised by the party calling for the Parliament to be dissolved immediately commenced from the Wijerama Junction and headed to Nugegoda where a public meeting was held at the Ananda Samarakoon Open Air Theatre.",
        "“In the last several months we witnessed the most significant uprising of the people in Sri Lanka’s recent history. That citizen’s struggle was able to strike off the head of the Rajapaksa clan. They were able to get rid of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa and Ministers Chamal Rajapaksa, Namal Rajapakasa and Shashindra Rajapaksa. But the torso of the clan by way of their supporting MPs remained in Parliament. Then a new head was just fixed on the remaining torso to survive. That head was Ranil Wickremesinghe,” Dissanayake said.",
        "According to the NPP leader, following this now only two political camps exist in the country. “One is the Ranil-Rajapaksa camp consisting of Ranil, the Rajapaksas, and a group consisting of criminals and frauds,” he noted, adding that there is also a smaller group milling about this camp including those claiming to be independent and certain MPs from Sajith’s faction.",
        "“This camp is not one accepted by the people of this country and is only surviving due to 134 heads in Parliament. They are dependent on the current Constitution as it has helped them to establish a constitutionally accepted power. This camp is also dependent on benefits and rewards,” he said, pointing out that a number of ministers are to be sworn in during the coming week.",
        "“This camp is surviving by wasting millions of public funds by granting additional plum positions. The United National Party managed to only get one MP into Parliament and that was Ranil Wickremesinghe. Every other person lost. But now all of them have also gathered around this camp,” he pointed out.",
        "According to Dissanayake, Ranil is now attempting to bolster his power through repression. “He believes his survival depends on repression. Recently making a speech, he said the citizen’s struggle had peaceful protestors but later that the protests turned towards terrorism. We too watched the arrests carefully to see these so-called terrorists.",
        "“Who were they? One was a person who bathed in the President›s pool, another who used the President›s washroom and another who had earned a slice of papaw at the President›s House,” he said, adding that there is no choice but to send President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the 134 who supported him home."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "AKD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "anti-Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wijerama Junction",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministers Chamal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shashindra Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil-Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් සහ ඔහුට සහාය දෙන 134 ගෙදර යැවිය යුතුයි: ඒ.කේ.ඩී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (NPP) නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂවරුන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් පරාජය කර නොමැති බවයි. ඔහුට අනුව, පුරවැසි විරෝධය එහි කැත හිසෙන් මිදීමට සමත් වූ අතර, කඳ අද දක්වාම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පවතී. “රට යළි පණ ගැන්වීමට නම් රාජපක්ෂ පාලනයේ මේ ඉතිරි කොටස් ද විනාශ කළ යුතුය,” ඔහු පැවසීය",
        "දිසානායක මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ එම පක්ෂය විසින් සෙනසුරාදා නුගේගොඩදී පැවැත්වූ දැවැන්ත ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී ජන රැළියට රැස්ව සිටි පිරිස අමතමිනි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වහා විසුරුවා හරින ලෙස ඉල්ලා එම පක්ෂය සංවිධානය කළ විරෝධතා පාගමනක් විජේරාම මංසන්ධියෙන් ආරම්භ වී නුගේගොඩ බලා පිටත්ව ගිය අතර එහිදී ආනන්ද සමරකෝන් එළිමහන් රංග පීඨයේ ජන හමුවක් පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "“පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෑත ඉතිහාසයේ වඩාත්ම කැපී පෙනෙන ජනතා නැගිටීම අපි දුටුවෙමු. එම පුරවැසි අරගලය රාජපක්ෂ වංශයේ හිස ගසා දැමීමට සමත් විය. ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ, අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්‍ෂ සහ චමල් රාජපක්‍ෂ, නාමල් රාජපක්‍ෂ, ශෂීන්ද්‍ර රාජපක්‍ෂ යන ඇමැතිවරුන්ගෙන් ගැලවීමට ඔවුහු සමත් වූහ. නමුත් ඔවුන්ගේ සහය දෙන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් මාර්ගයෙන් වංශයේ කඳන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රැඳී සිටියේය. එවිට ඉතිරිව ඇති කඳ මත නව හිසක් සවි කර ඇත. ඒ ප්‍රධානියා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතායි” දිසානායක කීවේය.",
        "NPP නායකයාට අනුව, මෙය අනුගමනය කරමින් දැන් රට තුළ පවතින්නේ දේශපාලන කඳවුරු දෙකක් පමණි. එකක් තමයි රනිල්, රාජපක්‍ෂලා, අපරාධකාරයන් සහ වංචාකාරයන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් කණ්ඩායමකින් සමන්විත රනිල්-රාජපක්‍ෂ කඳවුර, ස්වාධීන යැයි කියා ගන්නා අය ඇතුළු කුඩා කණ්ඩායමක් ද මේ කඳවුර ගැන හොල්මන් කරන බවත්, ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරු ද සිටින බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. සජිත්ගේ කල්ලිය.",
        "“මේ කඳවුර මේ රටේ ජනතාව පිළිගත් එකක් නෙවෙයි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඔළු 134ක් නිසා බේරිලා ඉන්නවා. ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව පිළිගත් බලයක් පිහිටුවීමට එය ඉවහල් වූ බැවින් ඔවුන් වත්මන් ව්‍යවස්ථාව මත යැපෙයි. මේ කඳවුරත් රඳාපවතින්නේ ප්‍රතිලාභ සහ ත්‍යාග මතයි.” ඉදිරි සතිය තුළදී අමාත්‍යවරුන් රැසක් දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිත බවද ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "“අතිරේක ප්ලම් තනතුරු ලබා දීමෙන් මිලියන ගණන් මහජන මුදල් නාස්ති කරමින් මේ කඳවුර බේරෙනවා. එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට යාමට හැකි වූයේ එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පමණක් වන අතර ඒ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාය. අනෙක් සෑම පුද්ගලයෙකුම අහිමි විය. නමුත් දැන් ඒ හැමෝමත් මේ කඳවුර වටා රොක් වෙලා.” ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "දිසානායකට අනුව දැන් රනිල් උත්සාහ කරන්නේ මර්දනය හරහා තම බලය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමටය. “ඔහුගේ පැවැත්ම රඳා පවතින්නේ මර්දනය මත බව ඔහු විශ්වාස කරයි. පසුගියදා කතාවක් කරමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ පුරවැසි අරගලයට සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන් සිටි නමුත් පසුව එම විරෝධතා ත්‍රස්තවාදය දෙසට හැරුණු බවයි. අපිත් මේ ඊනියා ත්‍රස්තවාදීන් දැකීමට අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් දෙස හොඳින් බලා සිටියෙමු.",
        "“ඔවුන් කවුද? එක්කෙනෙක් ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ පූල් එකේ නාපු කෙනෙක්, තව කෙනෙක් ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ වොෂ් රූම් එක පාවිච්චි කරපු කෙනෙක්, තව කෙනෙක් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ පැපොල් පෙත්තක් හම්බ කරපු කෙනෙක්,” යෑවීම හැර වෙනත් විකල්පයක් නොමැති බව ඔහු පැවසීය. රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඇතුළු ඔහුට සහය දුන් 134 දෙනා ගෙදර."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "AKD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේරාම හන්දිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන චමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශෂීන්ද්‍ර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙකක් පමණක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්-රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலையும் அவருக்கு ஆதரவான 134 பேரையும் வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்ப வேண்டும்: ஏ.கே.டி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் (NPP) தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, ராஜபக்ஷக்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து முழுமையாக தோற்கடிக்கப்படவில்லை என்று கூறினார். அவரைப் பொறுத்தவரை, குடிமக்களின் எதிர்ப்பு அதன் அசிங்கமான தலையை அகற்ற முடிந்தது, உடல் இன்றுவரை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ளது. \"நாடு புத்துயிர் பெற வேண்டுமானால் ராஜபக்ச ஆட்சியின் எஞ்சிய பகுதிகளும் அழிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்",
        "திஸாநாயக்க, நுகேகொடையில் சனிக்கிழமை நடைபெற்ற அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான பாரிய பேரணியில் கலந்து கொண்டவர்களுடன் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். பாராளுமன்றத்தை உடனடியாக கலைக்குமாறு கோரி அக்கட்சி ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்ட பேரணி விஜேராம சந்தியிலிருந்து ஆரம்பமாகி நுகேகொட வரை சென்று ஆனந்த சமரகோன் திறந்தவெளி அரங்கில் பொதுக்கூட்டம் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "“கடந்த சில மாதங்களில் இலங்கையின் அண்மைக்கால வரலாற்றில் மிக முக்கியமான மக்களின் எழுச்சியை நாங்கள் கண்டோம். அந்த பிரஜையின் போராட்டம் ராஜபக்ச குலத்தின் தலையை துண்டிக்க முடிந்தது. ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் அமைச்சர்களான சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, நாமல் ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் ஷசீந்திர ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோரை அவர்களால் அகற்ற முடிந்தது. ஆனால் அவர்களின் ஆதரவு எம்.பி.க்கள் மூலம் குலத்தின் உடல் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நிலைத்திருந்தது. பின்னர் ஒரு புதிய தலை உயிர்வாழ மீதமுள்ள உடற்பகுதியில் பொருத்தப்பட்டது. அந்தத் தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கதான்” என்று திஸாநாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "NPP தலைவரின் கூற்றுப்படி, இதைத் தொடர்ந்து இப்போது நாட்டில் இரண்டு அரசியல் முகாம்கள் மட்டுமே உள்ளன. ஒன்று, ரணில், ராஜபக்சக்கள் அடங்கிய ரணில்-ராஜபக்ஷ முகாம், குற்றவாளிகள் மற்றும் மோசடி செய்பவர்கள் அடங்கிய குழு, சுயேச்சை என்று கூறிக்கொள்பவர்கள் மற்றும் சில எம்.பி.க்கள் உட்பட ஒரு சிறிய குழுவும் இந்த முகாமை சுற்றிவளைத்து வருவதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டார். சஜித்தின் கோஷ்டி.",
        "“இந்த முகாம் இந்த நாட்டு மக்களால் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட ஒன்றல்ல, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள 134 தலைவர்களால்தான் இந்த முகாம் எஞ்சியிருக்கிறது. அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட அதிகாரத்தை நிறுவுவதற்கு உதவியதால் அவர்கள் தற்போதைய அரசியலமைப்பை நம்பியிருக்கிறார்கள். இந்த முகாம் நன்மைகள் மற்றும் வெகுமதிகளில் தங்கியுள்ளது, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார், வரும் வாரத்தில் பல அமைச்சர்கள் பதவியேற்க உள்ளனர்.",
        "“கூடுதல் பிளம் பதவிகளை வழங்குவதன் மூலம் மில்லியன் கணக்கான பொது நிதியை வீணடிப்பதன் மூலம் இந்த முகாம் பிழைத்து வருகிறது. ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியால் ஒரு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரை மாத்திரமே பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வரமுடிந்தது அது ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க. மற்ற ஒவ்வொரு நபரும் இழந்தனர். ஆனால் இப்போது அவர்கள் அனைவரும் இந்த முகாமைச் சுற்றி திரண்டுள்ளனர்,” என்று அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "திஸாநாயக்கவின் கூற்றுப்படி, ரணில் இப்போது அடக்குமுறை மூலம் தனது அதிகாரத்தை வலுப்படுத்த முயற்சிக்கிறார். \"அவரது பிழைப்பு அடக்குமுறையைச் சார்ந்தது என்று அவர் நம்புகிறார். சமீபத்தில் ஒரு உரை நிகழ்த்திய அவர், குடிமக்களின் போராட்டத்தில் அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் இருந்ததாகவும், பின்னர் போராட்டங்கள் பயங்கரவாதத்தை நோக்கி திரும்பியதாகவும் கூறினார். பயங்கரவாதிகள் என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர்களைப் பார்க்க நாங்களும் கைதுகளை கவனமாகப் பார்த்தோம்.",
        "\"யார் அவர்கள்? ஒருவர் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் குளத்தில் குளித்தவர், மற்றொருவர் குடியரசுத் தலைவரின் கழிவறையைப் பயன்படுத்தியவர், மற்றொருவர் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மாளிகையில் பாப்பா துண்டு சம்பாதித்தவர்,” என்று கூறி அனுப்புவதைத் தவிர வேறு வழியில்லை என்றார். ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் அவருக்கு ஆதரவளித்த 134 பேர் வீட்டில்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏ.கே.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசுக்கு எதிரானது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேராம சந்தி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பல மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷசீந்திர ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மட்டும்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்-ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}