{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Colombo-ports-transshipment-volumes-decline-for-second-straight-month-in-July/108-244289",
  "time_ut": 1662305156,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Colombo port’s transshipment volumes decline for second straight month in July",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo port’s transshipment volumes decline for second straight month in July",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Main shipping lines avoid Colombo amid social and political unrest",
        "Local shipping industry says regaining confidence of main shipping lines could take months",
        "Transshipment container volumes at the Port of Colombo fell for the second consecutive month in July by a record 7.5 percent year-on-year (YoY) to 460,736 TEUs as main shipping lines temporarily opted for alternative routes at the height of the country’s political and social unrest.",
        "Although, the operations at Port of Colombo remained largely intact despite the mass protests and political crisis, a local shipping agent pointed out that July 9th further escalated concerns on law and order in Sri Lanka among the main shipping lines.",
        "Industry stakeholders fear it might take several months to regain confidence of main shipping lines.",
        "In the seven-month period, transshipment container volumes declined by 0.2 percent YoY to 3.35 million TEUs.",
        "Overall, container throughput at the Port of Colombo declined by 10.5 percent YoY to 553,890 TEUs in July. In particular, import (laden) container volumes declined by a steep 21.4 percent YoY to 30,366 TEUs while export (laden) container volumes dipped by 6.8 percent YoY to 25,247 TEUs.",
        "The SLPA-managed Jaya Container Terminal (JCT) and its partially operational East Container Terminal (ECT) handled only 115,539 TEUs in July, recording a sharp YoY decline of 39 percent, due to the notable decline in transshipment container volumes from India.",
        "However, the port’s only fully operational deep container terminal, Colombo International Container Terminal (CICT) managed to handle 286,419 TEUs in the month, up by 1.2 percent YoY. Similarly, the container volumes handled by South Asia Gateway Terminal (SAGT) also rose by 3.5 percent YoY to 151,932 TEUs in the month.",
        "Overall, the container throughput of Port of Colombo declined by 2.1 percent YoY to 4.11 million TEUs in the seven-month period. Meanwhile, cargo handled by Hambatota Port also declined by 48.6 percent YoY to 147,495 TEUs in July."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "second straight month",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second consecutive month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a record 7.5 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "460,736",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.35 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.5 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "553,890",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21.4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,366",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,247",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaya Container Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "East Container Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 115,539",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "YoY",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo International Container Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "286,419",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia Gateway Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "151,932",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.11 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambatota Port",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "147,495",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ වරායේ ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත කිරීම් ප්‍රමාණය ජූලි මාසයේදී අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන මාසයටත් පහත වැටේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමාජ හා දේශපාලන නොසන්සුන්තා මධ්‍යයේ ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ග කොළඹ මග හැරේ",
        "දේශීය නැව් කර්මාන්තය පවසන්නේ ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ගවල විශ්වාසය නැවත ලබා ගැනීමට මාස කිහිපයක් ගත විය හැකි බවයි",
        "කොළඹ වරායේ ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත බහාලුම් පරිමාව ජූලි මාසයේදී අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන මාසයටත් වසරින් වසර (YoY) වාර්තාගත සියයට 7.5 කින් TEU 460,736 ක් දක්වා පහත වැටුණේ ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ග තාවකාලිකව විකල්ප මාර්ග තෝරා ගැනීම නිසා රටේ දේශපාලන සහ සමාජීය උච්චතම අවස්ථාවයි. නොසන්සුන්තාව.",
        "මහජන විරෝධතා සහ දේශපාලන අර්බුද මධ්‍යයේ වුවද කොළඹ වරායේ මෙහෙයුම් බොහෝ දුරට නොවෙනස්ව පැවතියද, ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ග අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නීතිය හා සාමය පිළිබඳ උත්සුකයන් ජුලි 9 වැනිදා තවදුරටත් උත්සන්න කළ බව දේශීය නැව් නියෝජිතයෙක් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ග පිළිබඳ විශ්වාසය නැවත ලබා ගැනීමට මාස කිහිපයක් ගතවනු ඇතැයි කර්මාන්ත පාර්ශවකරුවන් බිය වෙති.",
        "මාස හතක කාලය තුළ, ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත බහාලුම් පරිමාව TEU මිලියන 3.35 දක්වා YYY හි සියයට 0.2 කින් අඩු විය.",
        "සමස්තයක් වශයෙන්, කොළඹ වරායේ බහාලුම් ප්‍රතිදානය ජූලි මාසයේදී TEU 553,890 දක්වා සියයට 10.5 කින් අඩු විය. විශේෂයෙන්ම, ආනයන (පැටවූ) බහාලුම් පරිමාව වසරින් වසර සියයට 21.4 කින් ටීඊයූ 30,366 දක්වා ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් පහත වැටී ඇති අතර අපනයන (පැටවූ) බහාලුම් පරිමාව වසරින් වසර සියයට 6.8 කින් අඩු වී ටීඊයූ 25,247 ක් විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරාය අධිකාරිය විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරන ලද ජය බහලු පර්යන්තය (JCT) සහ එහි අර්ධ වශයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන නැගෙනහිර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය (ECT) ජුලි මාසයේදී TEU 115,539 ක් පමණක් හසුරුවා ඇති අතර, ඉන්දියාවෙන් ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත කිරීමේ බහාලුම් පරිමාවෙහි කැපී පෙනෙන අඩුවීමක් හේතුවෙන්, 39% ක තියුණු පහත වැටීමක් වාර්තා විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, වරායේ එකම පූර්ණ ක්‍රියාකාරී ගැඹුරු බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය වන කොළඹ ජාත්‍යන්තර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය (CICT) මාසය තුළ TEU 286,419 ක් හැසිරවීමට සමත් වූ අතර එය වසරින් වසර සියයට 1.2 කින් වැඩි විය. ඒ හා සමානව, දකුණු ආසියා ගේට්වේ ටර්මිනල් (SAGT) විසින් හසුරුවන ලද බහාලුම් පරිමාව ද මාසයේ දී TEUs 151,932 දක්වා සියයට 3.5 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "සමස්තයක් වශයෙන්, මාස හතක කාලය තුළ කොළඹ වරායේ බහාලුම් ප්‍රතිදානය වසරින් වසර සියයට 2.1 කින් TEU මිලියන 4.11 දක්වා අඩු විය. මේ අතර, හම්බන්තොට වරාය විසින් මෙහෙයවන ලද භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය ද ජූලි මාසයේදී TEUs 147,495 ක් දක්වා වසරින් වසර සියයට 48.6 කින් අඩු විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවන අඛණ්ඩ මාසය",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජුලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්තාගත සියයට 7.5 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "460,736 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.2 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.35 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10.5 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "553,890 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 21.4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,366 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6.8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,247 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජය බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115,539 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "YoY",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 39 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාත්‍යන්තර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "286,419 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.2 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියා ගේට්වේ පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 3.5 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "151,932 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 2.1 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.11 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 48.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "147,495 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் டிரான்ஷிப்மென்ட் அளவு ஜூலை மாதத்தில் தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது மாதமாக குறைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமூக மற்றும் அரசியல் அமைதியின்மைக்கு மத்தியில் பிரதான கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து கொழும்பைத் தவிர்க்கிறது",
        "முக்கிய கப்பல் பாதைகளின் நம்பிக்கையை மீட்டெடுக்க பல மாதங்கள் ஆகலாம் என்று உள்ளூர் கப்பல் துறை கூறுகிறது",
        "கொழும்புத் துறைமுகத்தில் உள்ள டிரான்ஸ்ஷிப்மென்ட் கொள்கலன் அளவுகள் ஜூலை மாதத்தில் தொடர்ச்சியாக இரண்டாவது மாதமாக 7.5 சதவிகிதம் ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு (YoY) 460,736 TEU க்கு வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தன அமைதியின்மை.",
        "பாரிய எதிர்ப்புக்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடிகள் இருந்தபோதிலும் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் செயற்பாடுகள் பெருமளவில் அப்படியே இருந்த போதிலும், ஒரு உள்ளூர் கப்பல் முகவர், ஜூலை 9 இலங்கையின் சட்டம் மற்றும் ஒழுங்கு தொடர்பான கவலைகளை பிரதான கப்பல் போக்குவரத்துக்களில் மேலும் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "முக்கிய ஷிப்பிங் லைன்களின் நம்பிக்கையை மீண்டும் பெற பல மாதங்கள் ஆகலாம் என்று தொழில்துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் அஞ்சுகின்றனர்.",
        "ஏழு மாத காலப்பகுதியில், டிரான்ஸ்ஷிப்மென்ட் கொள்கலன் அளவுகள் 0.2 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 3.35 மில்லியன் TEUகளாக உள்ளது.",
        "மொத்தத்தில், கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் கொள்கலன் உற்பத்தியானது ஜூலை மாதத்தில் 10.5 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 553,890 TEU ஆக இருந்தது. குறிப்பாக, இறக்குமதி (ஏற்றப்பட்ட) கொள்கலன் அளவுகள் ஆண்டுக்கு 21.4 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 30,366 TEUகளாக இருந்தது, அதே சமயம் ஏற்றுமதி (ஏற்றப்பட்ட) கொள்கலன் அளவுகள் 6.8 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 25,247 TEUகளாக உள்ளது.",
        "SLPA நிர்வகிக்கும் ஜெயா கன்டெய்னர் டெர்மினல் (JCT) மற்றும் அதன் பகுதியளவில் செயல்படும் கிழக்கு கொள்கலன் முனையம் (ECT) ஆகியவை ஜூலையில் 115,539 TEUகளை மட்டுமே கையாண்டன, இந்தியாவில் இருந்து டிரான்ஸ்ஷிப்மென்ட் கொள்கலன் அளவுகளில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சரிவு காரணமாக, 39 சதவிகிதம் கூர்மையான வீழ்ச்சியைப் பதிவு செய்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், துறைமுகத்தின் ஒரே முழு செயல்பாட்டு ஆழமான கொள்கலன் முனையமான கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் முனையம் (CICT) இந்த மாதத்தில் 286,419 TEUகளைக் கையாள முடிந்தது, இது ஆண்டுக்கு 1.2 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்துள்ளது. இதேபோல், தெற்காசியா கேட்வே டெர்மினல் (SAGT) கையாளும் கொள்கலன் அளவும் 3.5 சதவீதம் ஆண்டு அதிகரித்து 151,932 TEUகளாக உள்ளது.",
        "ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக, ஏழு மாத காலப்பகுதியில் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் கொள்கலன் உற்பத்தி 2.1 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 4.11 மில்லியன் TEU ஆக இருந்தது. இதற்கிடையில், ஹம்பதோட்டா துறைமுகத்தால் கையாளப்படும் சரக்குகளும் ஜூலை மாதத்தில் 48.6 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 147,495 TEU களாக இருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது தொடர் மாதம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாதனை 7.5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "460,736",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.35 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "553,890",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,366",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,247",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயா கொள்கலன் முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கொள்கலன் முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115,539 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஒய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "286,419",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா கேட்வே டெர்மினல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "151,932",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.11 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பத்தோட்ட துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "147,495",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}