{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මාගම්මන-නිවසේ-ගින්නෙන්-තුවාල-ලද-දියණියත්-මරුට/101-615553",
  "time_ut": 1656414356,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මාගම්මන නිවසේ ගින්නෙන් තුවාල ලද දියණියත් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Daughter injured in Magammana house fire dies",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kahathuduwa Police said that a 19-year-old girl who was receiving treatment at the Intensive Care Unit of the Colombo National Hospital after sustaining severe burn injuries in a fire that broke out at a house in the Magammana area in Homagama on the night of the 25th has died a short while ago.",
        "The deceased has been identified as Kavindi Ranasinghe, 19, a resident of Magammana, Homagama.",
        "The last rites of the parents of Kavindi Ranasinghe who died in the fire will be held on the 28th.",
        "The injured six-year-old daughter is currently being treated at Lady Ridgeway Children's Hospital."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Magammana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kahathuduwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Intensive Care Unit of the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama on the night of the 25th",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kavindi Ranasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kavindi Ranasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 28th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lady Ridgeway Children's Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාගම්මන නිවසේ ගින්නෙන් තුවාල ලද දියණියත් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෝමාගම මාගම්මන ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක ඉකුත් 25 දා රාත්‍රි  ඇතිවූ ගින්නෙන් බරපතල පිළිස්සුම් තුවාල ලබා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලේ දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටි 19 හැවිරිදි දියණිය මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර මිය ගිය බව කහතුඩුව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත්තේ හෝමාගම මාගම්මන පදිංචිව සිටි කාවින්දි රණසිංහ 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණියකි.",
        "ගින්නෙන් මීට පෙර මියගිය කාවින්දී රණසිංහ තරුණියගෙ මවුපියන් ගේ මෘත දේහය පිළිබඳ අවසන් කටයුතු (28) දා පැවැත්වේ .",
        "තුවාල ලැබූ සය හැවිරිදි දියණිය මේ වන විට රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාගම්මන",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කහතුඩුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලේ දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ හෝමාගම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාවින්දි රණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාවින්දි රණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாகம்மன வீட்டிற்க்கு ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் படுகாயமடைந்த மகள் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹோமாகம, மாகம்மன பகுதியில் உள்ள வீடொன்றில் நேற்று இரவு ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் 19 வயதுடைய இளம்பெண் ஒருவர் பலத்த தீக்காயங்களுக்கு உள்ளாகி கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையின் அதிதீவிர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக கஹதுடுவ பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். 25ஆம் திகதி சற்று முன்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் ஹோமாகம, மாகம்மன பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 19 வயதான கவிந்தி ரணசிங்க என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "தீ விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்த காவிந்தி ரணசிங்கவின் பெற்றோரின் இறுதிக் கிரியைகள் எதிர்வரும் 28ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "காயமடைந்த ஆறு வயது மகள் தற்போது லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே குழந்தைகள் மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மகம்மன",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கஹதுடுவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையின் அதிதீவிர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25ஆம் திகதி இரவு ஹோமாகம",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவிந்தி ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவிந்தி ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே குழந்தைகள் மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}