{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/25/jonas-vingegaard-seals-2022-tour-de-france-triumph-in-paris/",
  "time_ut": 1658721780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Jonas Vingegaard seals 2022 Tour de France triumph in Paris",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jonas Vingegaard seals 2022 Tour de France triumph in Paris",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Jonas Vingegaard claimed his maiden Tour de France title after Sunday’s 21st and final stage, completing a triumph he effectively sealed in the mountains after a vintage duel with Tadej Pogacar.",
        "The 25-year-old, who five years ago was working as a fish packer in a factory in the morning before training in the afternoon, followed up on his surprise second place last year.",
        "He finished Sunday’s ride to the Champs Elysees safely in the bunch as Belgian Jasper Philipsen won the last stage in a sprint ahead of Dutch Dylan Groenewegen and Norway’s Alexander Kristoff, who were second and third respectively.",
        "Vingegaard laid the foundations of his victory in the 10th stage, when he and his team-mate Primoz Roglic attacked Pogacar relentlessly and made him crack in the climb up to the Col du Granon.",
        "Pogacar hit back time and time again but Vingegaard and his Jumbo-Visma team contained the feisty Slovenian, with the new champion sealing the victory when he claimed another win at Hautacam in the final mountain stage.",
        "Overall, Vingegaard, who rocketed into the limelight last year, finished ahead of Pogacar and also won the polka-dot jersey for the mountains classification."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jonas Vingegaard",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tour de France",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Paris",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jonas Vingegaard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tour de France",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday’s 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tadej Pogacar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Champs Elysees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belgian Jasper Philipsen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dutch",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dylan Groenewegen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norway",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alexander Kristoff",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vingegaard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Primoz Roglic",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pogacar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jumbo-Visma",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Slovenian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vingegaard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pogacar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Jonas Vingegaard 2022 Tour de France පැරිසියේදී ජයග්‍රහණය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Jonas Vingegaard ඉරිදා 21 වන සහ අවසන් අදියරෙන් පසු ඔහුගේ මංගල Tour de France ශූරතාවයට හිමිකම් කීවේ, Tadej Pogacar සමඟ පැවති වින්ටේජ් ද්වන්ධ සටනකින් පසුව කඳුකරයේ සාර්ථක ලෙස මුද්‍රා තැබූ ජයග්‍රහණයක් සම්පූර්ණ කරමිනි.",
        "25 හැවිරිදි ඔහු, මීට වසර පහකට පෙර දහවල් පුහුණු වීමට පෙර උදෑසන කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවක මාළු අසුරන්නෙකු ලෙස සේවය කළ අතර, පසුගිය වසරේ ඔහු පුදුමයට පත් කරමින් දෙවන ස්ථානය ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "බෙල්ජියම් ජාතික ජැස්පර් ෆිලිප්සන් පිළිවෙළින් දෙවැනි සහ තෙවැනි ස්ථානවල සිටි ඕලන්ද ජාතික ඩිලන් ග්‍රෝනෙවේගන් සහ නෝර්වේහි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ක්‍රිස්ටෝෆ් අභිබවා අවසන් අදියර ජයගත් අතර ඔහු චැම්ප්ස් එලිසීස් වෙත ඉරිදා සවාරිය ආරක්ෂිතව අවසන් කළේය.",
        "Vingegaard 10 වන අදියරේදී ඔහුගේ ජයග්‍රහණයේ අඩිතාලම දැමුවේ ඔහු සහ ඔහුගේ කණ්ඩායමේ සගයා වන Primoz Roglic Pogacar හට නිර්දය ලෙස පහර දුන් අතර Col du Granon දක්වා නැගීමේදී ඔහුව බිඳ දැමීමට සැලැස්වූ විටය.",
        "Pogacar නැවත නැවතත් පහර දුන් නමුත් Vingegaard සහ ඔහුගේ Jumbo-Visma කණ්ඩායම දරුණු ස්ලෝවේනියානු ක්‍රීඩකයින් අඩංගු විය, නව ශූරයා අවසන් කඳුකර අදියරේදී Hautacam හි තවත් ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබා ගත් විට ජයග්‍රහණය මුද්‍රා කළේය.",
        "සමස්තයක් වශයෙන්, පසුගිය වසරේ ජනප්‍රියත්වයට පත් වූ Vingegaard, Pogacar ඉදිරියෙන් අවසන් වූ අතර කඳු වර්ගීකරණය සඳහා polka-dot jersey ද දිනා ගත්තේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජෝනාස් වින්ගගාඩ්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රංශ සංචාරය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැරිස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෝනාස් වින්ගගාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රංශ සංචාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tadej Pogacar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැම්ප්ස් එලිසීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල්ජියම් ජැස්පර් පිලිප්සන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්දේසි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලන් ග්‍රෝනෙවේගන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ක්‍රිස්ටෝෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වින්ග්ගාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Primoz Roglic",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pogacar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජම්බෝ-විස්මා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ලෝවේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වින්ග්ගාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pogacar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Jonas Vingegaard 2022 Tour de France வெற்றியை பாரிசில் முத்திரை பதித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜோனாஸ் விங்கேகார்ட் தனது முதல் டூர் டி பிரான்ஸ் பட்டத்தை ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை 21வது மற்றும் இறுதி கட்டத்திற்குப் பிறகு வென்றார், ததேஜ் போககருடன் விண்டேஜ் சண்டைக்குப் பிறகு மலைகளில் திறம்பட சீல் செய்த வெற்றியை முடித்தார்.",
        "25 வயதான, ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு, மதியம் பயிற்சிக்கு முன் காலையில் ஒரு தொழிற்சாலையில் மீன் பொதி செய்யும் தொழிலாளியாக பணிபுரிந்தார், கடந்த ஆண்டு இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார்.",
        "பெல்ஜியத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஜாஸ்பர் பிலிப்சன், முறையே இரண்டாவது மற்றும் மூன்றாவது இடத்தில் இருந்த டச்சு டிலான் க்ரோனெவெகன் மற்றும் நோர்வேயின் அலெக்சாண்டர் கிறிஸ்டாஃப் ஆகியோரை விட ஸ்பிரிண்டில் கடைசி கட்டத்தை வென்றதால், சாம்ப்ஸ் எலிஸீஸுக்கு ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை பயணத்தை அவர் பாதுகாப்பாக முடித்தார்.",
        "விங்கேகார்ட் 10 வது கட்டத்தில் அவரது வெற்றிக்கு அடித்தளம் அமைத்தார், அவரும் அவரது அணி வீரர் ப்ரிமோஸ் ரோக்லிக்கும் போகாக்கரை இடைவிடாமல் தாக்கி, கோல் டு கிரானான் வரை ஏறுவதில் அவரை விரிசல் செய்ய வைத்தனர்.",
        "போககர் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் அடித்தார், ஆனால் விங்கேகார்ட் மற்றும் அவரது ஜம்போ-விஸ்மா அணியானது பயங்கரமான ஸ்லோவேனியனைக் கொண்டிருந்தது, புதிய சாம்பியன் இறுதி மலை கட்டத்தில் ஹௌடாகாமில் மற்றொரு வெற்றியைப் பெற்றபோது வெற்றியை அடைத்தார்.",
        "ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக, கடந்த ஆண்டு பிரபலமடைந்த விங்கேகார்ட், போககரை விட முன்னேறி, மலைகள் வகைப்பாட்டிற்கான போல்கா-டாட் ஜெர்சியையும் வென்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜோனாஸ் விங்கேகார்ட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "டூர் டி பிரான்ஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாரிஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜோனாஸ் விங்கேகார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டூர் டி பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ததேஜ் போககார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்ப்ஸ் எலிசீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்ஜிய ஜாஸ்பர் பிலிப்சன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டச்சு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிலான் க்ரோனெவெகன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்சாண்டர் கிறிஸ்டாஃப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விங்கேகார்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ரிமோஸ் ரோக்லிக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போககார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜம்போ-விஸ்மா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்லோவேனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விங்கேகார்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போககார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}