{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-opposition-mp-says-agreed-with-rival-on-post-presidential-vote-economy-97596/",
  "time_ut": 1658174760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka opposition MP says agreed with rival on post-presidential vote economy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka opposition MP says agreed with rival on post-presidential vote economy",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka opposition law maker and economic expert Harsha de Silva on Monday said the fraction of former ruling party which now backs Dullas Alahapperuma at the Wednesday’s parliament vote for new president has agreed on a minimum economic program if his party forms the next government.",
        "The meeting comes amid speculations that de Silva’s party leader Sajith Premadasa would withdraw his candidacy from the presidential vote and agree with Alahapperuma’s emerging coalition mainly from the former ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) to settle with Prime Minister post.",
        "“Glad to note Dullas Alahapperuma’s team lead by Prof G L Pieris along with Charitha Herath and Nalaka Godahewa and others came to complete agreement with the common minimum economic program if we form the next Sri Lanka government,” de Silva tweeted.",
        "Glad to note @DullasOfficial team lead by Prof GLP along w @charith9 @GodahewaNalaka and others came to complete agreement with the common minimum economic program if we form the next #SriLanka government. This is based on multiparty proposals compiled by @samarajiva #NMSJ.",
        "The move also comes when Sri Lanka has started negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and debt restructuring with the help of international legal and financial advisors. Policy consistency is crucial for IMF deals and the common minimum program would be decide according to that need, political sources said.",
        "Premadasa’s party sources told EconomyNext that the 2019 presidential candidate and the country’s opposition leader, is considering to withdraw his decision to contest in presidential vote in the parliament on July 20 to ensure the current Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe is defeated without vote split in the parliament.",
        "Sri Lanka’s new president will be decided by the legislators of the 225-member parliament on Wednesday in line with the constitution after the former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country last week in an air force flight and later announced his resignation following months-long protests that plunged the country into a political crisis.",
        "After Rajapaksa resigned, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as the acting president until the new president is chosen.",
        "Premadasa, Alahapperuma, and Marxist Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake have agreed to contest in the presidential vote, while Wickremesinghe’s name is expected to be nominated by former ruling SLPP members.",
        "If both Premadasa and Alahapperuma contest, political analysts say Wickremesinghe has a better chance to win.",
        "Wickremesinghe’s party was defeated in the last parliament polls and he could not win through the public vote. However, he entered the parliament using a bonus seat won by the party. This has raised questions on if he has the people mandate to become a president. Legal experts say the constitution does not bar Wickremesinghe if he is elected by the simple majority in the parliament.  (Colombo/Jul18/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prof G L Pieris",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prof GLP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@samarajiva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa, Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marxist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පවසන්නේ පශ්චාත් ජනාධිපති ඡන්ද ආර්ථිකය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රතිවාදියා සමඟ එකඟ වූ බවයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂයේ නීති සම්පාදක සහ ආර්ථික විශේෂඥ හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා සඳුදා පැවසුවේ, නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහා බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දෙන හිටපු ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ කොටස තම පක්ෂය මීළඟ ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් අවම ආර්ථික වැඩපිළිවෙළකට එකඟ වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ද සිල්වාගේ පක්‍ෂයේ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරණ අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉවත් කර ගැනීමටත්, ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන්ම හිටපු පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් (SLPP) නැගී එන අලහප්පෙරුමගේ සන්ධානයට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරය සමඟ එකඟ වනු ඇති බවටත් අනුමාන කිරීම් මධ්‍යයේ මෙම හමුව සිදුවිය.",
        "\"මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුමගේ කණ්ඩායම චරිත හේරත් සහ නාලක ගොඩහේවා ඇතුළු තවත් පිරිසක් මීළඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් පොදු අවම ආර්ථික වැඩපිළිවෙල සමඟ සම්පුර්ණ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණීම ගැන සතුටුයි\" ද සිල්වා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "අපි මීළඟ #ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් පොදු අවම ආර්ථික වැඩපිළිවෙල සමඟ සම්පුර්ණ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණීමට w@charith9 @GodahewaNalaka සහ තවත් අය සමඟ මහාචාර්ය GLP විසින් නායකත්වය දෙන @DullasOfficial කණ්ඩායම සටහන් කිරීම සතුටක්. මෙය @samarajiva #NMSJ විසින් සම්පාදනය කරන ලද බහුපාර්ශ්වික යෝජනා මත පදනම් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර ජාත්‍යන්තර නීති සහ මූල්‍ය උපදේශකයින්ගේ සහාය ඇතිව ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ද ආරම්භ කර ඇති අවස්ථාවක මෙම පියවර ගෙන ඇත. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ගනුදෙනු සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්ති අනුකූලතාව ඉතා වැදගත් වන අතර එම අවශ්‍යතාව අනුව පොදු අවම වැඩපිළිවෙළ තීරණය කෙරෙනු ඇතැයි දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "වත්මන් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද භේදයකින් තොරව පරාජය කිරීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා 2019 ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයා සහ රටේ විපක්ෂ නායකයා ජූලි 20 වනදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වීමේ තීරණය ඉවත් කර ගැනීමට සලකා බලමින් සිටින බව ප්‍රේමදාසගේ පක්ෂ ආරංචි මාර්ග EconomyNext වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පසුගිය සතියේ ගුවන් හමුදා යානයකින් රටින් පලා ගොස් මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති විරෝධතාවලින් පසුව ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා බදාදා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුකූලව මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 කින් යුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයින් විසින් තීරණය කරනු ඇත. රට දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට ඇද දැමුවා.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගන්නා තෙක් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස, අලහප්පෙරුම සහ මාක්ස්වාදී ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ (ජවිපෙ) නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වීමට එකඟ වී ඇති අතර වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නම හිටපු පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් නම් කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස සහ අලහප්පෙරුම දෙදෙනාම තරග කළහොත් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට වැඩි අවස්ථාවක් තිබෙන බව දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "පසුගිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයෙන් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ පක්ෂය පරාජයට පත් වූ අතර ඔහුට මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට නොහැකි විය. කෙසේ වෙතත් ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේ පක්ෂය දිනාගත් ප්‍රසාද ආසනයක් භාවිතා කරමිනි. ඔහුට ජනාධිපති වීමට ජනවරමක් තිබේද යන්න මෙමගින් ප්‍රශ්න මතු වී තිබේ. නීති විශාරදයින් පවසන්නේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සරල බහුතරයෙන් තේරී පත් වුවහොත් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් ඔහුට බාධාවක් නොමැති බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි18/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.පී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@සමරජීව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස, අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාක්ස්වාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதிக்கு பிந்தைய வாக்கு பொருளாதாரத்தில் போட்டியாளருடன் உடன்பட்டதாக இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை ஆதரிக்கும் முன்னாள் ஆளும் கட்சியின் ஒரு பகுதி, தனது கட்சி அடுத்த அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்கும் பட்சத்தில் குறைந்தபட்ச பொருளாதார வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு இணங்கியுள்ளதாக இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமியற்றியவரும் பொருளாதார நிபுணருமான ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா திங்கட்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "டி சில்வாவின் கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதை வாபஸ் பெறுவார் என்றும், பிரதானமாக முன்னாள் ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் (SLPP) இருந்து பிரதம மந்திரி பதவியைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு அலஹப்பெருமவின் எழுச்சிமிக்க கூட்டணியுடன் உடன்படுவார் என்ற ஊகங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் இந்த சந்திப்பு இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "“அடுத்த இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை நாங்கள் அமைத்தால், பொதுவான குறைந்தபட்ச பொருளாதார வேலைத்திட்டத்துடன் பூரண உடன்பாட்டுக்கு பேராசிரியர் ஜி எல் பீரிஸ் மற்றும் சரித ஹேரத் மற்றும் நாலக கொடஹேவா மற்றும் பலர் இணைந்துள்ள டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் குழுவைக் குறிப்பிடுவதில் மகிழ்ச்சி” என டி சில்வா ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "அடுத்த # SriLanka அரசாங்கத்தை நாங்கள் அமைத்தால், பொதுவான குறைந்தபட்ச பொருளாதாரத் திட்டத்துடன் முழுமையான உடன்பாட்டிற்கு @charith9 @GodahewaNalaka மற்றும் பலர் இணைந்து பேராசிரியர் GLP தலைமையிலான @DullasOfficial குழுவைக் குறிப்பிடுவதில் மகிழ்ச்சி அடைகிறேன். இது @samarajiva #NMSJ ஆல் தொகுக்கப்பட்ட பலதரப்பு முன்மொழிவுகளை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) மற்றும் சர்வதேச சட்ட மற்றும் நிதி ஆலோசகர்களின் உதவியுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புடன் இலங்கை பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ள நிலையில் இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஒப்பந்தங்களுக்கு கொள்கை நிலைத்தன்மை மிகவும் முக்கியமானது மற்றும் பொதுவான குறைந்தபட்ச திட்டம் அந்த தேவைக்கு ஏற்ப தீர்மானிக்கப்படும் என்று அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளரும் நாட்டின் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவருமான தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்குப் பிளவின்றி தோற்கடிப்பதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி வாக்கெடுப்பில் போட்டியிடும் தனது முடிவை வாபஸ் பெறுவது குறித்து பிரேமதாசவின் கட்சி வட்டாரங்கள் எகனாமிநெக்ஸ்ட்க்கு தெரிவித்தன.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச கடந்த வாரம் விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பின்னர், பல மாத எதிர்ப்புகளைத் தொடர்ந்து அவர் ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அறிவித்ததையடுத்து, இலங்கையின் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் புதன்கிழமை அரசியலமைப்பின்படி முடிவு செய்வார்கள். நாட்டை அரசியல் நெருக்கடிக்குள் தள்ளியது.",
        "ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்ததையடுத்து, புதிய அதிபர் தேர்வு செய்யப்படும் வரை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே செயல் அதிபராக பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "பிரேமதாச, அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் மார்க்சிஸ்ட் ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுன (ஜேவிபி) தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட இணங்கியுள்ளனர், அதேவேளை விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பெயர் முன்னாள் ஆளும் SLPP உறுப்பினர்களால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "பிரேமதாச மற்றும் அழகப்பெரும இருவரும் போட்டியிட்டால், விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வெற்றி வாய்ப்பு அதிகம் என அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "கடந்த நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் விக்ரமசிங்கேவின் கட்சி தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்டதால், பொதுமக்களின் வாக்கு மூலம் அவரால் வெற்றிபெற முடியவில்லை. எவ்வாறாயினும், கட்சி பெற்ற போனஸ் ஆசனத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் நுழைந்தார். ஜனாதிபதியாக வருவதற்கு அவருக்கு மக்கள் ஆணை உள்ளதா என்ற கேள்வி எழுந்துள்ளது. விக்ரமசிங்கே நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் தனிப்பெரும்பான்மையால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டால், அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டம் அவரைத் தடுக்கவில்லை என்று சட்ட வல்லுநர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை18/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராசிரியர் ஜி எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@சமராஜீவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச, அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்சிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}