{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/48-navy-teams-remain-to-extend-relief-to-people-affected-by-weather/",
  "time_ut": 1659429300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "48 Navy teams remain to extend relief to people affected by weather",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "48 Navy teams remain to extend relief to people affected by weather",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy has kept 48 relief teams on standby as of the morning of 02nd August 2022, to provide relief to the people who would be vulnerable to flash floods, with the possible rise of the water levels of rivers, due to heavy downpour reported in several parts of the island.",
        "As per the directives of the Commander of the Navy, Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne, the Western, Southern, and Northwestern Naval Commands have kept ready 27, 08, and 13 relief teams respectively for flood relief duties.",
        "Meanwhile, the Navy deployed 02 flood relief teams in the New Town of Rathnapura and rushed another team to Muwagama in Rathnapura on the evening of 01st August 2022.",
        "In addition, navy flood relief teams have been kept on standby for prompt deployment, in close coordination with the Disaster Management Centre."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "48",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the morning of 02nd",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northwestern Naval Commands",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muwagama",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Disaster Management Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාලගුණයෙන් විපතට පත් ජනතාවට සහන සැලසීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදා කණ්ඩායම් 48ක් රැඳී සිටියි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 අගෝස්තු මස 02 වන දින උදෑසන වන විට ගංඟාවල ජල මට්ටම් ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ හදිසි ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයන්ට ගොදුරු විය හැකි ජනතාවට සහන සැලසීම සඳහා සහන කණ්ඩායම් 48ක් සීරුවෙන් තබා ඇත. දිවයිනේ කොටස් කිහිපයක්.",
        "නාවික හමුදාධිපති, වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි බස්නාහිර, දකුණ සහ වයඹ නාවික විධානයන් විසින් ගංවතුර සහන සේවා කටයුතු සඳහා සහන කණ්ඩායම් 27, 08 සහ 13ක් සූදානම් කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, නාවික හමුදාව විසින් රත්නපුර නව නගරයේ ගංවතුර සහන කණ්ඩායම් 02 ක් යොදවා ඇති අතර තවත් කණ්ඩායමක් 2022 අගෝස්තු 01 වන දින සවස රත්නපුර මුවගම වෙත කඩිනම් කරන ලදී.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය සමඟ සමීප සම්බන්ධීකරණයෙන් නාවික හමුදාවේ ගංවතුර සහන කණ්ඩායම් කඩිනමින් යෙදවීම සඳහා සූදානම්ව තබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "48",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02 වැනිදා උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ නාවික විධාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muwagama",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காலநிலையால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மக்களுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்க 48 கடற்படை குழுக்கள் உள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் 48 நிவாரண குழுக்களை 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 02 ஆம் தேதி காலை வரை தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளனர், வெள்ளத்தால் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மக்களுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்காக, ஆறுகளின் நீர்மட்டங்கள் அதிகரிக்கக்கூடும். தீவின் பல பகுதிகள்.",
        "கடற்படைத் தளபதி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகேதென்ன அவர்களின் பணிப்புரைக்கு அமைவாக மேற்கு, தெற்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கு கடற்படைக் கட்டளைகள் முறையே 27, 08 மற்றும் 13 நிவாரணக் குழுக்களை வெள்ள நிவாரணப் பணிகளுக்காக தயார் நிலையில் வைத்துள்ளன.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், கடற்படையினர் 02 வெள்ள நிவாரண குழுக்களை இரத்தினபுரி புதிய நகரத்தில் நிலைநிறுத்தியதோடு, மற்றொரு குழுவை 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 01 மாலை இரத்தினபுரியில் உள்ள முவாகமவுக்கு விரைந்தனர்.",
        "மேலும், பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையத்துடன் நெருக்கமான ஒருங்கிணைப்புடன், கடற்படை வெள்ள நிவாரணக் குழுக்கள் உடனடி நடவடிக்கைக்காக தயார் நிலையில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "48",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02 ஆம் தேதி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muwagama",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}