{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-lifts-import-ban-on-glyphosate-98338/",
  "time_ut": 1659934560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President lifts import ban on glyphosate",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President lifts import ban on glyphosate",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Ranil Wickremesinghe has lifted a ban on glyphosate, a weed killer giving into a long standing request of the island’s tea industry.",
        "In a gazette notice issued under the hand of President Wickremesinghe as Minister of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policies, the import ban on glyphosate has been lifted with effect from August 05.",
        "Glyphosate has been shifted to a list of goods requiring permits.",
        "Sri Lanka’s President Maithripala Sirisena originally banned glyphosate under the 2015-2015 administration where Wickremesinghe was Prime Minister.",
        "Sri Lanka’s tea industry in particular as been lobbying to allow glyphosate use as it is one of the internationally accepted weed killers and alternatives are not permitted under food regulation in some of the export destinations.",
        "Sri Lanka lifted the ban in November 2021 and it was re-imposed and then agriculture Minister Mahindanda Aluthgamage said he ordered the official responsible for the liberalization to be removed from the post. (Colombo/Aug09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Policies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahindanda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති ග්ලයිෆොසේට් ආනයන තහනම ඉවත් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවයිනේ තේ කර්මාන්තයේ දිගුකාලීන ඉල්ලීමක් කරමින් වල්නාශකයක් වන ග්ලයිෆොසේට් තහනම ඉවත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද ගැසට් නිවේදනයක අගෝස්තු 05 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි ග්ලයිෆොසේට් ආනයන තහනම ඉවත් කර ඇත.",
        "ග්ලයිෆොසේට් බලපත්‍ර අවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ ලැයිස්තුවකට මාරු කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා මුලින් ග්ලයිෆොසේට් තහනම් කළේ වික්‍රමසිංහ අගමැතිව සිටි 2015-2015 පරිපාලනය යටතේය.",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තේ කර්මාන්තය ග්ලයිෆොසේට් භාවිතයට අවසර දෙන ලෙස බලපෑම් කරමින් සිටින්නේ එය ජාත්‍යන්තරව පිළිගත් වල් නාශකයක් වන අතර සමහර අපනයන ගමනාන්තවල ආහාර නියාමනය යටතේ විකල්ප සඳහා අවසර දී නොමැති බැවිනි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2021 නොවැම්බරයේදී තහනම ඉවත් කළ අතර එය නැවත පනවන ලද අතර එවකට කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්දාන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ පැවසුවේ ලිබරල්කරණයට වගකිව යුතු නිලධාරියා එම තනතුරෙන් ඉවත් කරන ලෙස තමා නියෝග කළ බවයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්දාන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கிளைபோசேட் மீதான இறக்குமதி தடையை இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி நீக்கியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் தேயிலை தொழில்துறையின் நீண்டகால கோரிக்கையான களைக்கொல்லியான கிளைபோசேட் மீதான தடையை இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நீக்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சராக ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவின் கைவரிசையில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலில், ஆகஸ்ட் 05 ஆம் திகதி முதல் கிளைபோசேட் மீதான இறக்குமதித் தடை நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அனுமதி தேவைப்படும் பொருட்களின் பட்டியலுக்கு கிளைபோசேட் மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "விக்ரமசிங்கே பிரதமராக இருந்த 2015-2015 நிர்வாகத்தின் கீழ் இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன முதலில் கிளைபோசேட்டை தடை செய்தார்.",
        "குறிப்பாக இலங்கையின் தேயிலை கைத்தொழில் சர்வதேச ரீதியில் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட களைக்கொல்லிகளில் ஒன்றாக இருப்பதால் கிளைபோசேட் பாவனையை அனுமதிப்பதற்காக வற்புறுத்துகிறது.",
        "நவம்பர் 2021 இல் இலங்கை தடையை நீக்கியது, அது மீண்டும் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டது, பின்னர் விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்தந்த அலுத்கமகே தாராளமயமாக்கலுக்கு காரணமான அதிகாரியை பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்க உத்தரவிட்டார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கொள்கைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}