{
  "newspaper_id": "colombo-telegraph-com",
  "url": "https://www.colombotelegraph.com/index.php/22a-ensures-government-domination-in-constitutional-council/",
  "time_ut": 1660270295,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "22A Ensures Government Domination In Constitutional Council",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "22A Ensures Government Domination In Constitutional Council",
      "author": "Jayampathy Wickramaratne",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Wickremesinghe-Rajapaksa Government’s new Twenty-Second Amendment to the Constitution Bill was presented to Parliament on 10 August 2022. The earlier Bill, which was published in the Gazette in June 2022, lapsed as it was not presented before the recent prorogation of Parliament.",
        "The August Bill is an improvement on the June Bill from a Nineteenth Amendment perspective. Under 19A, Ministers and Deputy Ministers were appointed by the President on the advice of the Prime Minister. This was done away with by the Twentieth Amendment. The June Bill sought to bring back the requirement of the Prime Minister’s advice, but that provision would not apply during the present Parliament. The August Bill does not have such an exception.",
        "According to the June Bill, where the President is of the opinion that the Prime Minister has lost the confidence of the present Parliament, the Prime Minister can be removed. Such a provision is not found in the August Bill.",
        "Under 19A, the Speaker, Prime Minister and Leader of the Opposition were ex officio members of the Constitutional Council (CC), while the President would nominate one MP. Five persons were nominated jointly by the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition, two of them being MPs. In making such nominations, they were required to consult the leaders of political parties and independent groups represented in Parliament to ensure that the CC reflects the pluralistic character of Sri Lankan society, including professional and social diversity. One MP was nominated by the MPs belonging to parties other than those to which the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition belonged. The three persons from outside Parliament shall be persons of eminence and integrity who have distinguished themselves in public or professional life and who are not members of any political party. Parliament shall approve their nomination. In practice, such approval was a mere formality as they were nominated jointly and after a consultative process.",
        "The August Bill, like the June Bill, proposes the re-establishment of the CC but makes a crucial change. The five persons referred to are not appointed pursuant to the joint nomination of the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition. One MP is nominated by the Government Parliamentary Group, and the other MP is nominated by the party to which the Leader of the Opposition belongs. The three persons from outside are nominated not jointly by the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition but by the Speaker in consultation with them. The smaller parties are not consulted.",
        "This deviation from 19A gives rise to several issues. If the Speaker is partisan (and there have been several such Speakers), the Government could ensure that all three CC members from outside are their own nominees. The Government, by virtue of its majority, would have no difficulty getting Parliamentary approval. The smaller parties would have no say in the nomination of these three persons. Thus, in the current Parliament, parties such as the TNA, NPP, EPDP, TNPF etc., who together account for twenty-five MPs, would not be consulted.",
        "The 22A Bill says that in nominating the two MPs and the three persons from outside Parliament, Members of Parliament shall ensure that the CC reflects the pluralist character of Sri Lankan society. This would be most difficult as they would be nominated by separate processes. Under 19A, on the other hand, that was ensured as the nomination was jointly by the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition after consulting the leaders of all parties in Parliament.",
        "The composition of the CC is of crucial importance for the achievement of a national consensus on high-level appointments. The approval of the CC is a pre-requisite for the appointment of judges of the Supreme Court and Court of Appeal and appointments to high positions such as the Attorney-General and the Inspector-General of Police. Appointments to independent Commissions are made on the recommendation of the CC. As the other seven members of the CC are all Members of Parliament and may be swayed by political considerations, the three members who are appointed from outside have a vital role to play. They should be persons acceptable to all and who can have a moderating influence on the politicians.",
        "An argument that has been adduced by the Government is that the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition may not agree on the to be nominated jointly. No such issue arose both under the Seventeenth and Nineteenth Amendments. Members of Parliament nominated jointly acted with responsibility. Distinguished personalities appointed by joint nomination included Justice Dr A.R.B. Amarasinghe, Professor Colvin Gunaratne, Dr Jayantha Dhanapala, A.T. Ariyaratne, Shibley Aziz, and Dr Radhika Coomaraswamy, Javid Yusuf and Professor N. Selvakkumaran.",
        "That the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition may not agree is no reason to give the power of appointment to the Speaker. The writer proposes that the 19A provisions be re-enacted with the addition that if the Prime Minister and the Leader of the Opposition do not agree on the nominees within a stipulated period, the Speaker will make the nominations in consultation with the Prime Minister, the Leader of the Opposition and the leaders of the smaller parties."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Wickremesinghe-Rajapaksa Government’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twenty-Second Amendment",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitution Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nineteenth Amendment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Twentieth Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council (CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Parliamentary Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Speakers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EPDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "twenty-five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector-General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commissions",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seventeenth",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nineteenth Amendments",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.R.B. Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colvin Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Dhanapala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.T. Ariyaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shibley Aziz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Radhika Coomaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Javid Yusuf",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "N. Selvakkumaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22A ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව තුළ රජයේ ආධිපත්‍යය සහතික කරයි",
      "author": "ජයම්පති වික්‍රමරත්න",
      "body_lines": [
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ-රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ නව විසිදෙවැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත 2022 අගෝස්තු 10 වැනි දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී. 2022 ජූනි මාසයේ ගැසට් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද මීට පෙර පනත් කෙටුම්පත මෑතදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තැබීමට පෙර ඉදිරිපත් නොකළ බැවින් එය අවලංගු විය.",
        "අගෝස්තු පනත දහනව වන සංශෝධන ඉදිරිදර්ශනයකින් ජුනි පනතේ වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමකි. 19A යටතේ අමාත්‍යවරුන් සහ නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් පත් කළේ අගමැතිවරයාගේ උපදෙස් මත ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසිනි. විසිවැනි සංශෝධනයෙන් මේක නැති කළා. ජූනි පනත් කෙටුම්පත අගමැතිගේ උපදෙස් අවශ්‍යතාවය නැවත ගෙන ඒමට උත්සාහ කළ නමුත් වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ එම විධිවිධාන අදාළ නොවේ. අගෝස්තු පනතේ එවැනි ව්යතිරේකයක් නොමැත.",
        "වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විශ්වාසය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට අහිමි වී ඇතැයි ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ අදහස වන ජුනි පනත් කෙටුම්පතට අනුව අගමැතිවරයා ඉවත් කළ හැකිය. එවැනි විධිවිධානයක් අගෝස්තු පනතේ දක්නට නැත.",
        "19A යටතේ, කථානායක, අගමැති සහ විපක්ෂ නායක ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවේ (CC) නිල බලයෙන් සාමාජිකයින් වූ අතර, ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු නම් කරනු ලැබේ. අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එක්ව පස් දෙනෙකු නම් කළ අතර ඉන් දෙදෙනෙකු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්. එවැනි නාමයෝජනා ලබා දීමේදී, වෘත්තීය සහ සමාජ විවිධත්වය ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය සමාජයේ බහුත්ව ස්වභාවය CC මගින් පිළිබිඹු වන බව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම්වල නායකයින්ගෙන් උපදෙස් ලබා ගැනීමට ඔවුන්ට අවශ්‍ය විය. එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු නම් කළේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා අයත් පක්ෂ හැර වෙනත් පක්ෂවල මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසිනි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටත සිටින පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනා පොදු හෝ වෘත්තීය ජීවිතය තුළ කැපී පෙනෙන හා කිසිදු දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක සාමාජිකයන් නොවන කීර්තිමත් සහ අවංකභාවයෙන් යුත් පුද්ගලයන් විය යුතුය. ඔවුන්ගේ නාමයෝජනා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අනුමත කළ යුතුය. ප්‍රායෝගිකව, ඔවුන් ඒකාබද්ධව සහ උපදේශන ක්‍රියාවලියකින් පසුව නම් කරන ලද බැවින් එවැනි අනුමැතිය හුදු විධිමත් භාවයක් විය.",
        "ජූනි පනත් කෙටුම්පත මෙන් අගෝස්තු පනත ද CC යලි පිහිටුවීම යෝජනා කරන නමුත් තීරණාත්මක වෙනසක් සිදු කරයි. අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගේ ඒකාබද්ධ නාමයෝජනා අනුව අදාළ පුද්ගලයන් පස්දෙනා පත් කරන්නේ නැහැ. එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම විසින් නම් කරනු ලබන අතර අනෙක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා අයත් පක්ෂය විසින් නම් කරනු ලැබේ. පිටතින් එන පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනා නම් කරන්නේ අගමැති සහ විපක්ෂ නායක එක්ව නොව කථානායකවරයා ඔවුන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඉදිරිපත් කරමිනි. කුඩා පක්ෂවල අදහස් විමසන්නේ නැහැ.",
        "19A වෙතින් මෙම අපගමනය ගැටළු කිහිපයක් මතු කරයි. කථානායකවරයා පක්ෂග්‍රාහී නම් (සහ එවැනි කථානායකවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සිට ඇත), පිටතින් සිටින CC සාමාජිකයින් තිදෙනාම ඔවුන්ගේම නම් කළ අය බව රජයට සහතික කළ හැකිය. ආණ්ඩුවට බහුතර බලය අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු අනුමැතිය ලබාගැනීමට අපහසු නොවනු ඇත. මෙම පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනා නම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කුඩා පක්ෂවලට කිසිදු අදහසක් නැත. මේ අනුව, වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසිපහක් සිටින ටීඑන්ඒ, එන්පීපී, ඊපීඩීපී, ටීඑන්පීඑෆ් වැනි පක්ෂවල අදහස් විමසීමක් සිදු නොවනු ඇත.",
        "22A පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ දැක්වෙන්නේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනා සහ පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටත නම් කිරීමේදී, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය සමාජයේ බහුත්වවාදී ස්වභාවය පිළිබිඹු කරන බවට සහතික විය යුතු බවයි. ඔවුන් වෙනම ක්‍රියාවලීන් මගින් නම් කරනු ලබන බැවින් මෙය වඩාත් අපහසු වනු ඇත. අනෙක් අතට, 19A යටතේ, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ අදහස් විමසීමෙන් පසුව අගමැති සහ විපක්ෂ නායක ඒකාබද්ධව නාමයෝජනා ලබා දුන් බව සහතික විය.",
        "ඉහළ මට්ටමේ පත්වීම් පිළිබඳ ජාතික සම්මුතියක් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා CC හි සංයුතිය ඉතා වැදගත් වේ. ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ සහ අභියාචනාධිකරණයේ විනිසුරුවරුන් පත් කිරීම සහ නීතිපති සහ පොලිස්පති වැනි ඉහළ තනතුරු සඳහා පත්කිරීම් සඳහා CC හි අනුමැතිය පූර්ව අවශ්‍යතාවයකි. ස්වාධීන කොමිෂන් සභා සඳහා පත් කිරීම් CC හි නිර්දේශය මත සිදු කෙරේ. CC හි අනෙකුත් සාමාජිකයින් හත් දෙනාම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන අතර දේශපාලනික සලකා බැලීම්වලට හසු විය හැකි බැවින්, පිටතින් පත් කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනාට ඉටු කිරීමට වැදගත් කාර්යභාරයක් ඇත. ඔවුන් සියල්ලන්ටම පිළිගත හැකි සහ දේශපාලකයන්ට මධ්‍යස්ථ බලපෑමක් ඇති කළ හැකි පුද්ගලයන් විය යුතුය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුව විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති තර්කයක් වන්නේ අගමැති සහ විපක්ෂ නායක එක්ව නම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකඟ නොවිය හැකි බවයි. දහහත්වැනි සහ දහනවවැනි සංශෝධන යටතේ එවැනි ප්‍රශ්නයක් මතු වුණේ නැහැ. නම් කරන ලද මන්ත්‍රීවරු ඒකාබද්ධව වගකීමෙන් ක්‍රියා කළහ. ඒකාබද්ධ නාමයෝජනා මගින් පත් කරන ලද සම්භාවනීය පුද්ගලයන් අතර විනිසුරු ආචාර්ය ඒ.ආර්.බී. අමරසිංහ, මහාචාර්ය කොල්වින් ගුණරත්න, ආචාර්ය ජයන්ත ධනපාල, ඒ.ටී. ආරියරත්න, ෂිබ්ලි අසීස්, සහ ආචාර්ය රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි, ජාවිඩ් යූසුෆ් සහ මහාචාර්ය එන්. සෙල්වක්කුමාරන්.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එකඟ නොවීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව කථානායකවරයාට පත්වීමේ බලය ලබාදීමට හේතුවක් නොවේ. නියමිත කාලසීමාවක් තුළ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා විසින් නාමයෝජනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකඟ නොවන්නේ නම් කථානායකවරයා විසින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර නාමයෝජනා ලබා දෙනු ඇති බවට 19A ප්‍රතිපාදන නැවත බලාත්මක කළ යුතු බව ලේඛකයා යෝජනා කරයි. විපක්ෂ නායක හා කුඩා පක්ෂ නායකයන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ-රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසි දෙවන සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 අගෝස්තු 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහනව වන සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසිවන සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව (CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කථිකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊ.පී.ඩී.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසි පහයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පතිවරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිෂන් සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහහත්වැනි",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහනව වන සංශෝධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ආර්.බී. අමරසිංහ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්වින් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ධනපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිදී. ආරියරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂිබ්ලි අසීස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාවිඩ් යූසුෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.සෙල්වක්කුමාරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22A அரசியலமைப்பு சபையில் அரசாங்க ஆதிக்கத்தை உறுதி செய்கிறது",
      "author": "ஜயம்பதி விக்கிரமரத்ன",
      "body_lines": [
        "விக்ரமசிங்க-ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தின் அரசியலமைப்புக்கான புதிய இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் 10 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது. 2022 ஜூன் மாதம் வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட முந்தைய சட்டமூலம், அண்மையில் பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படாததால் காலாவதியானது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மசோதா, பத்தொன்பதாம் திருத்தக் கண்ணோட்டத்தில் ஜூன் மசோதாவின் முன்னேற்றமாகும். 19A இன் கீழ் அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் பிரதி அமைச்சர்கள் பிரதமரின் ஆலோசனையின் பேரில் ஜனாதிபதியால் நியமிக்கப்பட்டனர். இது இருபதாவது திருத்தத்தின் மூலம் நீக்கப்பட்டது. ஜூன் மசோதா, பிரதமரின் ஆலோசனையின் தேவையை மீண்டும் கொண்டுவர முயன்றது, ஆனால் தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றத்தின் போது அந்த விதி பொருந்தாது. ஆகஸ்ட் மசோதாவுக்கு அத்தகைய விதிவிலக்கு இல்லை.",
        "தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் நம்பிக்கையை பிரதமர் இழந்துவிட்டார் என்று ஜனாதிபதி கருதும் ஜூன் சட்டமூலத்தின்படி பிரதமரை நீக்க முடியும். ஆகஸ்ட் மசோதாவில் அத்தகைய ஏற்பாடு இல்லை.",
        "19A இன் கீழ், சபாநாயகர், பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஆகியோர் அரசியலமைப்பு சபையின் (CC) அதிகாரபூர்வ உறுப்பினர்களாக இருந்தனர், அதே நேரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ஒரு எம்.பி.யை நியமிப்பார். பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரால் கூட்டாக ஐந்து பேர் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டனர், அவர்களில் இருவர் எம்.பி. அத்தகைய நியமனங்களைச் செய்யும் போது, ​​அவர்கள் அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் சுயேச்சைக் குழுக்களின் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்தாலோசிக்க வேண்டியிருந்தது, CC இலங்கை சமூகத்தின் தொழில்முறை மற்றும் சமூக பன்முகத்தன்மை உட்பட பன்முகத்தன்மையை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது. பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் உள்ளிட்ட கட்சிகளைத் தவிர மற்ற கட்சிகளைச் சேர்ந்த எம்.பி.க்களால் ஒரு எம்.பி. பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வெளியில் இருந்து வரும் மூன்று நபர்களும், பொது அல்லது தொழில் வாழ்க்கையில் தங்களை தனித்துவம் மிக்கவர்களாகவும், எந்த அரசியல் கட்சியிலும் அங்கம் வகிக்காதவர்களாகவும், மேன்மையும் நேர்மையும் கொண்டவர்களாக இருக்க வேண்டும். அவர்களின் நியமனத்தை பாராளுமன்றம் அங்கீகரிக்கும். நடைமுறையில், அத்தகைய ஒப்புதல் வெறும் சம்பிரதாயமாக இருந்தது, ஏனெனில் அவர்கள் கூட்டாகவும் ஆலோசனை செயல்முறைக்குப் பிறகும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மசோதா, ஜூன் மசோதாவைப் போலவே, CC ஐ மீண்டும் நிறுவுவதை முன்மொழிகிறது, ஆனால் ஒரு முக்கியமான மாற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது. குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட ஐந்து பேரும் பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் கூட்டு நியமனத்தின் அடிப்படையில் நியமிக்கப்படவில்லை. ஒரு எம்.பி அரசாங்க நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுவால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறார், மற்றைய எம்.பி எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சார்ந்த கட்சியால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறார். வெளியில் இருந்து வரும் மூவரையும் பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டாக பரிந்துரைக்காமல், சபாநாயகர் அவர்களுடன் கலந்தாலோசித்து பரிந்துரை செய்கிறார். சிறிய கட்சிகளிடம் கருத்து கேட்கவில்லை.",
        "19A இலிருந்து இந்த விலகல் பல சிக்கல்களை உருவாக்குகிறது. சபாநாயகர் பக்கச்சார்புடையவராக இருந்தால் (அப்படிப் பல சபாநாயகர்கள் இருந்திருக்கிறார்கள்), வெளியில் இருந்து வரும் மூன்று சிசி உறுப்பினர்களும் தங்களின் சொந்த வேட்பாளர்கள் என்பதை அரசாங்கம் உறுதி செய்ய முடியும். பெரும்பான்மையின் அடிப்படையில், அரசாங்கம் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் ஒப்புதலைப் பெறுவதில் சிரமம் இருக்காது. இந்த மூன்று நபர்களின் வேட்புமனுவில் சிறிய கட்சிகளுக்கு எந்த கருத்தும் இருக்காது. எனவே, தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றத்தில், இருபத்தைந்து எம்.பி.க்களைக் கொண்ட TNA, NPP, EPDP, TNPF போன்ற கட்சிகள் கலந்தாலோசிக்கப்படாது.",
        "22A சட்டமூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வெளியில் இருந்து இரண்டு எம்.பி.க்கள் மற்றும் மூன்று நபர்களை நியமனம் செய்வதில், இலங்கை சமூகத்தின் பன்மைத்துவ குணாதிசயத்தை சிசி பிரதிபலிக்கிறது என்பதை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் உறுதி செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று கூறுகிறது. தனித்தனி செயல்முறைகள் மூலம் அவர்கள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுவதால் இது மிகவும் கடினமாக இருக்கும். மறுபுறம், 19A இன் கீழ், நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்தாலோசித்த பிறகு பிரதமரும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் கூட்டாக வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டதால் அது உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "உயர்மட்ட நியமனங்களில் தேசிய ஒருமித்த கருத்தை அடைவதற்கு CC இன் அமைப்பு மிகவும் முக்கியமானது. உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் மற்றும் மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தின் நீதிபதிகள் நியமனம் மற்றும் அட்டர்னி-ஜெனரல் மற்றும் இன்ஸ்பெக்டர்-ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ் போன்ற உயர் பதவிகளுக்கு நியமனம் செய்வதற்கு CC இன் ஒப்புதல் ஒரு முன்நிபந்தனையாகும். CC இன் பரிந்துரையின் பேரில் சுயாதீன ஆணையங்களுக்கான நியமனங்கள் செய்யப்படுகின்றன. CC இன் மற்ற ஏழு உறுப்பினர்களும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல் கருத்தினால் திசைதிருப்பப்படலாம், வெளியில் இருந்து நியமிக்கப்படும் மூன்று உறுப்பினர்களும் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கின்றனர். அவர்கள் அனைவரும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய மற்றும் அரசியல்வாதிகள் மீது மிதமான செல்வாக்கு செலுத்தக்கூடிய நபர்களாக இருக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு வாதம் என்னவென்றால், பிரதமரும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் கூட்டாக நியமனம் செய்யப்படுவதில் உடன்பட மாட்டார்கள். பதினேழாவது மற்றும் பத்தொன்பதாம் திருத்தங்களின் கீழ் அத்தகைய பிரச்சினை எதுவும் எழவில்லை. பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் கூட்டாக பொறுப்புடன் செயல்பட்டனர். கூட்டு நியமனம் மூலம் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட புகழ்பெற்ற நபர்களில் நீதிபதி டாக்டர் ஏ.ஆர்.பி. அமரசிங்க, பேராசிரியர் கொல்வின் குணரத்ன, கலாநிதி ஜயந்த தனபால, ஏ.டி. ஆரியரத்ன, ஷிப்லி அஸீஸ், மற்றும் டாக்டர் ராதிகா குமாரசுவாமி, ஜாவித் யூசுப் மற்றும் பேராசிரியர் என். செல்வக்குமரன்.",
        "பிரதமரும், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் ஒப்புக் கொள்ளாதது, சபாநாயகருக்கு நியமன அதிகாரத்தை வழங்குவதற்கான காரணமல்ல. குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்குள் பிரதமர் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஆகியோர் நியமனம் செய்யப்படாவிட்டால், சபாநாயகர் பிரதமருடன் கலந்தாலோசித்து வேட்புமனுக்களை வழங்குவார் என்ற 19A விதிகள் மீண்டும் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என்று எழுத்தாளர் முன்மொழிகிறார். எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் மற்றும் சிறிய கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க-ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தொன்பதாம் திருத்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபதாம் திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு கவுன்சில் (சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க பாராளுமன்ற குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேச்சாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈ.பி.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபத்து ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர்-ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமிஷன்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதினேழாவது",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தொன்பதாம் திருத்தங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.ஆர்.பி. அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொல்வின் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த தனபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.டி. ஆரியரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிப்லி அஜீஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராதிகா குமாரசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாவித் யூசுப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.செல்வக்குமரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19A",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}