{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130620",
  "time_ut": 1656748069,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கைக்கு உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என்றே ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் கூறினார் : விடயத்தை விளக்குகிறார் சுமந்திரன்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan's ambassador said he would provide aid to Sri Lanka: Sumandran explains",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The spokesperson of the Tamil Tessia Federation and Member of Parliament for Yallam District, President's Attorney MA Sumanthran has explained that the Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka who held a meeting with the representatives of the Tamil Tessia Association, did not say that Japan will not provide aid to Sri Lanka in the near future, but rather said that Japan will provide aid after the implementation of the International Monetary Fund's action plan.",
        "After the news published in some Tamil and English newspapers, the news was widely shared on social media that the Japanese ambassador had assured them that the Japanese government would not provide any assistance to Sri Lanka in the near future.",
        "After that, the Japanese Embassy, ​​which issued a statement explaining the matter, stated that the reports in the media that the Japanese ambassador had said that they would not provide any assistance to Sri Lanka were untrue.",
        "Apart from that, during the meeting held between the President and the Ambassador of Japan to Sri Lanka on Friday (01), he assured the President that he would continue to provide cooperation to Sri Lanka.",
        "In such a background, the spokesperson of the Federation of Tamil Tessia MA Sumanthran has said the above in his official Twitter account. He further stated in the report that:",
        "The leaders of the 3 partner parties of the Federation of Tamil Nadu participated in the meeting held in Jaffna with the Ambassador of Japan to Sri Lanka.",
        "Accordingly, Tamil Rashad Party President Mavai Senathiraja, Blot President Dharmalingam Siddharthan and RELO President Selvam Adhikalanathan participated, but I did not participate in the meeting. However I discussed with all three of them.",
        "Accordingly, I am giving this explanation as the media spokesperson of Tamil Thesia Federation after talking to the people who participated in the said meeting and clarifying the matter.",
        "The Japanese ambassador did not say that Japan would not provide aid to Sri Lanka. On the contrary, he said that Japan will provide assistance after the implementation of the International Monetary Fund's action plan.",
        "Accordingly, after the meeting with the Ambassador of Japan, the leaders of the Tamil Thesia Confederation, who spoke in a media conference, said the same thing as the Ambassador.",
        "Also, the representatives of Tamil Thesia Federation expressed their gratitude for the long-standing historical relations between Japan and Sri Lanka and requested the Ambassador of Japan to provide continuous assistance in the current crisis situation.",
        "We acknowledge Japan's contribution to Sri Lanka's economy through financial assistance and other forms of cooperation.",
        "In such a background, we are worried about the wrong news published in the media regarding this matter."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sumandran",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Tessia Federation",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MA Sumanthran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Tessia Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Federation of Tamil Tessia MA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumanthran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Federation of Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Rashad Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mavai Senathiraja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharmalingam Siddharthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RELO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvam Adhikalanathan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Thesia Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Thesia Confederation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Thesia Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර දෙන බව ජපාන තානාපති කියයි: සුමන්ද්‍රන් පැහැදිලි කරයි",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ද්‍රවිඩ ටෙසියා සංගමයේ නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා ජපානය ආධාර ලබා නොදෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ නොකළ බව ටැමිල් ටෙසියා සම්මේලනයේ ප්‍රකාශක සහ යල්ලම් දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ එම්.ඒ.සුමන්ත්‍රන් පැහැදිලි කර තිබේ. නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට, නමුත් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ක්‍රියාකාරී සැලැස්ම ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් පසු ජපානය ආධාර ලබා දෙන බව පැවසීය.",
        "ඇතැම් දෙමළ සහ ඉංග්‍රීසි පුවත්පත්වල පළවූ පුවතෙන් පසු ජපන් තානාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී කිසිදු සහයක් ලබා නොදෙන බවට ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා සහතික වූ බවට පුවත සමාජ මාධ්‍ය තුළ විශාල වශයෙන් හුවමාරු විය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කරුණු පැහැදිලි කරමින් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කළ ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කිසිදු සහයක් ලබා නොදෙන බවට ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවට මාධ්‍යවල පළ වූ වාර්තා අසත්‍ය බවයි.",
        "ඊට අමතරව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා අතර සිකුරාදා (01) පැවති හමුවේදී ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගීතාව ලබා දෙන බවට ඔහු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහතික විය.",
        "එවැනි පසුබිමක දෙමළ ටෙසියා සම්මේලනයේ ප්‍රකාශක එම් ඒ සුමන්ත්‍රන් සිය නිල ට්විටර් ගිණුමේ ඉහත අදහස් දක්වා ඇත. ඔහු එම වාර්තාවේ වැඩිදුරටත් මෙසේද සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා සමඟ යාපනයේ පැවති හමුවට තමිල්නාඩු සම්මේලනයේ හවුල්කාර පක්ෂ තුනේ නායකයින් සහභාගී විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව තමිල් රෂාද් පක්‍ෂයේ සභාපති මාවයි සේනාධිරාජා, බ්ලොට් සභාපති ධර්මලිංගම් සිද්ධාර්ථන් සහ රෙලෝ සභාපති සෙල්වම් අධිකලනාදන් සහභාගි වූ නමුත් මම එම රැස්වීමට සහභාගි වූයේ නැත. කෙසේ වෙතත් මම ඔවුන් තිදෙනා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළෙමි.",
        "ඒ අනුව දෙමළ තේසියා සම්මේලනයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා ලෙස මා මෙම පැහැදිලි කිරීම සිදු කරන්නේ එම රැස්වීමට සහභාගි වූ ජනතාව සමඟ කතා කර කරුණු පැහැදිලි කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි.",
        "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර ලබා නොදෙන බව ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා කීවේ නැත. ඊට පටහැනිව, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ක්‍රියාකාරී සැලැස්ම ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් පසු ජපානය සහාය ලබා දෙන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා හමුවීමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් අදහස් දැක්වූ දෙමළ තේසියා සම්මේලනයේ නායකයින් ද තානාපතිවරයා පැවසූ දෙයම කියා සිටියා.",
        "එමෙන්ම ජපානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර දීර්ඝ කාලීන ඓතිහාසික සබඳතාවයට කෘතඥතාව පළ කළ දෙමළ තීසියා සම්මේලනයේ නියෝජිතයින් වත්මන් අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය තුළ අඛණ්ඩව සහය ලබාදෙන ලෙස ජපාන තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා.",
        "මූල්‍ය ආධාර සහ අනෙකුත් සහයෝගිතා තුළින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකයට ජපානයේ දායකත්වය අපි පිළිගනිමු.",
        "එවැනි පසුබිමක මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍යවල පළ වූ වැරදි ප්‍රවෘත්ති පිළිබඳව අපි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිමු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සුමන්ද්‍රන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ටෙසියා සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ටෙසියා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ටෙසියා සම්මේලනය එම්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල් රෂාද් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාවෙයි සේනාධිරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්ලොට් කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධර්මලිංගම් සිද්ධාර්ථන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙලෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වම් අධිකලනාදන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ තීසියා සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ තීසියා සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ තීසියා සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என்றே ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் கூறினார் : விடயத்தை விளக்குகிறார் சுமந்திரன்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் சந்திப்பை நிகழ்த்திய இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவர், இனிவருங்காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு ஜப்பான் உதவிகளை வழங்காது என்று கூறவில்லை எனவும், மாறாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் செயற்திட்டம் நடைமுறைக்கு வந்ததன் பின்னர் ஜப்பான் உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என்றே கூறினார் எனவும் தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடாகப்பேச்சாளரும் யாழ்மாவட்டப் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் விளக்கமளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இனிவருங்காலங்களில் ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு எவ்வித உதவிகளையும் வழங்கப்போவதில்லை என்றும் அவர்களிடம் ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் உறுதியாகத் தெரிவித்ததாக தமிழ் மற்றும் ஆங்கிலப்பத்திரிகைகள் சிலவற்றில் வெளியான செய்தியையடுத்து, சமூகவலைத்தளங்களிலும் அச்செய்தி பரவலாகப் பகிரப்பட்டது.",
        "அதனையடுத்து இவ்விடயம் தொடர்பில் விளக்கமளித்து அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்ட ஜப்பான் தூதரகம், இலங்கைக்கு எவ்வித உதவிகளையும் வழங்கப்போவதில்லை என்று ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் கூறியதாக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான செய்திகள் உண்மைக்குப் புறம்பானவை என்று தெரிவித்திருந்தது.",
        "அதுமாத்திரமன்றி (01) வெள்ளிக்கிழமை  ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவருக்கும் இடையில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின்போது இலங்கைக்குத் தொடர்ச்சியான ஒத்துழைப்பை வழங்கத்தயாராக இருப்பதாக அவர் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியில் இதுகுறித்து தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடாகப்பேச்சாளர் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ டுவிட்டர் பக்கத்தில் செய்திருக்கும் விளக்கப்பதிவிலேயே மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அப்பதிவில் அவர் மேலும் கூறியிருக்கும் விடயங்கள் வருமாறு:",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவருடன் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பில் தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் 3 பங்காளிக்கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "அதன்படி தமிழரசுக்கட்சியின் தலைவர் மாவை சேனாதிராஜா, புளொட் தலைவர் தர்மலிங்கம் சித்தார்த்தன் மற்றும் ரெலோவின் தலைவர் செல்வம் அடைக்கலநாதன் ஆகியோர் பங்கேற்றிருந்ததுடன், அச்சந்திப்பில் நான் கலந்துகொண்டிருக்கவில்லை. இருப்பினும் நான் அவர்கள் மூவருடனும் கலந்துரையாடினேன்.",
        "அதன்படி குறித்த சந்திப்பில் பங்கேற்றிருந்தவர்களுடன்பேசி விடயத்தைத் தெளிவுபடுத்திக்கொண்டு, தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடகப்பேச்சாளர் என்ற ரீதியில் இந்த விளக்கத்தை வழங்குகின்றேன்.",
        "ஜப்பான் இலங்கைக்கு உதவிகளை வழங்காது என்று ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் கூறவில்லை. மாறாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் செயற்திட்டம் நடைமுறைக்கு வந்ததன் பின்னர் ஜப்பான் உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என்றே அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அதன்படி ஜப்பான் தூதுவருடனான சந்திப்பின் பின்னர் ஊடகசந்திப்பில் பேசிய தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் தலைவர்கள் தூதுவர் கூறிய அதே விடயத்தையே கூறினார்கள்.",
        "மேலும் ஜப்பான் இலங்கையுடன் நீண்டகாலமாகப் பேணிவரும் வரலாற்று முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த நல்லுறவிற்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்த தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் பிரதிநிதிகள், தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவிகளை வழங்குமாறும் ஜப்பான் தூதுவரிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "நிதியுதவிகள் மற்றும் ஏனைய ஒத்துழைப்புக்கள் மூலம் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு ஜப்பான் செய்திருக்கும் பங்களிப்பை நாம் நன்கறிவோம்.",
        "இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியில் இவ்விடயம் தொடர்பில் ஊடகமொன்றில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட தவறான செய்தி குறித்து நாம் கவலையடைகின்றோம் என்று தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் டெசியா கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் டெசியா சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் டெசியா கூட்டமைப்பு எம்.ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழரசுக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவை சேனாதிராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ளாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்மலிங்கம் சித்தார்த்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெலோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செல்வம் அடைக்கலநாதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தெசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தெசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தெசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}