{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132054",
  "time_ut": 1658490017,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மேல் கொத்மலை நீர்த்தேக்கத்திலிருந்து மாணவியின் சடலம் மீட்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Body of student recovered from Upper Kothmalai Reservoir",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The body of a schoolgirl was recovered from the Mel Kothmalai reservoir under Thalawakkala police division at around 3 pm today.",
        "Police inform Thalivaka that the dead body of a 19-year-old student named Muturatinam Zilogini from Melaku Senai Estate, Linthulai, was recovered from the West Gothamala reservoir.",
        "Relatives of the student said that she left home this morning saying she was going to a private class in Thalaiwakagi, but the student did not go to the private class. It is revealed from the initial stage of police investigations that she is a student who has failed in the high level examination to be held this year and is a high level student of a school in Linthulai area.",
        "Today around 2 o'clock in the afternoon, local residents informed the police that they saw a dead body floating in the Upper Kothumalai water reservoir, and the police recovered the body with the help of local residents.",
        "The Dalawake police are continuing to carry out investigations related to the incident and they are taking steps to take the dead body to the Nuwara Eliya District Hospital for post-mortem."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Upper Kothmalai Reservoir",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mel Kothmalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalawakkala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 3 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thalivaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muturatinam Zilogini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melaku Senai Estate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Linthulai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Gothamala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaiwakagi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Linthulai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper Kothumalai",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dalawake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nuwara Eliya District Hospital",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉහළ කොත්මලේ ජලාශයෙන් සිසුවාගේ මළ සිරුරක් සොයා ගැනේ",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "තලවක්කල පොලිස් වසමට අයත් මෙල් කොත්මලෙයි ජලාශයේ තිබී පාසල් සිසුවියකගේ මළ සිරුරක් අද පස්වරු 3 ට පමණ සොයා ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "ලින්තුලෙයි, මෙලකු සේනයි වත්තේ පදිංචිව සිටි 19 හැවිරිදි මුතුරාතිනම් සිලෝගිනි නමැති සිසුවියගේ මළ සිරුර බටහිර ගෝතමාල ජලාශයෙන් ගොඩගත් බව පොලිසිය තාලිවාකට දන්වා සිටී.",
        "අද උදෑසන ඇය තලෙයිවකගි ප්‍රදේශයේ පෞද්ගලික පන්තියකට යන බව පවසමින් නිවසින් පිටව ගිය නමුත් සිසුවිය පෞද්ගලික පන්තියට නොගිය බවයි සිසුවියගේ ඥාතීන් පැවසුවේ. ඇය මේ වසරේ පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත උසස් පෙළ විභාගයෙන් අසමත් වූ සිසුවියක් බවත් ලිංතුලෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ පාසලක උසස් පෙළ හදාරන සිසුවියක් බවත් පොලිස් පරීක්ෂණවල මූලික අදියරේදී අනාවරණය වේ.",
        "අද පස්වරු 2 ට පමණ ඉහළ කොතුමලේ ජල ජලාශයේ මළ සිරුරක් පාවෙමින් තිබෙනු දැක ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් පොලිසියට දන්වා ඇති අතර පොලිසිය ප්‍රදේශවාසීන්ගේ සහය ඇතිව සිරුර ගොඩගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් දලවාකේ පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදුකරන අතර මෘත ශරීරය පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා නුවරඑළිය දිසා රෝහල වෙත රැගෙන යාමට කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉහළ කොත්මලේ ජලාශය",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙල් කොත්මලෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලවක්කල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 3ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තාලිවක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුතුරාතිනම් සිලෝගිනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙලකු සේනයි වත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලින්තුලෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ගෝතමාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෛවකගී",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලින්තුලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ කොතුමලෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දලවක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය දිස්ත්‍රික් රෝහල",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேல் கொத்மலை நீர்த்தேக்கத்திலிருந்து மாணவியின் சடலம் மீட்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "தலவாக்கலை பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட மேல் கொத்மலை நீர்த்தேக்கத்திலிருந்து பாடசாலை மாணவி ஒருவரின் சடலம் இன்று மாலை 3 மணியளவில் மீட்கப்பட்டது.",
        "லிந்துலை - மெளகு சேனை தோட்டத்தை சேர்ந்த 19 வயதுடைய முத்துராட்டினம் ஜிலோஜினி என்ற மாணவியின் சடலமே மேற்கோத்மலை நீர் தேக்கத்தில் இருந்து வைக்கப்பட்டதாக தலைவாக்களை பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "குறித்த மாணவி இன்று காலை தலைவாக்களையில் உள்ள தனியார் வகுப்பு ஒன்றிற்கு செல்வதாக கூறி வீட்டிலிருந்து சென்றதாகவும் இருப்பினும் குறித்த மாணவி தனியார் வகுப்பிற்கு செல்லவில்லை என்றும் அவரின் உறவினர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். இவ்வருடம் நடைபெறவுள்ள உயர் தர பரீட்சைக்கு தோற்றவுள்ள மாணவி என்றும் லிந்துலை பிரதேசத்திலுள்ள பாடசாலை ஒன்றின் உயர் தர மாணவி என்றும் பொலிஸாரின் ஆரம்ப கட்ட விசாரனைகளிலிருந்து தெரிய வருகிறது.",
        "இன்று பகல் 2 மணியளவில் மேல் கொத்துமலை நீர் தேக்கத்தில் சடலம் ஒன்று மிதப்பதை கண்ட பிரதேச மக்கள் பொலிஸாருக்கு தகவல் வழங்கியதை தொடர்ந்து பிரதேச மக்களின் உதவியுடன் பொலிஸார் சடலத்தை மீட்டனர்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகளை தளவாக்களே பொலிஸார் தொடர்ந்து முன்னெடுத்து வருவதுடன் பிரேத பரிசோதனைகளுக்காக சடலம் நுவரெலியா மாவட்ட வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்வதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை பொலிஸார் முன்னெடுத்து வருவதாக தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மேல் கொத்மலை நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் கொத்மலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலவாக்கலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை சுமார் 3 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவாக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முத்துரத்தினம் ஜிலோகினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலக்கு சேனை தோட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிந்துலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கோதமலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவாகி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிந்துலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் கொத்துமலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலவாகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா மாவட்ட வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}