{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/21/sri-lanka-cid-probes-student-activists-for-anti-govt-conspiracy/",
  "time_ut": 1661081820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka: CID probes student Activists for anti govt conspiracy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: CID probes student Activists for anti govt conspiracy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo (News 1st); Sri Lanka's Criminal Investigations Department has taken over the Investigations on student Activists who were arrested and are held under detention orders.",
        "These Activists are Convener of the Inter University Students Federation Wasantha Mudalige, Ven. Galwewa Siridhamma Thera, and Hashantha Jawantha Gunathilake.",
        "The Inspector General of Police has instructed the detectives at the Criminal Investigations Department to probe the possibility of any link to an Anti-Government Conspiracy, said the Police Spokesperson speaking to News 1st on Sunday (21).",
        "Sri Lanka: CID probes student Activists for anti govt conspiracy",
        "Do not sign detention order – UN Rapporteur calls on President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inter University Students Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galwewa Siridhamma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashantha Jawantha Gunathilake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් CID ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විමර්ශනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo (News 1st); අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රැඳවුම් නියෝග යටතේ රඳවා සිටින ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් පිළිබඳ විමර්ශන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව භාරගෙන ඇත.",
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ, පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය. ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි, සහ හශාන්ත ජවන්ත ගුණතිලක.",
        "රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී කුමන්ත්‍රණයකට කිසියම් සම්බන්ධයක් තිබේදැයි සොයා බලන ලෙස පොලිස්පතිවරයා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ රහස් පරීක්ෂකයින්ට උපදෙස් දී ඇති බව ඉරිදා (21) News 1st වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් CID ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විමර්ශනය කරයි",
        "රැඳවුම් නියෝගයට අත්සන් කරන්න එපා - එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ වාර්තාකරු ජනපතිගෙන් ඉල්ලයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හශාන්ත ජවන්ත ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති තුමා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: அரசுக்கு எதிரான சதிக்காக மாணவர் ஆர்வலர்களிடம் CID விசாரணை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு (News 1st); கைது செய்யப்பட்டு தடுப்புக் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மாணவர் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் மீதான விசாரணைகளை இலங்கையின் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் பொறுப்பேற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே, வண. கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர், மற்றும் ஹஷந்த ஜவந்த குணதிலக்க.",
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான சதித்திட்டத்துடன் ஏதேனும் தொடர்பு இருப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராயுமாறு பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தின் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினருக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (21) நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை: அரசுக்கு எதிரான சதிக்காக மாணவர் ஆர்வலர்களிடம் CID விசாரணை",
        "தடுப்புக் காவலில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம் - ஐ.நா அறிக்கையாளர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அழைப்பு"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷந்த ஜவந்த குணதிலகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}