{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131228",
  "time_ut": 1657514916,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நாட்டின் சில பகுதிகளில் மழை பெய்யும் சாத்தியம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rain is likely in some parts of the country",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology has said that the Sabaragamuwa province and Nuwara Eliya and Kandy districts will experience several spells of rain.",
        "Occasional gusty winds of 40-50 kmph are expected over the western slopes of Central Highlands and Western, Southern and Sabaragamuwa provinces.",
        "Light rain is likely over coastal areas from Colombo to Mataravia Galle.",
        "Wind will be from West to South-West direction with wind speed of 30-40 kmph. The wind speed may increase to 50-55 kmph over the coasts from Neekombo to Puttalam and Mannar to Kangesanthurai and from Galle to Pottuvil through Matara and Ambantota.",
        "The seas from Nee Colombo to Puttalam and Mannar to Kangesanthurai and the seas from Galle to Pottuvil via Matara and Ambantota are expected to be rough from time to time."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Highlands",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mataravia Galle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-55 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neekombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nee Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිවයිනේ සමහර ප්‍රදේශවලට වැසි ඇති විය හැක",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව පළාතේ සහ නුවරඑළිය සහ මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල සහ බස්නාහිර, දකුණ සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වල විටින් විට හමන පැ.කි.මී.40-50 දක්වා තද සුළං අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "කොළඹ සිට මාතරවිය ගාල්ල දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල සිහින් වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී. 30-40 පමණ වන අතර බටහිර සිට නිරිත දෙසින් හමන පැ.කි.මී. නීකොම්බෝ සිට පුත්තලම සහ මන්නාරම සිට කාංගේසන්තුරය දක්වා සහ ගාල්ල සිට මාතර සහ අඹන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළ තීරයේ සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-55 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "නී කොළඹ සිට පුත්තලම දක්වා සහ මන්නාරම සිට කන්ගේසන්තුරේ දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ සහ ගාල්ල සිට මාතර සහ අම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට රළු විය හැකි බව අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතරවිය ගාල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-55 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීකොම්බෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෑ කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டின் சில பகுதிகளில் மழை பெய்யும் சாத்தியம்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் நுவரெலியா மற்றும் கண்டி மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும் மேற்கு, தெற்கு மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 40-50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து மாதராவியா காலி வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் சிறிதளவு மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "காற்றானது மேற்கு முதல் தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும் மற்றும் காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. நீர்கொழும்பிலிருந்து புத்தளம் மற்றும் மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் காலியிலிருந்து மாத்தறை மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-55 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "நீர்கொழும்பில் இருந்து புத்தளம் மற்றும் மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் காலியிலிருந்து மாத்தறை மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 40-50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய மலைநாடு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதராவியா காலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50-55 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீகோம்போ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீ கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}