{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-debt-rise-to-140-pct-pm-says-after-currency-collapse-96947/",
  "time_ut": 1657000560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka debt rise to 140-pct PM says after currency collapse",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka debt rise to 140-pct PM says after currency collapse",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s debt has shot up to 140 percent of gross domestic product Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe said as the rupee fell in the worst currency crisis in the history of the island’s intermediate regime central bank.",
        "Sri Lanka rupee has fallen to 360 to the US dollar from around 200 at the beginning of the years.",
        "Wickremesinghe said Sri Lanka is making progress towards and 4 year Extended Fund Facility with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "“With the IMF we hope to reduce it (debt) to 95 percent of GDP by 2032,” Wickremsinghe told parliament.",
        "Sri Lanka’s government debt which was Rs17,580 billion by end 2021 and risen to 2022 March Rs21,969 billion, he said.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted on its foreign debt after three currency crisis from 2015.",
        "Sri Lanka’s economy is expected to shrink to 76 billion US dollars in 2022 from 94 billion in 2018.",
        "It is expected to come back to the earlier level by 2026. (Colombo/July05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "140",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "up to 140 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the beginning of the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "95 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2032",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremsinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "94 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2026",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/July05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුදල් කඩාවැටීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය සියයට 140 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇතැයි අගමැති කියයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නය දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් සියයට 140 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, දිවයිනේ අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම ව්‍යවහාර මුදල් අර්බුදයේ දී රුපියල කඩා වැටීම නිසා ය.",
        "වසර ආරම්භයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ වසර 4ක විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම වෙත ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කර ගනිමින් සිටින බව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“ජාමූඅ සමග අපි එය (ණය) 2032 වන විට දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් සියයට 95 දක්වා අඩු කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,” වික්‍රමසිංහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "2021 අවසන් වන විට රුපියල් බිලියන 17,580 ක් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ණය ප්‍රමාණය 2022 මාර්තු වන විට රුපියල් බිලියන 21,969 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "2015 සිට මුදල් අර්බුදය තුනකින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය විදේශ ණය පැහැර හැරියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය 2018 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 94 සිට 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 76 දක්වා අඩු වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "එය 2026 වන විට පෙර පැවති මට්ටමට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. (කොළඹ/ජූලි05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "140",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 140 දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරවල ආරම්භය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 4 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 95 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2032",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 76 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 94 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2026",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாணய வீழ்ச்சிக்குப் பின்னர் இலங்கையின் கடன் 140 சதவீதமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் கடன் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 140 சதவீதமாக உயர்ந்துள்ளது என்று பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, தீவின் இடைநிலை ஆட்சியின் மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியில் ரூபாய் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்ததாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வருடங்களின் ஆரம்பத்தில் சுமார் 200 ஆக இருந்த இலங்கை ரூபா அமெரிக்க டொலருக்கு 360 ஆக வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் 4 வருட விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியை நோக்கி இலங்கை முன்னேறி வருவதாக விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "\"IMF உடன் 2032 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 95 சதவீதமாக கடனைக் குறைக்க நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்\" என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கூறினார்.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் 17,580 பில்லியனாக இருந்த இலங்கையின் அரசாங்கக் கடன் 2022 மார்ச்சில் 21,969 பில்லியனாக உயர்ந்துள்ளது என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "2015 முதல் மூன்று நாணய நெருக்கடியின் பின்னர் இலங்கை தனது வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் 2018ல் 94 பில்லியனாக இருந்த நிலையில் 2022ல் 76 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களாக சுருங்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இது 2026 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் மீண்டும் முந்தைய நிலைக்கு வரும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "140",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "140 சதவீதம் வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகளின் ஆரம்பம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "95 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2032",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "94 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2026",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}