{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/cannot-support-sri-lankas-imf-bound-caretaker-president-mp-vasudeva-n-98602/",
  "time_ut": 1660546740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cannot support Sri Lanka’s IMF-bound “caretaker” president: MP Vasudeva N",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cannot support Sri Lanka’s IMF-bound “caretaker” president: MP Vasudeva N",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka independent MP and leader of the Democratic Left Front Vasudeva Nanayakkara said his party cannot support President Ranil Wickremesnghe who is a “caretaker president” that “operates within the International Monetary Fund (IMF) framework.”",
        "Nanayakkara made this remark at a press conference in Colombo on Monday August 15 commenting on President Wickremesinghe’s invitation to all MPs to join an all-party government.",
        "“We cannot support Wickremesinghe who operates within the IMF framework, and because of us, Wickremesinghe cannot help the country either (sp),” he said.",
        "Nanayakkara is one the ‘group of 10’ independent MPs who were previously influential members of the government of ex President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that broke off following apparent disagreements with Rajapaka’s handling of Sri Lanka’s worsening economic crisis. Other prominent members include former ministers Wimal Weerawansa and Udaya Gammanpila.",
        "Nanayakkara claimed once their group comes into an agreement with the independent faction of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) led by Dullas Alahapperuma, the new alliance thus formed will be the opposition in parliament.",
        "“What is now in power is a caretaker government and a caretaker president. I said that at the start. [Wickremesinghe] must work within the reality that he is a caretaker president,” he said.",
        "The Ratnapura district national list MP, a former leftist leader, is a staunch critic of the IMF and famously said in parliament in November 2021: “We will not go to the IMF even if we die.”",
        "The group of 10 is also known for its pro-Russian, pro-China outlook and their suspicion of the West.",
        "President Wickremesinghe has repeatedly articulated his plans to work with the IMF and several rounds of negotiations have already been held, though there is still some uncertainty on when staff level agreement can be reached. The main opposition Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) has also expressed conditional support for an IMF programme. (Colombo/Aug15/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesnghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday August 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "pro-Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "pro-China",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට බැඳී සිටින “භාරකාර” ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහාය දිය නොහැක: පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව එන්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රී සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණේ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර පැවසුවේ \"ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) රාමුව තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන\" \"භාරකාර ජනාධිපති\" ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට තම පක්ෂයට සහාය දිය නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "නානායක්කාර මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අගෝස්තු 15 සඳුදා කොළඹදී පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවකට එක්වන ලෙස ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට කරන ආරාධනය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින්.",
        "“ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ රාමුව තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන වික්‍රමසිංහට අපට සහාය දිය නොහැකි අතර, අප නිසා වික්‍රමසිංහටද (එස්පී) රටට උදව් කළ නොහැක,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නානායක්කාර යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නරක අතට හැරෙමින් පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රාජපක්ෂගේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පෙනෙන එකඟ නොවීම් හේතුවෙන් බිඳී ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ රජයේ බලගතු සාමාජිකයින් වූ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 10 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමකි. හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන විමල් වීරවංශ සහ උදය ගම්මන්පිල ද සෙසු ප්‍රමුඛ සාමාජිකයින් වේ.",
        "තම කණ්ඩායම ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුමගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම සමඟ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණි පසු, එසේ පිහිටුවන නව සන්ධානය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විපක්ෂය වනු ඇතැයි නානායක්කාර ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“දැන් බලයේ සිටින්නේ භාරකාර ආණ්ඩුවක් සහ භාරකාර ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක්. මම ඒක ආරම්භයේදීම කිව්වා. [වික්‍රමසිංහ] ඔහු භාරකාර ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු යන යථාර්ථය තුළ ක්‍රියා කළ යුතුය,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු වාමාංශික නායකයෙකු වන රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික් ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ දැඩි විවේචකයෙකු වන අතර 2021 නොවැම්බරයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රසිද්ධ ලෙස පැවසුවේ “අපි මැරුණත් IMF එකට යන්නේ නැහැ.”",
        "10 දෙනාගේ කණ්ඩායම එහි රුසියානු හිතවාදී, චීනයට ගැති දැක්ම සහ බටහිර කෙරෙහි ඔවුන්ගේ සැකය සඳහා ද ප්‍රසිද්ධය.",
        "මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට එළඹිය හැක්කේ කවදාද යන්න පිළිබඳව තවමත් යම් අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයක් පවතින නමුත්, ජාමූඅ සමඟ වැඩ කිරීමේ සැලසුම් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් නැවත නැවතත් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති අතර දැනටමත් සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් පවත්වා ඇත. ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) ද ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනකට කොන්දේසි සහිත සහය පළ කර ඇත. (කොළඹ/අගෝ.15/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණ වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 15 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු ගැති",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනයට හිතවත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு கட்டுப்பட்ட \"காவல்காரர்\" ஜனாதிபதியை ஆதரிக்க முடியாது: பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வாசுதேவ என்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை சுயேச்சை எம்.பியும் ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் தலைவருமான வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, \"சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் செயல்படும்\" ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஆதரிக்க முடியாது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 15 திங்கட்கிழமை கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில், அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் இணையுமாறு அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க விடுத்த அழைப்பு குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த நாணயக்கார இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"IMF கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் செயல்படும் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நாங்கள் ஆதரிக்க முடியாது, மேலும் எங்களால், விக்கிரமசிங்கவால் நாட்டுக்கும் (sp) உதவ முடியாது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் அரசாங்கத்தில் செல்வாக்கு மிக்க உறுப்பினர்களாக இருந்த ‘10 பேர் கொண்ட’ சுயேச்சை எம்.பி.க்களில் நாணயக்காரவும் ஒருவர். இலங்கையின் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை ராஜபக்ச கையாள்வதில் வெளிப்படையான கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளைத் தொடர்ந்து முறித்துக் கொண்டார். முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்களான விமல் வீரவன்ச மற்றும் உதய கம்மன்பில உள்ளிட்ட முக்கிய அங்கத்தவர்கள்.",
        "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தலைமையிலான ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) சுயேச்சைப் பிரிவினருடன் தமது குழு உடன்படிக்கைக்கு வந்ததும், அவ்வாறு அமைக்கப்படும் புதிய கூட்டணியே நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சியாக இருக்கும் என நாணயக்கார கூறினார்.",
        "“இப்போது ஆட்சியில் இருப்பது ஒரு காபந்து அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் ஒரு தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி. அதை ஆரம்பத்திலேயே சொன்னேன். அவர் ஒரு தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி என்ற யதார்த்தத்திற்குள் [விக்கிரமசிங்க] பணியாற்ற வேண்டும்,” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இரத்தினபுரி மாவட்ட தேசியப் பட்டியல் எம்.பி., முன்னாள் இடதுசாரித் தலைவர், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் தீவிர விமர்சகர் மற்றும் நவம்பர் 2021 இல் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரபலமாக கூறினார்: \"நாங்கள் இறந்தாலும் IMF க்கு செல்ல மாட்டோம்.\"",
        "10 பேர் கொண்ட குழு அதன் ரஷ்ய சார்பு, சீனா சார்பு பார்வை மற்றும் மேற்கு நாடுகளின் சந்தேகத்திற்கும் பெயர் பெற்றது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதற்கான தனது திட்டங்களை பலமுறை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார் மற்றும் பல சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் ஏற்கனவே நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன, இருப்பினும் பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்பாடு எப்போது எட்டப்படும் என்பதில் இன்னும் சில நிச்சயமற்ற நிலை உள்ளது. பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகயாவும் (SJB) IMF திட்டத்திற்கு நிபந்தனை ஆதரவை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்15/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணி வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய சார்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா சார்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}