{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83896/names-of-new-ministerial-secretaries-gazetted",
  "time_ut": 1658893860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Names of new ministerial secretaries gazetted",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Names of new ministerial secretaries gazetted",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Gazette Extraordinary has been published on Tuesday (July 26), announcing the names of the newly-appointed ministerial secretaries.",
        "As per the communiqué, Mahinda Siriwardana has been re-appointed the Secretary to the Ministry of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policies.",
        "In addition, Aruni Wijewardana and General (Retd.) Kamal Gunaratna have been re-appointed to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Ministry of Defence, respectively.",
        "Meanwhile, Dr. Anil Jasinghe will continue to serve as the Secretary to the Environment Ministry, and Anusha Palpita as the Secretary to the Mass Media Ministry.",
        "In the same communiqué, Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake also gazetted the appointments of new Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena, the Cabinet Ministers, Secretary to the Prime Minister Anura Dissanayake, Secretary to the Cabinet of Minister W.M.D.J. Fernando."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "General (Retd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anil Jasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Environment Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anusha Palpita",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mass Media Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet Ministers",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.M.D.J. Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන්ගේ නම් ගැසට් කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අඟහරුවාදා (ජූලි 26) නව අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන්ගේ නම් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් අති විශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "එම නිවේදනයට අනුව මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන මහතා යළි පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයට සහ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයට පිළිවෙලින් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන සහ ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) කමල් ගුණරත්න නැවත පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, වෛද්‍ය අනිල් ජාසිංහ මහතා පරිසර අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙසත්, අනුෂ පැල්පිට මහතා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙසත් තවදුරටත් කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "එම නිවේදනයේම ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා විසින් නව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන, කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරුන්, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් අනුර දිසානායක, අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල ලේකම් ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනිල් ජාසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිසර අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනූෂ පැල්පිට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ඇමතිවරු",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அமைச்சு செயலாளர்களின் பெயர்கள் வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அமைச்சுச் செயலாளர்களின் பெயர்களை அறிவிக்கும் அதிவிசேட வர்த்தமானி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (ஜூலை 26) வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சின் செயலாளராக மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சுக்கு முறையே அருணி விஜேவர்தன மற்றும் ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு) கமல் குணரத்ன ஆகியோர் மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சின் செயலாளராக கலாநிதி அனில் ஜாசிங்கவும், வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சின் செயலாளராக அனுஷ பல்பிடவும் தொடர்ந்தும் பணியாற்றவுள்ளனர்.",
        "புதிய பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்கள், பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் அநுர திஸாநாயக்க, அமைச்சரவையின் செயலாளர் டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே ஆகியோரின் நியமனங்களையும் ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிட்டார். பெர்னாண்டோ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது (ஓய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனில் ஜாசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுஷா பல்பிடா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே. பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}