{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SLFP-presents-nine-point-proposal-for-formation-of-National-Government/56-738106",
  "time_ut": 1659124891,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLFP presents nine-point proposal for formation of National Government",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLFP presents nine-point proposal for formation of National Government",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Freedom Party submitted a nine-point proposal to President Ranil Wickremesinghe setting out the structure for a future National Government. The proposal was presented to the President during the meeting held yesterday with former President Maithripala Sirisena and several members of the SLFP at the Ministry of Finance.",
        "Among the proposals set out, the SLFP has suggested the establishment of a Crisis Management Cabinet and the inclusion of all Members of Parliament in the attached committees for Ministries, as well as the appointment of an Advisory Committee consisting of experts and intellectuals to each Ministry. In a release, the party said it also presented its stance about the structure and responsibilities of the National Assembly to be established in the Parliament.",
        "Representatives of the SLFP said the President appeared favourable to the proposals presented and he suggested that several rounds of discussions should take place in this regard. “The economic and political programs of a National Government were widely discussed, and an agreement is expected to be reached in the next few days,” the release said.",
        "Accordingly, discussions are set to be held in the next few days between a group of representatives of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party and a group of Government representatives. This will be followed by another meeting between President Wickremesinghe and former President Maithripala Sirisena."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "nine",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Government",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministries",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advisory Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රීලනිපය කරුණු නවයක යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉදිරි ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා වන ව්‍යුහය සකස් කරමින් කරුණු 9කින් යුත් යෝජනාවලියක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කළා. හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සමඟ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ඊයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී මෙම යෝජනාව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති යෝජනා අතර අර්බුද කළමනාකරණ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් පිහිටුවීම සහ අමාත්‍යාංශ සඳහා අනුයුක්ත කාරක සභාවලට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සියලු දෙනා ඇතුළත් කිරීම මෙන්ම සෑම අමාත්‍යාංශයකටම විශේෂඥයන් සහ බුද්ධිමතුන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් උපදේශක කමිටුවක් පත් කළ යුතු බවට ශ්‍රීලනිපය යෝජනා කර ඇත. නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් එම පක්ෂය කියා සිටියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ස්ථාපිත කිරීමට නියමිත ජාතික සභාවේ ව්‍යුහය සහ වගකීම් පිළිබඳ සිය ස්ථාවරය ද ඉදිරිපත් කළ බවයි.",
        "ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති යෝජනාවලට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ හිතකර බව පෙනී ගිය බව පැවසූ ශ්‍රීලනිප නියෝජිතයන් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් පැවැත්විය යුතු බවට ඔහු යෝජනා කළේය. \"ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන වැඩසටහන් පුළුල් ලෙස සාකච්ඡාවට ලක් වූ අතර ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය තුළ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ\" යනුවෙන් එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ නියෝජිතයින් පිරිසක් සහ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ නියෝජිතයින් පිරිසක් අතර ඉදිරි දින කිහිපයේදී සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි. ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා අතර තවත් හමුවක් පැවැත්වෙන්නේ ඉන් අනතුරුවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නවය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍යාංශ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஒன்பது அம்ச பிரேரணையை முன்வைத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்கால தேசிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கான கட்டமைப்பை வகுக்கும் வகையில் ஒன்பது அம்ச பிரேரணையை ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளது. முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர்கள் பலருடன் நேற்று நிதியமைச்சில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே ஜனாதிபதியிடம் இந்த யோசனை முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணைகளில், நெருக்கடி முகாமைத்துவ அமைச்சரவையை ஸ்தாபித்தல் மற்றும் அமைச்சுக்களுக்கான இணைக்கப்பட்ட குழுக்களில் அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களையும் இணைத்தல், அத்துடன் ஒவ்வொரு அமைச்சுக்கும் நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் புத்திஜீவிகளைக் கொண்ட ஆலோசனைக் குழுவை நியமிக்கவும் ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளது. பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறுவப்படவுள்ள தேசிய சபையின் கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் பொறுப்புகள் பற்றிய தனது நிலைப்பாட்டையும் முன்வைத்ததாக அக்கட்சி ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணைகளுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி சாதகமாக இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் பிரதிநிதிகள், இது தொடர்பில் பல சுற்று கலந்துரையாடல்களை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு அவர் பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளார். \"ஒரு தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் திட்டங்கள் பரவலாக விவாதிக்கப்பட்டன, மேலும் அடுத்த சில நாட்களில் ஒரு உடன்பாடு எட்டப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவிற்கும் அரசாங்கப் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவிற்கும் இடையில் அடுத்த சில தினங்களில் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தப்பட உள்ளது. இதனைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவிற்கும் இடையில் மீண்டும் சந்திப்பொன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்பது",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய அரசாங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சுக்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசனை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}