{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-presidents-policy-direction-correct-but-could-be-a-cuckoo-egg-harsha-99283/",
  "time_ut": 1661935260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President’s policy direction correct, but could be a cuckoo egg: Harsha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President’s policy direction correct, but could be a cuckoo egg: Harsha",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s policy direction in the budget is correct but whether it can be implemented while working with a party with opposite ideas, Samagi Jana Balawegaya legislator Harsha de Silva said.",
        "“This is the direction of the economic policy of the President,” de Silva said. “We are not against this plan.",
        "“This is what Bangladesh is doing. This is what Vietnam is doing.”",
        "The SLPP had consistently opposed all measures aimed to develop the country.",
        "However, analysts say both countries had long periods of monetary stability. Bangladesh for about 10 years, and Vietnam for longer periods.",
        "“Ranil Wickremesinghe had tried to do it before,” de Silva said. “But the SLPP and Rajapaksa ideology opposed them for political gain. We saw it happen with the Sri Lanka-Singapore free trade agreement.”",
        "“Will these people agree to this? Will a person in the custody of the SLPP be allowed to do it? We do not think.",
        "“Ranil Wickremesinghe’s economic strategy is like a keol egg in a crow’s nest.”",
        "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya believes in individual freedom, economic freedom and social justice, he said.",
        "De Silva said he was opposed to the arrest of protestors under the Wickremesinghe administration. (Colombo/Sep31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 10 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka-Singapore",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපතිගේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති දිශානතිය නිවැරදි නමුත් කුකුල් බිත්තරයක් විය හැකියි: හර්ෂ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අයවැයෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය මඟ පෙන්වීම නිවැරදි නමුත් ප්‍රතිවිරුද්ධ අදහස් ඇති පක්ෂයක් සමඟ කටයුතු කරමින් එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ හැකිද යන්න සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ දිශානතිය මේකයි යැයි ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය. “අපි මේ සැලැස්මට විරුද්ධ නැහැ.",
        "“බංගලාදේශය කරන්නේ මේකයි. වියට්නාමය කරන්නේ මෙයයි. ”",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රට සංවර්ධනය කිරීමේ සියලු ක්‍රියාමාර්ගවලට නිරන්තරයෙන් විරුද්ධ විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, විශ්ලේෂකයින් පවසන්නේ දෙරටේම දිගුකාලීන මුදල් ස්ථාවරත්වයක් පැවති බවයි. බංග්ලාදේශය වසර 10 ක් පමණ සහ වියට්නාමය දිගු කාලයක් සඳහා.",
        "\"රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මීට කලින් ඒක කරන්න හැදුවා\" ද සිල්වා කීවේය. නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සහ රාජපක්ෂ මතවාදය දේශපාලන වාසි තකා ඒවාට විරුද්ධ වුණා. ශ්‍රී ලංකා - සිංගප්පූරු නිදහස් වෙළෙඳ ගිවිසුමත් සමඟ එය සිදුවන බව අපි දැක්කා.",
        "“මේ අය මේකට එකඟ වෙයිද? ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ අත්අඩංගුවේ සිටින අයෙකුට එය කිරීමට ඉඩ දෙනවාද? අපි හිතන්නේ නැහැ.",
        "\"රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ ආර්ථික උපායමාර්ගය හරියට කපුටන්ගේ කූඩුවේ කියෝල බිත්තරයක් වගේ\"",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය පුද්ගල නිදහස, ආර්ථික නිදහස සහ සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය විශ්වාස කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ද සිල්වා කියා සිටියේ වික්‍රමසිංහ පාලනය යටතේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට තමන් විරුද්ධ බවයි. (කොළඹ/සැප්.31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව - සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியின் கொள்கை திசை சரியானது, ஆனால் அது காக்கா முட்டையாக இருக்கலாம்: ஹர்ஷா",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கொள்கை வழிகாட்டுதல் சரியானது ஆனால் எதிர் கருத்துக்கள் கொண்ட கட்சியுடன் இணைந்து செயற்படும் போது அதனை நடைமுறைப்படுத்த முடியுமா என சமகி ஜன பலவேகய சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இது ஜனாதிபதியின் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கையின் திசையாகும் என டி சில்வா கூறினார். “இந்த திட்டத்திற்கு நாங்கள் எதிரானவர்கள் அல்ல.",
        "“பங்களாதேஷ் இதைத்தான் செய்கிறது. இதைத்தான் வியட்நாம் செய்து வருகிறது.",
        "நாட்டின் அபிவிருத்தியை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளையும் SLPP தொடர்ந்து எதிர்த்தது.",
        "இருப்பினும், இரு நாடுகளும் நீண்ட கால பண ஸ்திரத்தன்மையைக் கொண்டிருந்ததாக ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். பங்களாதேஷ் சுமார் 10 ஆண்டுகள், மற்றும் வியட்நாம் நீண்ட காலத்திற்கு.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னரும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முயற்சித்திருந்தார் என டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். “ஆனால் SLPP மற்றும் ராஜபக்ச சித்தாந்தம் அரசியல் லாபத்திற்காக அவர்களை எதிர்த்தன. இலங்கை-சிங்கப்பூர் சுதந்திர வர்த்தக உடன்படிக்கையில் அது நடந்ததை நாங்கள் பார்த்தோம்.",
        "“இவர்கள் இதற்கு சம்மதிப்பார்களா? SLPP யின் காவலில் உள்ள ஒருவர் அதைச் செய்ய அனுமதிக்கப்படுவாரா? நாங்கள் நினைக்கவில்லை.",
        "\"ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பொருளாதார உத்தி காக்கைக் கூட்டில் கிடக்கும் முட்டை போன்றது.\"",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா தனிமனித சுதந்திரம், பொருளாதார சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் சமூக நீதி ஆகியவற்றில் நம்பிக்கை கொண்டுள்ளது, என்றார்.",
        "விக்ரமசிங்க நிர்வாகத்தின் கீழ் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்படுவதை தான் எதிர்ப்பதாக டி சில்வா கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/செப்31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}