{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/maybe-this-is-life-chinese-ambassadors-response-to-delayed-arrival-of-yuan-wang-5/",
  "time_ut": 1660637760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "“Maybe this is life” : Chinese Ambassadors response to delayed arrival of Yuan Wang 5",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "“Maybe this is life” : Chinese Ambassadors response to delayed arrival of Yuan Wang 5",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Qi Zhenhong, the Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka said that the Hambantota Port was not only a major Belt and Road cooperation project, but is also a symbol of China – Sri Lanka friendship.",
        "The Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka speaking to reporters in Hambantota following the arrival of the Yuan Wang 5 Chinese Research / Survey vessel said that is a normal visit, and it nothing special.",
        "In response to a question posed on concerns raised by India over the arrival of the vessel, he said \"I think you can ask those questions from the Indian friends.\"",
        "His reponse to a question on the diplimatic tussle over the past few days over the vessel was \"I don't know. Maybe this is life. This is nature.\"",
        "“Maybe this is life” : Chinese Ambassadors response to delayed arrival of Yuan Wang 5"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belt",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Research / Survey",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "“සමහර විට මෙය ජීවිතය විය හැකිය” : යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ප්‍රමාද වී පැමිණීමට චීන තානාපතිවරු ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හම්බන්තොට වරාය ප්‍රධාන තීරයක් සහ මාර්ග සහයෝගීතා ව්‍යාපෘතියක් පමණක් නොව, චීන - ශ්‍රී ලංකා මිත්‍රත්වයේ සංකේතයක් ද වන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 චීන පර්යේෂණ / සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීමෙන් පසු හම්බන්තොටදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ එය සාමාන්‍ය සංචාරයක් බවත් එහි විශේෂත්වයක් නොමැති බවත්ය.",
        "යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව විසින් මතු කරන ලද ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ \"ඔබට එම ප්‍රශ්න ඉන්දියානු මිතුරන්ගෙන් ඇසීමට හැකි යැයි මම සිතමි\" යනුවෙනි.",
        "යාත්‍රාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් පසුගිය දින කිහිපය තුළ ඇති වූ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුම පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නයකට ඔහුගේ පිළිතුර වූයේ \"මම නොදනිමි. සමහර විට මෙය ජීවිතය විය හැකිය. මෙය ස්වභාවයයි.\"",
        "“සමහර විට මෙය ජීවිතය විය හැකිය” : යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ප්‍රමාද වී පැමිණීමට චීන තානාපතිවරු ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන පර්යේෂණ / සමීක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"ஒருவேளை இது வாழ்க்கையாக இருக்கலாம்\" : யுவான் வாங் 5 தாமதமாக வருவதற்கு சீன தூதர்கள் பதிலளித்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகமானது ஒரு பெரிய பெல்ட் மற்றும் ரோடு ஒத்துழைப்பு திட்டம் மட்டுமல்ல, சீனா - இலங்கை நட்புறவின் சின்னம் என்றும் இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 சீன ரிசர்ச்/சர்வே கப்பலின் வருகையைத் தொடர்ந்து ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர், இது ஒரு சாதாரண விஜயம் என்றும், அதில் சிறப்பு எதுவும் இல்லை என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "கப்பலின் வருகை குறித்து இந்தியா எழுப்பிய கவலைகள் குறித்து எழுப்பப்பட்ட கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த அவர், \"இந்திய நண்பர்களிடம் அந்தக் கேள்விகளை நீங்கள் கேட்கலாம் என்று நினைக்கிறேன்\" என்றார்.",
        "கப்பலில் கடந்த சில நாட்களாக நிலவும் இராஜதந்திர தகராறு குறித்த கேள்விக்கு அவர் அளித்த பதில் \"எனக்குத் தெரியாது. ஒருவேளை இதுதான் வாழ்க்கை. இதுதான் இயல்பு.\"",
        "\"ஒருவேளை இது வாழ்க்கையாக இருக்கலாம்\" : யுவான் வாங் 5 தாமதமாக வருவதற்கு சீன தூதர்கள் பதிலளித்தனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சி / ஆய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}