{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මාතරින්-දුම්රිය-දෙකක්-එයි/101-616365",
  "time_ut": 1657711907,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මාතරින් දුම්රිය දෙකක් එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two trains arrive at Matherin",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "After the imposition of curfew in the Western Province, the railway authorities announced that trains to Colombo would be suspended, but with the intervention of the people and the station masters, several trains were running this afternoon (13).",
        "Railway General Manager Mr. Dhammika Jayasundara had informed all railway stations this afternoon (13) that trains coming to Colombo from faraway places will be suspended until further notice as per the instructions of the Prime Minister's Office.",
        "Mr. Jayasundara had further mentioned that the reason for this was the imposition of curfew in the Western Province.",
        "Mr. Kasun Chamara, General Secretary of the Railway Station Master's Association, said this afternoon that the station masters are ready to bring the railway career that has started to Colombo to Colombo and they should get the full support of the passengers for that.",
        "Mr. Kasun Chamara further mentioned that station masters and several stations have been attacked and requested to refrain from such things and support the running of trains.",
        "Meanwhile, the authorities of Matara railway station were forced to run two trains from Matara to Colombo and Kandy yesterday afternoon on the strong request of the train passengers.",
        "Although the heads of the railway department had informed the Matara railway station not to run the trains due to the curfew imposed in the Western Province, the train from Beliatta to Kandy had already arrived at the Matara railway station, so the Matara chief station master A. Mr. Priyantha was forced.",
        "Since tickets had already been issued and the railway unions had also informed to run the train, the Matara Railway authorities took steps to run the relevant train.",
        "The train, which was supposed to leave Matherin at 1.40 pm, was 30 minutes late and left for Kandy at 2.10 pm, and a large number of people boarded that train to participate in the struggle in Mather.",
        "After that, at 3.15 pm, another train was run towards Colombo and at the same time, a large number of army personnel had called the security at Matara railway station.",
        "How the Army had deployed heavy security at the Matara railway station."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Matherin",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kasun Chamara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Railway Station Master's Association",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kasun Chamara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Matara Railway",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matherin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.40 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.10 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mather",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.15 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාතරින් දුම්රිය දෙකක් එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතට ඇඳිරිනීතිය පැනවීමෙන් පසුව කොළඹට දුම්රිය ධාවනය අත්හිටුවන්නේ යැයි දුම්රිය බලධාරීන් නිවේදනය කළ ද ජනතාවගේ සහ දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්ගේ මැදිහත්වීමෙන් අද (13) පස්වරුවේ දුම්රිය කීපයක් ධාවනය කිරීම කැපී පෙනුණි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යයාලයේ උපදෙස් පරිදි දුර බැහැර සිට කොළඹට පැමිණෙන දුම්රියන් නැවත දැනුම්දෙන තුරු අත්හිටුවීමට කටයුතු කරන බව දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යධිකාරී ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර මහතා සියලුම දුම්රිය ස්ථානවලට අද (13) පස්වරුවේ දැනුම් දී තිබුණි.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතට ඇඳිරිනීතිය පැනවීම මෙයට හේතුව බවත් ජයසුන්දර මහතා වැඩි දුරටත් සඳහන් කර තිබුණි.",
        "කොළඹ බලා ගමන් අරඹා ඇති දුම්රිය වෘත්තිය අවධානම දරමින් කොළඹට ගෙන ඒමට දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරු සූදානම් බවත් ඒ සඳහා මගීන්ගේ පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලැබිය යුතු බවත් දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් කසුන් චාමර මහතා අද පස්වරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරු සහ දුම්රිය ස්ථාන කීපයකට පහර දී ඇති බවත් එවැනි දේවලින් වැලකී දුම්රිය ධාවනයට සහයෝගය දක්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත් කසුන් චාමර මහතා එහිදී වැඩි දුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ දුම්රිය මගීන්ගේ දැඩි ඉල්ලීම මත මාතර සිට දුම්රිය දෙකක් කොළඹට හා නුවරට ධාවනය කිරිමට මාතර දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේ බලධාරීන්ට සිදුවිය.",
        "බස්නාහිර පලාතට ඇදිරි නීතිය පනවා ඇති නිසා දුම්රිය ධාවනය නොකරන ලෙසට දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධානීන් මාතර දුම්රිය ස්ථානය වෙත දැනුම් දී තිබුණ ද, ඒ වන විටත් බෙලිඅත්ත සිට නුවර බලා යන දුම්රිය මාතර දුම්රිය ස්ථානයට පැමීණ තිබු නිසා විශාල පිරිසක් එම දුම්රිය ධාවනය කරවන ලෙසට මාතර ප්‍රධාන දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති ඒ.ප්‍රියන්ත මහතාට බලකර සිටියහ.",
        "ඒ වන විටත් ප්‍රවේශ පත්‍ර ද නිකුත් කර තිබු නිසාත් දුම්රිය වෘත්තීය සමිති ද දුම්රිය ධාවනය කරවන ලෙස දැනුම් දී තිබු නිසාත් අදාල දුම්රිය ධාවනය කරවීමට මාතර දුම්රිය බලධාරීහූ පියවර ගත්හ.",
        "මාතරින් පස්වරු 1.40 ට පිටත්ව විය යුතුව තිබු දුම්රිය මිනිත්තු 30 ක් ප්‍රමාද වී පස්වරු 2.10 ට නුවර බලා පිටත්ව ගිය අතර එම දුම්රියට මාතරදී අරගලයට සහභාගි වීම සඳහා විශාල පිරිසක් ගොඩවූහ.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව පස්වරු 3.15 ට කොළඹ බලා තවත් දුම්රියක් ධාවනය කළ අතර ඒ සමගම යුද හමුදා සාමාජිකයින් විශාල පිරිසක් මාතර දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේ ආරක්‍ෂාව කැඳවා තිබුණි.",
        "මාතර දුම්රිය ස්ථානයට දැඩි යුද හමුදාව ආරක්‍ෂාව යොදවා තිබූ ආකාරය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැටරින්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කසුන් චාමර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති සංගමය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කසුන් චාමර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර දුම්රිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැටරින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.40 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 30 ක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.10 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.15 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு ரயில்கள் மாத்தரின் வந்தடையும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டதையடுத்து, கொழும்புக்கான புகையிரதங்கள் இடைநிறுத்தப்படுவதாக புகையிரத அதிகாரிகள் அறிவித்திருந்த போதிலும், மக்கள் மற்றும் நிலைய அதிபர்களின் தலையீட்டினால் இன்று (13) பிற்பகல் பல ரயில்கள் இயங்கின.",
        "பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தின் பணிப்புரைக்கமைய தூர இடங்களிலிருந்து கொழும்புக்கு வரும் ரயில்கள் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை இடைநிறுத்தப்படும் என ரயில்வே பொது முகாமையாளர் திரு.தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர இன்று (13) பிற்பகல் அனைத்து ரயில் நிலையங்களுக்கும் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டமையே இதற்குக் காரணம் எனவும் திரு.ஜெயசுந்தர மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள புகையிரத வாழ்க்கையை கொழும்புக்கு கொண்டுவருவதற்கு நிலைய அதிபர்கள் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும், அதற்கு பயணிகளின் பூரண ஆதரவை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டுமெனவும் புகையிரத நிலைய அதிபர்கள் சங்கத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் திரு.கசுன் சாமர இன்று பிற்பகல் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ரயில் நிலைய அதிபர்கள் மற்றும் பல நிலையங்கள் தாக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், இதுபோன்ற செயல்களில் இருந்து விலகி, ரயில்களை இயக்குவதற்கு ஆதரவளிக்குமாறும் திரு.கசுன் சாமர மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, புகையிரத பயணிகளின் பலமான கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய மாத்தறை புகையிரத நிலைய அதிகாரிகள் நேற்று பிற்பகல் மாத்தறையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும் கண்டிக்கு இரண்டு ரயில்களை இயக்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "மேல்மாகாணத்தில் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் காரணமாக புகையிரதங்களை இயக்க வேண்டாம் என புகையிரத திணைக்கள தலைவர்கள் மாத்தறை புகையிரத நிலையத்திற்கு அறிவித்திருந்த போதிலும், பெலியத்தவிலிருந்து கண்டி நோக்கிய புகையிரதம் ஏற்கனவே மாத்தறை புகையிரத நிலையத்திற்கு வந்திருந்ததால் மாத்தறை பிரதான நிலைய அதிபர் ஏ. திரு.பிரியந்த கட்டாயப்படுத்தப்பட்டார்.",
        "பயணச்சீட்டுகள் ஏற்கனவே வழங்கப்பட்டு விட்டதாலும், புகையிரதத்தை இயக்குமாறு புகையிரத தொழிற்சங்கங்களும் தெரிவித்திருந்தமையினால், மாத்தறை புகையிரத அதிகாரிகள் குறித்த ரயிலை இயக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மாத்தரினில் இருந்து மதியம் 1.40 மணிக்கு புறப்பட வேண்டிய ரயில் 30 நிமிடம் தாமதமாக 2.10 மணிக்கு கண்டிக்கு புறப்பட்டதால், அந்த ரயிலில் ஏராளமானோர் ஏறி மாதேரில் நடந்த போராட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "அதனையடுத்து மாலை 3.15 மணியளவில் கொழும்பு நோக்கி மற்றுமொரு புகையிரதம் இயக்கப்பட்டதுடன், மாத்தறை புகையிரத நிலையத்தின் பாதுகாப்பிற்கு பெருமளவான இராணுவத்தினர் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மாத்தறை ரயில் நிலையத்தில் இராணுவம் எவ்வாறு பலத்த பாதுகாப்பை நிலைநிறுத்தியிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாத்தரின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கசுன் சாமர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே ஸ்டேஷன் மாஸ்டர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கசுன் சாமர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தரின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 1.40 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நிமிடம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2.10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை 3.15 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}