{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/නාමල්ට-ඇමතිකමක්-දෙනවට-Black-Cap-Movement-විරුද්ධ-වෙයි/11-396395",
  "time_ut": 1660795503,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නාමල්ට ඇමතිකමක් දෙනවට Black Cap Movement විරුද්ධ වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Black Cap Movement opposes giving Namal a ministry",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Black Cap Movement organization says that there is currently a rumor spreading in the political community that Parliament member Namal Rajapaksa has requested to be given a strong minister in the all-party or national government to be formed in the future and their organization is paying close attention to this.",
        "The Black Cap Movement, which was one of the organizations that participated in the Gallumuwadora struggle, says that the main goal of the people's struggle in the country against the tyranny of Rajapakse familyism was to create a new regime without Rajapakseism.",
        "\"The people did not expect the old Pohottu government to come back to the fore through the struggle. A country without the backwardness of Rajapaksaism. But we noticed that Namal Rajapaksa has recently pressured the Minister of Environment through two letters to appoint a high-ranking official of the Bureau of Geological Survey and Mines.",
        "Also, political sources mention that there are preparations to appoint Namal Rajapaksa MP as the National Organizer of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna. If the Rajapaksa cartel continues to trigger the people without any sensitivity to the people's opinion, the people will decide their political fate in the next election.",
        "But before that, we very seriously request all political groups not to allow the all-party government that is being formed to find solutions to the crisis in Sri Lanka to become Namalla's political gamble.",
        "The innocent people of the country are ultimately affected by the political games of the Namal Rajapaksa and we believe that it is the responsibility of all political activists to build the land that all the peaceful fighters who engaged in non-violent struggle hoped for.\" The organization further says in its announcement."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Black Cap Movement",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Black Cap Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Black Cap Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gallumuwadora",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bureau of Geological Survey",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Organizer of Sri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namalla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාමල්ට ඇමතිකමක් දෙනවට Black Cap Movement විරුද්ධ වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ, ඉදිරියේදි නිර්මාණය වීමට නියමිත සර්වපාක්ෂික හෝ ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවේ ප්‍රබල ඇමතිකමක් තමාට ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ඇති බවට දේශපාලන සමාජය තුළ මේ වනවිට රාවයක් පැතිරයමින් තිබෙන බවත් මේ පිලිබඳව තම සංවිධානයේ දැඩි අවධානය යොමුව ඇති බවත් Black Cap Movement සංවිධානය  පවසයි.",
        "ගාලුමුවදොර අරගලයට එක්ව සිටි සංවිධාන අතරින් එක් සංවිදායක් වූ මෙම Black Cap Movement සංවිධානය පවසන්නේ රාජපක්ෂ පවුල්වාදයේ අත්තනෝමතික භාවයට එරෙහිව රටේ පැනනැගෙනු ජන අරගලයේ ප්‍රධාන ඉලක්කය වූයේ රාජපක්ෂවාදයෙන් තොර නව පාලනතන්ත්‍රයක් නිර්මාණය කරගැනීමෙ බවයි.",
        "“අරගලයෙන් ජනතාව බලාපොරොත්තු වූයේ පැරණි පොහොට්ටු ආණ්ඩුවම නැවත සළුපිලි අන්දවා කරලියට ගැනීමට නොවේ. රාජපක්ෂවාදයේ පසුගාමීත්වයෙන් තොර රටකි. නමුත් නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ පසුගියදා භූවිද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණ හා පතල් කාර්යාංශයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීයෙකු පත් කිරීම සදහාද පරිසර අමාත්‍යවරයා වෙත ලිපි දෙකක් මාර්ගයෙන් බලපෑම් කර තිබෙනු අපට නිරීක්ෂණය විය.",
        "එමෙන්ම දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරන්නේ නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ශ්‍රීලංකා පොදුජන  පෙරමුණේ ජාතික සංවිධායකවරයා ලෙස පත්කිරීමට ද සූදානමක් ඇති බවකි. ජනතා මතය පිළිබඳව කිසිඳු සංවේදීත්වයක් නොමැතිව මෙලෙස ජනතාවට කොකා පෙන්වමින් කටයුතු කිරීමට රාජපක්ෂ කාටේලය කටයුතු කරයි  නම් ඔවුන්ගේ දේශපාලන ඉරණම  පිළිබඳව ඊළඟ මැතිවරණයේදී ජනතාව තීන්දු කරනු ඇත.",
        "එහෙත් ඊට ප්‍රථම ශ්‍රීලංකාවේ  අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා ගොඩනගන සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව ද නාමල්ලාගේ දේශපාලන සූදුවක් බවට පත්කිරීමට ඉඩ නොදෙන ලෙස සියලු දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් වෙතින් අප ඉතා බැරෑරුම්ව ඉල්ලා සිටිමු.",
        "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂලාගේ දේශපාලන ගේම් වලින් අවසානයේ පීඩාවට පත්වන්නේ රටේ අහිංසක ජනතාව වන අතර ඒ සඳහා ඉඩ නොතැබමින් අවිහිංසාවාදී අරගලයක නිරත වූ සියලුම සාමකාමී අරගලකරුවන් බලාපොරොත්තු වූ දේශය ගොඩනැගීම සියලු දේශපාලන ක්‍රියාකාරීන්ගේ උරමත පැටවී ඇති වගකීමක් බව අප විස්වාස කරමු.” යැයි එම සංවිධානය වැඩිදුරටත් සිය නිවේදනයෙන් පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කළු කැප් චලනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කළු කැප් ව්යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළු කැප් ව්යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ලුමුවදොර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භූ විද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණ කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සංවිධායක ශ්‍රී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாமலுக்கு அமைச்சு வழங்குவதற்கு கறுப்பு தொப்பி இயக்கம் எதிர்ப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் அமைக்கப்படவுள்ள சர்வகட்சி அல்லது தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தில் பலமான அமைச்சர் ஒருவரை வழங்குமாறு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாகவும், தமது அமைப்பு அதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை முன்னெடுத்து வருவதாகவும் அரசியல் சமூகத்தில் தற்போது வதந்தி பரவி வருவதாக கறுப்புத் தொப்பி இயக்கம் அமைப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இதில் கவனம்.",
        "ராஜபக்ஷ குடும்பவாதத்தின் கொடுங்கோன்மைக்கு எதிராக நாட்டில் நடைபெற்ற மக்கள் போராட்டத்தின் முக்கிய இலக்கு ராஜபக்ஷ இல்லாத புதிய ஆட்சியை உருவாக்குவதே என்று கல்லுமுவடோர போராட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்ட அமைப்புகளில் ஒன்றான கறுப்புத் தொப்பி இயக்கம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "“போராட்டத்தின் மூலம் பழைய பொஹொட்டு அரசாங்கம் மீண்டும் முன்னுக்கு வரும் என்று மக்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கவில்லை. ராஜபக்சவாதத்தின் பின்னடைவு இல்லாத நாடு. ஆனால் புவியியல் ஆய்வு மற்றும் சுரங்கப் பணியகத்தின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவரை நியமிக்குமாறு நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ அண்மையில் சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சருக்கு இரண்டு கடிதங்கள் மூலம் அழுத்தம் கொடுத்ததை அவதானித்தோம்.",
        "மேலும், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளராக நாமல் ராஜபக்ச எம்.பியை நியமிக்கவும் ஆயத்தங்கள் நடந்து வருவதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன. ராஜபக்சே கும்பல் மக்களின் கருத்தை உணராமல் மக்களைத் தூண்டிவிடுமானால், அடுத்த தேர்தலில் அவர்களின் அரசியல் தலைவிதியை மக்களே தீர்மானிப்பார்கள்.",
        "ஆனால் அதற்கு முன்னர் இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையில் உருவாகும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் நாமல்லாவின் அரசியல் சூதாட்டமாக மாற இடமளிக்க வேண்டாம் என அனைத்து அரசியல் குழுக்களிடமும் மிகத் தீவிரமாகக் கேட்டுக்கொள்கின்றோம்.",
        "நாமல் ராஜபக்சவின் அரசியல் விளையாட்டுக்களால் நாட்டின் அப்பாவி மக்கள் இறுதியில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், அகிம்சைப் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட அனைத்து அமைதிப் போராளிகளும் எதிர்பார்த்த மண்ணைக் கட்டியெழுப்புவது அனைத்து அரசியல் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களினதும் பொறுப்பு என நாங்கள் நம்புகின்றோம். அந்த அமைப்பு தனது அறிவிப்பில் மேலும் கூறியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கருப்பு தொப்பி இயக்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு தொப்பி இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு தொப்பி இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்லுமுவடோர",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவியியல் ஆய்வு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரங்கங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் ஸ்ரீ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நமல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}