{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/04/fuel-crisis-private-buses-limit-operations/",
  "time_ut": 1656909060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "FUEL CRISIS: Private Buses limit operations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "FUEL CRISIS: Private Buses limit operations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Lanka Private Bus Owners Association says that due to lack of fuel, it would be impossible to operate buses today (4).",
        "The Chairman of the Lanka Private Bus Owners Association Gemunu Wijeratne said that several buses are waiting in queues to obtain fuel.",
        "The Deputy General Manager of Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) Panduka Swarnahansa said that due to holidays, steps have been taken to deploy student buses for the transportation of passengers.",
        "Also, Sri Lanka Railways noted that trains will operate on Monday (4) as usual."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Private Buses",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panduka Swarnahansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය: පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ මෙහෙයුම් සීමා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් අද (4) බස් රථ ධාවනය කිරීමට නොහැකි වන බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා පැවසුවේ ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා බස් රථ කිහිපයක් පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටින බවයි.",
        "නිවාඩු දින හේතුවෙන් මගී ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා ශිෂ්‍ය බස් රථ යෙදවීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී පණ්ඩුක ස්වර්ණහංස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම, සඳුදා (4) දිනයේ ද සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි දුම්රිය ධාවනය කෙරෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පණ්ඩුක ස්වර්ණහංස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி: தனியார் பேருந்துகள் இயக்கங்களை கட்டுப்படுத்துகின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக இன்று (4) பஸ்களை இயக்க முடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொள்வதற்காக பல பஸ்கள் வரிசையில் காத்திருப்பதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "விடுமுறை காரணமாக மாணவர்களின் பேருந்துகளை பயணிகளின் போக்குவரத்திற்காக ஈடுபடுத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதி பொது முகாமையாளர் பண்டுக ஸ்வர்ணஹன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், திங்கட்கிழமை (4) வழமை போன்று ரயில் சேவைகள் இடம்பெறும் என இலங்கை ரயில்வே குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனியார் பேருந்துகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாண்டுக ஸ்வர்ணஹன்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}