{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/Diesel-shipment-due-mid-July-and-Petrol-by-July-22/155-240043",
  "time_ut": 1656501577,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Diesel shipment due mid July and Petrol by July 22",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Diesel shipment due mid July and Petrol by July 22",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister’s advisior Sagala Ratnayake today said that a Diesel shipment containing 30,000 metric tons was due between July 11-15 and a Petrol shipment from India is due by July 22 although the government is trying to source a Petrol shipment by July 10.",
        "Speaking at a media discussion at the Prime Minister’s Office he said only 11,000 MT of diesel, 30,000 MT of furnace oil, 800 MT of jet fuel and 5,000 MT of petrol are available at the CPC storages.",
        "He said that a Petrol shipment is expected to arrive by July 22 from India and no permanent order has been placed before that. However he said the CPC has strong connections with a network of suppliers around the world and they were trying to secure a shipment before that. He elaborated that there was a high demand for fuel in the international market and it was one reason for the delay in securing a new shipment.",
        "He said that 38,000 MT of diesel would be received between July 11 and 15.",
        "Therefore, the existing diesel stocks will only be available for essential services, until the new shipment reaches the country.",
        "There will be no issue with domestic gas supply by next month, as Litro Gas Lanka Ltd. will procure 100,000 MT of gas stock for the next four months. Another 33,000 MT of gas shipments will arrive in the country on July 6, 10, 16, 19, 21 and 31.",
        "He said that Domestic gas will be distributed on a priority basis and the first three days after receiving the shipment on July 6 will be for the delivery of LP gas to Colombo. Thereafter necessary distribution mechanisms have been put in place to deliver domestic gas around the country in an uninterrupted manner. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Diesel",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "mid July",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 22",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 11-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only 11,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between July 11 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "33,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 6, 10, 16, 19, 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම ජූලි මැද වන විට සහ පෙට්‍රල් ජූලි 22 වන විට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගමැති උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජුලි 10 වැනිදාට පෙර පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් ලබාගැනීමට රජය උත්සාහ කළද මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000ක් අඩංගු ඩීසල් තොගයක් ජූලි 11-15 අතර කාලයේදී ඉන්දියාවෙන් පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් ජූලි 22 වැනිදාට පැමිණීමට නියමිත බවයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ තෙල් සංස්ථාවේ ගබඩාවල ඇත්තේ ඩීසල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 11,000ක්, ගිනි උදුන මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000ක්, ජෙට් ඉන්ධන මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 800ක් සහ පෙට්‍රල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000ක් පමණක් බවයි.",
        "ජූලි 22 වැනිදා වන විට ඉන්දියාවෙන් පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් පැමිණීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත් ඊට පෙර ස්ථිර ඇණවුමක් කර නොමැති බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, CPC ලොව පුරා සැපයුම්කරුවන්ගේ ජාලයක් සමඟ ශක්තිමත් සම්බන්ධතා ඇති බවත්, ඊට පෙර භාණ්ඩ තොගයක් සුරක්ෂිත කිරීමට ඔවුන් උත්සාහ කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ ඉන්ධන සඳහා ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමක් පවතින බවත් එය නව තොගයක් සුරක්ෂිත කිරීම ප්‍රමාද වීමට එක් හේතුවක් බවත් ඔහු විස්තර කළේය.",
        "ජූලි 11 සිට 15 දක්වා කාලය තුළ ඩීසල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38,000ක් ලැබෙනු ඇතැයිද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එම නිසා දැනට පවතින ඩීසල් තොග අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පමණක් ලබා ගත හැකි අතර, නව තොගය දිවයිනට පැමිණෙන තෙක්.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගම ඉදිරි මාස හතර සඳහා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000 ක ගෑස් තොගයක් ලබා ගන්නා බැවින් ලබන මාසය වන විට ගෘහස්ථ ගෑස් සැපයුමේ කිසිදු ගැටලුවක් ඇති නොවේ. තවත් ගෑස් තොග මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 33,000ක් ජූලි 6, 10, 16, 19, 21 සහ 31 යන දිනවල දිවයිනට පැමිණේ.",
        "ගෘහස්ත ගෑස් ප්‍රමුඛතා පදනම මත බෙදා හරින බවත්, ජූලි 6 වැනිදා නැව්ගත කිරීමෙන් පසු පළමු දින තුන කොළඹට එල්පී ගෑස් බෙදා හැරීමට නියමිත බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. ඉන් අනතුරුව අඛණ්ඩව රට පුරා ගෘහස්ථ ගෑස් බෙදා හැරීමට අවශ්‍ය බෙදාහැරීමේ යාන්ත්‍රණයන් සකස් කර ඇත. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩීසල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි මැද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 22",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11-15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11,000 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "33,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 6, 10, 16, 19, 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමු දින තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில் டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் ஜூலை 22க்குள் பெட்ரோல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜூலை 11 முதல் 15 வரை 30,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் கொண்ட டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட உள்ளதாகவும், ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதிக்குள் பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியை பெற அரசாங்கம் முயற்சித்து வருவதாகவும், ஜூலை 22 ஆம் தேதிக்குள் இந்தியாவில் இருந்து பெற்றோல் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் பிரதமரின் ஆலோசகர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க இன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் பேசிய அவர், 11,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் டீசல், 30,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் ஃபர்னஸ் ஆயில், 800 மெட்ரிக் டன் ஜெட் எரிபொருள் மற்றும் 5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் பெட்ரோல் மட்டுமே சிபிசி சேமிப்புக் கிடங்குகளில் உள்ளன.",
        "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து ஜூலை 22 ஆம் தேதிக்குள் பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும், அதற்கு முன் நிரந்தர ஆர்டர் எதுவும் செய்யப்படவில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். இருப்பினும், உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள சப்ளையர்களின் வலையமைப்புடன் CPC வலுவான தொடர்புகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, அதற்கு முன்னர் அவர்கள் ஒரு கப்பலைப் பாதுகாக்க முயற்சிப்பதாக அவர் கூறினார். சர்வதேச சந்தையில் எரிபொருளுக்கான தேவை அதிகமாக இருப்பதாகவும், புதிய ஏற்றுமதியைப் பாதுகாப்பதில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டதற்கு இது ஒரு காரணம் என்றும் அவர் விரிவாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 11 முதல் 15 வரை 38,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் டீசல் பெறப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "எனவே, புதிய ஏற்றுமதி நாட்டிற்கு வரும் வரை, தற்போதுள்ள டீசல் கையிருப்பு அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு மட்டுமே கிடைக்கும்.",
        "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட் அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கு 100,000 MT எரிவாயு இருப்புக்களை கொள்வனவு செய்யும் என்பதால், அடுத்த மாதத்திற்குள் உள்நாட்டு எரிவாயு விநியோகத்தில் எந்தப் பிரச்சினையும் இருக்காது. ஜூலை 6, 10, 16, 19, 21 மற்றும் 31 ஆகிய தேதிகளில் மேலும் 33,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயு ஏற்றுமதி நாட்டிற்கு வரும்.",
        "உள்நாட்டு எரிவாயு முன்னுரிமை அடிப்படையில் விநியோகிக்கப்படும் என்றும், ஜூலை 6 ஆம் திகதி ஏற்றுமதி பெறப்பட்ட முதல் மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு எல்பி எரிவாயு கொழும்புக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். அதன்பிறகு, நாடு முழுவதும் உள்நாட்டு எரிவாயுவை தடையின்றி விநியோகிக்க தேவையான விநியோக வழிமுறைகள் ஏற்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டீசல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 22",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11-15 இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11,000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "33,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 6, 10, 16, 19, 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதல் மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}