{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඉන්ධන-පෝලිමේ-කුලියට-සිටි-දෙදරු-පියා-අනතුරින්-මරුට/1-615581",
  "time_ut": 1656480315,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ කුලියට සිටි දෙදරු පියා අනතුරින් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Father of two killed in fuel queue accident",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Aluthgama Police say that a person who was queuing on a hire basis to get diesel for an IOC Fuel Hall lorry in Dharga Town has collided with a tipper truck while crossing the main road in front of the petrol station and died, Aluthgama Police said.",
        "The driver who was allegedly involved in the accident had also been returning to Dharga Town from Aluthgama after having dinner at the fuel queue in Dharga Town."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC Fuel Hall",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharga Town",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharga Town",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharga",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ කුලියට සිටි දෙදරු පියා අනතුරින් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දර්ගා නගරයේ අයි.ඕ.සී ඉන්ධන හලේන් ලොරි රථයකට ඩීසල් ලබා ගැනීමට කුලී පදනම මත පෝලිමේ සිටි පුද්ගලයකු ඉන්ධනහල ඉදිරිපිට ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගය හරහා පාරමාරු වීමට යාමේදී ටිපර් රථයක ගැටී මියගොස් ඇතැයි අලූත්ගම පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "අනතුර සිදු කළ බව කියන සැකකාර රියදුරා ද දර්ගා නගරයේ ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ සිට රාත්‍රී ආහාර ගැනීමට අලුත්ගම නගරයට ගොස් නැවත ධර්ගා නගරය දෙසට පැමිණීමේදී මෙම අනතුර සිදුව තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC ඉන්ධන ශාලාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා නගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා නගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் வரிசை விபத்தில் இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தை பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தர்கா நகரில் ஐ.ஓ.சி எரிபொருள் மண்டப லொறிக்கு டீசல் பெறுவதற்காக வாடகை அடிப்படையில் வரிசையில் நின்ற ஒருவர் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு முன்பாக பிரதான வீதியைக் கடக்கும்போது டிப்பர் வாகனத்துடன் மோதி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக அளுத்கம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "விபத்துக்குள்ளானதாகக் கூறப்படும் சாரதியும் தர்கா நகரில் எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் இரவு உணவு உண்டுவிட்டு அளுத்கமவில் இருந்து தர்கா நகருக்குத் திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி எரிபொருள் கூடம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்கா நகரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்கா நகரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}