{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/CPC-expects-to-commence-refinery-operations-this-week-Minister/342-243239",
  "time_ut": 1660735456,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CPC expects to commence refinery operations this week: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CPC expects to commence refinery operations this week: Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) is hoping to commence refinery operations this week, Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said.",
        "Addressing a meeting at the Ministry, he said the refinery operations would be able to continue without any interruptions with the continuous supply of crude oil.",
        "The CPC Commercial Management and Refinery officials met the Minister this morning to discuss the oil tanker freight plans for September to December, including the refinery operations.",
        "Earlier, the Minister said while addressing in parliament that plans are underway to resume operations of the Sapugaskanda oil refinery last Monday (15) upon the anticipated arrival of a crude oil shipment on August 13. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "this week",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Refinery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "September to December",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sapugaskanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තෙල් සංස්ථාව මේ සතියේ පිරිපහදු මෙහෙයුම් ආරම්භ කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ: ඇමති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) පිරිපහදු මෙහෙයුම් මේ සතියේ ආරම්භ කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පැවති රැස්වීමක් අමතමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ අඛණ්ඩව බොරතෙල් සැපයීමත් සමඟ පිරිපහදු මෙහෙයුම් බාධාවකින් තොරව අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට හැකිවනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ වාණිජ කළමනාකරණ සහ පිරිපහදු නිලධාරීන් අද පෙරවරුවේ අමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවී පිරිපහදු මෙහෙයුම් ඇතුළුව සැප්තැම්බර් සිට දෙසැම්බර් දක්වා තෙල් නැව් භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන සැලසුම් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "සපුගස්කන්ද තෙල් පිරිපහදුව පසුගිය සඳුදා (15) අගෝස්තු 13 වැනිදා බොරතෙල් තොගයක් පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂාවෙන් එහි කටයුතු යළි ආරම්භ කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයා මීට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙම සතිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිරිපහදුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් සිට දෙසැම්බර් දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සපුගස්කන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த வாரம் சுத்திகரிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை தொடங்க CPC எதிர்பார்க்கிறது: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) இந்த வாரத்தில் சுத்திகரிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை ஆரம்பிக்க எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அமைச்சகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு பேசிய அவர், கச்சா எண்ணெய் தொடர்ந்து வழங்கப்படுவதால் சுத்திகரிப்பு பணிகள் எந்த தடங்கலும் இல்லாமல் தொடர முடியும் என்றார்.",
        "சுத்திகரிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகள் உட்பட செப்டம்பர் முதல் டிசம்பர் வரையிலான எண்ணெய் டேங்கர் சரக்கு திட்டங்கள் குறித்து விவாதிக்க CPC வணிக மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சுத்திகரிப்பு அதிகாரிகள் இன்று காலை அமைச்சரை சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "முன்னதாக, சபுகஸ்கந்த எண்ணெய் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையத்தின் செயற்பாடுகளை ஆகஸ்ட் 13 ஆம் திகதி எதிர்பார்க்கும் கச்சா எண்ணெய் ஏற்றுமதியை அடுத்து, கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை (15) மீண்டும் செயற்படத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உரையாற்றும் போதே தெரிவித்தார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் முதல் டிசம்பர் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சபுகஸ்கந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}