{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පොහොර-නැවත්-ප්‍රමාදයි/11-395137",
  "time_ut": 1657021977,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොර නැවත් ප්‍රමාදයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fertilizer stops late",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Agriculture and Wildlife Minister Mahinda Amaraweera says that the fertilizer ship that was supposed to arrive will also be delayed.",
        "The minister mentioned that the ship bringing 40,000 metric tons of fertilizer from Oman through the Government of India was scheduled to reach Sri Lanka today (5th), but due to the rough sea conditions, the arrival of the ship will be delayed until the 9th.",
        "The minister said this at the press conference to announce the cabinet decisions held at the Government Information Department."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොර නැවත් ප්‍රමාදයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ පොහොර නෞකාව ද ප්‍රමාද වනු ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම හා වනජීවී අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය රජය හරහා ඕමානයේ සිට පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක් ගෙන එන නෞකාව අද (5දා)  මෙරටට ළඟාවීමට නියමිතව තිබුණත් මුහුදේ පවතින රළු තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් නෞකාව පැමිණීම ලබන 9දා දක්වා කල් යනු ඇතැයි ඇමතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඇමතිවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දී පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உரம் தாமதமாக நிறுத்தப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வரவிருந்த உரக் கப்பலும் தாமதமாகும் என விவசாய மற்றும் வனஜீவராசிகள் அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஓமானில் இருந்து இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் ஊடாக 40,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் உரங்களைக் கொண்டு வரும் கப்பல் இன்று (5ஆம் திகதி) இலங்கையை வந்தடையத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டிருந்த போதிலும், கடல் சீற்றம் காரணமாக எதிர்வரும் 9ஆம் திகதி வரை கப்பலின் வருகை தாமதமாகும் எனவும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் அமைச்சர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}