{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/cabinet-nod-to-resume-jaffna-airport-operations/",
  "time_ut": 1656401220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cabinet nod to resume Jaffna Airport operations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cabinet nod to resume Jaffna Airport operations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Cabinet HAS granted approval for the resumption of international operations at the Jaffna International Airport with effect from 01st July 2022.",
        "Although International operations at the international airport of Jaffna were inaugurated on the 11th of November 2019 ensuring the fundamental international monitoring requirements, its operational activities were suspended from 15th March 2020 due to the COVID – 19 pandemic circumstances prevailed during that period.",
        "The internationally and locally based aeronautical companies have submitted requests now for the operation of rented air tours as well as time-framed aeronautical flights from that Airport to South Indian destinations, said a statement from the Department Government Information.",
        "Accordingly, the Cabinet of Ministers decided to grant their approval to the measures taken by the Minister of Ports, Naval, and Aviation Services concerning the resumption of international operational activities of Jaffna International Airport once again with effect from 01st July 2022.",
        "#Rambukkana Shooting: Human Rights Comm. wants action against SSP Keerthiratne"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jaffna Airport",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "01st July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 11th of November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th March 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department Government Information",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports, Naval",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "01st July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාපනය ගුවන් තොටුපළේ මෙහෙයුම් යළි ආරම්භ කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ජූලි 01 දින සිට යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මෙහෙයුම් නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "මූලික ජාත්‍යන්තර නිරීක්ෂණ අවශ්‍යතා සහතික කරමින් යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මෙහෙයුම් 2019 නොවැම්බර් 11 වන දින ආරම්භ කළද, එම කාලය තුළ පැවති COVID - 19 වසංගත තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් එහි මෙහෙයුම් කටයුතු 2020 මාර්තු 15 දින සිට අත්හිටුවන ලදී.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර සහ දේශීය වශයෙන් පදනම් වූ ගුවන් සමාගම් විසින් කුලියට ගත් ගුවන් සංචාර මෙන්ම එම ගුවන් තොටුපළේ සිට දකුණු ඉන්දීය ගමනාන්ත දක්වා කාල රාමුගත ගුවන් ගමන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා දැන් ඉල්ලීම් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව, යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මෙහෙයුම් කටයුතු නැවත වරක් 2022 ජූලි 01 දින සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වරාය, නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍යවරයා ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගවලට අනුමැතිය ලබාදීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කළේය.",
        "#රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම: මානව හිමිකම් කොම. ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්නට එරෙහිව පියවර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍යයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යාපනය ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර් 11 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 මාර්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව රජයේ තොරතුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය, නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் விமான நிலைய செயற்பாடுகளை மீள ஆரம்பிக்க அமைச்சரவை அனுமதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஜூலை 01 ஆம் திகதி முதல் யாழ்ப்பாண சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் சர்வதேச நடவடிக்கைகளை மீள ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "அடிப்படை சர்வதேச கண்காணிப்பு தேவைகளை உறுதி செய்யும் வகையில் 2019 நவம்பர் 11 ஆம் திகதி யாழ்ப்பாண சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் சர்வதேச நடவடிக்கைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும், அந்த காலப்பகுதியில் நிலவிய கோவிட் - 19 தொற்றுநோய் சூழ்நிலை காரணமாக அதன் செயற்பாடுகள் 2020 மார்ச் 15 ஆம் திகதி முதல் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "சர்வதேச மற்றும் உள்நாட்டில் இயங்கும் ஏரோநாட்டிகல் நிறுவனங்கள், வாடகை விமானப் பயணங்கள் மற்றும் அந்த விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து தென்னிந்திய இடங்களுக்கு நேரக் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்ட வானூர்தி விமானங்களை இயக்குவதற்கான கோரிக்கைகளை இப்போது சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளன என்று திணைக்கள அரசாங்கத் தகவல் திணைக்களத்தின் அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, 2022 ஜூலை 01 ஆம் திகதி முதல் மீண்டும் யாழ்ப்பாண சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் சர்வதேச செயற்பாடுகளை மீள ஆரம்பிப்பது தொடர்பில் துறைமுகங்கள், கடற்படை மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் அமைச்சரினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு தமது அங்கீகாரத்தை வழங்குவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "#ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கி சூடு: மனித உரிமைகள் கம்யூ. எஸ்எஸ்பி கீர்த்திரத்ன மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் விமான நிலையம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 11, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 மார்ச் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்னிந்தியா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை அரசாங்க தகவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள், கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}