{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SJB-ready-to-appoint-Ranjan-to-Parliamemnt-if-vacancy-exists-in-National-List-Sajith/342-243785",
  "time_ut": 1661503827,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB ready to appoint Ranjan to Parliamemnt if vacancy exists in National List: Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB ready to appoint Ranjan to Parliamemnt if vacancy exists in National List: Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya is ready to appoint former MP Ranjan Ramanayake to Parliament in the first instance of a vacancy falls in the national list, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa said.",
        "He said in a twitter post that \"We the Samagi Jana Balawegaya wholeheartedly pledge to appoint Ranjan Ramanayake to the parliament in the first instance of an occurrence of a vacancy in the national list\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan to",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliamemnt",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "National List: Sajith",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "We the Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇත්නම් රන්ජන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත්කිරීමට SJB සූදානම්: සජිත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයක් පළමු අවස්ථාවේදීම හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය සූදානම් බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු ට්විටර් සටහනක් තබමින් කියා සිටියේ \"ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇති වූ පළමු අවස්ථාවේදීම රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය අපි මුළු හදින්ම ප්‍රතිඥා දෙන බවයි\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan to",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව: සජිත්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපි සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசியப்பட்டியலில் வெற்றிடம் ஏற்பட்டால் ரஞ்சனை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமிக்க SJB தயார்: சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசியப்பட்டியலில் ஏற்பட்ட வெற்றிடமொன்றுக்கு முதற்கட்டமாக முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தயாராகவுள்ளதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் தனது டுவிட்டர் பதிவில், “தேசியப் பட்டியலில் வெற்றிடமொன்று ஏற்பட்டால் முதல் தடவையாக ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகய நாங்கள் முழு மனதுடன் உறுதியளிக்கிறோம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan to",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்: சஜித்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாங்கள் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}