{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/24/slpp-to-make-key-changes-to-posts-at-convention/",
  "time_ut": 1661327580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP to make key changes to posts at convention",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP to make key changes to posts at convention",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); General Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) Attorney-at-Law Sagara Kariyawasam says there will be a change in the party positions.",
        "General Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) Attorney-at-Law Sagara Kariyawasam said that these changes will be made at the SLPP National Convention scheduled for next month.",
        "Kariyawasam says certain party members who are currently holding key positions in the party, and who went against the political decisions taken by the SLPP in the recent past, will be removed.",
        "Recently, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna decided to support Ranil Wickremesinghe, as a party in the election to appoint the succeeding president.",
        "However, party chairman Professor G. L. Peiris, Treasurer Dullas Alahapperuma, and others were of different positions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasurer Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සමුළුවේදී තනතුරුවල ප්‍රධාන වෙනස්කම් සිදුකිරීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) පක්ෂයේ තනතුරුවල වෙනසක් සිදුවන බව එම පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසුවේ ලබන මස පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික මහා සම්මේලනයේදී මෙම වෙනස්කම් සිදු කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පසුගිය කාලයේ ගත් දේශපාලන තීන්දුවලට පටහැනිව කටයුතු කළ දැනට පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන තනතුරු දරන ඇතැම් පාක්ෂිකයන් ඉවත් කරන බව කාරියවසම් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පසුගිය දා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත්කිරීමේ මැතිවරණයේදී පක්ෂයක් ලෙස සහාය දැක්වීමට තීරණය කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පක්ෂයේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස්, භාණ්ඩාගාරික ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ඇතුළු පිරිස විවිධ තනතුරු දැරූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාරික ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாநாட்டில் பதவிகளில் முக்கிய மாற்றங்களைச் செய்ய SLPP",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பதவிகளில் மாற்றம் ஏற்படவுள்ளதாக கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அடுத்த மாதம் நடைபெறவுள்ள SLPP தேசிய மாநாட்டில் இந்த மாற்றங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியினால் அண்மைக்காலமாக எடுக்கப்பட்ட அரசியல் தீர்மானங்களுக்கு எதிராக செயற்பட்ட மற்றும் தற்போது கட்சியின் முக்கிய பதவிகளை வகிக்கும் சில கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் நீக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அண்மையில், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளித்து, ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்கான தேர்தலில் ஒரு கட்சியாகத் தீர்மானித்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், கட்சியின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ், பொருளாளர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் பலர் வெவ்வேறு நிலைப்பாட்டில் இருந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாளர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}