{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/හොරකම්-කරලා-හදපු-ගෙවල්-ගිනි-තැබීම-සාධාරණයි/1-615859",
  "time_ut": 1656938460,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හොරකම් කරලා හදපු ගෙවල් ගිනි තැබීම සාධාරණයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It is reasonable to set fire to stolen houses",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Chaminda Wijesiri, member of Samagi Jana Balawega, Badulla district, said in Parliament that it is reasonable to burn the houses built by stealing money.",
        "Mr. Wijesiri, who said that theft has not disappeared, said that all 225 are being branded because they are protecting those who have stolen and if there has been theft, there is no problem in burning down Chaminda's house.",
        "The Minister of Urban Development and Housing Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga said that if it is fair to say that it is fair to burn the houses of those who stole, not even a single person will be allowed to live there."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Wijesiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හොරකම් කරලා හදපු ගෙවල් ගිනි තැබීම සාධාරණයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුදල්  හොරකම් කරලා හදපු ගෙවල් ගිනි තැබීම සාධාරණ බව බදුල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික් සමගි ජන බලවේග මන්ත්‍රී චමින්ද විජේසිරි මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී  පැවසීය.",
        "තාමත් හොරකම නැති වී නැතැයි කී විජේසිරි මහතා  225 ටම හංවඩුව වැටෙන්නේ හොරා කාපු අය ආරක්ෂා කරන නිසා යැයිද හොරා කාලා තිබෙනවා නම් චමින්දගේ ගේත් ගිනි තිබ්බට කමක් නැතැයි ද කීය.",
        "නාගරික  සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා පැවැසූයේ හොරකම් කරපු  අයගේ ගෙවල් ගිනි තියපු එක සාධාරණයි කියනවා නම් ඒ පැත්තේ එක්කෙනෙකුට වත් ඉන්න ලැබෙන්නේ නැති බවයි.ඔවුන් ගේ ළඟ තිබෙන්නේ මහ බැංකුවෙන් හොරකම් කළ  සල්ලි බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද විජේසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திருடப்பட்ட வீடுகளுக்கு தீ வைப்பது நியாயமானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பணத்தை திருடி கட்டிய வீடுகளை எரிப்பது நியாயமானது என பதுளை மாவட்ட சமகி ஜன பலவேக உறுப்பினர் திரு.சமிந்த விஜேசிறி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திருட்டு ஒழியவில்லை என்று கூறிய திரு.விஜேசிறி, திருடியவர்களை பாதுகாப்பதால்தான் 225 பேரும் முத்திரை குத்தப்படுவதாகவும், திருட்டு நடந்திருந்தால் சமிந்தவின் வீட்டை எரிப்பதில் பிரச்சினை இல்லை என்றும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திருடியவர்களின் வீடுகளை எரிப்பது நியாயம் என்று கூறுவது நியாயமானால் ஒருவரைக் கூட அங்கு வாழ விடமாட்டோம் என நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த விஜேசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}