{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83618/pm-ranil-wickremesinghe-appointed-as-acting-president",
  "time_ut": 1657699020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PM Ranil Wickremesinghe appointed as Acting President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PM Ranil Wickremesinghe appointed as Acting President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has informed the Speaker of Parliament that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has been appointed as the Acting President of Sri Lanka.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena announced this in a brief statement made to the media today (13).",
        "“I was informed that under article 37 (1) of the Constitution, as His Excellency the President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is away from the country, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has been appointed to cover the duties and function of that position,” he said.",
        "Earlier today, the PM’s Office said that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, as the Acting President, has ordered to impose curfew in the Western Province with immediate effect and to impose emergency law island-wide.",
        "Wickremesinghe has also ordered the security forces to arrest those engaging in unruly behaviour and to take into custody the vehicles they travel in, the PM’s Office said.",
        "The move came as thousands of angry protesters gathered outside the PM’s office, and several other locations in Colombo this morning.",
        "“Since the president is out of the country, an emergency has been declared to deal with the situation in the country,” Dinouk Colombage, spokesman for Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, told AFP.",
        "Thousands of demonstrators had mobbed the premier’s office, prompting police to fire tear gas to hold them back from overrunning the compound.",
        "“There are ongoing protests outside the prime minister’s office in Colombo and we need the curfew to contain the situation,” a senior police officer told AFP.",
        "Asked how Mr. Wickremesinghe could invoke “powers of an acting President” when Mr. Gotabaya is still in office, PM’s spokesman Dinouk Colombage had told The Hindu: “The legal explanation will follow. We want to get the situation under control first.”",
        "Earlier on Wednesday, the Sri Lankan Air Force said that under the provisions of the Constitution and on a request by the government it provided a plane to fly the president, his wife and two security officials to the Maldives.",
        "“On government request and in terms of powers available to a President under the Constitution, with complete approval from the ministry of defence, the President, his wife and two security officials were provided a Sri Lanka Air Force plane to depart from the Katunayake international airport for the Maldives in the early hours of July 13,” an official announced.",
        "On Saturday, Rajapaksa announced that he would resign on July 13 after thousands of protestors stormed his official residence and office."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PM Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "article 37",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinouk Colombage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinouk Colombage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ministry of defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake international airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early hours of July 13",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13 after thousands",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කළ බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයාට දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "අද (13) මාධ්‍ය වෙත කෙටි ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 37 (1) වගන්තිය යටතේ, අතිගරු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් බැහැරව සිටින බැවින්, එම තනතුරේ රාජකාරි සහ කාර්ය භාරය ආවරණය කිරීම සඳහා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කර ඇති බව මට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි බස්නාහිර පළාතට ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීමටත් දිවයින පුරා හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීමටත් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නියෝග කර ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය අද පෙරවරු ‍වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "නොසන්සුන්කාරී ලෙස හැසිරීමේ යෙදෙන්නන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙසත් ඔවුන් ගමන් ගන්නා වාහන අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙසත් වික්‍රමසිංහ ආරක්ෂක අංශවලට නියෝග කර ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "කෝපාවිෂ්ට විරෝධතාකරුවන් දහස් ගණනක් අද උදෑසන අගමැති කාර්යාලය සහ කොළඹ තවත් ස්ථාන කිහිපයක රැස්ව සිටීමත් සමඟ මෙම පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "\"ජනාධිපතිවරයා රටින් බැහැරව සිටින බැවින් රටේ උද්ගතව ඇති තත්ත්වයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා හදිසි අවස්ථාවක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර තිබේ\" යැයි අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ ප්‍රකාශක දිනූක් කොළඹගේ AFP වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "දහස් ගනනක් පෙලපාලිකරුවන් අගමැති කාර්යාලයට රොක් වී සිටි අතර, පොලීසිය විසින් කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කරමින් ඔවුන්ව පරිශ්‍රය ඉක්මවා යාම වැළැක්වීමට පෙලඹී ඇත.",
        "“කොළඹ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයෙන් පිටත අඛණ්ඩ විරෝධතා පවතින අතර තත්වය පාලනය කිරීමට අපට ඇඳිරි නීතිය අවශ්‍යයි,” ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙක් AFP වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය මහතා තවමත් ධූරයේ සිටින විට වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා \"වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුගේ බලතල\" ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ කෙසේදැයි විමසූ විට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක දිනූක් කොළඹගේ ද හින්දු පුවත්පතට පවසා තිබුණේ, “නීතිමය පැහැදිලි කිරීම අනුගමනය කරනු ඇත. අපට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ පළමුව තත්ත්වය පාලනය කර ගැනීමටයි.”",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධාන යටතේ සහ රජයේ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනකු මාලදිවයිනට පියාසර කිරීමට ගුවන් යානයක් ලබාදුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව බදාදා මුලදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“රජයේ ඉල්ලීම මත සහ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට ඇති බලතල අනුව, ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පූර්ණ අනුමැතිය ඇතිව, ජනාධිපතිවරයා, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනෙකුට කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට අයත් ගුවන් යානයක් ලබා දෙන ලදී. මාලදිවයින සඳහා ජූලි 13 උදේ පාන්දර,” නිලධාරියෙක් නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "සිය නිල නිවසට සහ කාර්යාලයට දහස් ගණන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසුව, ජූලි 13 දා තමා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව රාජපක්ෂ සෙනසුරාදා නිවේදනය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනූක් කොළඹගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනූක් කොළඹගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස් ගණනකට පසු ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் பதில் அதிபராக பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகருக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன இன்று (13) ஊடகங்களுக்கு வழங்கிய சுருக்கமான அறிக்கையிலேயே இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“அரசியலமைப்பின் 37 (1) வது பிரிவின் கீழ், அதிமேதகு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அவர்கள் நாட்டிலிருந்து விலகி இருப்பதால், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அந்த பதவியின் கடமைகள் மற்றும் செயல்பாடுகளை உள்ளடக்கியதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார் என்று எனக்குத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் உடனடியாக அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவதற்கும் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவதற்கும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி என்ற வகையில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் இன்று முற்பகல் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கட்டுக்கடங்காத நடத்தையில் ஈடுபடுபவர்களை கைது செய்யவும், அவர்கள் பயணிக்கும் வாகனங்களை காவலில் எடுக்கவும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினருக்கு விக்ரமசிங்க உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்று காலை கொழும்பில் பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் மற்றும் பல இடங்களில் கோபமடைந்த ஆயிரக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் திரண்டதால் இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டிற்கு வெளியே இருப்பதால், நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நிலைமையை சமாளிக்க அவசரநிலை பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது” என பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பேச்சாளர் டினூக் கொலம்பகே AFP இடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பிரதமரின் அலுவலகத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டனர், பொலிசார் கண்ணீர்ப்புகைக் குண்டுகளை வீசத் தூண்டியது, அவர்களை வளாகத்தை மீறிச் செல்வதைத் தடுக்கிறது.",
        "\"கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு வெளியே தொடர்ந்து போராட்டங்கள் நடைபெற்று வருகின்றன, நிலைமையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த எங்களுக்கு ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் தேவை\" என்று மூத்த காவல்துறை அதிகாரி ஒருவர் AFP இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "திரு. கோட்டாபய இன்னும் பதவியில் இருக்கும் போது, ​​திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க எவ்வாறு \"செயல்திறன் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களை\" கோர முடியும் என்று கேட்டதற்கு, பிரதமரின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் டினூக் கொலம்பகே தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார்: \"சட்ட விளக்கம் தொடர்ந்து வரும். முதலில் நிலைமையை கட்டுக்குள் கொண்டு வர விரும்புகிறோம்.",
        "முன்னதாக புதன்கிழமை, இலங்கை விமானப்படை அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளின் கீழ் மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தின் கோரிக்கையின் பேரில் ஜனாதிபதி, அவரது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளை மாலைதீவுக்கு பறக்க விமானம் வழங்கியதாக கூறியது.",
        "“அரசாங்கத்தின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கிணங்க, அரசியலமைப்பின் கீழ் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு இருக்கும் அதிகாரங்களின் அடிப்படையில், பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் பூரண அனுமதியுடன், ஜனாதிபதி, அவரது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து புறப்படுவதற்கு இலங்கை விமானப்படை விமானம் வழங்கப்பட்டது. ஜூலை 13 அதிகாலையில் மாலத்தீவுக்கு,” என்று ஒரு அதிகாரி அறிவித்தார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று, ராஜபக்சே தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் மற்றும் அலுவலகத்தை ஆயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து, ஜூலை 13 அன்று ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அறிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 37",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டினூக் கொலம்பகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டினூக் கொலம்பகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான பிறகு ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}