{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79252",
  "time_ut": 1661713020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan Airlines Group  to be restructured  by inviting foreign operators to take up 49% equity stake and management;Govt Unable to fund Loss making National Carrier any longer",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Airlines Group  to be restructured  by inviting foreign operators to take up 49% equity stake and management;Govt Unable to fund Loss making National Carrier any longer",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Saddled with nearly half a trillion rupee accumulated losses and $ 1 billion in debt and dues, SriLankan Airlines Group is to be restructured inviting foreign operators to take up 49% equity stake and management to ensure the national carrier no longer becomes a burden on the public.",
        "Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva yesterday revealed the way forward for Sri Lanka’s flag carrier which he will propose to the Cabinet of Ministers for final approval. The rationale for critical restructuring and the process were shared with trade unions, industry stakeholders and media.",
        "Minister de Silva said given the country’s financial, forex and economic crisis, the Government can no longer fund the national carrier which for the past 10 years had made a collective loss of Rs. 435 billion. Latest FY22 saw the worst performance with Rs. 165 billion loss, largely due to 40% depreciation of the rupee whilst in the past 2019 Easter Sunday and COVID pandemic impacted its performance.",
        "SriLankan also owes $ 1 billion in foreign and domestic debt and dues. When Emirates Airlines managed and part-owned SriLankan from 1998 to 2008 the national carrier made a Rs. 22 million profit.",
        "“The only way to rescue the national carrier is via urgent restructuring. We are proposing the best route arrived at after consultation with officials of the Ministry, the Board of Directors of SriLankan Airlines, officials of the Civil Aviation Authority and industry experts,” de Silva told journalists at a briefing along with SriLankan Airlines Chairman Ashok Pathirage, Ministry Secretary Ruwan Chandra and officials.",
        "The staggering $ 1 billion debt and dues comprises $ 175 million Government guaranteed international bond, $ 380 million payable to the State banks BOC and People’s Bank, and $ 80 million loan taken from BOC by mortgaging shares of SriLankan Catering.",
        "Among liabilities are $ 325 million due in arrears to Ceylon Petroleum Corporation ($ 312 million), Airport and Aviation Services Ltd., and Civil Aviation Authority and $ 80 million in arrears for aircraft leases. National carrier doesn’t own a single aircraft and the fleet of 26 is on lease.",
        "Minister de Silva said funds realised from the 49% equity stake sales would be used to retire debt and settle dues. He said that SriLankan Airlines Group requires new capital infusion and this could be done only via restructuring.",
        "It was pointed out that the need for restructuring and part divestment of State-owned stakes wasn’t unique to SriLankan Airlines only but referred to the privatisation of Air India. “The Government cannot write off debt or absorb losses,” added SriLankan Chairman Pathirage.",
        "The Minister also said following the Cabinet approval Expressions of Interest (EOIs) will be sought from global operators and the exercise is also expected to bring in much needed foreign investment to Sri Lanka.",
        "“It will be a very transparent process and we will not compromise transparency for urgency,” Minister de Silva emphasised.",
        "Chairman Pathirage said that restructuring entity by entity or step by step was the best practical course and said catering business will be tackled first followed by ground handling, both of which are profitable. “The sooner we complete the restructure the better it is for the national carrier,” he added.",
        "Though justifying restructuring largely owing legacy debt and other issues, Pathirage said that between December 2021 and March 2022 the national carrier made a net profit. Last month SriLankan Airlines achieved a turnover of $ 90 million and reported a small loss of $ 1.5 million having to source jet fuel from overseas. “In August we are likely to make a profit,” he added.",
        "In the January-March 2022 quarter the airline recorded a Group Operating Profit in dollar terms for the first time after six years. It was also the first fourth quarter profit (in dollar terms) since 2006.",
        "Pathirage acknowledged that despite legacy issues, SriLankan offers great value being the largest foreign operator to India, the strategic location of Colombo for transit traffic, the landing rights, strong brand and goodwill among other factors. Sri Lankan Airlines presently serves 37 destinations in 23 countries being the only Asian airline which operates direct routes to Australia, France, Germany, Japan, South Korea and the UK from Sri Lanka.",
        "Minister de Silva said that retention of the existing staff is mandatory on the part of new owners cum managers unless a Voluntary Retirement Scheme (VRS) is offered to those interested. He said that unions were supportive of the restructuring process and made several recommendations which will be considered.",
        "Pathirage also denied the misconception that SriLankan which has 6400 employees is overstaffed and they are overpaid. He said that due to the pandemic and the resultant impact the airline lost many employees and like the global industry, is in need of additional staff in select functions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines Group",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "49%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Loss",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Carrier",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "nearly half a trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 10 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "165 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998 to 2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry, the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Civil Aviation Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashok Pathirage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwan Chandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 175 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 380 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 80 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Catering",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 325 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 312 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Civil Aviation Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 80 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathirage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pathirage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between December 2021 and March 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 90 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.5 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "January-March 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first fourth quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VRS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් සමූහය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා විදේශීය ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ට 49% කොටස් කොටස් සහ කළමනාකරණය ලබා ගැනීමට ආරාධනා කිරීම; පාඩු ලබන ජාතික ගුවන් සේවයට තවදුරටත් අරමුදල් සැපයීමට රජයට නොහැකිය",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් ටි‍්‍රලියන භාගයකට ආසන්න සමුච්චිත පාඩු සහ ඩොලර් බිලියන 1ක ණය සහ හිඟ මුදල්වලින් මිරිකී සිටින ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම, ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය තවදුරටත් මහජනතාවට බරක් නොවන බව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා විදේශීය මෙහෙයුම්කරුවන්ට 49% කොටස් කොටස් සහ කළමනාකාරිත්වය ලබා ගැනීමට ආරාධනා කරමින් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට නියමිතය. .",
        "වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන්සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධජ ප්‍රවාහකයාගේ ඉදිරි මාවත ඊයේ හෙළිදරව් කළ අතර එය අවසන් අනුමැතිය සඳහා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට යෝජනා කිරීමට නියමිතය. විවේචනාත්මක ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සහ ක්‍රියාවලිය සඳහා වන තාර්කිකත්වය වෘත්තීය සමිති, කර්මාන්ත පාර්ශවකරුවන් සහ මාධ්‍ය සමඟ බෙදා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "රටේ මූල්‍ය, විදේශ විනිමය සහ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ පසුගිය වසර 10ක කාලය තුළ රුපියල් මිලියන 10 ක සාමූහික පාඩුවක් සිදු කළ ජාතික ගුවන් සේවයට තවදුරටත් අරමුදල් සැපයීමට රජයට නොහැකි බව අමාත්‍ය ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය. බිලියන 435 කි. නවතම FY22 නරකම කාර්ය සාධනය දුටුවේ රු. බිලියන 165 ක පාඩුවක්, බොහෝ දුරට රුපියල 40% කින් අවප්‍රමාණය වීම හේතුවෙන් පසුගිය 2019 පාස්කු ඉරිදා සහ COVID වසංගතය එහි ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වයට බලපෑවේය.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් සමාගම ඩොලර් බිලියනයක විදේශීය හා දේශීය ණය සහ ගෙවිය යුතු ණය ද තිබේ. එමිරේට්ස් එයාර්ලයින්ස් 1998 සිට 2008 දක්වා ශ්‍රීලංකන් කළමනාකරණය සහ කොටස් හිමිකාරීත්වය දරන විට ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය රු. මිලියන 22 ක ලාභයක්.",
        "“ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය ගලවා ගැනීමට ඇති එකම ක්‍රමය හදිසි ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමකි. අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය, සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අධිකාරියේ නිලධාරීන් සහ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රවීණයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඇති හොඳම මාර්ගය අපි යෝජනා කරනවා,” ද සිල්වා මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමේ සභාපති අශෝක් පතිරගේ මහතා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් පැවසීය. අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම් රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර මහතා සහ නිලධාරීන්.",
        "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 ක විශ්මයජනක ණය සහ හිඟ මුදල් ඩොලර් මිලියන 175 ක රජයේ සහතික කළ ජාත්‍යන්තර බැඳුම්කර, රාජ්‍ය බැංකු BOC සහ මහජන බැංකුවට ගෙවිය යුතු ඩොලර් මිලියන 380 සහ ශ්‍රීලංකන් කේටරින් කොටස් උකස් කර BOC වෙතින් ලබාගත් ඩොලර් මිලියන 80 ක ණය ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "වගකීම් අතර, ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාවට (ඩොලර් මිලියන 312), ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා සමාගමට සහ සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අධිකාරියට ගෙවිය යුතු හිඟ ඩොලර් මිලියන 325 සහ ගුවන් යානා කල්බදු සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 80 ක හිඟ මුදල් වේ. ජාතික ගුවන් සේවයට එක ගුවන් යානයක් හිමි නොවන අතර 26 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ගුවන් යානා ඇණියක් බදු දී ඇත.",
        "ද සිල්වා අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසුවේ 49% ක කොටස් විකිණීමෙන් ලැබෙන අරමුදල් ණය විශ්‍රාම ගැනීමට සහ ගෙවිය යුතු මුදල් පියවීමට භාවිතා කරන බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමට නව ප්‍රාග්ධන මුදල් සම්භාරයක් අවශ්‍ය බවත් එය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම තුළින් පමණක් කළ හැකි බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රජය සතු කොටස් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සහ කොටස් වශයෙන් වෙන් කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයට පමණක් අනන්‍ය වූවක් නොවන බවත් එය එයාර් ඉන්දියා පුද්ගලීකරනය කිරීමට යොමු වූ බවත් පෙන්වා දෙන ලදී. “රජයට ණය කපා හැරීමට හෝ පාඩු උකහා ගත නොහැක,” ශ්‍රී ලංකන් සභාපති පතිරගේ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතියෙන් පසු ගෝලීය ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගෙන් උනන්දුව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම (EOIs) ලබා ගන්නා බවත්, අභ්‍යාසය මඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය විදේශ ආයෝජන ගෙන ඒමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "\"එය ඉතා විනිවිද භාවයෙන් යුත් ක්‍රියාවලියක් වනු ඇති අතර, හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාවයක් සඳහා අපි විනිවිද භාවයෙන් සම්මුතියක් ඇති කර නොගනිමු\" යනුවෙන් ද සිල්වා අමාත්‍යවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ආයතනයෙන් ආයතනය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම හෝ පියවරෙන් පියවර ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම හොඳම ප්‍රායෝගික පාඨමාලාව බව පැවසූ සභාපති පතිරගේ මහතා ප්‍රථමයෙන් කේටරින් ව්‍යාපාරයට මුහුණ දෙන බවත් පසුව භූමිය හැසිරවීමද ලාභ ලබන බවත් පැවසීය. “අපි ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ඉක්මනින් අවසන් කරන තරමට එය ජාතික ගුවන් සේවයට වඩා හොඳය,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "බොහෝ දුරට උරුම ණය සහ වෙනත් ගැටළු හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සාධාරණීකරණය කළද, පතිරගේ පැවසුවේ 2021 දෙසැම්බර් සහ 2022 මාර්තු අතර ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය ශුද්ධ ලාභයක් ලැබූ බවයි. පසුගිය මාසයේදී ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 ක පිරිවැටුමක් ලබා ගත් අතර ගුවන් යානා ඉන්ධන පිටරටින් ලබා ගැනීමට සිදුවීමෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.5 ක සුළු පාඩුවක් වාර්තා විය. \"අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී අපට ලාභයක් ලැබෙනු ඇත,\" ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "2022 ජනවාරි-මාර්තු කාර්තුවේදී ගුවන් සමාගම වසර හයකට පසු පළමු වතාවට ඩොලරයේ සමූහ මෙහෙයුම් ලාභයක් වාර්තා කළේය. එය 2006 සිට පළමු සිව්වන කාර්තුවේ ලාභය (ඩොලර් අනුව) ද විය.",
        "උරුම ප්‍රශ්න තිබියදීත්, ශ්‍රීලංකන් ඉන්දියාවට විශාලතම විදේශීය ක්‍රියාකරු වීම, සංක්‍රමණ ගමනාගමනය සඳහා කොළඹ උපායමාර්ගික ස්ථානය, ගොඩබෑමේ අයිතිය, ශක්තිමත් වෙළඳ නාමය සහ අනෙකුත් සාධක අතර හොඳ වටිනාකමක් ලබා දෙන බව පතිරගේ පිළිගත්තේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් දැනට රටවල් 23 ක ගමනාන්ත 37 කට සේවා සපයන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිට ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, ප්‍රංශය, ජර්මනිය, ජපානය, දකුණු කොරියාව සහ එක්සත් රාජධානිය වෙත සෘජු ගුවන් ගමන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන එකම ආසියානු ගුවන් සේවයයි.",
        "කැමති අයට ස්වේච්ඡා විශ්‍රාම ක්‍රමයක් (VRS) ලබා නොදෙන්නේ නම්, නව හිමිකරුවන් සහ කළමනාකරුවන් සඳහා දැනට සිටින කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය රඳවා තබා ගැනීම අනිවාර්ය බව අමාත්‍ය ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය. ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියට වෘත්තීය සමිති සහය දක්වන බවත් නිර්දේශ කිහිපයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ බවත් ඒවා සලකා බලන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "සේවකයන් 6400ක් සිටින ශ්‍රීලංකන් ආයතනයේ සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩි බවත් ඔවුන්ට වැටුප් වැඩිය යන වැරදි මතයද පතිරගේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. වසංගතය සහ එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ඇති වූ බලපෑම හේතුවෙන් ගුවන් සමාගමට බොහෝ සේවකයින් අහිමි වූ අතර ගෝලීය කර්මාන්තයට මෙන්ම තෝරාගත් කාර්යයන් සඳහා අමතර කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයක් අවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "49%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "අලාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන භාගයකට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 10 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 165 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998 සිට 2008 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍යාංශය, අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අශෝක් පතිරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 175 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 380 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 80 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කේටරින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 325 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 312 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ගුවන් සේවා සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 80 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් ඉන්දියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතිරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පතිරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 2021 සහ මාර්තු 2022 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය මාසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි-මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු හතරවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VRS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் குழுமம், வெளிநாட்டு ஆபரேட்டர்களை 49% ஈக்விட்டி பங்குகள் மற்றும் நிர்வாகத்தை எடுத்துக்கொள்ள அழைப்பதன் மூலம் மறுசீரமைக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஏறக்குறைய அரை டிரில்லியன் ரூபாய் திரட்டப்பட்ட நஷ்டம் மற்றும் 1 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் மற்றும் நிலுவைத் தொகையில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் குழுமம், தேசிய விமான நிறுவனம் இனி பொதுமக்களுக்கு சுமையாக மாறாமல் இருப்பதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக வெளிநாட்டு ஆபரேட்டர்களை 49% ஈக்விட்டி பங்குகள் மற்றும் நிர்வாகத்தை எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு மறுசீரமைக்க உள்ளது. .",
        "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா, இலங்கையின் கொடி ஏற்றிச் செல்வதற்கான முன்னோக்கி செல்லும் வழியை நேற்று வெளியிட்டார், அதை அமைச்சரவையின் இறுதி ஒப்புதலுக்காக அவர் முன்மொழிவார். முக்கியமான மறுசீரமைப்புக்கான காரணங்கள் மற்றும் செயல்முறை தொழிற்சங்கங்கள், தொழில்துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் மற்றும் ஊடகங்களுடன் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "நாட்டின் நிதி, அந்நியச் செலாவணி மற்றும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, கடந்த 10 வருடங்களாக ரூ. கோடி நஷ்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்திய தேசிய விமான சேவைக்கு இனி அரசாங்கத்தால் நிதியளிக்க முடியாது என அமைச்சர் டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். 435 பில்லியன். சமீபத்திய FY22 மிக மோசமான செயல்திறனைக் கண்டது ரூ. 165 பில்லியன் இழப்பு, கடந்த 2019 ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு மற்றும் கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய் அதன் செயல்திறனை பாதித்த போது, ​​ரூபாயின் 40% தேய்மானம் காரணமாக இருந்தது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் 1 பில்லியன் டொலர் வெளிநாட்டு மற்றும் உள்நாட்டு கடன் மற்றும் பாக்கிகளை செலுத்த வேண்டியுள்ளது. எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் 1998 முதல் 2008 வரை ஸ்ரீலங்கனை நிர்வகித்து அதன் பகுதிக்குச் சொந்தமானபோது தேசிய விமான நிறுவனம் ரூ. 22 கோடி லாபம்.",
        "\"தேசிய கேரியரை மீட்பதற்கான ஒரே வழி அவசர மறுசீரமைப்பு ஆகும். அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகள், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் பணிப்பாளர் சபை, சிவில் விமான சேவைகள் அதிகாரசபையின் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை நிபுணர்களுடன் கலந்தாலோசித்த பின்னர் சிறந்த பாதையை நாங்கள் முன்மொழிகிறோம், ”என்று டி சில்வா ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் தலைவர் அசோக் பத்திரகேவுடன் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார். அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ருவன் சந்திரா மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள்.",
        "$1 பில்லியன் கடன் மற்றும் பாக்கிகள் $175 மில்லியன் அரசாங்க உத்தரவாதம் பெற்ற சர்வதேச பத்திரம், $380 மில்லியன் அரச வங்கிகளான BOC மற்றும் மக்கள் வங்கிக்கு செலுத்தப்பட வேண்டியவை மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங் பங்குகளை அடமானம் வைத்து BOC இலிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட $80 மில்லியன் கடனை உள்ளடக்கியது.",
        "பொறுப்புகளில் சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் ($ 312 மில்லியன்), விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் ஏவியேஷன் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட் மற்றும் சிவில் ஏவியேஷன் அத்தாரிட்டி ஆகியவற்றிற்கு $ 325 மில்லியன் நிலுவைத் தொகை மற்றும் விமான குத்தகைக்காக $ 80 மில்லியன் பாக்கிகள் உள்ளன. தேசிய கேரியர் ஒரு விமானம் கூட சொந்தமாக இல்லை மற்றும் 26 கடற்படை குத்தகைக்கு உள்ளது.",
        "49% ஈக்விட்டி பங்கு விற்பனையில் இருந்து பெறப்படும் நிதியானது, கடனை ஓய்வு பெறவும், நிலுவைத் தொகையை செலுத்தவும் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் என்று அமைச்சர் டி சில்வா கூறினார். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் குழுமத்திற்கு புதிய மூலதன உட்செலுத்துதல் தேவைப்படுவதாகவும், இதனை மறுசீரமைப்பு மூலம் மட்டுமே செய்ய முடியும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான பங்குகளை மறுசீரமைத்தல் மற்றும் பங்கு விலக்கல் ஆகியவற்றின் தேவை ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திற்கு மட்டும் தனித்தன்மை வாய்ந்தது அல்ல, ஆனால் ஏர் இந்தியாவை தனியார் மயமாக்குவது பற்றியே குறிப்பிடப்பட்டது. \"அரசாங்கத்தால் கடனை தள்ளுபடி செய்யவோ அல்லது இழப்பை உறிஞ்சவோ முடியாது\" என ஸ்ரீலங்கன் தலைவர் பத்திரகே மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமைச்சரவையின் அங்கீகாரத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, உலகளாவிய செயற்பாட்டாளர்களிடமிருந்து ஆர்வத்தின் வெளிப்பாடுகள் (EOIs) கோரப்படும் என்றும், இந்தப் பயிற்சியானது இலங்கைக்கு தேவையான வெளிநாட்டு முதலீட்டைக் கொண்டுவரும் என்றும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது என்றும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இது மிகவும் வெளிப்படையான செயல்முறையாக இருக்கும், அவசரத்திற்காக நாங்கள் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையை சமரசம் செய்ய மாட்டோம்\" என்று அமைச்சர் டி சில்வா வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "நிறுவனத்தை அல்லது படிப்படியாக நிறுவனத்தை மறுசீரமைப்பது சிறந்த நடைமுறைப் பாடமாகும் எனத் தெரிவித்த தலைவர் பத்திரகே, கேட்டரிங் வர்த்தகம் முதலில் கையாளப்படும், அதன்பின் தரைவழி கையாளுதல் இரண்டும் லாபகரமானது என்றார். \"எவ்வளவு சீக்கிரம் மறுசீரமைப்பை முடிக்கிறோமோ அவ்வளவுக்கு தேசிய கேரியருக்கு நல்லது\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "மரபுக் கடன் மற்றும் பிற பிரச்சினைகள் காரணமாக மறுசீரமைப்பை நியாயப்படுத்தினாலும், டிசம்பர் 2021 மற்றும் மார்ச் 2022 க்கு இடையில் தேசிய கேரியர் நிகர லாபத்தை ஈட்டியதாக பத்திரகே கூறினார். கடந்த மாதம் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் 90 மில்லியன் டாலர் வருவாயை எட்டியது மற்றும் வெளிநாடுகளில் இருந்து ஜெட் எரிபொருளை பெற 1.5 மில்லியன் டாலர் சிறிய இழப்பை சந்தித்தது. \"ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் நாங்கள் லாபம் ஈட்ட வாய்ப்புள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனவரி-மார்ச் 2022 காலாண்டில் விமான நிறுவனம் ஆறு ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு முதல் முறையாக டாலர் அடிப்படையில் குழு இயக்க லாபத்தைப் பதிவு செய்தது. இது 2006 முதல் நான்காவது காலாண்டு லாபம் (டாலர் அடிப்படையில்) ஆகும்.",
        "பரம்பரைப் பிரச்சினைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் இந்தியாவிற்கான மிகப்பெரிய வெளிநாட்டு ஆபரேட்டர், போக்குவரத்து போக்குவரத்துக்கான மூலோபாயமான கொழும்பு இடம், தரையிறங்கும் உரிமைகள், வலுவான வர்த்தக நாமம் மற்றும் நல்லெண்ணம் போன்றவற்றிற்கு பெரும் மதிப்பை வழங்குகிறது என்பதை பத்திரகே ஒப்புக்கொண்டார். இலங்கையிலிருந்து அவுஸ்திரேலியா, பிரான்ஸ், ஜேர்மனி, ஜப்பான், தென் கொரியா மற்றும் ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம் ஆகிய நாடுகளுக்கு நேரடியான வழித்தடங்களைச் செலுத்தும் ஒரே ஆசிய விமானச் சேவையாக ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் தற்போது 23 நாடுகளில் 37 இடங்களுக்குச் சேவைகளை வழங்கி வருகின்றது.",
        "ஆர்வமுள்ளவர்களுக்கு விருப்ப ஓய்வு திட்டம் (VRS) வழங்கப்படாவிட்டால், புதிய உரிமையாளர்கள் மற்றும் மேலாளர்களின் தரப்பில் தற்போதுள்ள ஊழியர்களைத் தக்கவைத்துக்கொள்வது கட்டாயமாகும் என்று அமைச்சர் டி சில்வா கூறினார். மறுசீரமைப்பு செயல்முறைக்கு தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும், பரிசீலிக்கப்படும் பல பரிந்துரைகளை வழங்கியதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "6400 ஊழியர்களைக் கொண்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கன் நிறுவனத்தில் பணியாளர்கள் அதிகமாக உள்ளனர், அவர்களுக்கு அதிக ஊதியம் வழங்கப்படுகிறது என்ற தவறான கருத்தையும் பத்திரகே மறுத்தார். தொற்றுநோய் மற்றும் அதன் விளைவாக ஏற்பட்ட தாக்கம் காரணமாக விமான நிறுவனம் பல ஊழியர்களை இழந்துள்ளதாகவும், உலகளாவிய தொழில்துறையைப் போலவே, தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட செயல்பாடுகளில் கூடுதல் பணியாளர்கள் தேவைப்படுவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் குழுமம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "49%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "இழப்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய கேரியர்",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட அரை டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 10 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "165 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998 முதல் 2008 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம், இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவில் விமான போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசோக் பத்திரகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவன் சந்திரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 175 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 380 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 80 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 325 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 312 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏவியேஷன் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவில் விமான போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 80 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்திரகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 2021 மற்றும் மார்ச் 2022 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 90 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி-மார்ச் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் நான்காவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.ஆர்.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}