{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/india-sri-lanka-should-build-framework-to-discuss-maritime-concerns/",
  "time_ut": 1661588520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India-Sri Lanka should build framework to discuss maritime concerns",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India-Sri Lanka should build framework to discuss maritime concerns",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Amidst signs of New Delhi’s disappointment over Colombo’s decision to allow a Chinese tracking vessel to dock in Hambantota, Sri Lanka’s envoy in India called for building a new “framework” on how to deal with such maritime security concerns in the future.",
        "Speaking to The Hindu days after the Chinese satellite and missile tracking ship, the Yuan Wang 5 had departed from the Sri Lankan port after “refuelling and replenishing supplies”, High Commissioner Milinda Moragoda said that Colombo had kept the Modi government briefed at the “highest levels” through the controversy.",
        "In a possible sign of the strain in ties over the issue, the Ministry of External Affairs had issued a rare “travel guidance” on Thursday cautioning Indian tourists about visiting Sri Lanka, which is in the middle of a deep economic crisis.",
        "Without commenting on the MEA advisory, Moragoda said it was important to look to the future of ties, particularly in terms of India-Sri Lanka cooperation in the economic and strategic sphere.",
        "Apart from economic assistance of $3.8 billion, including credit lines from India, New Delhi and Colombo are discussing more trade ties, a power-sharing grid, and infrastructure projects in renewable energy and oil storage.",
        "India has also supported Sri Lanka in talks with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for a bailout.",
        "“There is no question that the docking of the ship was an issue between us. The question is how to build a framework for such problems in order to avoid them in the future, and not to allow this kind of issue to lead to a trust deficit,” Moragoda said, adding that despite “ups and downs”, Sri Lanka would like to “build an equilibrium in the relationship, where there are no surprises”.",
        "In an unusually public move, the Modi government had last month conveyed its concerns over the docking of the ship, believed to be a satellite research and surveillance vessel.",
        "While the Sri Lankan government had asked China to defer the ship’s plans entirely after India’s objections, the Chinese government had only agreed to delay its arrival in Hambantota by a few days, and eventually the Yuan Wang 5 docked at the port from August 16-22.",
        "According to Mr. Moragoda, the permissions for the docking had been granted to China amidst a period of political turmoil in Colombo, when President Ranil Wickremesinghe took charge after the ouster of previous President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, as well as the economic crisis, leading to “not enough attention” being given to the case.",
        "According to official data, the visit of the ship had also followed after at least 10 research vessels of a different class had docked in Colombo between 2019-2022, without raising any concerns in Delhi.",
        "“In this particular case, there could have been a level of confusion in Colombo when it came to differentiating between the classes of vessels and technologies involved. Unfortunately, once the approvals were given, it was hard to take them back,” Mr. Moragoda said, adding that Sri Lanka was hoping to focus on strengthening lines of communication, as well as high-level exchanges, and people-to-people ties.",
        "According to sources, both Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Wickremesinghe are expected to travel to Tokyo to attend former Japan Prime Minister Shinzo Abe’s state funeral.",
        "On a visit to Gujarat last week, Sri Lankan Tourism Minister Harin Fernando had also pitched for more Indian tourists, saying that he hoped that at least 10 lakh international tourists, mostly Indians, would visit this year.",
        "However, striking a cautionary note on Thursday, the MEA’s spokesperson said encouraged Indians to exercise all care and caution while in Sri Lanka, and “examine all relevant factors, including currency convertibility and the fuel situation before undertaking any essential travel to Sri Lanka”."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Milinda Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 2019-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gujarat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියා - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමුද්‍රීය ගැටලු සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට රාමුවක් ගොඩනගා ගත යුතුයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); චීන ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාවක් හම්බන්තොට නැංගුරම් ලෑමට කොළඹ ගත් තීරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් නව දිල්ලියේ බලාපොරොත්තු සුන්වීමේ සලකුනු මධ්‍යයේ, ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා අනාගතයේදී එවැනි සමුද්‍ර ආරක්‍ෂාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් කටයුතු කරන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව නව “රාමුවක්” ගොඩනඟන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "චීන චන්ද්‍රිකා සහ මිසයිල ලුහුබැඳීමේ නෞකාවෙන් දින කිහිපයකට පසු යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරායෙන් පිටත්ව ගියේ “ඉන්ධන පිරවීමෙන් සහ සැපයුම් නැවත පිරවීමෙන්” පසුවය, මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ කියා සිටියේ කොළඹ මෝදි රජයට “ඉහළම දැනුම් දීමක් කර ඇති” බවයි. මට්ටම්” මතභේදය හරහා.",
        "ප්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පවතින බැඳීම්වල ඇති විය හැකි සලකුණක් ලෙස, ගැඹුරු ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මැදිව සිටින ඉන්දීය සංචාරකයින්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීම ගැන අනතුරු අඟවමින් විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා දුර්ලභ “සංචාරක මාර්ගෝපදේශයක්” නිකුත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "MEA උපදේශනය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දැක්වීමකින් තොරව මොරගොඩ පැවසුවේ, විශේෂයෙන්ම ආර්ථික සහ උපායමාර්ගික ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ඉන්දු-ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහයෝගීතාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් සබඳතාවල අනාගතය දෙස බැලීම වැදගත් බවයි.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ණය මාර්ග ඇතුළුව ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක ආර්ථික ආධාරවලට අමතරව, නව දිල්ලිය සහ කොළඹ තවත් වෙළඳ සබඳතා, බලශක්ති බෙදාගැනීමේ ජාලයක් සහ පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සහ තෙල් ගබඩා කිරීමේ යටිතල පහසුකම් ව්‍යාපෘති පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටී.",
        "ඇපදීමක් සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමේදී ඉන්දියාව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "“නැව නැව්ගත කිරීම අප අතර ප්‍රශ්නයක් වූ බවට විවාදයක් නැත. ප්‍රශ්නය වන්නේ අනාගතයේදී එවැනි ගැටලු මඟහරවා ගැනීම සඳහාත්, මෙවැනි ප්‍රශ්න විශ්වාස හිඟයකට තුඩු දීමට ඉඩ නොතැබීම සඳහා රාමුවක් ගොඩනඟන්නේ කෙසේද යන්නයි, ”මොරගොඩ පැවසුවේ “උඩු සහ වැටීම්” තිබියදීත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව \"කිසිදු විස්මයක් නොමැති සම්බන්ධතාවයේ සමතුලිතතාවයක් ගොඩනඟා ගැනීමට\" කැමති වේ.",
        "අසාමාන්‍ය ලෙස ප්‍රසිද්ධ පියවරක් ලෙස, චන්ද්‍රිකා පර්යේෂණ සහ නිරීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් යැයි විශ්වාස කෙරෙන නෞකාව නැව්ගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෝඩි රජය පසුගිය මාසයේ සිය කනස්සල්ල පළ කර තිබුණි.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ විරෝධයෙන් පසු නෞකාවේ සැලසුම් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම කල් දමන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, චීන රජය එය හම්බන්තොටට පැමිණීම දින කිහිපයකින් ප්‍රමාද කිරීමට පමණක් එකඟ වී ඇති අතර අවසානයේ යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 අගෝස්තු 16-22 දක්වා වරායට නැංගේය. .",
        "මොරගොඩ මහතාට අනුව, පසුගිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බලයෙන් පහකිරීමෙන් පසු රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බලයට පත්වීමත් සමඟම මෙන්ම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට තුඩු දුන් කොළඹ දේශපාලන අවුල් සහගත කාල පරිච්ඡේදයක් මධ්‍යයේ චීනයට නැව්ගත කිරීම සඳහා අවසර ලබා දී ඇත. ප්‍රමාණවත් අවධානයක් නැහැ” නඩුවට ලබා දෙනවා.",
        "නිල දත්ත වලට අනුව, දිල්ලියේ කිසිදු සැලකිල්ලක් නොදක්වා 2019-2022 අතර කාලය තුළ අවම වශයෙන් වෙනස් පන්තියක පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රා 10 ක් කොළඹට නැව්ගත කිරීමෙන් පසුව නෞකාවේ සංචාරය ද අනුගමනය කර ඇත.",
        "“මෙම විශේෂිත අවස්ථාවෙහිදී, යාත්‍රා සහ තාක්ෂණික ක්‍රම අතර වෙනස හඳුනාගැනීමේදී කොළඹ ව්‍යාකූල මට්ටමක පැවතිය හැකිය. අවාසනාවකට, අනුමැතිය ලබා දුන් පසු, ඒවා ආපසු ගැනීම දුෂ්කර විය, ”මොරගොඩ මහතා පැවසුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සන්නිවේදන මාර්ග ශක්තිමත් කිරීම මෙන්ම ඉහළ මට්ටමේ හුවමාරු කිරීම් සහ මිනිසුන්ගෙන් මිනිසුන් අතර අවධානය යොමු කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව පැවසීය. බැඳීම්.",
        "ආරංචි මාර්ග වලට අනුව, හිටපු ජපාන අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේගේ රාජ්‍ය අවමංගල්‍යයට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි සහ ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ යන දෙදෙනාම ටෝකියෝ වෙත යාමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ගුජරාට් ප්‍රාන්තයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු ද ඉන්දීය සංචාරකයින් වැඩි පිරිසක් සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් වී ඇති අතර, මේ වසරේ අවම වශයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරකයින් ලක්ෂ 10 ක්, වැඩි වශයෙන් ඉන්දියානුවන් පැමිණෙනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව පවසමින්.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ සටහනක් තබමින් MEA හි ප්‍රකාශකයා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින විට සියලු ප්‍රවේශම් සහ ප්‍රවේශමෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන ලෙස ඉන්දියානුවන් දිරිමත් කරන බවත්, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඕනෑම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සංචාරයක් කිරීමට පෙර මුදල් පරිවර්තනය සහ ඉන්ධන තත්ත්වය ඇතුළු අදාළ සියලු සාධක පරීක්ෂා කරන” බවත්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවදිල්ලියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019-2022 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුජරාට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா-இலங்கை கடல்சார் கவலைகள் பற்றி விவாதிக்க கட்டமைப்பை உருவாக்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் சீன கண்காணிப்புக் கப்பலை நிறுத்துவதற்கு கொழும்பின் முடிவின் மீதான புது டெல்லியின் ஏமாற்றத்தின் அறிகுறிகளுக்கு மத்தியில், இந்தியாவில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் தூதுவர், எதிர்காலத்தில் இதுபோன்ற கடல்சார் பாதுகாப்புக் கவலைகளை எவ்வாறு கையாள்வது என்பது குறித்து புதிய \"கட்டமைப்பை\" உருவாக்க அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "சீன செயற்கைக்கோள் மற்றும் ஏவுகணை கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கை துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து \"எரிபொருள் நிரப்பி பொருட்களை நிரப்பிவிட்டு\" புறப்பட்டுச் சென்ற சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு தி ஹிந்துவிடம் பேசிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொடா, கொழும்பு மோடி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு \"உயர்ந்த நிலையில் விளக்கமளித்துள்ளது\" என்றார். நிலைகள்” சர்ச்சை மூலம்.",
        "இந்த விவகாரத்தில் உறவுகளில் விரிசல் ஏற்படுவதற்கான சாத்தியமான அறிகுறியாக, ஆழ்ந்த பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் மத்தியில் இருக்கும் இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தரும் இந்திய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை எச்சரிக்கும் வகையில் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு வியாழன் அன்று அரிய \"பயண வழிகாட்டல்\" ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டது.",
        "MEA ஆலோசனை குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவிக்காமல் மொரகொட, குறிப்பாக பொருளாதார மற்றும் மூலோபாயத் துறையில் இந்தியா-இலங்கை ஒத்துழைப்பின் அடிப்படையில் எதிர்கால உறவுகளைப் பார்ப்பது முக்கியம் என்றார்.",
        "$3.8 பில்லியன் பொருளாதார உதவியைத் தவிர, இந்தியாவிலிருந்து வரும் கடன் வரிகள் உட்பட, புது டெல்லி மற்றும் கொழும்பில் அதிக வர்த்தக உறவுகள், மின் பகிர்வு கட்டம் மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் மற்றும் எண்ணெய் சேமிப்பில் உள்கட்டமைப்பு திட்டங்கள் பற்றி விவாதிக்கின்றன.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பிணை எடுப்பு தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியாவும் ஆதரவளித்துள்ளது.",
        "“கப்பலை நிறுத்துவது எங்களுக்கு இடையே ஒரு பிரச்சினை என்பதில் எந்த சந்தேகமும் இல்லை. எதிர்காலத்தில் இவ்வாறான பிரச்சினைகளைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்கும், இவ்வாறான பிரச்சினைகளை நம்பிக்கைப் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு இடமளிக்காமல் இருப்பதற்கும் எவ்வாறு கட்டமைப்பை உருவாக்குவது என்பதே கேள்வியாகும்,” என்று மொரகொட கூறினார். \"ஆச்சரியங்கள் இல்லாத உறவில் ஒரு சமநிலையை உருவாக்க\" விரும்புகிறேன்.",
        "வழக்கத்திற்கு மாறான பொது நடவடிக்கையில், செயற்கைக்கோள் ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் கண்காணிப்புக் கப்பலாகக் கருதப்படும் கப்பலை நிறுத்துவது குறித்து மோடி அரசாங்கம் கடந்த மாதம் தனது கவலையை தெரிவித்தது.",
        "இந்தியாவின் ஆட்சேபனைகளுக்குப் பிறகு கப்பலின் திட்டங்களை முழுமையாக ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் சீனாவிடம் கேட்டுக் கொண்டாலும், சீன அரசாங்கம் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வருவதற்கு சில நாட்கள் தாமதிக்க ஒப்புக்கொண்டது, இறுதியில் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22 வரை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டது. .",
        "திரு. மொரகொடவின் கூற்றுப்படி, கொழும்பில் அரசியல் குழப்பங்கள் நிலவிய காலப்பகுதியில், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பதவி நீக்கம் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பொறுப்பேற்ற போது, ​​சீனாவிற்கு கப்பல்துறைக்கான அனுமதிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டன. போதுமான கவனம் இல்லை” என்று வழக்கு கொடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ தரவுகளின்படி, 2019-2022 க்கு இடையில் வேறு வகுப்பைச் சேர்ந்த குறைந்தது 10 ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல்கள் கொழும்பில் நிறுத்தப்பட்ட பின்னர், டெல்லியில் எந்த கவலையும் இல்லாமல் கப்பலின் வருகையும் தொடர்ந்தது.",
        "“இந்தக் குறிப்பிட்ட சந்தர்ப்பத்தில், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட கப்பல்கள் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பங்களை வேறுபடுத்தும் போது கொழும்பில் ஒரு குழப்ப நிலை இருந்திருக்கலாம். துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, அனுமதிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டவுடன், அவற்றை திரும்பப் பெறுவது கடினமாக இருந்தது,” என்று தெரிவித்த திரு. மொரகொட, தகவல்தொடர்புகளை வலுப்படுத்துதல், உயர்மட்ட பரிமாற்றங்கள் மற்றும் மக்களிடையேயான பரிமாற்றங்கள் ஆகியவற்றில் கவனம் செலுத்த இலங்கை நம்புகிறது. உறவுகள்.",
        "ஆதாரங்களின்படி, பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க இருவரும் ஜப்பான் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபேவின் இறுதிச் சடங்கில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக டோக்கியோவுக்குச் செல்வார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் குஜராத்துக்கு விஜயம் செய்திருந்த இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ மேலும் இந்திய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை வரவழைத்து, இந்த ஆண்டு குறைந்தது 10 லட்சம் சர்வதேச சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள், பெரும்பாலும் இந்தியர்கள் வருகை தருவார்கள் என்று நம்புவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், வியாழனன்று ஒரு எச்சரிக்கைக் குறிப்பைத் தாக்கி, MEA இன் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், இலங்கையில் இருக்கும் போது அனைத்து அக்கறையுடனும் எச்சரிக்கையுடனும் செயல்படுமாறு இந்தியர்களை ஊக்குவித்தார், மேலும் \"இலங்கைக்கு எந்தவொரு அத்தியாவசிய பயணத்தையும் மேற்கொள்வதற்கு முன் நாணய மாற்றம் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் நிலைமை உட்பட அனைத்து தொடர்புடைய காரணிகளை ஆராயவும்\" என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது டெல்லியின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிலிந்த மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019-2022 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குஜராத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}