{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/temple/இன்றிரவு-கதிர்காமம்-கொடியேற்றம்/64-301304",
  "time_ut": 1659027174,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இன்றிரவு கதிர்காமம் கொடியேற்றம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kadirgamam flag hoisting tonight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The annual flag hoisting event of the historic Kathirgamam Kandan Temple will be held today (29) Friday evening.",
        "On the other hand, the flag hoisting ceremony of the Udavai Hill Sri Murugan Temple will be held today under the leadership of the Gurus of the Temple Pradham Guru Shivsiri K.K. Seetharam.",
        "15 consecutive days of festivals starting with flag hoisting, berahara will be held, the tirtha utsavam will be held at Kathirgam on 12th, similarly, the tirtha utsavam of Udgai Murugan Temple will be held on 11th.",
        "It is reported that devotees traveling on the forest path to Kathirgamat are suffering from continuous rain.",
        "It is noteworthy that around 9,000 Padayatra pilgrims, including the group that left from Selvach Sannidhi Temple, Jaffna, have reached Kathirgam so far."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tonight",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathirgamam Kandan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Udavai Hill Sri Murugan Temple",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shivsiri K.K. Seetharam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15 consecutive days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathirgam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kathirgamat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Padayatra",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathirgam",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද රාත්‍රියේ කදිරගාමම් ධජය එසවීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඓතිහාසික කතිර්ගාමම් කන්දන් විහාරස්ථානයේ වාර්ෂික ධජය එසවීමේ උත්සවය අද (29) සිකුරාදා සවස පැවැත්වෙයි.",
        "අනෙක් අතට උඩවයි කඳුකර ශ්‍රී මුරුගන් විහාරස්ථානයේ ධජය එසවීමේ මංගල්‍යය එම විහාරස්ථානයේ ප්‍රධාන ගුරු ශිවසිරි කේ.කේ.සීතාරම් මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද පැවැත්වේ.",
        "ධජය එසවීම, බෙරහර ආදියෙන් ආරම්භ වන උත්සව දින 15 ක් අඛණ්ඩව පැවැත්වෙන අතර, 12 වැනිදා කතිර්ගම්හිදී තීර්ත උත්සවය ද, එසේම 11 වැනිදා උද්ගයි මුරුගන් කෝවිලේ තීර්ථ උත්සවය ද පැවැත්වේ.",
        "කතිර්ගාමට් දක්වා වන මාර්ගයේ ගමන් ගන්නා බැතිමතුන් අඛණ්ඩ වර්ෂාවෙන් පීඩාවට පත්ව සිටින බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "යාපනය සෙල්වච් සන්නිධි විහාරස්ථානයේ සිට පිටත්ව ගිය පිරිස ඇතුළු පාදයාත්‍රා වන්දනාකරුවන් 9000ක් පමණ මේ වන විට කතිර්ගම් වෙත පැමිණ තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද රෑ",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතිර්ගාමම් කන්දන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උඩවයි කන්දේ ශ්‍රී මුරුගන් පන්සල",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිවසිරි කේ.කේ. සීතාරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දින 15 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතිර්ගම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කතිර්ගාමත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාදයාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතිර්ගම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்றிரவு கதிர்காமம் கொடியேற்றம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "வரலாற்றுப் பிரசித்தி பெற்ற கதிர்காமம் கந்தன் கோவிலின் வருடாந்த கொடியேற்ற நிகழ்வு, இன்று (29) வெள்ளிக்கிழமை மாலை இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "அதேவேளை, உகந்தை மலை ஸ்ரீ முருகன் கோவில் கொடியேற்றமும், கோவில் பிரதமகுரு சிவசிறி க.கு.சீதாராம் குருக்கள் தலைமையில் இன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "கொடியேற்றம் தொடங்கி தொடர்ச்சியாக 15 நாட்கள் திருவிழாக்கள், பெரஹரா இடம்பெற்று, எதிர்வரும் 12ஆம் திகதி கதிர்காமத்தில் தீர்த்த உற்சவமும் அதேபோன்று, உகந்தை முருகன் கோவிலின் தீர்த்த உற்சவம் எதிர்வரும் 11ஆம் திகதியும் இடம்பெறவுள்ளன.",
        "இது இவ்வாறு இருக்க கதிர்காமத்துக்கான காட்டுப்பாதையில் பயணிக்கும் பக்தர்கள் தொடர்ச்சியான மழையால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம், செல்வச் சந்நிதி கோவிலில் இருந்து புறப்பட்ட குழுவினர் உள்ளிட்ட சுமார் 9,000 பாதயாத்திரை அடியார்கள் இதுவரை கதிர்காமத்தை சென்றடைந்திருக்கின்றார்கள் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்றிரவு",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம் கந்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உதவை மலை ஸ்ரீ முருகன் கோவில்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவசிறி கே.கே. சீதாராம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 15 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்கம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதயாத்திரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்கம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}