{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/12/fugitive-mahendran-speaks-about-sri-lankas-economy/",
  "time_ut": 1657640220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fugitive Mahendran speaks about Sri Lanka’s economy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fugitive Mahendran speaks about Sri Lanka’s economy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Fugitive Former Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka Arjuna Mahendran has told CNN Philippines that the Sri Lankan Government is finding it difficult to persuade lenders.",
        "“Because of the accumulation of previous debt, the Government is finding it difficult to persuade lenders, even neighboring India to put in fresh money,” said Mahendran.",
        "Speaking on the reasons that led to the present crisis in Sri Lanka, Arjuna Mahendran said that the new government that came in cut taxes abruptly which created this inflationary pressure because most of the government spending had been funded by the printing of new money.",
        "“There was a change in agricultural policy regarding the imports of fertilizer, where there was a switch from Chemical Fertilizer to Organic and that deeply affected the plantations which export tea and other products. Once COVID struck Sri Lanka the economy was already faltering. This is why Sri Lanka has been affected much earlier than other countries,” he added.",
        "“I am informed that the Prime Minister is back at work, He is in his office. So, the government is functioning. and there are crucial talks going on regarding the economy and economic policy in general which has to be set right and fast before the economic crisis results in starvation and unnecessary pain for the population of Sri Lanka,” he said.",
        "Arjuna Mahendran is the 1st suspect in the case filed over the Central Bank Treasury Bond Scam of 2015 & 2016.",
        "In the Treasury Bond Scam, Perpetual Treasuries Limited, a primary dealer company owned by Arjun Aloysius benefited from Insider Information given by then Governor of CBSL Arjuna Mahendran, who is also the Father-in-Law of Aloysius.",
        "According to reports, he fled Sri Lanka for Singapore soon after the irregularities in the Central Bank bond transactions came to light and the commencement of the investigations from different establishments.",
        "Extradition requests made from Singapore, along with the two Red Notices for the arrest of former Central Bank Governor Arjuna Mahendran, issued through INTERPOL, are still pending a response."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fugitive",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN Philippines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahendran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chemical Fertilizer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Organic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank Treasury Bond Scam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 & 2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perpetual Treasuries Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjun Aloysius",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INTERPOL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පලාගිය මහේන්ද්‍රන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය ගැන කතා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ පලාගිය හිටපු අධිපති අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් CNN පිලිපීනයට පවසා ඇත්තේ ණය දෙන්නන් ඒත්තු ගැන්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට අපහසු වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"පෙර ණය සමුච්චය වීම නිසා, රජයට ණය දෙන්නන්, අසල්වැසි ඉන්දියාව පවා නැවුම් මුදල් දැමීමට පොළඹවා ගැනීමට අපහසු වී ඇත,\" මහේන්ද්‍රන් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අර්බුදයට හේතු වූ කරුණු පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් කියා සිටියේ හදිසියේ බදු කපා දැමූ නව රජය මෙම උද්ධමන පීඩනය ඇති කළේ රජයේ වියදම්වලින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් නව මුදල් මුද්‍රණයෙන් මුදල් යෙදවීම නිසා බවයි.",
        "“පොහොර ආනයනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෘෂිකාර්මික ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ වෙනසක් ඇති වූ අතර එහිදී රසායනික පොහොරවලින් කාබනික බවට මාරුවීමක් ඇති වූ අතර එය තේ සහ අනෙකුත් නිෂ්පාදන අපනයනය කරන වැවිලිවලට දැඩි ලෙස බලපෑවේය. කොවිඩ් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පහර දීමත් සමඟ ආර්ථිකය දැනටමත් අඩාල විය. මේ නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අනෙකුත් රටවලට වඩා බොහෝ කලකට පෙර බලපෑමට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "“අගමැතිවරයා නැවත වැඩට බැස ඇති බවත්, ඔහු සිය කාර්යාලයේ සිටින බවත් මට දන්වා ඇත. ඉතින් ආණ්ඩුව ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙනවා. ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනගහනයට සාගින්න සහ අනවශ්‍ය වේදනාවක් ඇති වීමට පෙර නිවැරැදිව හා වේගවත්ව සකස් කළ යුතු ආර්ථිකය සහ පොදුවේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තීරණාත්මක සාකච්ඡා සිදුවෙමින් පවතී,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් 2015 සහ 2016 මහ බැංකු බැඳුම්කර වංචාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් පවරා ඇති නඩුවේ පළමු සැකකරු වේ.",
        "Treasury Bond Scam හි දී, අර්ජුන් ඇලෝසියස්ට අයත් ප්‍රාථමික අලෙවි නියෝජිත සමාගමක් වන Perpetual Treasuries Limited ප්‍රතිලාභ ලැබුවේ, ඇලෝසියස්ගේ මාමණ්ඩිය ද වන එවකට මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් විසින් ලබා දුන් අභ්‍යන්තර තොරතුරු වලිනි.",
        "මහබැංකු බැඳුම්කර ගනුදෙනුවල අක්‍රමිකතා හෙළිවී විවිධ ආයතනවලින් පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ වීමත් සමඟම ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පලාගොස් ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සඳහා INTERPOL හරහා නිකුත් කර ඇති රතු නිවේදන දෙක සමඟ සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් කරන ලද පිටුවහල් කිරීමේ ඉල්ලීම් තවමත් ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලාගිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රසායනික පොහොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාබනික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකු භාණ්ඩාගාර බැඳුම්කර මගඩිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 සහ 2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පර්පෙචුවල් ට්‍රෙෂරීස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන් ඇලෝසියස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ටර්පෝල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தப்பியோடிய மகேந்திரன் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் பற்றி பேசுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன் சிஎன்என் பிலிப்பைன்ஸிடம், கடன் வழங்குபவர்களை சம்மதிக்க வைப்பதில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் சிரமப்படுவதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"முந்தைய கடன்கள் குவிந்து கிடப்பதால், கடன் வழங்குபவர்களை, அண்டை நாடான இந்தியாவைக் கூட, புதிய பணத்தைப் போட வைப்பதில், அரசாங்கம் கடினமாக உள்ளது\" என்று மகேந்திரன் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு வழிவகுத்த காரணங்கள் குறித்து பேசிய அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன், வரிகளை திடீரென குறைத்த புதிய அரசாங்கம் பணவீக்க அழுத்தத்தை உருவாக்கியது, ஏனெனில் அரசாங்க செலவினங்களில் பெரும்பாலானவை புதிய பணத்தை அச்சிடுவதன் மூலம் நிதியளிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "\"உர இறக்குமதி தொடர்பான விவசாயக் கொள்கையில் மாற்றம் ஏற்பட்டது, அங்கு இரசாயன உரத்திலிருந்து கரிமத்திற்கு மாறியது மற்றும் தேயிலை மற்றும் பிற பொருட்களை ஏற்றுமதி செய்யும் தோட்டங்களை ஆழமாக பாதித்தது. கோவிட் இலங்கையை தாக்கியவுடன் பொருளாதாரம் ஏற்கனவே தள்ளாடிக்கொண்டிருந்தது. இதனால்தான் ஏனைய நாடுகளை விட இலங்கை மிகவும் முன்னதாகவே பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது” என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“பிரதமர் மீண்டும் வேலைக்கு வந்துவிட்டார், அவர் தனது அலுவலகத்தில் இருக்கிறார் என்று எனக்குத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது. அதனால், அரசு செயல்படுகிறது. பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கை தொடர்பாக முக்கியமான பேச்சுக்கள் நடைபெற்று வருகின்றன, பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியானது இலங்கையின் மக்களுக்கு பட்டினி மற்றும் தேவையற்ற வலியை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்கு முன்னர் சரியாகவும் வேகமாகவும் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "2015 மற்றும் 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான மத்திய வங்கி திறைசேரி பிணைமுறி மோசடி தொடர்பில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கில் அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன் முதலாம் சந்தேகநபர் ஆவார்.",
        "திறைசேரி பிணைமுறி மோசடியில், அர்ஜுன் அலோசியஸுக்குச் சொந்தமான பெர்பெச்சுவல் ட்ரஷரீஸ் லிமிடெட் என்ற முதன்மை வியாபாரி நிறுவனமானது, அலோசியஸின் மாமனாரான அப்போதைய CBSL இன் ஆளுனர் அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன் வழங்கிய உள் தகவல்களால் பயனடைந்தது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் பிணைமுறி பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் இடம்பெற்ற முறைகேடுகள் வெளிச்சத்துக்கு வந்ததும், பல்வேறு ஸ்தாபனங்களில் இருந்து விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதும் அவர் இலங்கையிலிருந்து சிங்கப்பூருக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "முன்னாள் மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரனைக் கைது செய்வதற்கான இரண்டு சிவப்பு அறிவிப்புகளுடன், INTERPOL மூலம் வழங்கப்பட்ட சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து விடுக்கப்பட்ட நாடு கடத்தல் கோரிக்கைகள் இன்னும் பதிலளிக்கப்படாமல் உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தப்பியோடியவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என் பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரசாயன உரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரிம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி திறைசேரி பத்திர மோசடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 & 2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்பெச்சுவல் ட்ரசரீஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன் அலோசியஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்டர்போல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}