{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලක්ෂ-20-ගංජා-සමග-අයෙක්-සැකපිට/101-618897",
  "time_ut": 1661741645,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලක්ෂ 20 ගංජා සමග අයෙක් සැකපිට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A person is suspected with 20 lakhs of ganja",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A suspect was arrested by the Special Task Force in Kirulapana along with a stock of Kerala Ganja worth over twenty lakh rupees.",
        "According to information that the suspect is ready to sell a stock of Kerala ganja, the troops have conducted this raid.",
        "At the time of arrest, the suspect was in possession of more than 6 kilos of Kerala Ganja Kerala Ganja.",
        "The arrested suspect is a resident of Kirulapana area and he and the stock of Kerala ganja have been handed over to the Kirulapana police for further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirulapana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ganja Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirulapana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirulapana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලක්ෂ 20 ගංජා සමග අයෙක් සැකපිට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් ලක්ෂ විස්සකට අධික වටිනා කේරල ගංජා තොගයක් සමඟ සැකකරුවකු කිරුළපන ප්‍රදේශයේ දී විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය මගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත",
        "සැකකරු කේරල ගංජා තොගයක් අලෙවි කිරීමට සූදානමින් සිටින බවට ලද තොරතුරකට අනුව භට පිරිස් මෙම වැටලීම සිදුකර ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා අවස්ථාවේ සැකකරු සන්තකයේ කේරල ගංජා කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ 6 ට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් තිබී ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු කිරුළපන ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවකු බවත් ඔහු සහ කේරල ගංජා තොගය වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා කිරුළපන පොලිසියට බාර දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරුළපන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 ට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංජා කේරල ගංජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරුළපන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරුළපන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "20 லட்சம் கஞ்சாவுடன் நபர் ஒருவர் மீது சந்தேகம் உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இருபது இலட்சம் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான கேரள கஞ்சா கையிருப்புடன் சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவர் கிருலப்பனையில் வைத்து விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் கேரள கஞ்சாவை விற்பனை செய்ய தயாராக இருப்பதாக கிடைத்த தகவலுக்கு அமைய, படையினர் இந்த சுற்றிவளைப்பை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்படும் போது சந்தேகநபர் 6 கிலோவுக்கும் அதிகமான கேரள கஞ்சா கேரளா கஞ்சா வைத்திருந்தார்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர் கிருலப்பனை பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர் எனவும், அவரும் கேரள கஞ்சாவும் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக கிருலப்பனை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருலப்பனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6 க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஞ்சா கேரளா கஞ்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிருலப்பனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருலப்பனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}