{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/25/delayed-super-diesel-cargo-being-unloaded-distribution-to-continue-tonight/",
  "time_ut": 1661427600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Delayed Super Diesel cargo being unloaded, distribution to continue tonight",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Delayed Super Diesel cargo being unloaded, distribution to continue tonight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka's Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera said that there was a delay in unloading the super diesel cargo on Wednesday (24) due to bank clearances.",
        "He said that the unloading commenced on Thursday (25) afternoon.",
        "\"Auto Diesel cargo arriving tonight (25) will commence unloading tomorrow (26). CPSTL Distribution will continue during the night today to make up for the delays,\" tweeted the Minister.",
        "There was a delay in unloading the super diesel cargo yesterday due to bank clearances & discharging has commenced an hour ago. Auto Diesel cargo arriving tonight will commence unloading tomorrow. CPSTL Distribution will continue during the night today to make up for the delays.",
        "Delayed Super Diesel cargo being unloaded, distribution to continue tonight",
        "Time for Ranil to fulfil pledge on repealing PTA made five years ago – Sumanthiran",
        "Deputy Police Chief testifies in probe on assault on journalists",
        "Multiple unapproved Fuel Storage Tanks at business premises – Kanchana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Delayed Super Diesel",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tonight",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "bank clearances & discharging",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an hour ago",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delayed Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fuel Storage Tanks",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑම, බෙදා හැරීම අද රාත්‍රියේ සිදු කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බැංකු නිෂ්කාශන හේතුවෙන් බදාදා (24) සුපර් ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑමේ ප්‍රමාදයක් සිදුවූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බ‍්‍රහස්පතින්දා (25) පස්වරුවේ ගොඩබෑම ආරම්භ කළ බවයි ඔහු කියා සිටියේ.",
        "\"අද (25) රාත්‍රියේ පැමිණෙන ඔටෝ ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑම හෙට (26) ආරම්භ වේ. ප්‍රමාදය පියවා ගැනීම සඳහා CPSTL බෙදා හැරීම අද රාත්‍රියේදී සිදු කෙරේ,\" අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "බැංකු නිෂ්කාශන හේතුවෙන් ඊයේ සුපර් ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑමේ ප්‍රමාදයක් සිදුවී පැයකට පෙර නිකුත් කිරීම ආරම්භ කර ඇත. අද රාත්‍රියේ පැමිණෙන ඔටෝ ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑම හෙට සිට ආරම්භ කෙරේ. ප්‍රමාදයන් පියවා ගැනීම සඳහා CPSTL බෙදාහැරීම අද රාත්‍රියේ දිගටම සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල් භාණ්ඩ ගොඩබෑම, බෙදා හැරීම අද රාත්‍රියේ සිදු කෙරේ",
        "වසර පහකට පෙර දුන් ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අහෝසි කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඥාව ඉටු කිරීමට රනිල්ට කාලයයි - සුමන්තිරන්",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියේ විමර්ශනයේදී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති සාක්ෂි දෙයි",
        "ව්‍යාපාරික ස්ථානවල අනුමත නොකළ ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි කිහිපයක් - කාංචන"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද රෑ",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකු නිෂ්කාශන සහ විසර්ජන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයකට කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමාද වූ සුපර් ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන ගබඩා ටැංකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல் சரக்குகள் இறக்கப்படும், விநியோகம் இன்று இரவு தொடரும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வங்கி அனுமதிகள் காரணமாக சுப்பர் டீசல் சரக்குகளை இறக்குவதில் புதன்கிழமை (24) தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டதாக இலங்கையின் மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வியாழக்கிழமை (25) பிற்பகல் இறக்கும் பணி ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இன்று (25) இரவு வரும் ஆட்டோ டீசல் சரக்குகள் நாளை (26) இறக்கத் தொடங்கும். தாமதத்தை ஈடுசெய்ய இன்று இரவு CPSTL விநியோகம் தொடரும்\" என்று அமைச்சர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "வங்கி அனுமதி காரணமாக நேற்று சூப்பர் டீசல் சரக்குகளை இறக்குவதில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டது மற்றும் ஒரு மணி நேரத்திற்கு முன்பே வெளியேற்றப்பட்டது. இன்று இரவு வரும் ஆட்டோ டீசல் சரக்குகள் நாளை இறக்கும் பணி தொடங்கும். CPSTL விநியோகம் தாமதத்தை ஈடுசெய்ய இன்று இரவில் தொடரும்.",
        "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல் சரக்குகள் இறக்கப்படும், விநியோகம் இன்று இரவு தொடரும்",
        "பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தை நீக்குவது தொடர்பான உறுதிமொழியை ரணில் நிறைவேற்றும் தருணம் ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் – சுமந்திரன்",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பான விசாரணையில் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சாட்சியமளித்தார்",
        "வணிக வளாகத்தில் பல அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாத எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகள் - காஞ்சனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்றிரவு",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி அனுமதி மற்றும் வெளியேற்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம் முன்பு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாமதமான சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் சேமிப்பு தொட்டிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}