{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79031",
  "time_ut": 1660763160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa Likely to Return to Sri Lanka on Aug 25th From Thailand; will be Provided House and Security by State as a former President is entitled to; wants to go back to California after obtaining  US Green Card",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa Likely to Return to Sri Lanka on Aug 25th From Thailand; will be Provided House and Security by State as a former President is entitled to; wants to go back to California after obtaining  US Green Card",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who fled the country last month amidst public protests calling for his resignation, is awaiting to obtain a US Green Card to return back to the United States and settle there with his wife and son, the Daily Mirror learns.",
        "Highly placed sources said that Rajapaksa’s lawyers in the United States had already begun the procedure last month for his application to obtain the Green Card as he was eligible to apply due to his wife Ioma Rajapaksa being a US citizen.",
        "The procedure will also now involve his lawyers in Colombo submitting the additional documents here in order to go ahead with the procedure.",
        "The former President who is presently in a hotel in Thailand along with his wife will return back to Sri Lanka on Aug. 25, cancelling his initial plan to remain in Thailand at least till November.",
        "Sources said that two days ago, Rajapaksa had consulted his lawyers and had decided to return back to Sri Lanka later this month as he was not allowed the freedom to move in Thailand as initially expected, due to security concerns.",
        "Upon his arrival in Bangkok, Thai police had advised the ousted President to remain indoors for security reasons.",
        "Foreign Media reports said that at the hotel, the location of which has not been disclosed, plainclothes police officers from the Special Branch Bureau had been deployed to ensure the safety of Rajapaksa. Officials had asked the former Sri Lankan president to remain within the hotel during his stay in the country.",
        "Upon his arrival back to Sri Lanka this month, the cabinet will discuss to provide Rajapaksa a state house and security accorded to a former President.",
        "Rajapaksa fled for Maldives last month and thereafter to Singapore. He entered Singapore on a medical visa and had it extended twice to remain there as much as possible. As his visa could not be extended further, Rajapaksa and his wife left for Thailand and was assured he could remain there till he finalizes his third destination.",
        "However with his movements now restricted in Thailand, he will return back to the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa Likely",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aug 25th",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thailand",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "California",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Green Card",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Green Card",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Green Card",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aug. 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "later this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Foreign Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Branch Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තායිලන්තයේ සිට අගෝස්තු 25 වැනිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට ඉඩ තිබේ. හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට හිමිවන පරිදි රාජ්‍යය විසින් නිවස සහ ආරක්ෂාව ලබා දෙනු ඇත; US Green Card ලබා ගැනීමෙන් පසු නැවත කැලිෆෝනියාවට යාමට අවශ්‍යයි",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට ජනතා විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ පසුගිය මාසයේ රටින් පැන ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ යළි ඇමරිකාවට පැමිණ සිය බිරිඳ සහ පුත්‍රයා සමඟ එහි පදිංචි වීම සඳහා ඇමරිකානු හරිත කාඩ්පතක් ලබා ගැනීමට බලා සිටින බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ ඇමරිකානු පුරවැසිභාවය ලබා සිටින නිසා අයදුම් කිරීමට සුදුසුකම් ලබා ඇති බැවින් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සිටින රාජපක්ෂගේ නීතීඥයින් හරිත කාඩ්පත ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා අයදුම් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය පසුගිය මාසයේ සිට ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව ඉහළ පෙළේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ක්‍රියාපටිපාටිය ඉදිරියට යාමට කොළඹ සිටින ඔහුගේ නීතීඥයින් විසින් අතිරේක ලේඛන මෙහි ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම ද දැන් ක්‍රියා පටිපාටියට ඇතුළත් වනු ඇත.",
        "මේ වන විට සිය බිරිඳ සමඟ තායිලන්තයේ හෝටලයක සිටින හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා අවම වශයෙන් නොවැම්බර් මාසය දක්වා තායිලන්තයේ රැඳී සිටීමේ මූලික සැලසුම අවලංගු කර අගෝස්තු 25 වැනිදා නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙනු ඇත.",
        "මීට දින දෙකකට පෙර රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය නීතීඥවරුන්ගෙන් උපදෙස් ලබාගෙන ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත මුලින් අපේක්ෂා කළ පරිදි තායිලන්තයේ පදිංචියට යාමට නිදහස ලබා නොදුන් බැවින් මේ මස අගදී යළි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට තීරණය කළ බව ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "බැංකොක් නුවරට පැමිණීමත් සමඟ තායි පොලිසිය විසින් බලයෙන් පහකළ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත නිවෙස් තුළම සිටින ලෙස උපදෙස් දී තිබුණි.",
        "විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේ, එම හෝටලය පිහිටි ස්ථානය අනාවරණය කර නොමැති අතර, රාජපක්ෂගේ ආරක්ෂාව සඳහා විශේෂ ශාඛා කාර්යාංශයේ සිවිල් ඇඳුමින් සැරසුණු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් යොදවා තිබූ බවයි. හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙරට රැඳී සිටින කාලය තුළ හෝටලය තුළම රැඳී සිටින ලෙස නිලධාරීන් දන්වා තිබුණි.",
        "ඔහු මේ මාසයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට ලබා දී ඇති රාජ්‍ය නිවසක් සහ ආරක්ෂාවක් ලබාදීමට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය සාකච්ඡා කරනු ඇත.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ පසුගිය මාසයේ මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගිය අතර ඉන් පසුව සිංගප්පූරුවට ගියේය. ඔහු වෛද්‍ය වීසා මත සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වූ අතර හැකිතාක් එහි රැඳී සිටීමට එය දෙවරක් දීර්ඝ කර ඇත. ඔහුගේ වීසා බලපත්‍රය තවදුරටත් දීර්ඝ කිරීමට නොහැකි වූ හෙයින්, රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ තායිලන්තය බලා පිටත්ව ගිය අතර, ඔහුගේ තුන්වන ගමනාන්තය අවසන් කරන තෙක් ඔහුට එහි රැඳී සිටිය හැකි බවට සහතික විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, දැන් තායිලන්තයේ ඔහුගේ ගමන් බිමන් සීමා කර ඇති හෙයින්, ඔහු නැවත රටට පැමිණෙනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ වෙන්න ඇති",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 25",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තායිලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කැලිෆෝනියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හරිත කාඩ්පත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත කාඩ්පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත කාඩ්පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකකට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මාසයේ පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශීය මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ ශාඛා කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து ஆகஸ்ட் 25ஆம் தேதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கை திரும்புவார். ஒரு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு உரிமையுள்ளதால், மாநிலத்தால் வீடு மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு வழங்கப்படும்; அமெரிக்க கிரீன் கார்டைப் பெற்ற பிறகு மீண்டும் கலிபோர்னியா செல்ல விரும்புகிறார்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த மாதம் தாம் பதவி விலகக் கோரி பொதுமக்களின் எதிர்ப்புக்களுக்கு மத்தியில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, மீண்டும் அமெரிக்காவுக்குச் சென்று தனது மனைவி மற்றும் மகனுடன் அங்கு குடியேற அமெரிக்க கிரீன் கார்டைப் பெறுவதற்கு காத்திருப்பதாக டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அவரது மனைவி அயோமா ராஜபக்ச அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமை பெற்றுள்ளதால், கிரீன் கார்டு பெறுவதற்கான விண்ணப்பத்தை அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள ராஜபக்சேவின் வழக்கறிஞர்கள் கடந்த மாதமே தொடங்கிவிட்டதாக உயர்மட்ட வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "இந்த நடைமுறையில் இப்போது கொழும்பில் உள்ள அவரது வழக்கறிஞர்கள் கூடுதல் ஆவணங்களை இங்கு சமர்ப்பித்து நடைமுறையை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வதை உள்ளடக்கும்.",
        "தற்போது தனது மனைவியுடன் தாய்லாந்தில் உள்ள ஹோட்டலில் இருக்கும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி, நவம்பர் மாதம் வரை தாய்லாந்தில் தங்குவதற்கான தனது ஆரம்ப திட்டத்தை ரத்து செய்துவிட்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 25 ஆம் தேதி மீண்டும் இலங்கை திரும்புவார்.",
        "இரண்டு நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு, ராஜபக்சே தனது வழக்கறிஞர்களுடன் கலந்தாலோசித்ததாகவும், பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக தாய்லாந்தில் முதலில் எதிர்பார்த்தபடி சுதந்திரம் செல்ல அனுமதிக்கப்படாததால், இந்த மாத இறுதியில் இலங்கை திரும்ப முடிவு செய்ததாகவும் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "பாங்காக் வந்தடைந்தவுடன், தாய்லாந்து பொலிஸ் பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதியை வீட்டுக்குள்ளேயே இருக்குமாறு அறிவுறுத்தியது.",
        "அந்த ஹோட்டலின் இருப்பிடம் வெளியிடப்படாத நிலையில், ராஜபக்சேவின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக சிறப்புப் பிரிவுப் பணியகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சிவில் உடையில் போலீஸ் அதிகாரிகள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டில் தங்கியிருக்கும் போது ஹோட்டலிலேயே தங்குமாறு அதிகாரிகள் கேட்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "அவர் இம்மாதம் இலங்கைக்கு திரும்பியதும், ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு அரச இல்லம் மற்றும் முன்னாள் அதிபர் ஒருவருக்கு வழங்கப்படும் பாதுகாப்பை வழங்குவது குறித்து அமைச்சரவை ஆலோசிக்கவுள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்சே கடந்த மாதம் மாலத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்று அதன் பிறகு சிங்கப்பூருக்குத் தப்பிச் சென்றார். மருத்துவ விசாவில் சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழைந்த அவர், முடிந்தவரை அங்கேயே இருக்க இரண்டு முறை நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டார். அவரது விசாவை மேலும் நீட்டிக்க முடியாததால், ராஜபக்சேவும் அவரது மனைவியும் தாய்லாந்திற்குச் சென்றனர், மேலும் அவர் தனது மூன்றாவது இலக்கை இறுதி செய்யும் வரை அவர் அங்கேயே இருக்க முடியும் என்று உறுதியளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இருப்பினும் தாய்லாந்தில் அவரது நடமாட்டம் தற்போது கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், அவர் நாடு திரும்புவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வாய்ப்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 25",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கலிபோர்னியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பச்சை அட்டை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பச்சை அட்டை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பச்சை அட்டை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு கிளை பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}