{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83772/cbsl-chief-confident-sri-lanka-can-overcome-economic-crisis-within-5-months",
  "time_ut": 1658326260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CBSL chief confident Sri Lanka can overcome economic crisis within 5 months",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CBSL chief confident Sri Lanka can overcome economic crisis within 5 months",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe says he is confident that Sri Lanka can come out of this severe economic crisis within a period of 05 months. “We have a clear program and a clear path,” he added.",
        "In an interview with CNN, the governor said, Sri Lanka will, however, experience a difficult time until then.",
        "If Sri Lanka has a stable administration from tomorrow onwards, we can make strong decisions by the administration, Dr. Weerasinghe pointed out. Sri Lanka parliament voted in acting-President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the new Head of State in a vote held earlier today. He will take oaths tomorrow.",
        "Speaking further, the CBSL governor said he is hopeful that people would be patient until Sri Lanka can ride out the crisis situation over the next couple of months.",
        "When asked if he agrees with President-elect Ranil Wickremesinghe’s claims that the previous government was covering up facts about the country’s crippling financial crisis, Dr. Weerasinghe said, as the governor is it not appropriate of him to comment political matters.",
        "With regard to how concerning the country’s current situation is, the governor said the liquid resources in the central bank are almost “non-existent” because these resources had to be utilized to support the import of some shipments of petroleum products and LP gas supplies.",
        "Owing to this, Sri Lanka has managed to secure some shipments of petrol and diesel for the next couple of weeks, Dr. Weerasinghe said further. Beyond that, it is in fact the responsibility of the new government to secure some short-term bridging financing to finance the import of essentials until the country receives the bailout package from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), he added.",
        "Starting from the next month, Sri Lanka will negotiate some bridging financing facilities from friendly countries such as India and China, the governor continued. “So we need the new administration to start approaching these friendly countries to secure short-term financing so that we are able to supply essential items to the people to continue their day-to-day lives smoothly.”",
        "When asked about the financial support extended by India and China, the governor said he is hopeful that India would continue to support. However, it depends on the new administration’s negotiations and talks with the neighbouring country, he explained. According to the governor, Sri Lanka has also made some requests from China on relaxing some of the conditions in a swap facility.",
        "If India and China agree to continue to support the island nation, the situation can be improved until IMF’s bailout package is made available, Dr. Weerasinghe added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "5 months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next couple of months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next couple of weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මාස 5ක් ඇතුළත ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදිය හැකි බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ ප්‍රධානියා විශ්වාස කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසන්නේ මාස 05ක කාලයක් තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මෙම උග්‍ර ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට හැකිවනු ඇති බවට තමා විශ්වාස කරන බවයි. “අපට පැහැදිලි වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සහ පැහැදිලි මාවතක් තිබෙනවා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එතෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දුෂ්කර කාලයක් අත්විඳින බව CNN සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "හෙට සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ස්ථාවර පාලනයක් තිබේ නම් පරිපාලනයට දැඩි තීන්දු තීරණ ගත හැකි බවද ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නව රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස පත් කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද පෙරවරු 10ට පැවැති ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ඔහු හෙට දිවුරුම් දෙයි.",
        "එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දැක්වූ මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ ඉදිරි මාස දෙක තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයෙන් මිදීමට හැකි වන තෙක් ජනතාව ඉවසීමෙන් කටයුතු කරනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවයි.",
        "පසුගිය රජය රට අබලන් වී ඇති මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය පිළිබඳ කරුණු වසන් කළ බවට පත් වූ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කරන ප්‍රකාශවලට ඔබ එකඟ දැයි ඇසූ විට ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේ ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා දේශපාලන කරුණු සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දැක්වීම සුදුසු නොවන බවයි.",
        "රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, මහ බැංකුවේ ද්‍රව සම්පත් පාහේ “නොපවතින” බව ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා පැවසුවේ, ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන සහ එල්පී ගෑස් සැපයුම් සමහර නැව්ගත කිරීම් සඳහා ආනයනය කිරීමට සහාය වීමට මෙම සම්පත් භාවිතා කළ යුතු බැවිනි.",
        "මේ හේතුවෙන් ඉදිරි සති දෙක තුළ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් කිහිපයක් සුරක්ෂිත කර ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමත් වී ඇති බව ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. ඉන් ඔබ්බට, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් (IMF) ඇපදීමේ පැකේජය රටට ලැබෙන තෙක් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීමට මුදල් සැපයීම සඳහා කෙටි කාලීන පාලම් මූල්‍යකරණයක් ලබා ගැනීම ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම නව රජයේ වගකීම බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඉදිරි මාසයේ සිට, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය වැනි මිත්‍ර රටවල් වලින් යම් පාලම් මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් ලබා ගැනීමට සාකච්ඡා කරන බව ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා තවදුරටත් පැවසීය. \"එබැවින් අපට නව පරිපාලනය අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ කෙටි කාලීන මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා මෙම මිත්‍ර රටවල් වෙත ප්‍රවේශ වීම ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා වන අතර එමඟින් ජනතාවට ඔවුන්ගේ එදිනෙදා ජීවිතය සුමටව කරගෙන යාමට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ සැපයීමට අපට හැකි වේ.\"",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය විසින් ලබා දෙන මූල්‍ය ආධාර පිළිබඳව විමසූ විට ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා පැවසුවේ ඉන්දියාව තවදුරටත් සහාය දෙනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එය නව පරිපාලනයේ සාකච්ඡා සහ අසල්වැසි රට සමඟ සාකච්ඡා මත රඳා පවතී, ඔහු පැහැදිලි කළේය. ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයාට අනුව, හුවමාරු පහසුකමක කොන්දේසි කිහිපයක් ලිහිල් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලීම් කිහිපයක් කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය දූපත් ජාතියට අඛණ්ඩව සහය දැක්වීමට එකඟ වන්නේ නම්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ඇපදීමේ පැකේජය ලබා දෙන තෙක් තත්වය වැඩිදියුණු කළ හැකි බව ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාස 5 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාල සීමාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 05 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை 5 மாதங்களுக்குள் சமாளிக்க முடியும் என CBSL தலைவர் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் (CBSL) ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, இந்த கடுமையான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து 05 மாத காலப்பகுதிக்குள் இலங்கை மீள முடியும் என நம்புவதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார். \"எங்களிடம் தெளிவான வேலைத்திட்டம் மற்றும் தெளிவான பாதை உள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "சிஎன்என் தொலைக்காட்சிக்கு வழங்கிய நேர்காணலில், அதுவரை இலங்கை கடினமான காலத்தை அனுபவிக்கும் என்று ஆளுநர் கூறினார்.",
        "நாளை முதல் இலங்கையில் ஸ்திரமான நிர்வாகம் அமையுமானால் நிர்வாகத்தின் மூலம் வலுவான தீர்மானங்களை எடுக்க முடியும் எனவும் கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார். இலங்கையின் புதிய அரச தலைவராக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பில் இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இன்று வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டது. அவர் நாளை பதவியேற்கிறார்.",
        "மேலும் பேசிய CBSL ஆளுநர், அடுத்த இரண்டு மாதங்களில் இலங்கை நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்து சவாரி செய்யும் வரை மக்கள் பொறுமையாக இருப்பார்கள் என்று நம்புவதாக கூறினார்.",
        "நாட்டின் முடங்கும் நிதி நெருக்கடி குறித்த உண்மைகளை கடந்த அரசாங்கம் மூடி மறைத்து வருவதாக ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கூற்றுகளுடன் நீங்கள் உடன்படுகிறீர்களா என வினவிய போது, ​​கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க, ஆளுநராக அரசியல் விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவிப்பது பொருத்தமானதல்ல.",
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையைப் பொறுத்தவரை, மத்திய வங்கியில் திரவ வளங்கள் கிட்டத்தட்ட \"இல்லாதவை\" என்று ஆளுநர் கூறினார், ஏனெனில் இந்த வளங்கள் பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள் மற்றும் எல்பி எரிவாயு விநியோகங்களின் சில ஏற்றுமதிகளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய பயன்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "இதன் காரணமாக, அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு பெற்றோல் மற்றும் டீசலின் சில ஏற்றுமதிகளை இலங்கை பாதுகாக்க முடிந்துள்ளதாக டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். அதற்கு அப்பால், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடமிருந்து (IMF) நாடு பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதியைப் பெறும் வரை அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் இறக்குமதிக்கு நிதியளிப்பதற்காக சில குறுகிய கால பிணைப்பு நிதியைப் பெறுவது உண்மையில் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் பொறுப்பாகும்.",
        "அடுத்த மாதம் முதல், இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனா போன்ற நட்பு நாடுகளிடம் இருந்து சில பாலம் நிதி வசதிகளை இலங்கை பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தும், ஆளுநர் தொடர்ந்தார். \"எனவே புதிய நிர்வாகம் குறுகிய கால நிதியுதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கு இந்த நட்பு நாடுகளை அணுகத் தொடங்க வேண்டும், இதன் மூலம் மக்களுக்கு அவர்களின் அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையை சீராக தொடர அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களை நாங்கள் வழங்க முடியும்.\"",
        "இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவின் நிதியுதவி குறித்து கேட்டபோது, ​​இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று நம்புவதாக ஆளுநர் கூறினார். எவ்வாறாயினும், இது புதிய நிர்வாகத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் மற்றும் அண்டை நாட்டுடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளைப் பொறுத்தது என்று அவர் விளக்கினார். ஆளுநரின் கூற்றுப்படி, இடமாற்று வசதியில் சில நிபந்தனைகளைத் தளர்த்துவது குறித்து இலங்கையும் சீனாவிடம் சில கோரிக்கைகளை முன்வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "தீவு தேசத்திற்கு தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்க இந்தியாவும் சீனாவும் ஒப்புக்கொண்டால், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதி கிடைக்கும் வரை நிலைமையை மேம்படுத்த முடியும் என்று டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "5 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}