{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/06/hirunika-several-others-arrested-for-protesting-outside-presidents-house/",
  "time_ut": 1657094280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hirunika & several others arrested for protesting outside President’s House",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika & several others arrested for protesting outside President’s House",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Former Parliamentarian Hirunika Premachandara and six others were arrested by police for protesting outside the President’s House in Fort, Colombo on Wednesday (6).",
        "Hirnuka Premachandra led a protest on Wednesday (6) morning demanding the immediate resignation of the president and blamed his government for the present crisis.",
        "News 1st correspondent Vindana Prasad who was reporting from site said the group started protesting from Chatham Street Colombo and then proceeded to the President’s House.",
        "Hirunika & several others arrested for protesting outside President’s House",
        "Nimal Siripala resigns as Minister of Ports, Shipping, and aviation",
        "Finance Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe must RESIGN – Min. Dhammika Perera"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hirunika &",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirnuka Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vindana Prasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chatham Street Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shipping",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ හිරුණිකා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීනී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය ඇතුළු 06 දෙනෙකු බදාදා (6) කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වීම හේතුවෙන් පොලිස් අත්අඩංගුවට පත් විය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා වහා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් බදාදා (6) පෙරවරුවේ උද්ඝෝෂණ ව්‍යාපාරයක් පැවැත්වූ හිරුනුක ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහතා වත්මන් අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තම රජයට දොස් පැවරීය.",
        "එම ස්ථානයෙන් වාර්තා කළ News 1st වාර්තාකරු වින්දන ප්‍රසාද් කියා සිටියේ මෙම පිරිස කොළඹ චැතම් වීදියෙන් විරෝධතාවයක් ආරම්භ කර අනතුරුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය වෙත ගිය බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ හිරුණිකා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
        "නිමල් සිරිපාල වරාය, නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි – මිනි. ධම්මික පෙරේරා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hirunika &",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණක ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වින්දන ප්‍රසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ චැතම් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு வெளியே ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட ஹிருணிகா மற்றும் பலர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர உள்ளிட்ட 6 பேர் புதன்கிழமை (6) கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு வெளியே ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதற்காக பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியை உடனடியாக இராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு கோரியும் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு அவரது அரசாங்கத்தை குற்றம் சாட்டியும் ஹிர்னுக பிரேமச்சந்திர புதன்கிழமை (6) காலை ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் ஒன்றை நடத்தினார்.",
        "கொழும்பு சாத்தம் தெருவில் இருந்து ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை ஆரம்பித்து பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு சென்றதாக அந்த தளத்தில் இருந்து செய்திகளை வெளியிட்ட நியூஸ் 1ஸ்ட் செய்தியாளர் விந்தன பிரசாத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு வெளியே ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட ஹிருணிகா மற்றும் பலர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
        "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் பதவியை நிமல் சிறிபால இராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளார்",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவி விலக வேண்டும் – குறைந்தபட்சம். தம்மிக்க பெரேரா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hirunika &",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிர்னுகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விந்தன பிரசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாத்தம் தெரு கொழும்பு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}