{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84451/chinese-research-ship-to-leave-sri-lanka-today",
  "time_ut": 1661148120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese research ship to leave Sri Lanka today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese research ship to leave Sri Lanka today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Chinese high-tech research vessel ‘Yuan Wang 5’, which had arrived in the island last week, is scheduled to leave for China again today (22).",
        "Accordingly, it has been informed that the ship will leave for China again at 4 pm today, said the Harbor Master Captain Nirmal Silva.",
        "The ship arrived at the Hambantota port on the 16th of August and it was allowed to dock at the port until today.",
        "The Yuan Wang 5 survey vessel is described by security analysts as the latest generation of China’s space-tracking ships capable of monitoring satellites, rockets and intercontinental ballistic missiles.",
        "The vessel with some 2,000 sailors on board has facilities to track satellites and intercontinental missiles.",
        "The stopover was initially scheduled for August 11, but was delayed at the request of the Sri Lankan government. According to reports, Sri Lanka had asked China to defer the visit following reported concerns expressed by India and the U.S.",
        "According to Sri Lanka’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Yuan Wang 5 was cleared to dock at Hambantota port from Tuesday to August 22 after the government “engaged in extensive consultations at a high level through diplomatic channels with all parties concerned.”",
        "After Sri Lanka asked it to defer the entry of the ship, China on August 8 reacting angrily said it was “completely unjustified” for certain countries to cite the so-called “security concerns” to pressure Colombo and “grossly interfere” in its internal affairs.",
        "Sri Lankan Foreign Ministry statement on August 13 said that Colombo held extensive consultations about “certain concerns”.",
        "Apparently, referring to Indian and US concerns over the ship with military applications berthing at the Hambantota port in the Indian Ocean, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said on August 17, “I want to stress again that the marine scientific research activities of the Yuan Wang-5 ship are consistent with international law and international customary practice.”",
        "“They do not affect the security and economic interests of any country and should not be obstructed by any third party,” he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nirmal Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "some 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday to August 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාව අද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටත්ව යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය සතියේ දිවයිනට පැමිණි ‘යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5’ නම් චීන අධි තාක්ෂණික පර්යේෂණ නෞකාව අද (22) යළි චීනය බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව එම නෞකාව අද පස්වරු 4ට යළි චීනය බලා පිටත්ව යන බව දන්වා ඇති බව වරාය මාස්ටර් කපිතාන් නිර්මාල් සිල්වා මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම නෞකාව අගෝස්තු මස 16 වන දින හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණි අතර අද දක්වා එය වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට අවසර ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව ආරක්ෂක විශ්ලේෂකයින් විසින් විස්තර කරනු ලබන්නේ චන්ද්‍රිකා, රොකට් සහ අන්තර් මහද්වීපික බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල නිරීක්ෂණය කළ හැකි චීනයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ නිරීක්ෂණ නෞකාවල නවතම පරම්පරාව ලෙසය.",
        "නැවියන් 2000ක් පමණ සිටින මෙම යාත්‍රාවට චන්ද්‍රිකා සහ අන්තර් මහද්වීපික මිසයිල නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීමට පහසුකම් ඇත.",
        "මෙම නැවතුම මුලින් අගෝස්තු 11 වැනිදාට නියමිතව තිබුණත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ඉල්ලීම මත එය ප්‍රමාද විය. වාර්තාවලට අනුව, ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය විසින් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද කනස්සල්ල හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සංචාරය කල් දමන ලෙස චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයට අනුව, යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 අඟහරුවාදා සිට අගෝස්තු 22 දක්වා හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට අවසර දෙනු ලැබුවේ “ආන්ඩුව අදාළ සියලු පාර්ශ්ව සමඟ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මාර්ග හරහා ඉහළ මට්ටමේ පුළුල් උපදේශනවල නිරත වීමෙන්” පසුවය.",
        "නෞකාව ඇතුළුවීම කල් දමන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉල්ලා සිටීමෙන් පසුව, අගෝස්තු 8 දා චීනය කෝපයෙන් ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ, කොළඹට බලපෑම් කිරීමට සහ එහි අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතුවලට “දරුණු ලෙස ඇඟිලි ගැසීමට” ඇතැම් රටවල් ඊනියා “ආරක්ෂක උත්සුකයන්” උපුටා දැක්වීම “සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම අසාධාරණ” බවයි. කටයුතු.",
        "අගෝස්තු 13 දා ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශය කියා සිටියේ කොළඹ “සමහර උත්සුකයන්” ගැන පුළුල් උපදේශන පැවැත්වූ බවයි.",
        "පෙනෙන විදිහට, ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලා ඇති මිලිටරි යෙදවුම් සහිත නෞකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියානු සහ එක්සත් ජනපද උත්සුකයන් ගැන සඳහන් කරමින්, චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක වැන්ග් වෙන්බින් අගෝස්තු 17 දා පැවසුවේ, “යුවාන් හි සාගර විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් බව මට නැවත අවධාරණය කිරීමට අවශ්‍යයි. වැන්ග්-5 නෞකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර නීතියට සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සිරිත් විරිත්වලට අනුකූල වේ.",
        "\"ඒවා කිසිම රටක ආරක්‍ෂාවට සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතාවලට බලපාන්නේ නැති අතර කිසිම තුන්වන පාර්ශ්වයකින් බාධා නොකළ යුතුයි\" ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 4",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිර්මාල් සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,000ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා සිට අගෝස්තු 22 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் இன்று இலங்கையிலிருந்து புறப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த வாரம் தீவை வந்தடைந்த சீன உயர் தொழில்நுட்ப ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல் ‘யுவான் வாங் 5’ இன்று (22) மீண்டும் சீனாவுக்குப் புறப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி இன்று மாலை 4 மணிக்கு மீண்டும் சீனா நோக்கி கப்பல் புறப்படும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக துறைமுக மாஸ்டர் கப்டன் நிர்மல் சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 16 ஆம் திகதி அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடைந்த இந்த கப்பல் இன்று வரை துறைமுகத்தில் தரித்து நிற்க அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆய்வுக் கப்பல், செயற்கைக்கோள்கள், ராக்கெட்டுகள் மற்றும் கண்டம் விட்டு கண்டம் பாயும் ஏவுகணைகளை கண்காணிக்கும் திறன் கொண்ட சீனாவின் விண்வெளி கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல்களின் சமீபத்திய தலைமுறை என பாதுகாப்பு ஆய்வாளர்களால் விவரிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஏறக்குறைய 2,000 மாலுமிகளைக் கொண்ட கப்பலில் செயற்கைக்கோள்கள் மற்றும் கண்டம் விட்டு கண்டம் பாயும் ஏவுகணைகளைக் கண்காணிக்கும் வசதிகள் உள்ளன.",
        "இந்த நிறுத்தம் முதலில் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி திட்டமிடப்பட்டது, ஆனால் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் தாமதமானது. இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் வெளிப்படுத்திய கவலைகளை அடுத்து, பயணத்தை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு இலங்கை சீனாவிடம் கேட்டுள்ளதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் கூற்றுப்படி, யுவான் வாங் 5 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 22 வரை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்துவதற்கு அனுமதியளிக்கப்பட்டது, அரசாங்கம் \"சம்பந்தப்பட்ட அனைத்து தரப்பினருடனும் இராஜதந்திர வழிகள் மூலம் உயர் மட்டத்தில் விரிவான ஆலோசனையில் ஈடுபட்டதன்\" பின்னர்.",
        "கப்பலின் பிரவேசத்தை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு இலங்கை கேட்டுக் கொண்டதை அடுத்து, ஆகஸ்ட் 8 அன்று சீனா கோபத்துடன் பதிலளித்தது, கொழும்பிற்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பதற்கும் அதன் உள் விவகாரங்களில் \"மொத்தமாக தலையிடுவதற்கும்\" சில நாடுகள் \"பாதுகாப்பு கவலைகள்\" என்று அழைக்கப்படுவதை மேற்கோள் காட்டுவது \"முற்றிலும் நியாயமற்றது\" என்று கூறியது. விவகாரங்கள்.",
        "\"சில கவலைகள்\" பற்றி கொழும்பு விரிவான ஆலோசனைகளை நடத்தியதாக ஆகஸ்ட் 13 அன்று இலங்கை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் உள்ள ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் ராணுவ பயன்பாட்டுடன் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள கப்பல் குறித்த இந்திய மற்றும் அமெரிக்கா கவலைகளை குறிப்பிடுகையில், சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் வாங் வென்பின் ஆகஸ்ட் 17 அன்று, “யுவானின் கடல் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகள் என்பதை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்த விரும்புகிறேன். வாங்-5 கப்பல் சர்வதேச சட்டம் மற்றும் சர்வதேச பாரம்பரிய நடைமுறைக்கு இசைவானது.",
        "\"அவை எந்த நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களை பாதிக்காது மற்றும் எந்த மூன்றாம் தரப்பினராலும் தடுக்கப்படக்கூடாது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்மல் சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 22 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}