{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පෙට්‍රල්-ලීටර්-1400ක්-සමග-02ක්-මාට්ටූ/11-396397",
  "time_ut": 1660799303,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 1400ක් සමග 02ක් මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "02 with 1400 liters of petrol",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "1429 liters of petrol, which was being illegally transported from Halawata to Kalpitiya in a refrigerated lorry, was seized by the Norochchola Police and the Navy in Dalua area early today (18th).",
        "The driver and assistant of the lorry along with the fuel stock have also been arrested.",
        "According to the information received by the Navy, the arrest was made during an immediate roadblock operated by the Norochchola Police and the Navy.",
        "The two suspects, aged 26 and 29, are residents of Halawatha Mugunawatawana and Reedi Wella areas. It has been reported that they have been engaged in fuel smuggling for some time.",
        "The suspects are to be produced in Puttalam Magistrate's Court. Norochchola Police is conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "02",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1400",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1429",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawata to Kalpitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Norochchola Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "early today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Norochchola Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 and 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawatha Mugunawatawana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reedi Wella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam Magistrate's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochchola Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 1400ක් සමග 02ක් මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හලාවත සිට කල්පිටියට නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස,අධි ශීතාගාර ලොරියකින් ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 1429 ක්,නොරොච්චෝල පොලිසිය හා නාවුක හමුදාව විසින් දලුව ප්‍රදේශයේ දී අද (18දා) අලුයම අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ඉන්ධන තොගය සමග ලොරියේ රියදුරු සහ සහායකව ද අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "නාවුක හමුදාවට ලද තොරතුරකට අනුව,නොරොච්චෝල පොලිසිය හා නාවුක හමුදාව විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ ක්ෂණික මාර්ග  බාධකයකදී මෙම අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කොට ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා  අවුරුදු 26 සහ 29 වියේ පසුවන,හලාවත මුගුණවටවන සහ රීදී වැල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන් වෙති. කලක පටන් මොවුන් මෙම ඉන්ධන ජාවාරමේ නිරතව පසුවන බවට තොරතුරු අණාවරණය වී ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් පුත්තලම මහෙස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය.නොරොච්චෝල පොලිසිය වැඩි දුර පරීක්ෂණ මෙහෙයවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "02",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1400",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1429",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත සිට කල්පිටිය දක්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දලුවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද වේලාසනින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 සහ 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත මුගුණවටවන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රීඩි වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "1400 லிட்டர் பெட்ரோலுடன் 02",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹலவத்தையில் இருந்து கல்பிட்டிக்கு குளிரூட்டப்பட்ட லொறியில் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட 1429 லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் இன்று (18ஆம் திகதி) அதிகாலை தலுவா பகுதியில் வைத்து நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸார் மற்றும் கடற்படையினரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருட்களுடன் லொறியின் சாரதி மற்றும் உதவியாளரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் பிரகாரம், நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸாரும் கடற்படையினரும் இணைந்து மேற்கொண்ட உடனடி வீதித்தடையின் போது கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் 26 மற்றும் 29 வயதுடைய ஹலவத்த முகுனவடவன மற்றும் ரீடி வெல்ல பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்கள். இவர்கள் சில காலமாக எரிபொருள் கடத்தலில் ஈடுபட்டு வருவதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் புத்தளம் நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட உள்ளனர்.நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "02",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1400",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1429",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவத்த முதல் கல்பிட்டி வரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலுவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 மற்றும் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவத முகுனவதவன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரீடி வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் நீதவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}