{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SriLankan-Airlines-celebrates-43-years-of-flying/342-244091",
  "time_ut": 1661974300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SriLankan Airlines celebrates 43 years of flying",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SriLankan Airlines celebrates 43 years of flying",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "SriLankan Airlines has been the fabric of commercial aviation in Sri Lanka since the dawn of the airline 43 years ago. It was launched on 1 September 1979, and the airline’s greatest accomplishments, are often intertwined with Sri Lanka’s own milestones in aviation and tourism.",
        "SriLankan’s contribution to the economy of Sri Lanka as the country’s flag carrier cannot be understated. The airline has been the ultimate gateway between Sri Lanka and the world. With a current all-Airbus fleet of 24 aircraft, SriLankan has been connecting Sri Lankans to 119 cities in 60 countries across continents through direct and codeshare operations.",
        "Moreover, SriLankan Airlines is the only airline to operate direct flights between Colombo and several global power cities including London; Paris; Frankfurt; Melbourne; Sydney; and Tokyo, enabling socio-economic ties with these markets.",
        "SriLankan has also played a central role in introducing Sri Lanka and the country’s spectacular heritage to discerning international travellers. SriLankan has for nearly half a century helped bridge distances; position Sri Lanka as one of the most desired holiday destinations; and link millions of passengers to Colombo, Southern India and the Maldives with expedient connections. Over 95 per cent of passengers transiting via Bandaranaike International Airport are carried by SriLankan Airlines and SriLankan remains the most frequently booked airline to travel to Sri Lanka.",
        "The proof is in the numbers. Between 1979 and now, SriLankan has served over 89 million passenger journeys for both local and foreign passengers – a number that is equal to the population of Sri Lanka, four times over. The airline is, unquestionably, a key foreign currency earner for Sri Lanka as over 85 per cent of its revenue is earned in foreign currency from international markets.",
        "SriLankan Airlines has also powered economic activity across thes upply chain of the travel and tourism trade of Sri Lanka. This includes creating jobs and supporting the livelihoods, even if indirectly, for thousands employed in the sector. Consequently, it has been estimated that SriLankan Airlines makes a significant contribution to Sri Lanka’s gross domestic product.",
        "Aside from passenger services, strategic business units of the airline such as SriLankan Cargo and SriLankan Engineering have all progressively contributed to the organization and country.",
        "Reflecting on the significance of the airline to the country, Ashok Pathirage, Chairman of SriLankan Airlines stated, “For the past four decades, we have been flag bearers of the nation through thick and thin. SriLankan Airlines has not only prevailed through each challenging chapter that the country has had to navigate through, but endeavored to help the country back on its feet.",
        "From sustaining travel and trade links between Sri Lanka and the world as other airlines cut back on flights to Sri Lanka due to the country’s ongoing economic crisis to bringing down stranded Sri Lankans home during the thick of the pandemic in the recent past, SriLankan has always been a pillar of strength to the nation.",
        "The resilience of our legacy is really the resilience of our people, and I would like to thank every employee of SriLankan Airlines for their show of dedication and commitment that has seen us through difficult times.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43 years",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 September 1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airbus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Frankfurt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melbourne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sydney",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly half a century",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "holiday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern India",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "95 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Between 1979 and now",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 89 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cargo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Engineering",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ashok Pathirage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past four decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය පියාසර කර වසර 43ක් සපිරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර 43 කට පෙර ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය ආරම්භ වූ දා සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වාණිජ ගුවන් සේවා නිර්මාණය විය. එය 1979 සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වන දින දියත් කරන ලද අතර, ගුවන් සේවයේ විශිෂ්ටතම ජයග්‍රහණ බොහෝ විට ගුවන් සේවා සහ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේම සන්ධිස්ථාන සමඟ බද්ධ වී ඇත.",
        "රටේ ධජ වාහකයා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකයට ශ්‍රීලංකන් දක්වන දායකත්වය අවතක්සේරු කළ නොහැක. ගුවන් සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ලෝකය අතර ඇති අවසාන දොරටුවයි. දැනට ගුවන් යානා 24 කින් සමන්විත එයාර්බස් ඇණියක් සමඟින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකන් සෘජු සහ කේත හුවමාරු මෙහෙයුම් හරහා මහාද්වීප පුරා රටවල් 60 ක නගර 119 කට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සම්බන්ධ කර ඇත.",
        "එපමනක් නොව, කොළඹ සහ ලන්ඩන් ඇතුළු ගෝලීය බල නගර කිහිපයක් අතර සෘජු ගුවන් ගමන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන එකම ගුවන් සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමයි; පැරිස්; ෆ්රැන්ක්ෆර්ට්; මෙල්බර්න්; සිඩ්නි; සහ ටෝකියෝ, මෙම වෙළඳපල සමඟ සමාජ-ආර්ථික සබඳතා සක්‍රීය කරයි.",
        "විචක්ෂණශීලී ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරකයින්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ රටේ දර්ශනීය උරුමය හඳුන්වා දීම සඳහා ශ්‍රීලංකන් ප්‍රධාන භූමිකාවක් ද ඉටු කර ඇත. අඩ සියවසකට ආසන්න කාලයක් ශ්‍රීලංකන් දුර පාලම් සඳහා උපකාර කර ඇත; ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වඩාත් කැමති නිවාඩු ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස ස්ථානගත කිරීම; සහ කොළඹ, දකුණු ඉන්දියාව සහ මාලදිවයින වෙත මිලියන ගණනක් මගීන් ඉක්මන් සම්බන්ධතා සමඟ සම්බන්ධ කරයි. බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ හරහා සංක්‍රමණය වන මගීන්ගෙන් සියයට 95 කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් රැගෙන යන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය වන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගමන් කිරීම සඳහා වැඩිපුරම වෙන් කරවා ගන්නා ගුවන් සේවය ලෙස පවතී.",
        "සාක්ෂිය ඉලක්කම් වල ඇත. 1979 සිට මේ දක්වා කාලය තුළ ශ්‍රීලංකන් දෙස් විදෙස් මගීන් සඳහා මගී ගමන් මිලියන 89කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් සේවය කර ඇත - එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනගහනයට සමාන සංඛ්‍යාවක්, සිව් ගුණයකින් වැඩිය. ගුවන් සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රධාන විදේශ මුදල් උපයන්නෙක් බවට සැකයක් නැත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක සහ සංචාරක වෙළෙඳාමේ සැපයුම් දාමය හරහා ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ද බලගන්වා ඇත. මෙම අංශයේ රැකියා කරන දහස් ගණනකට වක්‍රව වුවද රැකියා උත්පාදනය කිරීම සහ ජීවනෝපාය සඳහා ආධාර කිරීම ඇතුළත් වේ. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයට සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් සපයන බවට ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇත.",
        "මගී සේවා හැරුණු විට, ශ්‍රීලංකන් කාගෝ සහ ශ්‍රීලංකන් ඉන්ජිනියරින් වැනි ගුවන් සමාගමේ උපාය මාර්ගික ව්‍යාපාරික ඒකක සියල්ල සංවිධානයට සහ රටට ප්‍රගතිශීලී දායකත්වයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ සභාපති අශෝක් පතිරගේ මහතා මෙරටට ගුවන් සේවයේ වැදගත්කම පිළිබඳව සිහිපත් කරමින්, “පසුගිය දශක හතරක කාලය තුළ අපි ඝන සහ කෙට්ටු හරහා ජාතියේ පතාක යෝධයන් වී සිටිමු. ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම රටට ගමන් කිරීමට සිදු වූ එක් එක් අභියෝගාත්මක පරිච්ජේදය හරහා ජයග්‍රහණය කළා පමණක් නොව, රට නැවතත් දෙපයින් තබා ගැනීමට උපකාර කිරීමට උත්සාහ කර ඇත.",
        "රටේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ලෝකය අතර සංචාර සහ වෙළඳ සබඳතා පවත්වාගෙන යාමේ සිට අනෙකුත් ගුවන් සමාගම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන ගුවන් ගමන් කපා හැරීමේ සිට මෑත අතීතයේ වසංගතයේ ඝණත්වය තුළ අතරමං වූ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ගෙදර ගෙන ඒම දක්වා ශ්‍රීලංකන් සැමවිටම ජාතියට ශක්තියක් විය.",
        "අපගේ උරුමයේ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව සැබවින්ම අපගේ ජනතාවගේ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව වන අතර දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී අප දුටු කැපවීම සහ කැපවීම ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ සෑම සේවකයෙකුටම මම ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 43 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 43 කට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 සැප්තැම්බර් 1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රෑන්ක්ෆර්ට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙල්බර්න්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිඩ්නි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩ සියවසකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවාඩු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 95 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1979 සිට මේ දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 89 ඉක්මවයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් භාණ්ඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ඉංජිනේරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අශෝක් පතිරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශක හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமான சேவையின் 43 வருடங்களை கொண்டாடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் 43 வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இலங்கையில் விமான சேவை ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து வர்த்தக விமானப் போக்குவரத்தை உருவாக்கியது. இது 1 செப்டெம்பர் 1979 இல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் விமான சேவையின் மிகப் பெரிய சாதனைகள், பெரும்பாலும் விமான போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் சுற்றுலாத்துறையில் இலங்கையின் சொந்த மைல்கற்களுடன் பின்னிப் பிணைந்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் கொடி ஏந்திய நாடாக இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கனின் பங்களிப்பை குறைத்து மதிப்பிட முடியாது. இலங்கைக்கும் உலகிற்கும் இடையிலான இறுதி நுழைவாயிலாக இந்த விமான சேவை விளங்குகிறது. 24 விமானங்களைக் கொண்ட தற்போதைய அனைத்து ஏர்பஸ் கடற்படையுடன், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் நேரடி மற்றும் குறியீட்டு பகிர்வு நடவடிக்கைகள் மூலம் கண்டங்கள் முழுவதும் 60 நாடுகளில் உள்ள 119 நகரங்களுக்கு இலங்கையர்களை இணைத்து வருகிறது.",
        "மேலும், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் கொழும்பு மற்றும் லண்டன் உட்பட பல உலகளாவிய சக்தி நகரங்களுக்கு இடையே நேரடி விமானங்களை இயக்கும் ஒரே விமான சேவையாகும்; பாரிஸ்; பிராங்பேர்ட்; மெல்போர்ன்; சிட்னி; மற்றும் டோக்கியோ, இந்த சந்தைகளுடன் சமூக-பொருளாதார உறவுகளை செயல்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை மற்றும் நாட்டின் கண்கவர் பாரம்பரியத்தை சர்வதேச பயணிகளுக்கு அறிமுகம் செய்வதிலும் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏறக்குறைய அரை நூற்றாண்டு காலமாக பாலம் தூரத்திற்கு உதவியது; மிகவும் விரும்பப்படும் விடுமுறை இடங்களுள் ஒன்றாக இலங்கையை நிலைநிறுத்தவும்; மற்றும் இலட்சக்கணக்கான பயணிகளை கொழும்பு, தென்னிந்தியா மற்றும் மாலத்தீவுகளுக்கு விரைவான இணைப்புகளுடன் இணைக்கிறது. பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் ஊடாக பயணிக்கும் பயணிகளில் 95 வீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமானோர் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் மூலம் பயணிக்கின்றனர் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கு செல்வதற்கு அடிக்கடி முன்பதிவு செய்யப்படும் விமான சேவையாக ஸ்ரீலங்கன் உள்ளது.",
        "ஆதாரம் எண்களில் உள்ளது. 1979 மற்றும் இப்போது வரை, ஸ்ரீலங்கன் உள்ளூர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு பயணிகளுக்காக 89 மில்லியன் பயணிகள் பயணங்களைச் செய்துள்ளது - இது இலங்கையின் மக்கள்தொகைக்கு சமமான எண்ணிக்கை, நான்கு மடங்கு அதிகமாகும். விமான நிறுவனம், சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமின்றி, இலங்கைக்கு வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தை ஈட்டித்தரும் முக்கிய நிறுவனமாகும், ஏனெனில் அதன் வருவாயில் 85 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமானவை சர்வதேச சந்தைகளில் இருந்து வெளிநாட்டு நாணயத்தில் ஈட்டப்படுகின்றன.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் இலங்கையின் பயண மற்றும் சுற்றுலா வர்த்தகத்தின் விநியோகச் சங்கிலி முழுவதும் பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகளையும் ஆற்றியுள்ளது. இத்துறையில் பணிபுரியும் ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோருக்கு மறைமுகமாக இருந்தாலும் கூட வேலைகளை உருவாக்குவதும் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை ஆதரிப்பதும் இதில் அடங்கும். இதன் விளைவாக, இலங்கையின் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்களிப்பை வழங்குவதாக மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பயணிகள் சேவைகளைத் தவிர, ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கார்கோ மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் இன்ஜினியரிங் போன்ற விமான நிறுவனத்தின் மூலோபாய வணிக பிரிவுகள் அனைத்தும் நிறுவனத்திற்கும் நாட்டிற்கும் படிப்படியாக பங்களித்துள்ளன.",
        "நாட்டிற்கு விமான சேவையின் முக்கியத்துவத்தைப் பிரதிபலிக்கும் வகையில், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் தலைவர் அசோக் பத்திரகே, “கடந்த நான்கு தசாப்தங்களாக, நாங்கள் தடித்த மற்றும் மெல்லிய மூலம் தேசத்தின் கொடியை ஏந்தியவர்களாக இருந்தோம். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் நாடு கடந்து செல்ல வேண்டிய ஒவ்வொரு சவாலான அத்தியாயத்திலும் வெற்றி பெற்றது மட்டுமல்லாமல், நாட்டை மீண்டும் அதன் காலடியில் வைக்க உதவ முயற்சித்தது.",
        "இலங்கை மற்றும் உலக நாடுகளுக்கிடையிலான பயண மற்றும் வர்த்தக தொடர்புகளை பேணுவதில் இருந்து மற்றைய விமான நிறுவனங்கள் இலங்கையில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இலங்கைக்கான விமானங்களை குறைத்துக்கொண்டது முதல் சமீபகாலமாக தொற்றுநோய்களின் போது சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் இலங்கையர்களை வீட்டிற்கு அழைத்து வருவது வரை, ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எப்போதும் தேசத்தின் வலிமையின் தூணாக இருந்தது.",
        "எங்களுடைய பாரம்பரியத்தின் பின்னடைவு உண்மையில் எமது மக்களின் பின்னடைவு ஆகும், மேலும் கடினமான காலங்களில் எம்மைப் பார்த்த அர்ப்பணிப்பு மற்றும் அர்ப்பணிப்பை வெளிப்படுத்திய ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் ஒவ்வொரு பணியாளருக்கும் நான் நன்றி தெரிவிக்க விரும்புகிறேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43 ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 செப்டம்பர் 1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்பஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராங்பேர்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்போர்ன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிட்னி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட அரை நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுமுறை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "95 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1979 முதல் இப்போது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "89 மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சரக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொறியியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அசோக் பத்திரகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த நான்கு தசாப்தங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}