{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Exports-to-major-markets-record-strong-growth/273-239937",
  "time_ut": 1656358417,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Exports to major markets record strong growth",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Exports to major markets record strong growth",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s export performance in major markets witnessed a strong growth for the month of May, statistics from the Export Development Board (EDB) showed.",
        "In May 2022, exports to the United States, Sri Lanka’s single largest export destination, increased by 25.02 percent to US $ 266.42 million compared to the month of May 2021.",
        "The better performance was led by an increase in exports of apparel and textile (40.83 percent) and coconut-based products (29.69 percent).",
        "India emerged as the second largest export destination for May 2022, contributing US $ 82.51 million to the total revenue.",
        "Exports to the neighbouring giant increased by 49.26 percent when compared with May 2021.",
        "The United Kingdom became the third largest export destination, contributing US $ 78.22 million, which is an 8.20 growth YoY. On a cumulative basis, for the first five months of 2022 ending in May, the US remains the largest export destination, contributing to US $ 1.36 billion in earnings fetched (20.32 percent YoY growth). The UK ranked second, contributing US $ 411.62 million to the total export revenue earned for the period, whereas India ranks third, accounting for US $ 364.99 million of the total export earnings for the January-May 2022 period.  However, for the month of May and for the January to May 2022 period, exports to China dipped by 9.33 percent and 15.96 percent. Meanwhile, during the period of January to May 2022, exports to free trade agreement (FTA) partners accounted for 7.2 percent of total merchandise exports, which increased by 17.67 percent to US $ 398.98 million. Although exports to India increased, exports to Pakistan decreased by 6.75 percent to US $ 33.99 million during the said period. The region-wise comparison shows exports to all regions, except for the CIS countries, increased during the period of January to May 2022 compared with the corresponding period of 2021. Exports to the EU, South Asia, Africa and the Middle East increased in the month of May 2022 compared to May 2021."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Export Development Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25.02 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 266.42 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of May 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40.83 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.69 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 82.51 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "49.26 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 78.22 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first five months of 2022 ending in May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.36 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.32 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "YoY",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 411.62 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 364.99 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "January-May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the January to May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.33 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.96 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the period of January to May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.67 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 398.98 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.75 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 33.99 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the period of January to May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රධාන වෙලඳපොලවල් වෙත අපනයනය ශක්තිමත් වර්ධනයක් වාර්තා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රධාන වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයන කාර්ය සාධනය මැයි මාසය සඳහා ශක්තිමත් වර්ධනයක් පෙන්නුම් කළ බව අපනයන සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලයේ (EDB) සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "2022 මැයි මාසයේදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තනි විශාලතම අපනයන ගමනාන්තය වන එක්සත් ජනපදයට කරන ලද අපනයන 2021 මැයි මාසයට සාපේක්ෂව ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 266.42 දක්වා සියයට 25.02 කින් වැඩි විය.",
        "ඇඟලුම් සහ රෙදිපිළි අපනයනය (සියයට 40.83) සහ පොල් ආශ්‍රිත නිෂ්පාදන (සියයට 29.69) ඉහළ යාම මගින් වඩා හොඳ කාර්ය සාධනය හේතු විය.",
        "2022 මැයි මාසය සඳහා ඉන්දියාව දෙවන විශාලතම අපනයන ගමනාන්තය බවට පත් වූ අතර මුළු ආදායමට ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 82.51 ක දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "2021 මැයි මාසය හා සසඳන විට අසල්වැසි දැවැන්තයා වෙත අපනයනය සියයට 49.26 කින් වැඩි විය.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් මිලියන 78.22 ක දායකත්වයක් ලබා දෙමින් තුන්වන විශාලතම අපනයන ගමනාන්තය බවට පත් විය, එය වසර 8.20 ක වර්ධනයකි. සමුච්චිත පදනමක් මත, මැයි මාසයෙන් අවසන් වන 2022 පළමු මාස ​​පහ සඳහා, එක්සත් ජනපදය විශාලතම අපනයන ගමනාන්තය ලෙස පවතින අතර, ඉපැයූ ඉපැයීම් සඳහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.36 (ප්‍රතිශතයක් ලෙස 20.32% වර්ධනය) දායක වේ. 2022 ජනවාරි-මැයි කාලසීමාව සඳහා උපයාගත් මුළු අපනයන ආදායමට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 411.62 ක දායකත්වයක් ලබා දෙමින් එක්සත් රාජධානිය දෙවන ස්ථානයට පත්ව ඇති අතර ඉන්දියාව තෙවැනි ස්ථානයට පත්ව ඇති අතර එය 2022 ජනවාරි-මැයි කාලසීමාව සඳහා වූ මුළු අපනයන ආදායමෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 364.99 කි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මැයි මාසය සඳහා සහ 2022 ජනවාරි සිට මැයි දක්වා කාලය තුළ චීනය වෙත අපනයනය සියයට 9.33 කින් සහ සියයට 15.96 කින් පහත වැටී ඇත. මේ අතර, 2022 ජනවාරි සිට මැයි දක්වා කාලය තුළ නිදහස් වෙළඳ ගිවිසුම් (FTA) හවුල්කරුවන් වෙත අපනයනය සමස්ත වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ අපනයනයෙන් සියයට 7.2 ක් වූ අතර එය ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 398.98 ක් දක්වා සියයට 17.67 කින් වැඩි විය. ඉන්දියාවට අපනයනය ඉහළ ගියද, එම කාලය තුළ පකිස්තානයට කරන ලද අපනයන ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 33.99 දක්වා සියයට 6.75 කින් අඩු විය. කලාපීය වශයෙන් සැසඳීමේදී පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ 2021 වසරේ අනුරූප කාලපරිච්ඡේදය හා සසඳන විට CIS රටවල් හැර අනෙකුත් සියලුම කලාප වෙත අපනයනය 2022 ජනවාරි සිට මැයි දක්වා කාලය තුළ ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බවයි. 2021 මැයි මාසයට සාපේක්ෂව 2022 මැයි මාසය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයන සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 25.02 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 266.42 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මැයි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 40.83 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 29.69 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 82.51 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 49.26 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 78.22 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි මාසයෙන් අවසන් වන 2022 පළමු මාස ​​පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.36 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20.32 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "YoY",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 411.62 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 364.99 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි-මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි සිට මැයි දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 9.33 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15.96 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි සිට මැයි දක්වා කාලය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 7.2 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 17.67 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 398.98 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6.75 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 33.99 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි සිට මැයි දක්වා කාලය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முக்கிய சந்தைகளுக்கான ஏற்றுமதி வலுவான வளர்ச்சியைப் பதிவு செய்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதான சந்தைகளில் இலங்கையின் ஏற்றுமதி செயல்திறன் மே மாதத்திற்கான வலுவான வளர்ச்சியைக் கண்டுள்ளது என்று ஏற்றுமதி அபிவிருத்திச் சபையின் (EDB) புள்ளிவிபரங்கள் காட்டுகின்றன.",
        "மே 2022 இல், இலங்கையின் மிகப்பெரிய ஏற்றுமதி இலக்கான அமெரிக்காவுக்கான ஏற்றுமதிகள் 2021 மே மாதத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் 25.02 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து 266.42 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக இருந்தது.",
        "ஆடை மற்றும் ஜவுளி ஏற்றுமதி (40.83 சதவீதம்) மற்றும் தேங்காய் அடிப்படையிலான பொருட்கள் (29.69 சதவீதம்) ஆகியவை சிறந்த செயல்திறனுக்கு வழிவகுத்தன.",
        "மே 2022 இல் இந்தியா இரண்டாவது பெரிய ஏற்றுமதி இடமாக உருவெடுத்தது, மொத்த வருவாயில் 82.51 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை பங்களித்தது.",
        "மே 2021 உடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது அண்டை நிறுவனத்திற்கான ஏற்றுமதி 49.26 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "யுனைடெட் கிங்டம் மூன்றாவது பெரிய ஏற்றுமதி இடமாக ஆனது, 78.22 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை பங்களித்தது, இது 8.20 ஆண்டு வளர்ச்சியாகும். ஒட்டுமொத்த அடிப்படையில், மே மாதத்துடன் முடிவடையும் 2022 இன் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்களில், அமெரிக்கா மிகப்பெரிய ஏற்றுமதி இடமாக உள்ளது, இது 1.36 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் வருவாய் ஈட்டப்பட்டது (20.32 சதவீதம் ஆண்டு வளர்ச்சி). 2022 ஜனவரி முதல் மே வரையிலான மொத்த ஏற்றுமதி வருவாயில் 364.99 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைக் கணக்கில் கொண்டு, இந்த காலகட்டத்தில் ஈட்டிய மொத்த ஏற்றுமதி வருவாயில் 411.62 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை UK பங்களித்து இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தது. இருப்பினும், மே மாதம் மற்றும் ஜனவரி முதல் மே 2022 வரையிலான காலகட்டத்தில், சீனாவுக்கான ஏற்றுமதி 9.33 சதவீதம் மற்றும் 15.96 சதவீதம் குறைந்துள்ளது. இதற்கிடையில், ஜனவரி முதல் மே 2022 வரையிலான காலப்பகுதியில், தடையற்ற வர்த்தக ஒப்பந்தத்தின் (FTA) பங்காளிகளுக்கான ஏற்றுமதிகள் மொத்த வர்த்தகப் பொருட்களின் ஏற்றுமதியில் 7.2 சதவீதமாக இருந்தது, இது 17.67 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து 398.98 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக இருந்தது. இந்தியாவுக்கான ஏற்றுமதி அதிகரித்தாலும், பாகிஸ்தானுக்கான ஏற்றுமதி 6.75 சதவீதம் குறைந்து 33.99 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது. பிராந்திய வாரியான ஒப்பீடு, சிஐஎஸ் நாடுகளைத் தவிர, 2021 ஜனவரி முதல் மே வரையிலான காலகட்டத்தில், 2021ஆம் ஆண்டின் தொடர்புடைய காலகட்டத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில், அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளுக்கான ஏற்றுமதி அதிகரித்துள்ளது. மே 2021 உடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது 2022 மே மாதம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதி மேம்பாட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25.02 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 266.42 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 மே மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40.83 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.69 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 82.51 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "49.26 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 78.22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே மாதம் முடிவடையும் 2022 இன் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.36 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.32 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஒய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 411.62 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 364.99 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி-மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி முதல் மே 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.33 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.96 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி முதல் மே 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.67 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 398.98 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.75 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 33.99 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி முதல் மே 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 மே மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}