{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/registrar-general-dept-limits-services/",
  "time_ut": 1656430920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Registrar General Dept limits services",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Registrar General Dept limits services",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Registrar General’s Department has limited the issuance of birth, marriage, death and land certificates for just two days per week.",
        "In a statement, the Registrar General states that services provided by all Divisional Secretariats and District Registrar Divisions will be available on Mondays and Wednesdays only.",
        "Moreover, the services will only be available only from 8.30 AM to 4 PM.",
        "However, the District Registrar’s Divisions of the Divisional Secretariats of the Department at the Battaramulla Suhurupaya, Kurunegala, Kandy, Matara, Branch Offices of the Department of Immigration and Emigration will be kept open 5 days a week as usual."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Registrar General’s Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "just two days per week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Registrar General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divisional Secretariats",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mondays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesdays",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8.30 AM to 4 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the District Registrar’s Divisions of the Divisional Secretariats of the Department at the Battaramulla Suhurupaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සේවා සීමා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් උප්පැන්න, විවාහ, මරණ සහ ඉඩම් සහතික නිකුත් කිරීම සතියකට දින දෙකකට සීමා කර ඇත.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල්වරයා පවසන්නේ සියලුම ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාල සහ දිස්ත්‍රික් රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් කොට්ඨාශ මගින් සපයනු ලබන සේවාවන් සඳුදා සහ බදාදා දිනවල පමණක් පවතින බවයි.",
        "තවද, සේවාවන් ලබා ගත හැක්කේ පෙරවරු 8.30 සිට සවස 4 දක්වා පමණි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, බත්තරමුල්ල සුහුරුපාය, කුරුණෑගල, මහනුවර, මාතර යන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලවල දිස්ත්‍රික් රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් කොට්ඨාශ, ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ශාඛා කාර්යාල සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි සතියේ දින 5 විවෘතව තැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට දින දෙකක් පමණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදේ 8.30 සිට සවස 4 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල සුහුරුපායේ දී දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලවල දිස්ත්‍රික් රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් කොට්ඨාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 5 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரெஜிஸ்ட்ரார் ஜெனரல் டிபார்ட்மென்ட் வரம்புகள் சேவைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பதிவாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களம் பிறப்பு, திருமணம், இறப்பு மற்றும் காணிச் சான்றிதழ்கள் வழங்குவதை வாரத்திற்கு இரண்டு நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "அனைத்து பிரதேச செயலகங்கள் மற்றும் மாவட்ட பதிவாளர் பிரிவுகளினால் வழங்கப்படும் சேவைகள் திங்கள் மற்றும் புதன் கிழமைகளில் மட்டுமே வழங்கப்படும் என பதிவாளர் நாயகம் விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், சேவைகள் காலை 8.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4 மணி வரை மட்டுமே கிடைக்கும்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், திணைக்களத்தின் பத்தரமுல்ல சுஹுருபாய, குருநாகல், கண்டி, மாத்தறை ஆகிய பிரதேச செயலகங்களின் மாவட்ட பதிவாளர் பிரிவுகளும், குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் கிளை அலுவலகங்களும் வழமை போன்று வாரத்தில் 5 நாட்கள் திறந்திருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரத்திற்கு இரண்டு நாட்கள் மட்டுமே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 முதல் மாலை 4 மணி வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல சுஹுருபாயவில் உள்ள திணைக்களத்தின் பிரதேச செயலகங்களின் மாவட்ட பதிவாளர் பிரிவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}