{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78547",
  "time_ut": 1657714980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "The departure of . Gotabaya   Rajapaksa from rge Island  has not reduced the uncertainty prevailing in Sri Lanka because  the President is yet to officially resign, though he had promised to do so on Wednesday.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The departure of . Gotabaya   Rajapaksa from rge Island  has not reduced the uncertainty prevailing in Sri Lanka because  the President is yet to officially resign, though he had promised to do so on Wednesday.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the island and reached the nearby Maldives in the early hours of Wednesday, ahead of his promised resignation, days after enraged protesters overran his office and residence in a protest sparked by a devastating economic crisis.",
        "However, a top official in Maldives, who asked not to be named, citing “sensitivity” of the embattled leader’s arrival, told The Hindu that Mr. Gotabaya would “only transit” the country. Asked where the Sri Lankan leader was headed next, the source declined comment. Mr. Gotabaya’s final destination remains unclear.",
        "The United States refused a visa to him, while India has “categorically denied” facilitating travel of Mr. Gotabaya, or his younger brother and former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa.",
        "In a couple of tweets put out on Wednesday morning, the Indian High Commission in Colombo “reiterated” its support to the people of Sri Lanka, “as they seek to realise their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values, established democratic institutions and constitutional framework.”",
        "Sri Lanka Air Force (SLAF) confirmed that the President, First Lady and two bodyguards boarded an Air Force flight to the Maldives early on Wednesday. “In accordance with the powers vested in an Executive President in the Constitution of Sri Lanka, at the request of the existing Government, subject to the full approval of the Ministry of Defence, and subject to immigration, customs and all other laws at the Katunayake International Airport, the President along with the First Lady and two security guards departed on an Air Force flight to Maldives early this morning,” the SLAF said in a statement, of its services to Mr. Gotabaya, who holds the positions of Minister of Defence and Commander-in-Chief, until his likely resignation later on Wednesday.",
        "Media reports said the Maldives’s Parliamentary Speaker and former President Mohamed Nasheed received Mr. Gotabaya at the airport, but there is no official word from Male so far.",
        "Mr. Nasheed has maintained close friendships with all Sri Lankan leaders, across the political spectrum. In May, Sri Lankan Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe appointed Mr. Nasheed as the “coordinator” for securing foreign aid to Sri Lanka.",
        "Further, the Maldives and Sri Lanka are bound by strong ties and familial connections. Sri Lanka has often given refuge to Maldivian leaders in exile. Exactly 10 years ago, the wife and daughters of Mr. Nasheed fled to Colombo amid escalating violence in the Maldives.",
        "Media reports from 2012 quoted a spokesman of then President Mahinda Rajapaksa as saying: “President Rajapakse was concerned over the safety of Mr. Nasheed and his family”, while confirming their arrival in Sri Lanka.",
        "The departure of Mr. Gotabaya has not reduced the uncertainty prevailing in Sri Lanka. To start with, the President is yet to officially resign, though he has promised to do so on Wednesday.",
        "Mr. Gotabaya has not appointed the Prime Minister as acting President. In the event the President resigns, Sri Lanka’s Constitution provides for the Prime Minister to serve as acting President briefly, until the Parliament elects one of its members to the office of President, within one month from the date of the vacancy. If Mr. Wickremesinghe, too, resigns as per his pledge, the Speaker will serve as acting President until the Parliament elects a new President."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya   Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Island",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wednesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early hours of Wednesday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පිටත්වීම. rge Island හි සිට ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින අවිනිශ්චිතතාවය අඩු කර නැත්තේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පොරොන්දු වුවද නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී නොමැති බැවිනි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ පොරොන්දු වූ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර, බදාදා අලුයම දිවයිනෙන් පලා ගොස් අසල මාලදිවයිනට ළඟා වූයේ, විනාශකාරී ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකින් අවුලුවාලූ විරෝධතාවයකින් කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය සහ නිවස කඩාවැටීමෙන් දින කිහිපයකට පසුවය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මාලදිවයිනේ ප්‍රධාන නිලධාරියෙකු, නම සඳහන් නොකරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, ගැටුමට ලක් වූ නායකයාගේ පැමිණීමේ “සංවේදීභාවය” උපුටා දක්වමින්, ද හින්දු වෙත පැවසුවේ ගෝඨාභය මහතා රට “සංක්‍රමණය” පමණක් කරන බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයා මීළඟට යන්නේ කොතැනටදැයි ඇසූ විට මූලාශ්‍රය අදහස් දැක්වීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. ගෝඨාභය මහතාගේ අවසන් ගමනාන්තය තවමත් අපැහැදිලි ය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය ඔහුට වීසා බලපත්‍රයක් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති අතර, ඉන්දියාව ගෝඨාභය මහතාගේ හෝ ඔහුගේ බාල සොහොයුරා සහ හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ ගමන් පහසුකම් \"තදින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇත\".",
        "බදාදා උදෑසන නිකුත් කරන ලද ට්විටර් කිහිපයක, කොළඹ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට “ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ආයතන හරහා සෞභාග්‍යය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන විට ඔවුන්ට නැවත වරක්” තම සහයෝගය “නැවත අවධාරණය කළේය. සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා, ආර්යාව සහ ආරක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු බදාදා අලුයම මාලදිවයිනට ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකට ගොඩ වූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව (ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව) තහවුරු කළේය. “ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට පැවරී ඇති බලතල අනුව, පවතින රජයේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි, ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පූර්ණ අනුමැතියට යටත්ව, ආගමන විගමන, රේගු සහ අනෙකුත් සියලුම නීතිවලට යටත්ව කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ, ජනාධිපති ආර්යාව සහ ආරක්‍ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනකු සමඟ අද අලුයම මාලදිවයිනට ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් පිටත්ව ගියහ. සහ සේනාධිනායක, බදාදා පසුව ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ඉඩ ඇති තෙක්.",
        "මාලදිවයිනේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ් විසින් ගෝඨාභය මහතා ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී පිළිගත් නමුත් මාලේ වෙතින් මෙතෙක් නිල වචනයක් ලැබී නොමැති බව මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "නෂීඩ් මහතා දේශපාලන වර්ණාවලිය හරහා සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයන් සමඟ සමීප මිත්‍රත්වයක් පවත්වා ගෙන ගොස් ඇත. මැයි මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විදේශ ආධාර ලබා ගැනීමේ “සම්බන්ධීකාරක” ලෙස නෂීඩ් මහතා පත් කළේය.",
        "තවද, මාලදිවයින සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ශක්තිමත් බැඳීම්වලින් සහ පවුල් සබඳතාවලින් බැඳී ඇත. පිටුවහල්ව සිටින මාලදිවයිනේ නායකයින්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බොහෝ විට රැකවරණය ලබා දී ඇත. හරියටම වසර 10 කට පෙර මාලදිවයිනේ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය උත්සන්න වීම මධ්‍යයේ නෂීඩ් මහතාගේ බිරිඳ සහ දියණියන් කොළඹට පලා ගියහ.",
        "2012 සිට මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා මගින් එවකට ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු උපුටා දක්වමින්: \"ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ නෂීඩ් මහතාගේ සහ ඔහුගේ පවුලේ අයගේ ආරක්ෂාව ගැන සැලකිලිමත් විය\", ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීම තහවුරු කරමින්.",
        "ගෝඨාභය මහතාගේ නික්ම යාමෙන් ලංකාවේ පවතින අවිනිශ්චිතතාවය අඩු වී නැත. ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා, ජනාධිපතිවරයා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පොරොන්දු වුවද නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී නැත.",
        "ගෝඨාභය මහතා වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස අගමැති පත් කර නැත. ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත්, පුරප්පාඩු වූ දින සිට මාසයක් ඇතුළත, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සිය මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ජනාධිපති ධූරයට තෝරා ගන්නා තෙක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව මඟින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කෙටියෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට විධිවිධාන සලසා ඇත. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාද ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිඥාව පරිදි ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත්කර ගන්නා තෙක් කතානායකවරයා වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දිවයින",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බදාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා හිමිදිරියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "என்ற புறப்பாடு. rge தீவைச் சேர்ந்த கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச, இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மையை குறைக்கவில்லை, ஏனெனில் ஜனாதிபதி இன்னும் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பதவி விலகவில்லை, ஆனால் அவர் புதன்கிழமை அவ்வாறு செய்வதாக உறுதியளித்தார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிறிலங்கா அதிபர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச, பேரழிவுகரமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் தூண்டப்பட்ட ஒரு போராட்டத்தில் கோபமடைந்த எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் அவரது அலுவலகம் மற்றும் வீட்டை முற்றுகையிட்ட சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, அவர் உறுதியளித்த ராஜினாமாவுக்கு முன்னதாக, புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை தீவை விட்டு வெளியேறி அருகிலுள்ள மாலத்தீவுகளை அடைந்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மாலத்தீவில் உள்ள ஒரு உயர் அதிகாரி, தலைவரின் வருகையின் \"உணர்திறன்\" மேற்கோளிட்டு, பெயரை குறிப்பிட வேண்டாம் என்று கேட்டுக்கொண்டார், திரு. கோட்டாபய நாட்டை \"கடந்து செல்வார்\" என்று தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார். இலங்கைத் தலைவர் அடுத்து எங்கு செல்கிறார் என்று கேட்டதற்கு, ஆதாரம் மறுத்து விட்டது. கோட்டாபயவின் இறுதி இலக்கு இன்னும் தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "அமெரிக்கா அவருக்கு விசாவை மறுத்துள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில் திரு. கோட்டாபய அல்லது அவரது இளைய சகோதரரும் முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சருமான பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவின் பயணத்தை இந்தியா \"அட்டவணையாக மறுத்துவிட்டது\".",
        "புதன்கிழமை காலை வெளியிடப்பட்ட இரண்டு ட்வீட்களில், கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு தனது ஆதரவை \"மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியது\", \"ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் மதிப்புகள், நிறுவப்பட்ட ஜனநாயக நிறுவனங்கள் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை அவர்கள் உணர முயல்கிறார்கள். மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பு.\"",
        "ஜனாதிபதி, முதல் பெண்மணி மற்றும் இரண்டு மெய்ப்பாதுகாவலர்கள் புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை மாலைதீவுக்கு விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் ஏறியதை இலங்கை விமானப்படை (SLAF) உறுதிப்படுத்தியது. “இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பில் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரங்களுக்கு இணங்க, தற்போதுள்ள அரசாங்கத்தின் கோரிக்கையின் பேரில், பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் பூரண அங்கீகாரத்திற்கு உட்பட்டு, குடிவரவு, சுங்கம் மற்றும் கட்டுநாயக்காவில் உள்ள அனைத்து சட்டங்களுக்கும் உட்பட்டது. சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம், ஜனாதிபதி, முதல் பெண்மணி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாவலர்களுடன் இன்று அதிகாலை மாலத்தீவுக்கு விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றார்கள்,” என பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் பதவிகளை வகிக்கும் திரு. கோட்டாபயவுக்கு விமானப்படை தனது சேவைகளை ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. மற்றும் தளபதி-தலைமை, அவர் புதன்கிழமை பின்னர் ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை.",
        "மாலத்தீவின் பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மொஹமட் நஷீத் திரு.கோட்டாபயவை விமான நிலையத்தில் வரவேற்றதாக ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் தெரிவித்தன, ஆனால் மாலேயில் இருந்து இதுவரை உத்தியோகபூர்வ தகவல் எதுவும் இல்லை.",
        "திரு. நஷீத் அனைத்து இலங்கைத் தலைவர்களுடனும், அரசியல் ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் முழுவதும் நெருங்கிய நட்பைப் பேணி வருகிறார். மே மாதம், இலங்கை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இலங்கைக்கான வெளிநாட்டு உதவிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கான \"ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளராக\" திரு நஷீத்தை நியமித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், மாலைதீவும் இலங்கையும் வலுவான உறவுகளாலும் குடும்ப உறவுகளாலும் பிணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. நாடுகடத்தப்பட்ட மாலத்தீவு தலைவர்களுக்கு இலங்கை அடிக்கடி அடைக்கலம் கொடுத்துள்ளது. சரியாக 10 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு, மாலைதீவில் வன்முறைகள் அதிகரித்து வருவதால் திரு. நஷீத்தின் மனைவி மற்றும் மகள்கள் கொழும்புக்குத் தப்பிச் சென்றனர்.",
        "2012 இல் இருந்து ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் கூறியது: \"ஜனாதிபதி இராஜபக்ஷ அவர்கள் இலங்கைக்கு வந்ததை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் போது, ​​திரு. நஷீத் மற்றும் அவரது குடும்பத்தினரின் பாதுகாப்பு குறித்து அக்கறை கொண்டிருந்தார்\".",
        "கோட்டாபயவின் விலகல் இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மையை குறைக்கவில்லை. தொடங்குவதற்கு, ஜனாதிபதி இன்னும் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பதவி விலகவில்லை, ஆனால் அவர் புதன்கிழமை அவ்வாறு செய்வதாக உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "திரு. கோட்டாபய பிரதமரை தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கவில்லை. ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா செய்யும் பட்சத்தில், வெற்றிடமான நாளிலிருந்து ஒரு மாத காலத்திற்குள், பாராளுமன்றம் தனது உறுப்பினர்களில் ஒருவரை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் வரை, பிரதமரை தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக பணியாற்றுவதற்கு இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பு வழிவகை செய்கிறது. திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் தனது உறுதிமொழியின்படி ராஜினாமா செய்தால், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை பாராளுமன்றம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் வரை சபாநாயகர் தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக பணியாற்றுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தீவு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முகமது நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}