{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83304/energy-minister-in-talks-with-qatari-officials-seeks-possible-credit-line",
  "time_ut": 1656417360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Energy Minister in talks with Qatari officials, seeks possible credit line",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Energy Minister in talks with Qatari officials, seeks possible credit line",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara today (June 28) called on Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi, Qatar’s Minister of State for Energy Affairs, the President and CEO of Qatar Energy.",
        "The two ministers have discussed the supply of petroleum products, liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) and liquefied natural gas (LNG) to Sri Lanka to overcome the energy crisis with the assistance of Qatar Energy – the country’s state-owned petroleum company – and The Qatar Development Fund.",
        "Minister Wijesekara also met with the Deputy Director-General of the Qatar Fund for Development for a discussion on a possible credit line facility for petroleum and gas supply to Sri Lanka.",
        "The lawmaker said he was informed that funds have been allocated for medical supplies and the request for a credit facility and support for the IMF program is under consideration.",
        "Met with HE Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi, the Minister of State for Energy Affairs and the President and CEO of Qatar Energy to discuss the supply of Petrolieum Products, LPG and LNG to SL to overcome the Energy crisis with the assistance of Qatar Energy and The Qatar Development Fund. pic.twitter.com/jLQPqssSon— Kanchana Wijesekera (@kanchana_wij) June 28, 2022",
        "Met with Deputy Director General of the Qatar Fund for Development. Discussed possible Credit Line facility for Petrolium and Gas supply. Was informed that funds has been allocated for medical supplies and will consider the request for a credit facility n support the IMF program. pic.twitter.com/tGy82y10Cs— Kanchana Wijesekera (@kanchana_wij) June 28, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Qatari",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LNG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Qatar Development Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Energy Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrolieum Products",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LNG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Qatar Development Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා කටාර් නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින්, හැකි ණය මාර්ගයක් සොයයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචනා විජේසේකර අද (ජූනි 28) කටාර් බලශක්ති කටයුතු පිළිබඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය, කටාර් බලශක්ති ජනාධිපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi හමුවිය.",
        "බලශක්ති අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන, ද්‍රව පෙට්‍රෝලියම් වායු (LPG) සහ ද්‍රව ස්වභාවික වායු (LNG) සැපයීම පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා සාකච්ඡා කර ඇත්තේ Qatar Energy - රටේ රජයට අයත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් සමාගම - සහ කටාර් රාජ්‍යයේ සහාය ඇතිව ය. සංවර්ධන අරමුදල.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පෙට්‍රෝලියම් සහ ගෑස් සැපයීම සඳහා ලබාදිය හැකි ණය පහසුකම් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර සංවර්ධන කටාර් අරමුදලේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා ද හමුවිය.",
        "නීති සම්පාදකවරයා පැවසුවේ වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා මුදල් වෙන් කර ඇති බවත් ණය පහසුකම් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහන සඳහා ආධාර කිරීම සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම සලකා බලමින් සිටින බවත් තමාට දන්වා ඇති බවයි.",
        "බලශක්ති අර්බුධයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා කටාර් බලශක්ති සහ ඩී.එන්.ජී. හි සහය ඇතිව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන, LPG සහ LNG සැපයීම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට බලශක්ති කටයුතු පිළිබඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය HE Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi සහ කටාර් බලශක්තියේ සභාපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරිනිය හමුවිය. කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල. pic.twitter.com/jLQPqssSon— Kanchana Wijesekera (@kanchana_wij) 2022 ජූනි 28",
        "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදලේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් හමුවිය. පෙට්‍රෝලියම් සහ ගෑස් සැපයුම සඳහා ලබාදිය හැකි ණය මාර්ග පහසුකම් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරන ලදී. වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා මුදල් වෙන් කර ඇති බවත් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනට සහය වෙමින් ණය පහසුකමක් සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම සලකා බලන බවත් දන්වන ලදී. pic.twitter.com/tGy82y10Cs— Kanchana Wijesekera (@kanchana_wij) 2022 ජූනි 28"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්ති කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්එන්ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලශක්ති කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්එන්ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கத்தார் அதிகாரிகளுடன் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் பேச்சுவார்த்தையில், சாத்தியமான கடன் வரியை நாடுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர இன்று (ஜூன் 28) கத்தாரின் எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான இராஜாங்க அமைச்சரும், கட்டார் எரிசக்தியின் ஜனாதிபதியும் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரியுமான சாத் ஷெரிடா அல்-காபியை சந்தித்தார்.",
        "எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள், திரவமாக்கப்பட்ட பெட்ரோலிய வாயு (எல்பிஜி) மற்றும் திரவமாக்கப்பட்ட இயற்கை எரிவாயு (எல்என்ஜி) வழங்குவது குறித்து கத்தார் எனர்ஜி - நாட்டின் அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான பெட்ரோலிய நிறுவனமான கத்தார் ஆகியவற்றின் உதவியுடன் இரு அமைச்சர்களும் விவாதித்துள்ளனர். வளர்ச்சி நிதி.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் எரிவாயு விநியோகத்திற்கான சாத்தியமான கடன் வசதி தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடலுக்காக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர அபிவிருத்திக்கான கட்டார் நிதியத்தின் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகத்தையும் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "மருத்துவப் பொருட்களுக்கு நிதி ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், IMF திட்டத்திற்கான கடன் வசதி மற்றும் ஆதரவுக்கான கோரிக்கை பரிசீலனையில் இருப்பதாகவும் தனக்குத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டதாக சட்டமியற்றுபவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கத்தார் எரிசக்தி துறையின் உதவியோடு எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள், எல்பிஜி மற்றும் எல்என்ஜி வழங்குவது குறித்து விவாதிக்க எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான இராஜாங்க அமைச்சரும், கத்தார் எரிசக்தியின் தலைவர் மற்றும் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரியுமான HE Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi ஐ சந்தித்தார். கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி. pic.twitter.com/jLQPqssSon— காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர (@kanchana_wij) ஜூன் 28, 2022",
        "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதியத்தின் துணை இயக்குநர் ஜெனரலைச் சந்தித்தார். பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் எரிவாயு விநியோகத்திற்கான சாத்தியமான கடன் இணைப்பு வசதி பற்றி விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. மருத்துவப் பொருட்களுக்கு நிதி ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், கடன் வசதிக்கான கோரிக்கையை பரிசீலித்து IMF திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது. pic.twitter.com/tGy82y10Cs— காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர (@kanchana_wij) ஜூன் 28, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவர் & எனர்ஜி காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாத் ஷெரிடா அல்-காபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்என்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷெரிடா அல்-காபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்என்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}