{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-repeal-kandyan-marriage-law-provision-on-parental-consent-for-minors-98117/",
  "time_ut": 1659434700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to repeal Kandyan marriage law provision on parental consent for minors",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to repeal Kandyan marriage law provision on parental consent for minors",
      "author": "Mahadiya Hamza",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s cabinet of ministers has approved a proposal to gazette and table in parliament a bill seeking to repeal section II of the Kandyan Marriages and Divorce Act that requires parental consent for the marriage of a minor and to remove the existing non-conformities.",
        "The previous cabinet of ministers had approved the draft bill on October 26, 2021, a statement from the Government Information Department said.",
        "The legal draftsman had prepared the bill and the Attorney General has also cleared it, the statement said.",
        "Minister of Justice, Prison Affairs and Constitutional Reforms Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe will publish a gazette and subsequently table it in the parliament, it added.",
        "“An amendment for the Kandyan law was approved at yesterday’s cabinet meeting. Under the Kandyan law, the female should first obtain her parents’ permission. That is contradictory to the common law in the country. This amendment seeks to remove that requirement in the Kanydan law and resolve some other laws in the registration process as well,” Minister Rajapakshe said at the weekly cabinet press briefing on Tuesday August 02.",
        "A minor under the age of 18 cannot enter legal marriage in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kandyan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "section II",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandyan Marriages",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "October 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prison Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kandyan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandyan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanydan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බාල වයස්කරුවන් සඳහා දෙමාපියන්ගේ කැමැත්ත මත උඩරට විවාහ නීති විධිවිධාන අවලංගු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තීරණය කරයි",
      "author": "මහදිය හම්සා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - බාල වයස්කරුවෙකුගේ විවාහය සඳහා දෙමාපියන්ගේ අනුමැතිය අවශ්‍ය වන උඩරට විවාහ සහ දික්කසාද පනතේ II වන වගන්තිය අවලංගු කිරීමට සහ පවතින නොගැලපීම් ඉවත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් ගැසට් කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් යෝජනාවක් අනුමත කර ඇත.",
        "2021 ඔක්තෝම්බර් 26 වන දින මෙම කෙටුම්පත් කෙටුම්පතට පෙර පැවති අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇති බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "නීති කෙටුම්පත් සම්පාදකයා විසින් පනත් කෙටුම්පත සකස් කර ඇති අතර නීතිපතිවරයා ද එය නිෂ්කාශනය කර ඇති බව එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ විසින් ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර පසුව එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභාගත කිරීමට නියමිත බව එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන්.",
        "“උඩරට නීතිය සඳහා වූ සංශෝධනයක් ඊයේ කැබිනට් රැස්වීමේදී අනුමත වුණා. උඩරට නීතියට අනුව ගැහැනිය පළමුව දෙමාපියන්ගේ අවසරය ලබාගත යුතුය. ඒක රටේ සාමාන්‍ය නීතියට පටහැනියි. මෙම සංශෝධනයෙන් අපේක්ෂා කරන්නේ කැනිඩාන් නීතියේ එම අවශ්‍යතාවය ඉවත් කර ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේදී වෙනත් නීති කිහිපයක්ද විසඳීමටය.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු බාල වයස්කරුවෙකුට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නීත්‍යානුකූල විවාහයට ඇතුළත් විය නොහැක."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "උඩරට",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "II කොටස",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩරට විවාහ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උඩරට",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩරට",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනිඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 02 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிறார்களுக்கான பெற்றோரின் சம்மதத்தின் பேரில் கண்டிய திருமணச் சட்டத்தை இலங்கை ரத்து செய்யவுள்ளது",
      "author": "மஹதியா ஹம்சா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - மைனர் ஒருவரின் திருமணத்திற்கு பெற்றோரின் சம்மதம் தேவைப்படும் மற்றும் தற்போதுள்ள இணக்கமின்மைகளை நீக்கும் கண்டிய திருமணங்கள் மற்றும் விவாகரத்துச் சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு II ஐ நீக்குவதற்கான சட்டமூலத்தை வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிட்டு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான முன்மொழிவுக்கு இலங்கையின் அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த 2021ஆம் ஆண்டு ஒக்டோபர் 26ஆம் திகதி வரைவுச் சட்டமூலத்திற்கு முந்தைய அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக அரசாங்கத் தகவல் திணைக்களத்தின் அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சட்ட வரைவாளர் இந்த சட்டமூலத்தை தயாரித்துள்ளதாகவும், சட்டமா அதிபரும் அதற்கு அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளதாகவும் அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீதி, சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ வர்த்தமானியை வெளியிட்டு அதன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "“கண்டிய சட்ட திருத்தம் நேற்றைய அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது. கண்டி சட்டத்தின் கீழ், பெண் முதலில் பெற்றோரின் அனுமதியைப் பெற வேண்டும். இது நாட்டின் பொதுச் சட்டத்திற்கு முரணானது. இந்த திருத்தம், கேணிடான் சட்டத்தில் உள்ள அந்தத் தேவையை நீக்கி, பதிவுச் செயல்பாட்டில் வேறு சில சட்டங்களையும் தீர்க்க முயல்கிறது” என்று ஆகஸ்ட் 02 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் அமைச்சர் ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் 18 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட மைனர் சட்டப்பூர்வ திருமணத்தில் நுழைய முடியாது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கண்டியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு II",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டிய திருமணங்கள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறை விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்டியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்னிடன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 02 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}