{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගිනි-අවිය-පැහැර-ගැනීම-ගැන-පරීක්ෂණ-කොළඹ-අපරාධ-කොට්ඨාසය/1-616424",
  "time_ut": 1657808320,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගිනි අවිය පැහැර ගැනීම ගැන පරීක්ෂණ කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo Crime Division investigates the theft of the firearm",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Police Media Spokesman Senior Superintendent of Police Advocate Nihal Talduwa, the Colombo Crime Division has handed over the investigation into the attack on an army soldier near Parliament and the kidnapping of his firearm and two magazines containing sixty bullets.",
        "The media spokesman said that on the advice of the Senior Deputy Inspector General of Western Province, Mr. Deshbandu Tennakoon, the investigation has been assigned to the Colombo Crime Division.",
        "During the protest held at Polduwa intersection, a soldier of the Wellawaya army camp who came for duty was beaten with an iron rod and this abduction was carried out.",
        "The seriously injured army soldiers are currently being treated at the army hospital",
        "The Police Media Spokesperson added that a special police team from the Colombo Crime Division has gone to the military hospital and obtained statements from the concerned army soldier."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo Crime Division",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deshbandu Tennakoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polduwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගිනි අවිය පැහැර ගැනීම ගැන පරීක්ෂණ කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අසලදී හමුදා සෙබළකුට පහරදී ඔහු සතුව තිබූ ගිනිඅවිය සහ උණ්ඩ හැටක් අඩංගු මැගසින් දෙක පැහැරගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන කටයුතු කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසයට බාර දුන් බව පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නීතිඥ නිහාල් තල්දූව මහතා පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාත බාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන් මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත එම විමර්ශන කටයුතු කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය වෙත පවරා ඇතැයි මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කීය",
        "පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියේ පැවති විරෝධතාව අතරතුර දී එහි රාජකාරි සඳහා පැමිණි වැල්ලවාය හමුදා කඳවුරේ සෙබළකුට යකඩ පොල්ලකින් පහරදී මෙම පැහැර ගැනීම සිදුකර තිබිණි",
        "එහිදී බරපතළ තුවාල ලද යුද හමුදා සෙබලා මේ වන විට යුද හමුදා රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබයි",
        "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසයේ විශේෂ පොලිස් කණ්ඩායමක් හමුදා රෝහලට ගොස් අදාළ හමුදා සෙබළාගෙන් මේ වන විට ප්‍රකාශ ලබාගෙන ඇතැයි පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த துப்பாக்கி திருட்டு தொடர்பாக கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் சட்டத்தரணி நிஹால் தல்துவாவின் கருத்துப்படி, பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகில் இராணுவ சிப்பாய் ஒருவரை தாக்கி அறுபது தோட்டாக்கள் அடங்கிய துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் இரண்டு மகசீன்கள் கடத்தப்பட்டமை தொடர்பான விசாரணைகளை கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினர் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மேல்மாகாண சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேஷ்பந்து தென்னகோனின் ஆலோசனையின் பேரில், கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்புப் பிரிவினரிடம் விசாரணைகள் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பொல்துவ சந்தியில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது கடமைக்காக வந்த வெல்லவாய இராணுவ முகாமின் சிப்பாய் ஒருவரை இரும்பு கம்பியால் தாக்கி இந்த கடத்தல் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பலத்த காயம் அடைந்த ராணுவ வீரர்கள் தற்போது ராணுவ மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகின்றனர்",
        "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவின் விசேட பொலிஸ் குழுவொன்று இராணுவ வைத்தியசாலைக்கு சென்று குறித்த இராணுவ சிப்பாயிடம் வாக்குமூலம் பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அறுபது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேஷ்பந்து தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லவாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}