{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83602/kurunegala-teaching-hospitals-opd-closed",
  "time_ut": 1657621260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kurunegala Teaching Hospital’s OPD closed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kurunegala Teaching Hospital’s OPD closed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Measures have been taken to close the out-patient department (OPD) of the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital, as a result of the fuel crisis.",
        "Meanwhile, the hospital administration also mentioned that only inpatients are being treated.",
        "Specialist Dr. Dayananda Bandara said that the fuel shortage has become serious as 90% of the specialist doctors working in the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital are not residents of the area, and most of them are from Kandy or Colombo areas.",
        "“Then we have to come by bus or train. There is a situation where we cannot go home for about a week and a half after arriving. As we have discussed with the Ministry of Health and informed, we will not be able to get fuel to the health sector until Thursday or Friday depending on the situation in the country.\"",
        "However, the patients arriving at the hospital have faced difficulties due to the measures taken by the hospital staff."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kurunegala Teaching Hospital’s",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "OPD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Specialist",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayananda Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about a week and a half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ බාහිර රෝගී අංශය වසා දමයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ බාහිර රෝගී අංශය (OPD) වසා දැමීමට පියවර ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර නේවාසික රෝගීන් පමණක් ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බවද රෝහල් පාලනාධිකාරිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ සේවය කරන විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍යවරුන්ගෙන් 90%ක් එම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන් නොවන බවත්, ඔවුන්ගෙන් වැඩි පිරිසක් මහනුවර හෝ කොළඹ ප්‍රදේශවල අය වීම නිසා ඉන්ධන හිඟය උග්‍ර වී ඇති බව විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය දයානන්ද බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“එහෙනම් අපිට එන්න වෙන්නේ බස් එකේ හරි කෝච්චියේ හරි. ඇවිල්ලා සතියක් හමාරක් විතර යනකන් ගෙදර යන්න බැරි තත්ත්වයක් තියෙනවා. අපි සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර දැනුම් දී ඇති පරිදි රටේ පවතින තත්ත්වය අනුව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා හෝ සිකුරාදා වනතුරු සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍රයට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් රෝහල් කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග හේතුවෙන් රෝහලට පැමිණෙන රෝගීන් දැඩි අසීරුතාවයකට පත්ව තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "බාහිර රෝගී අංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බාහිර රෝගී අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂඥ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයානන්ද බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති එකහමාරක් පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையின் OPD மூடப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையின் வெளிநோயாளர் பிரிவு (OPD) மூடுவதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, உள்நோயாளிகளுக்கு மட்டுமே சிகிச்சை அளிக்கப்படுவதாகவும் வைத்தியசாலை நிர்வாகம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் கடமையாற்றும் விசேட வைத்தியர்களில் 90 வீதமானவர்கள் பிரதேசத்தில் வசிப்பவர்கள் அல்லாததாலும், அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலானவர்கள் கண்டி அல்லது கொழும்பு பிரதேசங்களை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என்பதாலும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு பாரியளவில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக விசேட வைத்திய நிபுணர் டாக்டர் தயானந்த பண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“அப்படியானால் நாங்கள் பஸ் அல்லது ரயிலில் வர வேண்டும். வந்து ஒன்றரை வாரமாகியும் வீட்டிற்கு செல்ல முடியாத நிலை உள்ளது. நாங்கள் சுகாதார அமைச்சுடன் கலந்துரையாடி தெரிவித்ததன் பிரகாரம், நாட்டின் நிலைமையைப் பொறுத்து வியாழன் அல்லது வெள்ளி வரை சுகாதாரத் துறைக்கு எரிபொருளைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்ள முடியாது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் வைத்தியசாலை ஊழியர்களின் நடவடிக்கைகள் காரணமாக வைத்தியசாலைக்கு வரும் நோயாளர்கள் சிரமங்களை எதிர்நோக்கியுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "OPD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிபுணர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயானந்த பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ஒன்றரை வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}