{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Sri-Lanka-products-promotion-in-Chinese-TikTok-Douyin-draws-over-1-mn-views/34-739430",
  "time_ut": 1662143433,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka products promotion in Chinese TikTok Douyin draws over 1 mn views",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka products promotion in Chinese TikTok Douyin draws over 1 mn views",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Embassy in Beijing, in association with the China – Sri Lanka Association for Trade and Economic Cooperation and the Douyin (TikTok) Social Media Platform, launched the Sri Lanka National Pavilion on 30 August 2022.",
        "This event took place during the Embassy’s celebration of the Kandy Esala Perahera and Sri Lanka culture and food. The Kandy Esala Perahera, with all its glamour and historical glory, was presented to the Chinese audience through Douyin.",
        "Sri Lankan products were also showcased and marketed through Douyin, which has an audience of over 600 million viewers. (2 billion worldwide on TikTok). The new Sri Lanka National Pavilion on Douyin attracted more than one million viewers online immediately and added more than 27,000 new followers. During the five-hour live broadcast, more than 16,000 Sri Lankan products were purchased online, making it a huge success.",
        "Addressing the selected audience, the Ambassador of Sri Lanka to China, Dr Palitha Kohona said that the national pavilion will assist Sri Lankan exporters to showcase and market their products in China while opening up opportunities for Chinese consumers to buy Sri Lankan products. He invited Sri Lankan exporters to grab this opportunity.",
        "Ambassador Kohona demonstrated the method of preparation of a cup of Ceylon Black Tea, ‘Hong Cha’, and a spicy Sri Lankan Crab dish. Crabs and other sea foods are immensely popular in China.",
        "More than 10 Key Opinion Leaders (KOLs) from Douyin participated, adding glamour to the event, which was live streamed.",
        "Colombo, Sigiriya, Galle, Matale, Kandy, the Temple of the Tooth Relic and the Perahera, Yala, Nuwara Eliya, and Ratnapura were highlighted on a large map of Sri Lanka by the Ambassador. He further explained the potential for trade, investment, and tourism in these cities and their cultural background.",
        "The Ambassador explained the historical significance of the Kandy Perahera, focusing on the Chinese Buddhist Monk, Fa’Xian, who visited Sri Lanka in the early 5th Century and wrote of the Esala Perahera in detail. He invited the Chinese people to visit Sri Lanka to see the Kandy Perahera in all its glory.",
        "The invitees were served, a traditional Sri Lankan Dinner including the Ambassador›s crab dish."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "TikTok Douyin",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the China – Sri Lanka Association for Trade and Economic Cooperation and the Douyin (TikTok) Social Media Platform",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka National Pavilion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Esala Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Esala Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douyin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TikTok",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka National Pavilion on Douyin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 27,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 16,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Black Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Crab",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Crabs",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "More than 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douyin",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sigiriya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale, Kandy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kandy Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fa’Xian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early 5th Century",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esala Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandy Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Dinner",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන TikTok Douyin හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිෂ්පාදන ප්‍රවර්ධනය මිලියන 1 කට අධික දර්ශන ලබා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බීජිං හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය, වෙළඳ හා ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව සඳහා වූ චීන - ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංගමය සහ ඩූයින් (ටික්ටොක්) සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වේදිකාව සමඟ එක්ව 2022 අගෝස්තු 30 වන දින ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික මණ්ඩපය දියත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංස්කෘතිය සහ ආහාර ප්‍රදානය කිරීම තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ උත්සවය අතරතුර මෙම සිදුවීම සිදුවිය. මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර එහි සියලු විචිත්‍රවත් ඓතිහාසික ශ්‍රී විභූතියත් සමඟින් චීන ප්‍රේක්ෂකයන්ට තිළිණ කළේ ඩූයින් හරහාය.",
        "මිලියන 600කට අධික ප්‍රේක්ෂක සංඛ්‍යාවක් සිටින Douyin හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිෂ්පාදන ප්‍රදර්ශනය කර අලෙවි කරන ලදී. (TikTok හි ලොව පුරා බිලියන 2). Douyin හි නව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික මණ්ඩපය අන්තර්ජාලය හරහා මිලියනයකට අධික නරඹන්නන් වහාම ආකර්ෂණය කර ගත් අතර නව අනුගාමිකයින් 27,000 කට වඩා එකතු විය. පැය පහක සජීවී විකාශනය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය නිෂ්පාදන 16,000කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් අන්තර්ජාලය හරහා මිලදී ගෙන ඇති අතර එය අති සාර්ථක විය.",
        "තෝරාගත් ප්‍රේක්ෂකයින් අමතමින් චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති ආචාර්ය පාලිත කොහොන මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ චීන පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිෂ්පාදන මිලදී ගැනීමට අවස්ථාව සලසන අතරම ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයනකරුවන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ නිෂ්පාදන චීනයේ ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමට සහ අලෙවි කිරීමට ජාතික මණ්ඩපය සහාය වන බවයි. මෙම අවස්ථාව ලබා ගන්නා ලෙස ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයනකරුවන්ට ආරාධනා කළේය.",
        "තානාපති කොහොන විසින් සිලෝන් බ්ලැක් ටී කෝප්පයක්, ‘හොං චා’ සහ කුළුබඩු සහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා කකුළුවන් කෑමක් සකස් කිරීමේ ක්‍රමය නිරූපණය කළේය. කකුළුවන් සහ අනෙකුත් මුහුදු ආහාර චීනයේ ඉතා ජනප්‍රියයි.",
        "සජීවීව විකාශනය කරන ලද උත්සවයට අලංකාරයක් එක් කරමින් Douyin හි ප්‍රධාන අදහස් නායකයින් (KOL) 10කට වැඩි පිරිසක් සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "කොළඹ, සීගිරිය, ගාල්ල, මාතලේ, මහනුවර, දළදා මාලිගාව සහ පෙරහැර, යාල, නුවරඑළිය, රත්නපුර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාල සිතියමක තානාපතිවරයා විසින් උද්දීපනය කරන ලදී. මෙම නගරවල වෙළඳාම, ආයෝජන සහ සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය සඳහා ඇති හැකියාව සහ ඒවායේ සංස්කෘතික පසුබිම පිළිබඳව ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "පස්වන සියවසේ මුල් භාගයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ ඇසළ පෙරහැර පිළිබඳව විස්තරාත්මකව ලියා පළ කළ චීන බෞද්ධ භික්‍ෂුවක් වන Fa’Xian පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරමින් තානාපතිවරයා මහනුවර පෙරහැරේ ඓතිහාසික වැදගත්කම පැහැදිලි කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ඔහු චීන ජනතාවට ආරාධනා කළේ මහනුවර මහා පෙරහැර එහි විචිත්‍රවත් ලෙස දැක බලා ගැනීමටය.",
        "ආරාධිතයන් හට තානාපති කකුළු කෑම ඇතුළු සම්ප්‍රදායික ශ්‍රී ලාංකික රාත්‍රී භෝජන සංග්‍රහයක් පිරිනැමිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටික්ටොක් ඩූයින්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙළෙඳ සහ ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව පිළිබඳ සංගමය සහ ඩූයින් (ටික්ටොක්) සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වේදිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර ඇසළ පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douyin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 600 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටික් ටොක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩූයින් හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "27,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය පහක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16,000 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කළු තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකාවේ කකුළුවා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කකුළුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douyin",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීගිරිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ, මහනුවර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fa’Xian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වන සියවසේ මුල් භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇසළ පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාත්‍රී ආහාරය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன TikTok Douyin இல் இலங்கை தயாரிப்புகள் விளம்பரம் 1 மில்லியன் பார்வைகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெய்ஜிங்கில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகம், சீனா - இலங்கை வர்த்தக மற்றும் பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்பு சங்கம் மற்றும் Douyin (TikTok) சமூக ஊடக தளத்துடன் இணைந்து, இலங்கை தேசிய பெவிலியனை 30 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது.",
        "கண்டி எசல பெரஹரா மற்றும் இலங்கை கலாச்சாரம் மற்றும் உணவு தொடர்பான தூதரகத்தின் கொண்டாட்டத்தின் போது இந்த நிகழ்வு இடம்பெற்றது. கண்டி எசல பெரஹெரா, அதன் அனைத்து கவர்ச்சியுடனும், வரலாற்றுப் பெருமையுடனும், டவுயின் மூலம் சீன பார்வையாளர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "600 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான பார்வையாளர்களைக் கொண்ட Douyin மூலம் இலங்கை தயாரிப்புகளும் காட்சிப்படுத்தப்பட்டு சந்தைப்படுத்தப்பட்டன. (TikTok இல் உலகம் முழுவதும் 2 பில்லியன்). Douyin இல் உள்ள புதிய இலங்கை தேசிய பெவிலியன் ஆன்லைனில் உடனடியாக ஒரு மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான பார்வையாளர்களை ஈர்த்தது மற்றும் 27,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட புதிய பின்தொடர்பவர்களைச் சேர்த்தது. ஐந்து மணி நேர நேரடி ஒளிபரப்பின் போது, ​​16,000க்கும் மேற்பட்ட இலங்கை தயாரிப்புகள் இணையத்தில் வாங்கப்பட்டு, அது மிகப்பெரிய வெற்றியைப் பெற்றது.",
        "தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட பார்வையாளர்களிடம் உரையாற்றிய சீனாவுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் கலாநிதி பாலித கொஹொன, இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்கள் சீனாவில் தமது உற்பத்திப் பொருட்களைக் காட்சிப்படுத்தவும் சந்தைப்படுத்தவும் தேசிய பெவிலியன் உதவுவதுடன், சீன நுகர்வோருக்கு இலங்கைப் பொருட்களை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கான வாய்ப்புகளைத் திறக்கும் என்றார். இந்த வாய்ப்பைப் பயன்படுத்திக் கொள்ளுமாறு அவர் இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "தூதுவர் கொஹோனா ஒரு கோப்பை சிலோன் பிளாக் டீ, ‘ஹொங் சா’ மற்றும் காரமான இலங்கை நண்டு உணவை தயாரிக்கும் முறையை செய்து காட்டினார். நண்டுகள் மற்றும் பிற கடல் உணவுகள் சீனாவில் மிகவும் பிரபலமாக உள்ளன.",
        "Douyin ல் இருந்து 10 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட முக்கிய கருத்துத் தலைவர்கள் (KOLகள்) கலந்து கொண்டனர், இது நேரலையில் ஒளிபரப்பப்பட்டது.",
        "கொழும்பு, சீகிரியா, காலி, மாத்தளை, கண்டி, பல்லக்கு ஆலயம் மற்றும் பெரஹெரா, யால, நுவரெலியா, மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி ஆகியவை இலங்கையின் பெரிய வரைபடத்தில் தூதுவரால் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்டன. இந்த நகரங்களில் வர்த்தகம், முதலீடு, சுற்றுலா ஆகியவற்றுக்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் மற்றும் அவற்றின் கலாச்சாரப் பின்னணி குறித்து அவர் மேலும் விளக்கினார்.",
        "ஐந்தாம் நூற்றாண்டின் முற்பகுதியில் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்து எசல பெரஹெரா பற்றி விரிவாக எழுதிய சீன பௌத்த பிக்கு Fa’Xian ஐ மையமாக வைத்து கண்டி பெரஹெராவின் வரலாற்று முக்கியத்துவத்தை தூதுவர் விளக்கினார். கண்டி பெரஹராவை அதன் அனைத்து மகிமையிலும் காண இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தருமாறு அவர் சீன மக்களை அழைத்தார்.",
        "அழைக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு, தூதுவரின் நண்டு உணவு உட்பட இலங்கையின் பாரம்பரிய இரவு உணவு வழங்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "டிக்டாக் டூயின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா - இலங்கை வர்த்தக மற்றும் பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்பு சங்கம் மற்றும் Douyin (TikTok) சமூக ஊடக தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தேசிய பெவிலியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி எசல பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி எசல பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douyin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TikTok",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டூயின் மீது இலங்கை தேசிய பெவிலியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "27,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித கொஹோன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹோனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் பிளாக் டீ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நண்டு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நண்டுகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douyin",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிகிரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை, கண்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யால",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்டி பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fa’Xian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் முற்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எசல பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இரவு உணவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}