{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83935/court-issues-travel-ban-on-21-protesters-including-dhaniz-ali",
  "time_ut": 1659015300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Court issues travel ban on 21 protesters including Dhaniz Ali",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court issues travel ban on 21 protesters including Dhaniz Ali",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court has imposed travel bans on 21 Aragalaya activists including Dhaniz Ali who was recently arrested for forcibly entering the Rupavahini Corporation and disrupting the broadcast.",
        "Among those who were barred from leaving the country are IUSF convener Wasantha Mudalige, CTU leader joseph Stalin, Lahiru Weerasekara, Eranga Gunasekara and Rev. Fr. Jeewantha Peiris.",
        "They have been named as suspects in a case filed against them for taking part in unlawful assembly and blocking the entry to Lotus Road, Finance Ministry and Presidential Secretariat.",
        "The travel ban was imposed by Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage after taking into account a request made by the Colombo Fort Police who told the court that as per intelligence information received, the individuals in question were planning to leave the country.",
        "The magistrate ordered to communicate the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration of the travel ban imposed on the said individuals."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rupavahini Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "joseph Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara and Rev. Fr",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeewantha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lotus Road, Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධනීස් අලි ඇතුළු විරෝධතාකරුවන් 21 දෙනෙකුට විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම් කිරීමට අධිකරණය නියෝග කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළු වී විකාශනයට බාධා කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පසුගියදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ධනීස් අලි ඇතුළු අරගල සංවිධානයේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් 21 දෙනෙකුට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "රටින් පිටවීම තහනම් කළ අය අතර අවිශිබම කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ, ත්‍රස්ත සංගමයේ නායක ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්, ලහිරු වීරසේකර, එරංග ගුණසේකර සහ ගරු පියතුමා වේ. ජීවන්ත පීරිස්.",
        "ලෝටස් පාරට, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයට සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට ඇතුළුවීම අවහිර කිරීම සහ නීති විරෝධී රැස්වීම්වලට සහභාගි වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති නඩුවක සැකකරුවන් ලෙස ඔවුන් නම් කර ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා විසින් මෙම විදේශ ගමන් තහනම පනවනු ලැබුවේ කොළඹ කොටුව පොලිසිය විසින් අධිකරණයට කළ ඉල්ලීමක් සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ලැබුණු බුද්ධි තොරතුරකට අනුව අදාළ පුද්ගලයින් රට හැර යාමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "එම පුද්ගලයන්ට පනවා ඇති සංචාරක තහනම පිළිබඳව ආගමන විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්වරයාට දැනුම් දෙන ලෙස මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරංග ගුණසේකර සහ ගරු පියතුමා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්ත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝටස් පාර, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனிஸ் அலி உட்பட 21 போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு நீதிமன்றம் செல்ல தடை விதித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் பலவந்தமாக பிரவேசித்து ஒளிபரப்புக்கு இடையூறு ஏற்படுத்திய குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் அண்மையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட தனிஸ் அலி உள்ளிட்ட 21 அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர்களுக்கு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் பயணத்தடை விதித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களில் IUSF அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே, CTU தலைவர் ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின், லஹிரு வீரசேகர, எரங்க குணசேகர மற்றும் வண. ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ்.",
        "லோட்டஸ் வீதி, நிதியமைச்சு மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு செல்ல தடை விதித்தமை மற்றும் சட்டவிரோதமாக ஒன்றுகூடல் செய்தமை தொடர்பில் அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கிலேயே இவர்கள் சந்தேகநபர்களாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினருக்கு கிடைத்த புலனாய்வுத் தகவலுக்கு அமைய, குறித்த நபர்கள் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக, கொழும்பு கோட்டை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் முன்வைத்த கோரிக்கையை கருத்திற்கொண்டு, கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இந்த பயணத்தடையை விதித்துள்ளார்.",
        "குறித்த நபர்களுக்கு விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பயணத் தடை குறித்து குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டு நாயகத்திற்கு அறிவிக்குமாறு நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரங்க குணசேகர மற்றும் வண",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லோட்டஸ் சாலை, நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}