{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/තවත්-110ක්-අද-දකුණු-කොරියාවට/11-395358",
  "time_ut": 1657625168,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තවත් 110ක් අද දකුණු කොරියාවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another 110 to South Korea today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Another 110 Sri Lankans who received contracts for Korean jobs are scheduled to leave for South Korea today (12th). This group is the 724th group to leave for South Korea.",
        "During the last season's discussions between the representatives of the Sri Lankan government and the representatives of the South Korean government, attention was paid to the sending of 5800 Sri Lankans for Korean jobs in 6 months. As a result, work is being done to quickly sign employment contracts and send Sri Lankans to South Korea.",
        "According to the diplomatic agreement signed between Sri Lanka and South Korea, South Korea is bringing in people for Korean jobs, and after receiving the agreements related to the Sri Lanka Foreign Employment Bureau, the work of referring the job seekers is being carried out promptly.",
        "Although there was some delay in recruitment and recruitment for foreign jobs during the Covid epidemic, the recruitment of workers for Korean jobs is growing due to the Bureau's continued cooperation with the Korean government.",
        "Meanwhile, the 725th group of 39 people leaving for Korean work is scheduled to leave for Korea tomorrow (13). Since January 2022, 3219 Sri Lankans have left for work in South Korea."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "South Korea",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "110",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "724th",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last season's",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "5800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Foreign Employment Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "725th",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2022, 3219",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවත් 110ක් අද දකුණු කොරියාවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා ගිවිසුම් හිමි වූ තවත් ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් 110 දෙනෙකු අද දින (12දා) දකුණු කොරියාව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතයි. මෙම කණ්ඩායම දකුණු කොරියාව බලා පිටත්ව යන 724 වන කණ්ඩායමයි.",
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකා රජයේ නියෝජිතයින් හා දකුණු කොරියානු රජයේ නියෝජිතයින් අතර පසුගිය සමයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලදී මාස 6ක් තුළ ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් 5800 දෙනෙකු කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා පිටත්කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානය යොමුකරන ලදී. එහි ප්‍රථිඵලයක් ලෙස කඩිනමින් රැකියා ගිවිසුම් අත්සන් කර ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් දකුණු  කොරියාවට පිටත්කිරිමට කටයුතු කරමින් පවතී.",
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකාව හා දකුණු කොරියාව අතර අත්සන් කෙරුණු රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික ගිවිසුම අනුව කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා පුද්ගලයින් ගෙන්වා ගැනීම දකුණු කොරියාව විසින් සිදුකරන අතර, ශ්‍රි ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශයට අදාල ගිවිසුම් ලැබීමෙන් අනතුරුව රැකියා ලාභීන් යොමුකිරීමේ කටයුතු කඩිනමින් සිදුකරමින් සිටියි.",
        "කොවිඩ් වසංගතය සමයේ විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා ගෙන්වාගැනීමේ හා බඳවාගැනීම්වල යම් ප්‍රමාදයක් සිදුවුවද, කොරියානු රජය සමග කාර්යාංශය අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කිරීම හේතුවෙන් කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා ශ්‍රමිකයින් ගෙන්වාගැනීම් වර්ධනය වෙමින් තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, 39 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා පිටත්ව යන 725 වන කණ්ඩායම හෙට දින (13)  දින කොරියාව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතය. 2022 වර්ෂයේ ජනවාරි සිට මේ දක්වා ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් 3219 දෙනෙකු දකුණු කොරියාවේ රැකියා සඳහා පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "110",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "724 වැනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය කන්නයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "5800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 6 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "725 වැනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 2022, 3219",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று தென் கொரியாவுக்கு மேலும் 110",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கான ஒப்பந்தங்களைப் பெற்ற மேலும் 110 இலங்கையர்கள் இன்று (12ஆம் திகதி) தென்கொரியாவுக்குச் செல்லவுள்ளனர். இந்த குழு தென் கொரியாவுக்கு புறப்படும் 724வது குழுவாகும்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் தென்கொரிய அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் இடையில் கடந்த பருவகால கலந்துரையாடலின் போது, ​​6 மாதங்களில் 5800 இலங்கையர்களை கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கு அனுப்புவது குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. இதனையடுத்து, தொழில் ஒப்பந்தங்களில் விரைவாக கைச்சாத்திடுவதுடன், இலங்கையர்களை தென்கொரியாவுக்கு அனுப்பும் பணிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் தென்கொரியாவுக்கும் இடையில் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்டுள்ள இராஜதந்திர ஒப்பந்தத்தின் பிரகாரம் கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கு தென்கொரியா ஆட்களை அழைத்துவருவதுடன், இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம் தொடர்பான ஒப்பந்தங்கள் கிடைத்ததையடுத்து, வேலை தேடுபவர்களை அனுப்பும் பணிகள் துரிதமாக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.",
        "கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய்களின் போது வெளிநாட்டு வேலைகளுக்கான ஆட்சேர்ப்பு மற்றும் ஆட்சேர்ப்புகளில் சிறிது தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டாலும், கொரிய அரசாங்கத்துடன் பணியகத்தின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஒத்துழைப்பின் காரணமாக கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கான பணியாளர்களின் ஆட்சேர்ப்பு அதிகரித்து வருகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, கொரிய பணிக்காக புறப்படும் 39 பேர் கொண்ட 725வது குழு நாளை (13) கொரியா செல்லவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஜனவரி 2022 முதல், 3219 இலங்கையர்கள் தென் கொரியாவில் வேலைக்காக சென்றுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தென் கொரியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "110",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "724வது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "5800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "725வது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2022, 3219",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}