{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131943",
  "time_ut": 1658390800,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனத்துக்கு யாரை நியமிப்பது ? கட்சியின் முகாமைத்துவ குழு தீர்மானிக்கும்- ரங்கே",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Who will be appointed for the vacant parliamentary seat? The management committee of the party will decide- Range",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "A name from the United National Party will be announced soon for Ranil Wickramasinghe's parliamentary seat.",
        "In this regard, the party's management committee chaired by President Ranil Wickramasinghe is meeting to decide, said the secretary of the party, Palitha Range Bandara.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe said this in reference to the member to be appointed to the vacant seat in the Parliament as he has accepted the post as President.",
        "The United National Party did not get any seats in the general election held on 5th August 2020.",
        "However, Ranil Wickramasinghe represented the United National Party through the only national list seat available to the party and went to the Parliament and took oath.",
        "However, following the resignation of Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa due to popular protests in the country, former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appointed Ranil Wickramasinghe as Prime Minister.",
        "Following the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Ranil Wickramasinghe was elected as the President by a majority vote in the Parliament.",
        "Following Ranil Wickramasinghe's election as President, the seat of UNP's Ranil Wickramasinghe in Parliament has become vacant.",
        "It has not yet been decided who will be appointed for this vacancy. However, based on President Ranil Wickramasinghe's advice, the party's management committee will meet and take steps to quickly name someone to the parliament, he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පුරප්පාඩු වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයට පත් කරන්නේ කවුරුන්ද? පක්ෂයේ කළමනාකරණ කමිටුව තීරණය කරනු ඇත- පරාසය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු අසුන සඳහා එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයෙන් නමක් ඉදිරියේදී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පක්ෂ කළමනාකරණ කමිටුව රැස්වී තීරණයක් ගන්නා බව එම පක්ෂයේ ලේකම් පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් ජනාධිපති ධුරය භාරගත් බැවින් පුරප්පාඩු වූ මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයට පත්කිරීමට නියමිත මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පිළිබඳව සඳහන් කරමිනි.",
        "2020 අගෝස්තු 05 වැනි දින පැවැති මහ මැතිවරණයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට ආසනයක් හිමි නොවීය.",
        "නමුත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට තිබෙන එකම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය හරහා එම පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගොස් දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් රට තුළ ඇති වූ ජනතා විරෝධය හේතුවෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වැඩි ඡන්දයෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත්වීමත් සමඟ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අසුන පුරප්පාඩු වී තිබේ.",
        "මෙම පුරප්පාඩුව සඳහා කවුරුන් පත් කරන්නේද යන්න මෙතෙක් තීරණය කර නොමැත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත පක්ෂයේ කළමනාකරණ කමිටුව රැස්වී කඩිනමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට කෙනෙකු නම් කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனத்துக்கு யாரை நியமிப்பது ? கட்சியின் முகாமைத்துவ குழு தீர்மானிக்கும்- ரங்கே",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனத்துக்கு ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியில் இருந்து விரைவாக ஒருவரின் பெயர் அறிவிக்கப்படும்.",
        "அதுதொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் ஆலாேசனைக்கமைய கட்சியின் முகாமைத்துவ குழு கூடி தீர்மானிக்க இருக்கின்றது என கட்சியின் செயலாளர் பாலித்த ரங்கே பண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவி ஏற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வெற்றிடமாகும் அந்த ஆசனத்துக்கு நியமிக்க இருக்கும் உறுப்பினர் தொடர்பில் குறிப்பிடுகையிலேயே இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2020 ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 5ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற பொதுத் தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சிக்கு எந்தவொரு ஆசனமும் கிடைக்கவில்லை.",
        "என்றாலும் கட்சிக்கு கிடைத்த ஒரே ஒரு தேசியப் பட்டியல் ஆசனம் ஊடாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியை பிரதிநித்துவப்படுத்தி பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு சென்று சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "என்றாலும் நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்ட மக்கள் போராட்டம் காரணமாக பிரதமராக இருந்து மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ் பதவி விலகியதைத்தொடர்ந்து, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தாபய ராஜபக்ஷ்வினால் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக நியமித்தார்.",
        "அதனைத்தொடர்ந்து கோத்தாபய ராஜபக்ஷ் பதவி விலகியதைத் தொடர்ந்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை வாக்குகளால் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சிக்குரிய ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் ஆசனம் வெற்றிடமாகி இருக்கின்றது.",
        "இந்த வெற்றிடத்துக்கு யாரை நியமிப்பதென்று இதுவரை தீர்மானிக்கவில்லை. என்றாலும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் ஆலாேசனையின் அடிப்படையில் கட்சியின் முகாமைத்துவ குழு கூடி விரைவாக ஒருவரை பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு பெயரிட நடவடிக்கை எடுப்போம் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}