{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඩලස්ගෙන්-ජනපතිට-සුභ-පැතුම්/1-616787",
  "time_ut": 1658379599,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩලස්ගෙන් ජනපතිට සුභ පැතුම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Greetings to the President from Dallas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma, who ran as a candidate for the parliamentary presidential election, says that he congratulates the new president from the bottom of his heart.",
        "Mr. Alahapperuma, who claims that his political ideology was not defeated by numbers, says that the reason is because he represented 225 people in Diwannawe Island and 58 lakh people outside of Nuwata Island. Mr. Alahapperuma also says that he would like to express his respectful thanks to all the parties and members who believed in him.",
        "Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma mentions this in a post on his Facebook account."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diwannawe Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwata Island",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්ගෙන් ජනපතිට සුභ පැතුම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අභිනව ජනපතිට හදවතින් සුබ පතන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු ජනපතිවරණයට අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් වූ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඉලක්කම් වලින් පැරදූනූ නමූදූ තම දේශපාලන මතවාදය පරාජය වූයේ නැතැයි කියන අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා  එයට හේතුව තමා දියවන්නාවේ දූපත තුල පවූල් 225 වෙනූවට දූපතෙන් පිටත පවූල් ලක්ෂ 58 වෙනූවෙන් පෙනී සිටි බැවින් යැයි සඳහන් කරයි. තමා කෙරෙහි විශ්වාසය තැබූ සියළුම පක්ෂ සහ සාමාජිකයන් වෙත  ගෞරවාදර ස්තුතිය පූදකරන බවද අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා කියයි.",
        "සිය ෆේස්බුක් ගිණුමේ සටහනක් තබමින් ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා මේ බව සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවන්නාවේ දූපත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවට දූපත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வாழ்த்துக்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு இதயப்பூர்வமான வாழ்த்துக்களை தெரிவிப்பதாக பாராளுமன்ற ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் வேட்பாளராகப் போட்டியிட்ட திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தனது அரசியல் சித்தாந்தம் எண்ணிக்கையால் தோற்கடிக்கப்படவில்லை என்று கூறும் திரு.அழகப்பெரும, திவான்னாவ தீவில் 225 பேரையும் நுவத்த தீவிற்கு வெளியே 58 இலட்சம் மக்களையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தியதே காரணம் என்கிறார். தம்மை நம்பிய அனைத்துக் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு எனது மரியாதைக்குரிய நன்றிகளைத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்வதாகவும் திரு.அழபெரும கூறுகிறார்.",
        "திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தனது முகநூல் கணக்கின் பதிவில் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திவான்னாவே தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவாடா தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}