{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SLTDA-Chairman-complains-to-IGP-over-incident-involving-a-Police-Officer-and-a-tourist/108-240231",
  "time_ut": 1656791002,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLTDA Chairman complains to IGP over incident involving a Police Officer and a tourist",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLTDA Chairman complains to IGP over incident involving a Police Officer and a tourist",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) yesterday lodged a complaint with the Inspector General of Police (IGP) over an incident involving a Police Officer and a tourist at the petrol shed in Galle on Friday.",
        "SLTDA Chairman Priyantha Fernando said a video is being circulated on social media showing a senior police officer refusing to allow a tourist on a motorbike to get fuel from the shed in Galle.",
        "\"This video clip has been in circulation reaching millions of people not only in Sri Lanka but in most foreign countries. It has created a major negative impact from a tourism perspective surmounting unrepairable damage at a time when we are doing our very best to ensure that tourists do not undergo any harassment and inconvenience in spite of the economic difficulties that we as Sri Lankans have to undergo,\" the Chairman said in a letter to the IGP.",
        "I am certain that you will agree with me that tourism is an important industry that is capable of generating the much-required foreign exchange earnings for Sri Lanka. It creates direct and indirect employment opportunities for almost 4 million Sri Lankans. The manner in which the Police Officer conducted himself is disgraceful and reflects negatively on the entire Police Force of Sri Lanka, the letter further stated.",
        "The Chairman said he has requested the SSP Nawaz who is in charge of the Tourist Police to take the necessary steps through the Tourist Police to ensure the safety and minimal inconvenience to tourists while in Sri Lanka.",
        "\"In a bid to mitigate the damage that is being caused and to counter the damage, thankful if you could make an official statement for which maximum publicity will be arranged. It could be either a written statement or a video recording that could be disseminated on YouTube and other social media platforms,\" he told IGP in his letter."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IGP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the SSP Nawaz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tourist Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tourist Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YouTube",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු සහ සංචාරකයෙකු සම්බන්ධ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් SLTDA සභාපති පොලිස්පතිට පැමිණිලි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සිකුරාදා ගාල්ල පෙට්‍රල් ෂෙඩ් එකේදී පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු සහ සංචාරකයෙකු සම්බන්ධ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය (SLTDA) ඊයේ පොලිස්පතිවරයාට (IGP) පැමිණිල්ලක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "SLTDA සභාපති ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසුවේ, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු විසින් ගාල්ලේ මඩුවෙන් ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි සංචාරකයෙකුට අවසර දීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ආකාරය දැක්වෙන වීඩියෝවක් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ සංසරණය වන බවයි.",
        "“මෙම වීඩියෝ පටය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පමණක් නොව බොහෝ විදේශ රටවල මිලියන සංඛ්‍යාත ජනතාවක් වෙත ළඟා වෙමින් සංසරණය වෙමින් පවතී. එය සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ දෘෂ්ටිකෝණයෙන් විශාල ඍණාත්මක බලපෑමක් ඇති කර ඇති අතර එය පිළිසකර කළ නොහැකි හානියක් අභිබවා යාමට අප අපගේ උපරිමයෙන් කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින අවස්ථාවක ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් වශයෙන් අපට මුහුණ දීමට සිදුවන ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා මධ්‍යයේ වුවද සංචාරකයින්ට කිසිදු හිරිහැරයක් සහ අපහසුතාවයක් සිදු නොවේ,\" සභාපතිවරයා පොලිස්පතිවරයා වෙත ලිපියක් යවමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉතා අවශ්‍ය විදේශ විනිමය ඉපැයීමේ හැකියාව ඇති වැදගත් කර්මාන්තයක් බවට ඔබ මා සමඟ එකඟ වනු ඇතැයි මට විශ්වාසයි. එය මිලියන 4 කට ආසන්න ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සඳහා සෘජු හා වක්‍ර රැකියා අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය කරයි. පොලිස් නිලධාරියා ක්‍රියා කළ ආකාරය නින්දිත වන අතර එය සමස්ත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොලිස් හමුදාවටම අහිතකර ලෙස පිළිබිඹු වන බවද එම ලිපියේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින සංචාරකයින්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ අවම අපහසුතා සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සංචාරක පොලිසිය හරහා අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සංචාරක පොලිසිය භාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නවාස් මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව සභාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "\"සිදුවෙමින් පවතින හානිය අවම කර ගැනීමට සහ හානියට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා, ඔබට උපරිම ප්‍රචාරණයක් ලබා දෙන නිල ප්‍රකාශයක් කළ හැකි නම් ස්තූතියි. එය ලිඛිත ප්‍රකාශයක් හෝ වීඩියෝ පටිගත කිරීමක් විය හැකිය. යූ ටියුබ් සහ අනෙකුත් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වේදිකා, ”ඔහු සිය ලිපියෙන් පොලිස්පතිවරයාට පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොලිස්පති",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නවාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YouTube",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLTDA தலைவர், பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி மற்றும் சுற்றுலா பயணி சம்பந்தப்பட்ட சம்பவம் குறித்து IGPயிடம் புகார் செய்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலியில் உள்ள பெற்றோல் கொட்டகையில் பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர் மற்றும் சுற்றுலாப் பயணி ஒருவருக்கும் இடையில் இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை (SLTDA) நேற்று பொலிஸ் மா அதிபரிடம் (IGP) முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "SLTDA தலைவர் பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ கூறுகையில், காலியில் உள்ள கொட்டகையில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை பெறுவதற்கு மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் பயணித்த சுற்றுலாப் பயணி ஒருவருக்கு சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர் ஒருவர் அனுமதி மறுப்பதைக் காட்டும் காணொளி சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பரவிவருகிறது.",
        "\"இந்த வீடியோ கிளிப் இலங்கையில் மட்டுமின்றி பெரும்பாலான வெளிநாடுகளில் மில்லியன் கணக்கான மக்களைச் சென்றடையும் வகையில் புழக்கத்தில் உள்ளது. இது சுற்றுலாக் கண்ணோட்டத்தில் பெரும் எதிர்மறையான தாக்கத்தை உருவாக்கியுள்ளது, சரி செய்ய முடியாத சேதத்தை நாங்கள் உறுதிசெய்து வருகிறோம். இலங்கையர்களாகிய நாம் அனுபவிக்க வேண்டிய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள் இருந்தபோதிலும் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் எந்தவிதமான துன்புறுத்தலுக்கும் அசௌகரியங்களுக்கும் உள்ளாவதில்லை\" என தலைவர் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சுற்றுலாத்துறை என்பது இலங்கைக்கு மிகவும் தேவையான அந்நிய செலாவணியை ஈட்டித் தரக்கூடிய ஒரு முக்கியமான தொழில் என்பதை நீங்கள் ஏற்றுக் கொள்வீர்கள் என்பதில் நான் உறுதியாக உள்ளேன். இது கிட்டத்தட்ட 4 மில்லியன் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு நேரடி மற்றும் மறைமுக வேலை வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்குகிறது. பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர் நடந்துகொண்ட விதம் அவமானகரமானது மற்றும் இலங்கையின் முழு பொலிஸ் படைக்கும் எதிர்மறையாக பிரதிபலிக்கிறது என்று கடிதத்தில் மேலும் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் இருக்கும் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் பாதுகாப்பையும் குறைந்தபட்ச அசௌகரியத்தையும் உறுதிப்படுத்த சுற்றுலாப் பொலிஸாரின் ஊடாகத் தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு சுற்றுலாப் பொலிஸாருக்குப் பொறுப்பான எஸ்.எஸ்.பி நவாஸிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக தலைவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஏற்படும் சேதத்தைத் தணிக்க மற்றும் சேதத்தை எதிர்கொள்ளும் முயற்சியில், அதிகபட்ச விளம்பரம் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்படும் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ அறிக்கையை நீங்கள் வழங்கினால் நன்றி. அது எழுத்துப்பூர்வ அறிக்கையாகவோ அல்லது வீடியோ பதிவாகவோ இருக்கலாம். யூடியூப் மற்றும் பிற சமூக ஊடக தளங்களில்,” என்று அவர் தனது கடிதத்தில் ஐஜிபியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நவாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வலைஒளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}