{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78647",
  "time_ut": 1658170080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "A new President will be elected by MPs  through  secret ballot today(July 20) morning in Parliament with a close fight expected among the top two contenders  Wickremesinghe and Alahapperuma in the three-cornered battle.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A new President will be elected by MPs  through  secret ballot today(July 20) morning in Parliament with a close fight expected among the top two contenders  Wickremesinghe and Alahapperuma in the three-cornered battle.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The all-important Presidency will come up for a secret ballot today morning in Parliament with a close fight expected among the top two contenders in the three-cornered battle.",
        "When nominations were called in yesterday in Parliament, Prime Minister and Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe was proposed by SLPP MP Dinesh Gunawardena who is tipped to be Prime Minister candidate and seconded by Manusha Nanayakkara. SLPP independent group MP Dullas Alahapperuma was proposed by SJB leader Sajith Premadasa and seconded by G.L. Peiris. This was after Premadasa withdrew from the race claiming it was for the greater good of the country and the people. He said SJB, alliance and opposition partners will work hard towards making Dullas victorious. Premadasa hopes to be the Prime Minister if Dullas wins.",
        "JVP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake was proposed by Vijitha Herath and seconded by Dr. Harini Amarasuriya.",
        "A close fight between veteran Wickremesinghe, who is backed by the majority of SLPP MPs among others and under-dog Dullas, is expected at the vote which begins at 10 a.m.",
        "SLFP with nine MPs last night formally announced its support to Dullas, a decision made with the backing of leader and former President Maithripala Sirisena and General Secretary MP Dayasiri Jayasekara and the Central Working Committee.",
        "The 10-member TNA also pledged support to Dullas whilst its MPs held a joint meeting with him and Premadasa.",
        "Separately former Government MPs but now independent Wimal Weerawansa, Udaya Gammanpila, Vasudeva Nanayakkara, Prof. Tissa Vitarana, Athuraliye Rathana Thero, Weerasumana Weerasinghe, Asanka Nawarathne, Gevindu Kumaratunga and others also pledged support to Dullas. This twin move was a major breakthrough for Dullas, according to political analysts.",
        "Among other parties to announce support were Sri Lanka Muslim Congress-led by Rauff Hakeem and Mano Ganesan-led  Tamil Progressive Alliance.",
        "There are 225 MPs and individual camps were upbeat of victory for their respective candidates. Pro-Wickremesinghe camp was said to be referring to 150-170 votes in favour whilst the Dullas camp reference was over 140 winning votes.",
        "Wickremesinghe on Monday night had met with around 100 SLPP MPs and sources in his camp claimed that they have managed to garner additional support from dissidents within SJB as well as other independent groups of MPs.",
        "It was claimed that the decision by Premadasa to withdraw from the race had irked some members including Presidential aspirant Gen. Sarath Fonseka.",
        "Despite die-hard SJBers terming Sajith decision as tactical to rally more support to Dullas as a common candidate from like-minded Opposition MPs, some ridiculed the leader’s withdrawal as amateurish and signalled the beginning of the end of his political career.",
        "Despite confidence in each camp, eleventh hour negotiations were continuing to garner more support especially among those who are undecided.",
        "Political analysts however pointed to the secret ballot factor for the difficulty in making any clear predictions and dismissed reference numbers cited by individual camps.",
        "Aragalaya activists at a media conference issued a warning against electing Acting President Wickremesinghe to serve the remainder of the ousted Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s term. Their stand was that the people’s struggle was to oust corrupt Rajapaksa regime and with Wickremesinghe agreeing to serve as Prime Minister in May colluded with and gave protection to the Rajapaksas and their loyalists. They insisted that their demand of a truly All-Party temporary caretaker Government was critical to resolve immense hardships faced by the people.",
        "The previously announced National Day of Protest on Tuesday demanding the withdrawal of Wickremesinghe from the Presidential race was not successful though some of the activists, trade union leaders and citizens did take part in a rally from Fort Railway station to GotaGoGama yesterday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today(July 20) morning",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe and Alahapperuma",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harini Amarasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Working Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Vitarana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasumana Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asanka Nawarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gevindu Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pro-Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "150-170",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJBers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the beginning of the end of",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "eleventh hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National Day of Protest",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Railway",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "GotaGoGama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුන්කොන් සටනේ ප්‍රමුඛ අපේක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනා වන වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ අලහප්පෙරුම අතර තියුණු සටනක් අපේක්ෂාවෙන් අද (ජූලි 20) පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී රහස් ඡන්දයෙන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට නියමිතය.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "තුන්කොන් සටනේ ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටින තරගකරුවන් දෙදෙනා අතර තියුණු සටනක් අපේක්ෂාවෙන් ඉතා වැදගත් ජනාධිපති ධූරය අද පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී රහස් ඡන්දයක් සඳහා පැමිණේ.",
        "ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී නාමයෝජනා කැදවූ අවස්ථාවේදී අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය අපේක්ෂකයා ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කරන ලද අතර මනූෂ නානායක්කාර විසින් එය ස්ථිර කරන ලදී. SLPP ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස විසින් යෝජනා කරන ලද අතර G.L. පීරිස් විසින් ස්ථිර කරන ලදී. ඒ ප්‍රේමදාස රටේත් ජනතාවගේත් යහපත පිණිස යැයි කියමින් තරගයෙන් ඉවත්වීමෙන් පසුවය. ඩලස් ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට SJB, සන්ධානය සහ විපක්ෂයේ හවුල්කරුවන් වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. ඩලස් දිනුවොත් ප්‍රේමදාස අගමැති වෙන්න බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා.",
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට විජිත හේරත් මහතා යෝජනා කළ අතර වෛද්‍ය හරිනි අමරසූරිය මහත්මිය ස්ථිර කළාය.",
        "පෙරවරු 10 ට ආරම්භ වන ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බහුතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සහාය ලබන ප්‍රවීණ වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ බල්ලාට යට වූ ඩලස් අතර සමීප සටනක් අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 9 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රීලනිපය ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ නිල වශයෙන් ඩලස්ට සහය පළ කරන බව නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ අතර, එය නායක හා හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන සහ මහලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දයාසිරි ජයසේකර සහ මධ්‍යම කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලයේ සහාය ඇතිව ගත් තීරණයකි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 10 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ටීඑන්ඒ ද ඩලස්ට සහය දැක්වීමට ප්‍රතිඥා දුන් අතර එහි මන්ත්‍රීවරු ඔහු සහ ප්‍රේමදාස සමඟ ඒකාබද්ධ රැස්වීමක් පැවැත්වූහ.",
        "වෙන වෙනම ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ හිටපු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන නමුත් දැන් ස්වාධීනව සිටින විමල් වීරවංශ, උදය ගම්මන්පිල, වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර, මහාචාර්ය තිස්ස විතාරණ, අතුරලියේ රතන හිමි, වීරසුමන වීරසිංහ, අසංක නවරත්න, ගෙවිඳු කුමාරතුංග ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ද ඩලස්ට සහය පළ කළහ. දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයින්ට අනුව මෙම ද්විත්ව පියවර ඩලස්ගේ ප්‍රධාන ඉදිරි ගමනක් විය.",
        "සහාය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අනෙකුත් පක්ෂ අතර රවුෆ් හකීම්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය සහ මනෝ ගනේෂන්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය ද විය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 ක් සිටින අතර තනි තනි කඳවුරු ඔවුන්ගේ අපේක්ෂකයින් ජයග්‍රහණය කර ඇත. වික්‍රමසිංහ හිතවාදී කඳවුරට පක්ෂව ඡන්ද 150-170ක් ලැබුණු බව පැවසෙන අතර ඩලස් කඳවුරේ යොමුව ජයග්‍රාහී ඡන්ද 140කට වඩා වැඩි විය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ සඳුදා රාත්‍රියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 100ක් පමණ මුණගැසී ඇති අතර ඔහුගේ කඳවුරේ ආරංචි මාර්ග කියා සිටියේ ඔවුන් SJB තුළ සිටින විරුද්ධවාදීන්ගෙන් මෙන්ම අනෙකුත් ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම්වල අමතර සහයෝගය ලබා ගැනීමට සමත් වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා තරගයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට ගත් තීරණය ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක ජෙනරාල් සරත් ෆොන්සේකා මහතා ඇතුළු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කම්පනයට පත් කළ බව ප්‍රකාශ විය.",
        "සමාන අදහස් ඇති විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් පොදු අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ලෙස ඩලස්ට වැඩි සහයෝගයක් ලබා ගැනීමට සජිත් ගත් තීරණය උපායශීලී බව දැඩි SJBවරු හැඳින්වුවද, ඇතැමුන් නායකයාගේ ඉවත්වීම ආධුනික යැයි උපහාසයට ලක් කරමින් ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන දිවියේ අවසානය සනිටුහන් කළහ.",
        "සෑම කඳවුරකම විශ්වාසය තිබියදීත්, එකොළොස්වන පැය සාකච්ඡා විශේෂයෙන් තීරණය නොකළ අය අතර වැඩි සහයෝගයක් ලබා ගැනීමට දිගටම පැවතුනි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයින් රහස් ඡන්ද සාධකය පෙන්වා දුන්නේ කිසියම් පැහැදිලි පුරෝකථනයක් කිරීමට ඇති දුෂ්කරතාවය සහ තනි කඳවුරු විසින් උපුටා දක්වන ලද යොමු අංක ඉවත් කර ඇත.",
        "බලයෙන් පහකළ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ධූර කාලය තුළ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කර ගැනීමට එරෙහිව අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකදී අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් කළේය. ඔවුන්ගේ ස්ථාවරය වූයේ ජනතා අරගලය දූෂිත රාජපක්ෂ පාලනය පලවා හැරීම බවත්, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මැයි මාසයේදී අගමැති වීමට එකඟ වීමත් සමඟ රාජපක්ෂලාට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ හිතවාදීන්ට සහයෝගය ලබාදී ඔවුන්ට ආරක්ෂාව ලබාදුන් බවත්ය. ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන අතිවිශාල දුෂ්කරතා විසඳීම සඳහා සැබෑ සර්ව පාක්ෂික තාවකාලික භාරකාර රජයක් පිළිබඳ ඔවුන්ගේ ඉල්ලීම ඉතා වැදගත් බව ඔවුහු අවධාරණය කළහ.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරණ සටනෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස බලකරමින් පෙරේදා ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ ජාතික විරෝධතා දිනය ඊයේ කොටුව දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේ සිට ගොටගොගම දක්වා පැවති රැළියකට ක්‍රියාකාරීන්, වෘත්තීය සමිති නායකයින් සහ පුරවැසියන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සහභාගී වුවද එය සාර්ථක වූයේ නැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද (ජූලි 20) උදෑසන",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ අලහප්පෙරුම",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිනි අමරසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතන හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසුමන වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසංක නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෙවිඳු කුමාරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ හිතවාදී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "150-170",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJBers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසානයෙහි ආරම්භය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එකොළොස්වන පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂිකයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික විරෝධතා දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව දුම්රිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාගෝගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முக்கோணப் போரில் முதல் இரண்டு போட்டியாளர்களான விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோருக்கு இடையே கடும் போட்டி நிலவிய நிலையில் இன்று (ஜூலை 20) காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "மிகவும் முக்கியமான ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெறவுள்ளதுடன், முக்கோணப் போரில் முதல் இரண்டு போட்டியாளர்களுக்கிடையில் கடும் போட்டி நிலவுகிறது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நேற்று வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்பட்ட போது, ​​பிரதமரும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பிரதமர் வேட்பாளராக முன்னிறுத்தப்பட்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவினால் முன்மொழியப்பட்டு மனுஷ நாணயக்காரவினால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டது. ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சுயேட்சைக் குழு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச முன்மொழிந்தார் மற்றும் G.L. பீரிஸ் அவர்களால் ஆதரித்தார். பிரேமதாச நாட்டிற்கும் மக்களுக்கும் நன்மை பயக்கும் என்று கூறி போட்டியிலிருந்து விலகியதை அடுத்து இது நடந்தது. SJB, கூட்டணி மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி பங்காளிகள் டல்லாஸை வெற்றிபெறச் செய்ய கடுமையாக உழைக்கும் என்றார். டலஸ் வெற்றி பெற்றால் பிரேமதாச பிரதமராக வருவார் என நம்புகிறார்.",
        "ஜே.வி.பி.யின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவை விஜித ஹேரத் முன்மொழிந்தார் மற்றும் கலாநிதி ஹரிணி அமரசூரிய ஆதரித்தார்.",
        "முற்பகல் 10 மணிக்குத் தொடங்கும் வாக்கெடுப்பில், SLPP எம்.பி.க்களில் பெரும்பான்மையினரின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்ற மூத்த வீரரான விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கும், கீழ்நாய் டல்லாஸ்க்கும் இடையே ஒரு நெருக்கமான போட்டி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "தலைவரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் பொதுச் செயலாளர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர மற்றும் மத்திய செயற்குழுவின் ஆதரவுடன் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானம் நேற்றிரவு ஒன்பது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுடன் கூடிய ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி டலஸுக்கு தனது ஆதரவை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவித்தது.",
        "10 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட தமிழ் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பும் டலஸுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்தது, அதே நேரத்தில் அதன் எம்.பி.க்கள் அவருடனும் பிரேமதாசாவுடனும் கூட்டுச் சந்திப்பை நடத்தினர்.",
        "தனித்தனியாக அரசாங்கத்தின் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான விமல் வீரவன்ச, உதய கம்மன்பில, வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, பேராசிரியர் திஸ்ஸ விதாரண, அத்துரலியே ரத்தின தேரர், வீரசுமண வீரசிங்க, அசங்க நவரத்ன, கெவிந்து குமாரதுங்க மற்றும் பலர் டலஸுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்தனர். அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்களின் கூற்றுப்படி, இந்த இரட்டை நடவடிக்கை டல்லாஸுக்கு ஒரு பெரிய திருப்புமுனையாகும்.",
        "ஏனைய கட்சிகளில் ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் தலைமையிலான ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸும் மனோ கணேசன் தலைமையிலான தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணியும் ஆதரவை அறிவித்தன.",
        "225 எம்.பி.க்கள் உள்ளனர் மற்றும் தனிப்பட்ட முகாம்கள் அந்தந்த வேட்பாளர்களுக்கு வெற்றியை உற்சாகப்படுத்தியது. விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆதரவு முகாம் ஆதரவாக 150-170 வாக்குகளைக் குறிப்பிடுவதாகக் கூறப்பட்டது, டல்லாஸ் முகாம் குறிப்பு 140 வெற்றி வாக்குகளுக்கு மேல் இருந்தது.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை இரவு விக்கிரமசிங்க சுமார் 100 SLPP எம்.பி.க்களை சந்தித்தார் மற்றும் அவரது முகாமில் உள்ள வட்டாரங்கள், SJB யில் உள்ள அதிருப்தியாளர்கள் மற்றும் எம்.பி.க்களின் மற்ற சுயேச்சைக் குழுக்களிடமிருந்து கூடுதல் ஆதரவைப் பெற முடிந்ததாகக் கூறினர்.",
        "போட்டியிலிருந்து விலகிய பிரேமதாசவின் தீர்மானம் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் ஜெனரல் சரத் பொன்சேகா உட்பட சில உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு எரிச்சலை ஏற்படுத்தியதாக கூறப்பட்டது.",
        "சஜித்தின் முடிவு, எதிர்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களின் பொது வேட்பாளராக டல்லாஸுக்கு அதிக ஆதரவைத் திரட்டுவதற்கான தந்திரோபாயமானது என்று தீவிர எஸ்.ஜே.பி.க்கள் கூறிய போதிலும், சிலர் தலைவரின் விலகலை அமெச்சூர் என்று கேலி செய்தனர் மற்றும் அவரது அரசியல் வாழ்க்கையின் தொடக்கத்தை சமிக்ஞை செய்தனர்.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு முகாமிலும் நம்பிக்கை இருந்தபோதிலும், பதினொன்றாவது மணிநேர பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் குறிப்பாக முடிவெடுக்கப்படாதவர்களிடையே அதிக ஆதரவைப் பெற்றன.",
        "இருப்பினும், அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்கள், எந்தவொரு தெளிவான கணிப்புகளையும் செய்வதில் உள்ள சிரமம் மற்றும் தனிப்பட்ட முகாம்களால் மேற்கோள் காட்டப்பட்ட குறிப்பு எண்களை நிராகரிப்பதற்கான ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு காரணியை சுட்டிக்காட்டினர்.",
        "பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு எதிராக அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் ஊடக சந்திப்பில் எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர். ஊழலற்ற ராஜபக்சே ஆட்சியை அகற்றுவதே மக்களின் போராட்டம் என்பதும், மே மாதம் பிரதமராக பதவியேற்க விக்கிரமசிங்க உடன்பட்டதும், ராஜபக்சேக்களுக்கும் அவர்களின் விசுவாசிகளுக்கும் கூட்டுச் சேர்ந்து பாதுகாப்பு அளித்தது என்பதே அவர்களின் நிலைப்பாடாக இருந்தது. மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பாரிய இன்னல்களுக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்கு உண்மையான சர்வகட்சி தற்காலிக காபந்து அரசாங்கம் என்ற தமது கோரிக்கை முக்கியமானது என அவர்கள் வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் இருந்து விலக்கக் கோரி செவ்வாய்கிழமை முன்னரே அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட தேசிய எதிர்ப்பு தினம் வெற்றியளிக்கவில்லை எனினும் சில செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள், தொழிற்சங்க தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பொதுமக்கள் நேற்று கோட்டை புகையிரத நிலையத்தில் இருந்து கோட்டகோகம வரை பேரணியில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று (ஜூலை 20) காலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் அழகப்பெரும",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரினி அமரசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்தின தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசுமண வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசங்க நவரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெவிந்து குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "150-170",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கள் இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJBers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முடிவின் ஆரம்பம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதினோராம் மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எதிர்ப்பு தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை இரயில்வே",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டகோகாமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}