{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඩීසල්-ලීටර්-1800-වාලච්චේනෙන්-අල්ලයි/1-617180",
  "time_ut": 1658998733,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩීසල් ලීටර් 1800 වාලච්චේනෙන් අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "1800 liters of diesel is caught from Valachchen",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Valachchena Police say that 1800 liters of diesel taken from the Valachchena Fisherman's Harbor fuel station were prepared to be transported to Katthankudi by a lorry and a van and seven persons were arrested with the diesel stock and the lorry early this morning.",
        "The arrested suspects are residents of Kalmunai and Kattankudi areas, Valachchena Acting Police Station Sub-Inspector RM Kumarasinghe said during our enquiry.",
        "Valachchena Police, who are conducting the investigation, states that the seized 1800 diesel was packed into eighteen buckets and packed into the van, and another 21 buckets were carefully packed and loaded into the lorry.",
        "They did not have a license to transport the seized diesel and the police suspect that it was sent ready to be transported for sale at a higher price."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Valachchen",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Valachchena Fisherman's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katthankudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalmunai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kattankudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valachchena Acting Police Station Sub-Inspector",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RM Kumarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Valachchena Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighteen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩීසල් ලීටර් 1800 වාලච්චේනෙන් අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වාලච්චේන ධීවර වරාය ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලෙන් ලබාගත් ඩීසල් ලීටර් 1800ක් ලොරි රථයකින් සහ වෑන් රථයකින් කාත්තන්කුඩිය දක්වා ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට සූදානම් කර අද අලූයම  ඩීසල් තොගය සහ ලොරිය  සමග හත්දෙනකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව වාලච්චේන පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් කල්මුණේ සහ කාත්තන්කුඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි පුද්ගලින් බව වාලච්චේන වැඩබලන පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක අර්.එම් කුමාරසිංහ මහතා අප කළ විමසීමකදී පැවසීය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ඩීසල් 1800 ප්‍රමාණය බූලි දහඅටකට ඇසුරුම් කර වෑන් රථයේද, තවත් බූලි 21 ඇසුරුම් කර ඒවා ලොරියටද ඉතා සූක්ෂම ලෙස පටවා තිබූ බව පරීක්ෂණ සිදුකරන වාලච්චේන පොලිසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුටගත් මෙම ඩීසල් ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ට බලපත්‍රයක් නොතිබි අතර මෙය වැඩි මිලට විකිණීම සඳහා රැගෙන යෑමට සූදානම් කර තිබූ එව්වාද යන්න පොලිසිය සැක පළ කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "වාලච්චේන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලච්චේන ධීවරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාත්තන්කුඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාත්තන්කුඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලච්චේන වැඩබලන පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්.එම් කුමාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාලච්චේන පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහඅට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வாழச்சென்னில் இருந்து 1800 லிட்டர் டீசல் பிடிக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வாழைச்சேனை கடற்றொழிலாளர் துறைமுக எரிபொருள் நிலையத்தில் இருந்து எடுக்கப்பட்ட 1800 லீற்றர் டீசல் லொறி மற்றும் வேன் மூலம் காத்தான்குடிக்கு கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு தயார் நிலையில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த நிலையில் டீசல் மற்றும் லொறியுடன் 7 பேர் இன்று அதிகாலை கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக வாழைச்சேனை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைதுசெய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் கல்முனை மற்றும் காத்தான்குடி பிரதேசங்களை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என வாழச்சேனை பொலிஸ் நிலைய பதில் பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் ஆர்.எம்.குமாரசிங்க எமது விசாரணையின் போது தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட 1800 டீசலை பதினெட்டு பக்கெட்டுகளில் அடைத்து வேனில் ஏற்றியதாகவும் மேலும் 21 பக்கெட்டுகளை கவனமாக பொதி செய்து லொறியில் ஏற்றியதாகவும் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வரும் வாழைச்சேனை பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட டீசலை எடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கான உரிமம் அவர்களிடம் இல்லாததால், அதிக விலைக்கு விற்பனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்ல தயாராக அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் என போலீசார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "வாழச்சென்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழச்சேனை மீனவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காத்தான்குடி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காத்தான்குடி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழைச்சேனை பொலிஸ் நிலையப் பணிப்பாளர் சப்-இன்ஸ்பெக்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எம்.குமாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாழைச்சேனை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதினெட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}