{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/slfp-to-meet-president-for-talks-on-national-govt-sirisena/",
  "time_ut": 1658995320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLFP to meet President for talks on National Govt – Sirisena",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLFP to meet President for talks on National Govt – Sirisena",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  The Sri Lanka Freedom Party will meet President Ranil Wickremesinghe for discussions on forming a national government, said Former President Maithripala Sirisena on Thursday (28).",
        "He told a media briefing that the Sri Lanka Freedom Party had continuously called for an all party government, however, that call has not been taken into consideration.",
        "SLFP to meet President for talks on National Govt – Sirisena",
        "Appropriate to call for elections – Maha Sangha tells elections Chief"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික ආණ්ඩුව ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ශ්‍රීලනිපය ජනපති හමුවෙයි – සිරිසේන",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කරන බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (28) ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය දිගින් දිගටම ඉල්ලා සිටි නමුත් එම ඉල්ලීම සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන නොමැති බව ඔහු මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "ජාතික ආණ්ඩුව ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ශ්‍රීලනිපය ජනපති හමුවෙයි – සිරිසේන",
        "මැතිවරණයක් කැඳවීම සුදුසුයි – මහා සංඝරත්නය මැතිවරණ ප්‍රධානියාට කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிறீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்து தேசிய அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தவுள்ளது - சிறிசேன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன வியாழக்கிழமை (28) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி தொடர்ச்சியாக சர்வகட்சி ஆட்சியமைப்பிற்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்து வந்த போதிலும், அந்த அழைப்பு கவனத்தில் கொள்ளப்படவில்லை என ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சிறீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்து தேசிய அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தவுள்ளது - சிறிசேன",
        "தேர்தலுக்கு அழைப்பது பொருத்தமானது - தேர்தல் தலைமைக்கு மகா சங்கத்தினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}