{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/05/fuelcrisis-private-bus-services-at-a-standstill/",
  "time_ut": 1656992160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "#FUELCRISIS: Private Bus services at a standstill",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "#FUELCRISIS: Private Bus services at a standstill",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Lanka Private Bus Owners Association says due to the fuel crisis the bus service will be completely disrupted on Tuesday (5).",
        "The Chairman of Lanka Private Bus Owners Association Gemunu Wijeratne said that this situation has arisen because SLTB Depots are not issuing sufficient fuel for private buses.",
        "He also said that at present around 10,000 buses are waiting in queues near the depots in hope of purchasing fuel.",
        "Meanwhile, the General Secretary of Ceylon Private Bus Owners’ Association Anjana Priyanjith says that the Government has failed to provide fuel to private buses.",
        "The Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) says that nearly 4,800 buses will operate on Tuesday (5).",
        "The Chief operating officer of SLTB A.S.B Weerasuriya said that inter-provincial services and provincial services are expected to be operated as usual.",
        "Meanwhile, Sri Lanka Railways noted that trains are operating on Tuesday (5) as usual.",
        "Bastian Mawath shooter killed in police shootout : Detectives reveal criminal past"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Private Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anjana Priyanjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 4,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bastian Mawath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "#FUELCRISIS: පෞද්ගලික බස් සේවා ඇනහිට ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් අඟහරුවාදා (5) බස් ධාවනය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම අඩාල වන බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න කියා සිටියේ ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ සඳහා ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් නොකිරීම හේතුවෙන් මෙම තත්ත්වය උද්ගතව ඇති බවයි.",
        "මේ වන විට ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමේ බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් බස් රථ දස දහසක් පමණ ඩිපෝ අසල පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටින බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියේය.",
        "මේ අතර ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත් මහතා පවසන්නේ පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට රජය අපොහොසත් වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා (5) බස් රථ 4800කට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක් ධාවනය කෙරෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "අන්තර් පළාත් සේවා සහ පළාත් සේවා සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ලංගම ප්‍රධාන මෙහෙයුම් නිලධාරී A.S.B වීරසූරිය මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය සඳහන් කළේ අඟහරුවාදා (5) සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි දුම්රිය ධාවනය වන බවයි.",
        "පොලිස් වෙඩි හුවමාරුවකින් බැස්ටියන් මාවතේ වෙඩික්කරු මරුට : රහස් පරීක්ෂකයින් අපරාධ අතීතය හෙළි කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,800කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "#FUELCRISIS: தனியார் பேருந்து சேவைகள் ஸ்தம்பிதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (5) பஸ் சேவை முற்றாக தடைப்படும் என இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை டிப்போக்கள் தனியார் பஸ்களுக்கு போதியளவு எரிபொருளை வழங்காத காரணத்தினால் இந்த நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது 10,000 பேருந்துகள் எரிபொருள் வாங்கும் நம்பிக்கையில் டிப்போக்களுக்கு அருகில் வரிசையில் காத்திருப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, தனியார் பேருந்துகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குவதில் அரசாங்கம் தவறியுள்ளதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் அஞ்சன பிரியஞ்சித் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "செவ்வாய்கிழமை (5) ஏறக்குறைய 4,800 பேருந்துகள் சேவையில் ஈடுபடவுள்ளதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை (SLTB) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையிலான சேவைகள் மற்றும் மாகாண சேவைகள் வழமை போன்று இடம்பெறும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதம செயற்பாட்டு அதிகாரி A.S.B வீரசூரிய தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (5) புகையிரத சேவைகள் வழமை போன்று இடம்பெறும் என இலங்கை ரயில்வே குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் போலீஸ் துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் கொல்லப்பட்டார்: துப்பறியும் நபர்கள் குற்றவியல் கடந்த காலத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தினர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஞ்சனா பிரியஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 4,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}