{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131757",
  "time_ut": 1658208913,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரணிலின் தேசிய பட்டியல் நியமனம் ! வெளியானது உயர் நீதிமன்றின் அறிவிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil's National List Appointment! The notification of the High Court was published",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe has been dismissed by the High Court questioning his right to be a member of Parliament.",
        "Today (19) the High Court was to announce whether or not the fundamental rights violation petition filed by lawyer Nagananda Kodithuwa to issue an order to weaken Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe's right to be a member of Parliament.",
        "In this case, the High Court dismissed the petition filed by questioning the right of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe to be a member of Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil's",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodithuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල්ගේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු පත්වීම! මහාධිකරණයේ නිවේදනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වීමට ඇති අයිතිය ප්‍රශ්න කරමින් මහාධිකරණය විසින් ඔහුව නෙරපා හැර තිබේ.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයක් දැරීමට ඇති අයිතිය අහෝසි කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා නීතීඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුව මහතා ගොනු කළ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩකිරීමේ පෙත්සම අද (19) මහාධිකරණය විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වීමට ඇති අයිතිය ප්‍රශ්න කරමින් ගොනුකර තිබූ පෙත්සම මහාධිකරණය නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්ගේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலின் தேசிய பட்டியல் நியமனம் ! வெளியானது உயர் நீதிமன்றின் அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்புரிமையை கேள்விக்குறியாக்கி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவை உயர்நீதிமன்றம் தள்ளுபடி செய்துள்ளது.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்புரிமையை  வலுவிழக்கச் செய்து  உத்தரவொன்றினை  பிறப்பிக்குமாறு கோரி  சட்டத்தரணி நாகாநந்த கொடித்துவக்கு  தாக்கல் செய்த  அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுவை விசாரணைக்கு ஏற்பதா இல்லையா என உயர் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (19) அறிக்கவிக்க இருந்தது.",
        "இந்நிலையில்,  பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்புரிமையை கேள்விக்குறியாக்கி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவை உயர்நீதிமன்றம் தள்ளுபடி செய்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணிலின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகாநந்த கொடித்துவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}