{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පහරදීම-නීතිඥ-සංගමය-හෙළා-දකී/101-616841",
  "time_ut": 1658457838,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පහරදීම නීතිඥ සංගමය හෙළා දකී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Bar Association condemns the attack",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Bar Association has issued a statement saying that it strongly condemns the forceful and violent attack by the authorities on the protestors at the Galle mouth around the Presidential Secretariat this morning (22).",
        "According to the statement issued by the Bar Association, it appeared that hundreds of military personnel and policemen were blocking the roads leading to the mouth of Galle and preventing the public from entering the area.",
        "The Law Society of Sri Lanka states in its announcement that at least two lawyers who tried to intervene at their professional level were assaulted by military personnel.",
        "According to the announcement, the videos also show unarmed civilians being attacked by the security forces."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The Bar Association",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පහරදීම නීතිඥ සංගමය හෙළා දකී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අවට ගාලු මුවදොරහි සිටි විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට බලධාරින් බලහත්කාරී හා ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ලෙස අද (22) අලුයම කළ පහර දීම තරයේ හෙළා දකින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ගාලු මුවදොරට පිවිසෙන මාර්ග අවහිර කරමින් හමුදා නිලධාරීන් සහ පොලිසිය සිය ගණනක් මහජනතාවට එම ප්‍රදේශයට ඇතුළුවීම වළක්වා ඇති බව පෙනෙන්නට තිබුණි බව ද නීතිඥ සංගමය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "එම ප්‍රදේශයට ඇතුළුවීමට උත්සාහ කළ නීතීඥවරුන් කිහිපදෙනකුම බලධාරින් විසින් වළකා ඇති බව කියන නීතිඥ සංගමය තම වෘත්තීය මට්ටමින් මැදිහත් වීමට උත්සාහ කළ නීතීඥවරුන් අවම වශයෙන් දෙදෙනෙකුට හමුදා නිලධාරීන් විසින් පහර දී ඇති බවට දන්වා ඇතැයි ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය සිය නිවේදනය මඟින් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "නිරායුධ සිවිල් වැසියන්ට ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් පහර දෙන අයුරු ද වීඩියෝ දර්ශනවල දැක්වෙන බව අදාළ නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த தாக்குதலை வழக்கறிஞர்கள் சங்கம் கண்டிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (22) காலை ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தை சுற்றி காலி முகத்திடலில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்கள் மீது அதிகாரிகள் நடத்திய பலவந்தமான மற்றும் வன்முறைத் தாக்குதலை வன்மையாகக் கண்டிப்பதாக இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில், நூற்றுக்கணக்கான இராணுவத்தினரும் பொலிஸாரும் காலி முகத்திடலுக்குச் செல்லும் வீதிகளை மறித்து பொதுமக்களை அப்பகுதிக்குள் நுழையவிடாமல் தடுத்ததாகத் தெரிகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் சட்டச் சங்கம் தனது அறிவிப்பில், அவர்களது தொழில் மட்டத்தில் தலையிட முயன்ற குறைந்தது இரண்டு சட்டத்தரணிகள் இராணுவத்தினரால் தாக்கப்பட்டதாகக் கூறுகிறது.",
        "அறிவிப்பின்படி, நிராயுதபாணியான பொதுமக்கள் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் தாக்கப்படுவதும் வீடியோக்களில் காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}