{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/verstappen-cruises-to-belgian-grand-prix-victory/",
  "time_ut": 1661752080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Verstappen cruises to Belgian Grand Prix victory",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Verstappen cruises to Belgian Grand Prix victory",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Max Verstappen made light work of his grid penalties to win the 2022 Belgian Grand Prix from P14 on the grid in a Red Bull one-two backed up by Sergio Perez, while pole-sitter Carlos Sainz finished P3 for Ferrari.",
        "Lewis Hamilton and Fernando Alonso tangled at Les Combes on Lap 1, leaving the Mercedes driver out of the race before Valtteri Bottas spun out in avoidance of Nicholas Latifi and brought out a Safety Car on Lap 2.",
        "The restart saw Verstappen line up eighth while Sainz led Perez – Leclerc having had to pit for mediums with a tear-off in his brake duct. Verstappen made quick work of the cars ahead, sweeping into P3 by Lap 8 with only Perez and Sainz to beat.",
        "Sainz pitted from softs to mediums on Lap 12, when Perez allowed Verstappen past and into the lead. The Dutchman extended his lead until Lap 15 and clawed back the deficit to Sainz, taking the lead on Lap 19 – taking another free pit stop on Lap 31 – before going on to win over Perez by over 18 seconds in a dominant display, with fastest lap to boot.",
        "Sainz completed the podium ahead of Mercedes’ George Russell, who had previously passed Charles Leclerc but lost out on the final podium place by just over two seconds.",
        "Leclerc made a late pit stop for soft tyres in an effort to take fastest lap, but missed out on the bonus point and only just held on to P5 ahead of Fernando Alonso. However, after being caught for speeding in the pit lane, a five-second penalty dropped him to P6.",
        "The two-time champion was re-passed by the Ferrari on the final lap but finished ahead of team mate Esteban Ocon, who overhauled Sebastian Vettel (P8) and Pierre Gasly (P9) late in the race. Alex Albon rounded out the top 10 for Williams, fending off Lance Stroll for the final point.",
        "Lando Norris caught up to a battling Albon and Stroll by the end of the race but the McLaren driver missed out and finished 12th, ahead of Yuki Tsunoda, who won a late-race battle against Alfa Romeo's Zhou Guanyu.",
        "That left Daniel Ricciardo in P15 ahead of the Haas pair – Kevin Magnussen 16th and Mick Schumacher 17th – while Nicholas Latifi finished 18th after taking three pit stops."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Belgian Grand Prix",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Max Verstappen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belgian Grand Prix",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "P14",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sergio Perez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carlos Sainz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ferrari",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lewis Hamilton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando Alonso",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Les Combes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valtteri Bottas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nicholas Latifi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sainz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leclerc",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "P3",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sainz",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sainz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 12",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dutchman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sainz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 19",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 31",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sainz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes’ George Russell",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charles Leclerc",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "just over two seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Leclerc",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando Alonso",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-second",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ferrari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esteban Ocon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sebastian Vettel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P8",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pierre Gasly",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alex Albon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Williams",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lance Stroll",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lando Norris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Albon",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "McLaren",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuki Tsunoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alfa Romeo's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhou Guanyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daniel Ricciardo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kevin Magnussen 16th",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mick Schumacher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nicholas Latifi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Verstappen බෙල්ජියම් ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී ජයග්‍රහණය කරා ගමන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මැක්ස් වර්ස්ටැපන් සිය ජාල දඬුවම්වලින් සැහැල්ලුවෙන් ක්‍රියා කර, සර්ජියෝ පෙරෙස්ගේ සහාය ඇතිව රෙඩ්බුල් එක-දෙකක ග්‍රිඩ් මත පී 14 සිට පී 14 බෙල්ජියම් ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී දිනා ගැනීමට සමත් වූ අතර පොලු-සිටර් කාලෝස් සයින්ස් ෆෙරාරි වෙනුවෙන් පී 3 අවසන් කළේය.",
        "Lewis Hamilton සහ Fernando Alonso 1 ලැප් එකේ Les Combes හිදී පැටලී සිටි අතර, Valtteri Bottas නිකොලස් ලැටිෆි මගහැර 2 ලැප් එකේ ආරක්ෂිත මෝටර් රථයක් ගෙන ඒමට පෙර මර්සිඩීස් රියදුරා තරඟයෙන් ඉවත් විය.",
        "නැවත ආරම්භයේදී Verstappen අටවැනි ස්ථානයට පත් වූ අතර Sainz විසින් නායකත්වය දුන් Perez – Leclerc හට ඔහුගේ තිරිංග නාලිකාවේ ඉරීමක් සමඟ මාධ්‍යයන් සඳහා පිටව යාමට සිදු විය. Verstappen ඉදිරියෙන් ඇති මෝටර් රථ ඉක්මනින් වැඩ කළේය, පෙරෙස් සහ Sainz පමණක් පරාජය කිරීමට ලැප් 8 වන විට P3 වෙත අතුගා දැමීය.",
        "පෙරෙස් Verstappen පසුකර පෙරමුණට යාමට ඉඩ දුන් විට Sainz 12 වන වටයේ දී මෘදු සිට මාධ්‍ය දක්වා තරඟ වැදුණි. ලන්දේසි ජාතිකයා 15 වන වටය දක්වා තම ඉදිරිය දිගු කර, 19 වන වටයේ පෙරමුණ ගෙන, සයින්ස් වෙත හිඟය ආපසු ලබා දුන්නේය - 31 වන වටයේදී තවත් නොමිලේ පිට් නැවතුමක් ලබා ගනිමින් - ප්‍රමුඛ සංදර්ශනයකින් තත්පර 18කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයකින් පෙරෙස්ව ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට පෙර, වේගවත්ම ප්‍රදර්ශනයකින්. lap එකට boot.",
        "මීට පෙර චාල්ස් ලෙක්ලර්ක් පසුකර ගිය නමුත් තත්පර දෙකකින් අවසන් වේදිකාවේ ස්ථානය අහිමි වූ මර්සිඩීස් කණ්ඩායමේ ජෝර්ජ් රසල්ට වඩා ඉදිරියෙන් සයින්ස් වේදිකාව සම්පූර්ණ කළේය.",
        "Leclerc වේගවත්ම ලැප් ලබා ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස මෘදු ටයර් සඳහා ප්‍රමාද වූ වළක් නැවැත්වූ නමුත් ප්‍රසාද ලකුණ අහිමි වූ අතර ප්‍රනාන්දු ඇලන්සෝට වඩා ඉදිරියෙන් P5 පමණක් අල්ලාගෙන සිටියේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, වළේ මංතීරුවේදී වේගයෙන් රිය පැදවීම නිසා ඔහුට හසුවීමෙන් පසු තත්පර පහක දඬුවම් පහරකින් ඔහු P6 වෙත වැටුණි.",
        "දෙවතාවක් ශූරයා ෆෙරාරි විසින් අවසන් වටයේදී යලි පසුකර ගිය නමුත් සෙබස්තියන් වෙටෙල් (පී 8) සහ පියරේ ගැස්ලි (පී 9) තරගයේ ප්‍රමාද වී නැවත සකස් කළ කණ්ඩායම් සගයා වන එස්ටෙබන් ඔකොන් ඉදිරියෙන් අවසන් විය. ඇලෙක්ස් ඇල්බන් විලියම්ස් සඳහා හොඳම 10 දෙනා අතරට ගිය අතර, අවසාන කරුණ සඳහා ලාන්ස් ස්ට්‍රෝල්ගෙන් වැළකී සිටියේය.",
        "ලැන්ඩෝ නොරිස් තරඟය අවසන් වන විට ඇල්බන් සහ ස්ට්‍රෝල් සමඟ සටන් කළ නමුත් මැක්ලරන් රියැදුරුට අහිමි වී 12 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත් විය, ඇල්ෆා රෝමියෝගේ ෂෝ ගුවාන්යුට එරෙහිව ප්‍රමාද වූ ධාවන තරඟයක් ජයගත් යුකී ට්සුනෝඩා ඉදිරියෙන්.",
        "එය P15 හි Haas යුගලයට වඩා ඉදිරියෙන් සිටි Daniel Ricciardo - Kevin Magnussen 16th සහ Mick Schumacher 17th - Nicholas Latifi 18 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත් වූයේ පිට් නැවතුම් තුනකින් පසුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බෙල්ජියම් ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැක්ස් වර්ස්ටැපන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල්ජියම් ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "P14",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ජියෝ පෙරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carlos Sainz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුවිස් හැමිල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු ඇලන්සෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Les Combes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මර්සිඩීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valtteri Bottas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිකලස් ලැටිෆි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සයින්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "P3",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සයින්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයින්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වටය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්දේසි ජාතිකයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සයින්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වන වටය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 වටය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයින්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මර්සිඩීස්ගේ ජෝර්ජ් රසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාල්ස් ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර දෙකකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු ඇලන්සෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර පහක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esteban Ocon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙබස්තියන් වෙටෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P8",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියරේ ගෑස්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්ස් ඇල්බන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විලියම්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාන්ස් ස්ට්‍රෝල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලැන්ඩෝ නොරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්බන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැක්ලරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuki Tsunoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ෆා රෝමියෝගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhou Guanyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daniel Ricciardo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙවින් මැග්නුසන් 16 වැනියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මික් ෂූමාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිකලස් ලැටිෆි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெல்ஜிய கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸ் வெற்றிக்கு வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் பயணம் செய்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேக்ஸ் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் தனது கிரிட் பெனால்டிகளை இலகுவாகச் செய்து, 2022 பெல்ஜிய கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸை P14 இலிருந்து செர்ஜியோ பெரெஸால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்ட ரெட் புல் ஒன்று-இரண்டில் வென்றார், அதே நேரத்தில் போல்-சிட்டர் கார்லோஸ் சைன்ஸ் ஃபெராரிக்கு P3 ஐ முடித்தார்.",
        "லூயிஸ் ஹாமில்டன் மற்றும் பெர்னாண்டோ அலோன்சோ ஆகியோர் லேப் 1 இல் லெஸ் கோம்ப்ஸில் சிக்கினார்கள், மெர்சிடிஸ் டிரைவரை பந்தயத்திலிருந்து வெளியேற்றினார், வால்டேரி போட்டாஸ் நிக்கோலஸ் லாடிஃபியைத் தவிர்த்துவிட்டு லேப் 2 இல் ஒரு பாதுகாப்பு காரை வெளியே கொண்டு வந்தார்.",
        "மறுதொடக்கத்தில் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் எட்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார், அதே நேரத்தில் சைன்ஸ் தலைமையிலான பெரெஸ் - லெக்லெர்க் தனது பிரேக் டக்டில் ஒரு கிழிந்த நிலையில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு பிட் செய்ய வேண்டியிருந்தது. வெர்ஸ்டாப்பென் முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும் கார்களை விரைவாகச் செயல்படுத்தினார், பெரெஸ் மற்றும் சைன்ஸ் ஆகியோரை மட்டுமே கொண்டு லேப் 8 இல் P3 இல் ஸ்வீப் செய்தார்.",
        "லேப் 12 இல், பெரெஸ் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பனைக் கடந்து முன்னணியில் இருக்க அனுமதித்தபோது, ​​சைன்ஸ் சாஃப்ட்ஸ் முதல் மீடியம்ஸ் வரை ஆட்டமிழந்தார். டச்சுக்காரர் லேப் 15 வரை தனது முன்னிலையை நீட்டித்து, பின்னடைவை சைன்ஸுக்குத் திருப்பி, லேப் 19 இல் முன்னிலை பெற்றார் - லேப் 31 இல் மற்றொரு இலவச பிட் ஸ்டாப் எடுத்து - மேலாதிக்கக் காட்சியில் 18 வினாடிகளுக்கு மேல் பெரெஸை வென்றார். மடியில் துவக்க.",
        "முன்னதாக சார்லஸ் லெக்லெர்க்கைத் தாண்டிய மெர்சிடிஸின் ஜார்ஜ் ரஸ்ஸலை விட சைன்ஸ் மேடையை நிறைவு செய்தார், ஆனால் அவர் இரண்டு வினாடிகளுக்கு மேல் இறுதி மேடையில் தோற்றார்.",
        "லெக்லெர்க் மிக வேகமாக மடியில் ஏறும் முயற்சியில் மென்மையான டயர்களுக்கு தாமதமாக பிட் ஸ்டாப் செய்தார், ஆனால் போனஸ் புள்ளியைத் தவறவிட்டார், மேலும் பெர்னாண்டோ அலோன்சோவை விட P5 ஐ மட்டுமே பிடித்தார். இருப்பினும், பிட் லேனில் வேகமாகச் சென்றதற்காக பிடிபட்ட பிறகு, ஐந்து வினாடி பெனால்டி அவரை P6 க்கு வீழ்த்தியது.",
        "இரண்டு முறை சாம்பியனான ஃபெராரி கடைசி மடியில் ஃபெராரியால் மீண்டும் கடந்து சென்றார், ஆனால் பந்தயத்தில் தாமதமாக செபாஸ்டியன் வெட்டல் (பி 8) மற்றும் பியர் கேஸ்லி (பி 9) ஆகியோரை மாற்றியமைத்த அணித் தோழர் எஸ்டெபன் ஓகானை விட முன்னேறினார். அலெக்ஸ் ஆல்பன் வில்லியம்ஸுக்கு முதல் 10 இடங்களைப் பிடித்தார், இறுதிப் புள்ளிக்கு லான்ஸ் ஸ்ட்ரோலைத் தடுக்கிறார்.",
        "பந்தயத்தின் முடிவில் லாண்டோ நோரிஸ் அல்பான் மற்றும் ஸ்ட்ரோலை எதிர்த்துப் போராடினார், ஆனால் மெக்லாரன் ஓட்டுநர் ஆட்டமிழந்து 12வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார், அவர் ஆல்ஃபா ரோமியோவின் ஜாவ் குவான்யுவுக்கு எதிராக தாமதமான பந்தயப் போரில் வென்ற யுகி சுனோடாவை விட முன்னேறினார்.",
        "இது ஹாஸ் ஜோடியை விட P15 இல் டேனியல் ரிச்சியார்டோவை விட்டுச் சென்றது - கெவின் மேக்னுசென் 16வது மற்றும் மிக் ஷூமேக்கர் 17வது - நிக்கோலஸ் லதிஃபி மூன்று பிட் ஸ்டாப்களை எடுத்து 18வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பெல்ஜிய கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேக்ஸ் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்ஜிய கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "P14",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செர்ஜியோ பெரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்லோஸ் சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபெராரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லூயிஸ் ஹாமில்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ அலோன்சோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெஸ் கோம்ப்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெர்சிடிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டேரி போட்டாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக்கோலஸ் லத்திஃபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி3",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடி 12",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டச்சுக்காரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடி 19",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடி 31",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெர்சிடிஸ் ஜார்ஜ் ரஸ்ஸல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சார்லஸ் லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வினாடிகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ அலோன்சோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து-வினாடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபெராரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்டெபன் ஓகான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செபாஸ்டியன் வெட்டல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P8",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியர் கேஸ்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்ஸ் அல்பன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வில்லியம்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லான்ஸ் உலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லாண்டோ நோரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்பன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெக்லாரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuki Tsunoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆல்ஃபா ரோமியோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhou Guanyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டேனியல் ரிச்சியார்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெவின் மேக்னுசென் 16வது இடம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிக் ஷூமேக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக்கோலஸ் லத்திஃபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}