{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/ranil-wickremesinghe-sworn-in-as-sri-lanka-president-97747/",
  "time_ut": 1658378880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe sworn in as Sri Lanka President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe sworn in as Sri Lanka President",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Ranil Wickremesinghe was swron is as the President of Sri Lanka Lanka at the Parliament complex in the presence of Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, his office said.",
        "He was elected by 134 legislators of the 225 member assembly after President Gotabaya Rajapaksa resigned amid protests triggered by severe monetary instability from two years of money printing.",
        "Sri Lanka’s 12-month inflation topped 50 percent and the rupee had collapsed from 200 to 360 in the second quarter of 2022."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second quarter of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන් බව ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "වසර දෙකක මුදල් මුද්‍රණයෙන් ඇති වූ දැඩි මූල්‍ය අස්ථාවරත්වය හේතුවෙන් ඇති වූ විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ඔහු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 කින් යුත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 දෙනෙකු විසින් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මාස 12 ක උද්ධමනය සියයට 50 ඉක්ම වූ අතර 2022 දෙවන කාර්තුවේදී රුපියල 200 සිට 360 දක්වා කඩා වැටී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 දෙවන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அதிபராக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய முன்னிலையில் பதவியேற்றதாக அவரது அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளாக பணம் அச்சடித்ததில் இருந்து கடுமையான பண ஸ்திரமின்மையால் தூண்டப்பட்ட எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ராஜினாமா செய்த பின்னர், 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட சட்டமன்றத்தில் 134 சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் 12 மாத பணவீக்கம் 50 சதவீதத்தை எட்டியது மற்றும் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இரண்டாவது காலாண்டில் ரூபாயின் மதிப்பு 200 இலிருந்து 360 ஆக சரிந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் இரண்டாவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}