{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/spc-embraces-biggest-technological-shift-in-school-book-printing-arena/",
  "time_ut": 1660478100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SPC embraces biggest technological shift in school book printing arena",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SPC embraces biggest technological shift in school book printing arena",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Inauguration of the state-of-the-art Komori GL440 advanced offset printing machine followed by a tree planting program took place at the State Printing Corporation (SPC), Panaluwa recently.The ceremony was conducted in the presence of the Corporation staff, officials from the Ministry of Education and members of JDC Printing Technologies (Pvt) Ltd., the local agents for Komori, Japan who handled the installation and commissioning of the machine. The investment in the new Lithrone G40 advance model is an important upgrade from conventional presses achieved in partnership with Komori, Japan.",
        "This is the first 4 color sheet fed offset printing machine SPC has installed since 1982. The new Lithrone G40 Advance is by far the biggest technological shift in the schoolbook printing arena in Sri Lanka. Upscaling is a constant process and now with Komori, SPC has the tools and techniques to deliver on time without any compromise in quality. Investment in this press certainly contributes to the modernization of the factory and creates new markets and opportunities for SPC.",
        "JDC Printing Technologies, incorporated in 1979, a subsidiary of Nawaloka Holdings and a member of Redline Capital is a well recognized name in the printing and packaging industry in Sri Lanka having established its position as one of the leading suppliers of machinery and materials from pre-press to finishing.Chandula Perera, Managing Director, Redline Capital; Dinesh Mervyn, CEO, JDC Group of Companies; Buddhike Fernando, Head of Sales; Chaminda de Silva, Technical Manager (offset) and the Technical Team from JDC participated in the event while Invitees from the Ministry of Education were M.N. Ranasinghe, Secretary, and D.S. Pathmasiri, Chief Financial Officer.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Komori GL440",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Printing Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC Printing Technologies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Komori",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithrone",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Komori",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithrone G40 Advance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Komori",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JDC Printing Technologies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nawaloka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Redline Capital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandula Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Redline Capital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Mervyn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC Group of Companies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhike Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda de Silva, Technical",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Technical Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Invitees from the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.N. Ranasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.S. Pathmasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SPC පාසල් පොත් මුද්‍රණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ විශාලතම තාක්‍ෂණික වෙනසක් වැළඳ ගනී",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවීනතම Komori GL440 උසස් ඕෆ්සෙට් මුද්‍රණ යන්ත්‍රය විවෘත කිරීම සහ රුක් රෝපණ වැඩසටහනක් පසුගියදා පානළුව රාජ්‍ය මුද්‍රණ නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ දී සිදු විය. අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් සහ JDC Printing Technologies (Pvt) Ltd හි සාමාජිකයින්, ජපානයේ Komori හි දේශීය නියෝජිතයින්, යන්ත්‍රය ස්ථාපනය කිරීම සහ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සිදු කරන ලදී. නව Lithrone G40 අත්තිකාරම් මාදිලියේ ආයෝජනය ජපානයේ Komori සමඟ හවුල්කාරිත්වයෙන් සාම්ප්‍රදායික මුද්‍රණ යන්ත්‍රවලින් වැදගත් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමකි.",
        "මෙය 1982 සිට SPC ස්ථාපනය කරන ලද ප්‍රථම වර්ණ පත්‍ර 4 කින් සමන්විත ඕෆ්සෙට් මුද්‍රණ යන්ත්‍රය වේ. නව Lithrone G40 Advance යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් පොත් මුද්‍රණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ මෙතෙක් සිදු වූ විශාලතම තාක්ෂණික පෙරළියයි. Upscaling යනු නිරන්තර ක්‍රියාවලියක් වන අතර දැන් Komori සමඟින්, ගුණාත්මක භාවයේ කිසිදු සම්මුතියකින් තොරව නියමිත වේලාවට ලබා දීමට SPC සතුව මෙවලම් සහ ශිල්පීය ක්‍රම තිබේ. මෙම මුද්‍රණාලයේ ආයෝජනය නිසැකවම කර්මාන්තශාලාවේ නවීකරණයට දායක වන අතර SPC සඳහා නව වෙලඳපොලවල් සහ අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය කරයි.",
        "නවලෝක හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි අනුබද්ධිත සහ රෙඩ්ලයින් කැපිටල් හි සාමාජිකයෙකු වන 1979 දී සංස්ථාපිත JDC Printing Technologies, පෙර සිට යන්ත්‍රෝපකරණ සහ ද්‍රව්‍ය සපයන ප්‍රමුඛතම සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු ලෙස තම ස්ථානය තහවුරු කර ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම් ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රසිද්ධ නමකි. අවසන් කිරීමට ඔබන්න. Redline Capital හි කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ චන්දුල පෙරේරා; JDC සමාගම් සමූහයේ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී දිනේෂ් මර්වින්; බුද්ධිකේ ප්‍රනාන්දු, විකුණුම් ප්‍රධානී; මෙම අවස්ථාවට JDC හි තාක්ෂණික කළමනාකරු (ඕෆ්සෙට්) චමින්ද ද සිල්වා සහ තාක්ෂණික කණ්ඩායම සහභාගී වූ අතර අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ආරාධිතයින් වූයේ M.N. රණසිංහ, ලේකම්, ඩී.එස්. පත්මසිරි, ප්‍රධාන මූල්‍ය නිලධාරී.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමෝරි GL440",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුද්රණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංස්ථා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC මුද්‍රණ තාක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමෝරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිත්රෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමෝරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝෂණය කළා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithron G40 අත්තිකාරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමෝරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JDC මුද්‍රණ තාක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවලෝක හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Redline Capital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දුල පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Redline Capital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් මර්වින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC සමාගම් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධික ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද ද සිල්වා, තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාක්ෂණික කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් ආරාධිතයෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.එන්. රණසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එස් පත්මසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பள்ளி புத்தக அச்சிடும் அரங்கில் SPC மிகப்பெரிய தொழில்நுட்ப மாற்றத்தை தழுவியுள்ளது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "அதிநவீன Komori GL440 அதிநவீன ஆஃப்செட் அச்சிடும் இயந்திரத்தின் திறப்பு விழாவும் அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து மரம் நடும் நிகழ்ச்சியும் பனலுவையில் உள்ள அரச அச்சகக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தில் (SPC) அண்மையில் இடம்பெற்றது. மாநகராட்சி ஊழியர்கள், அதிகாரிகள் முன்னிலையில் விழா நடைபெற்றது. கல்வி அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் JDC பிரிண்டிங் டெக்னாலஜிஸ் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் உறுப்பினர்கள், ஜப்பானின் கொமோரிக்கான உள்ளூர் முகவர்கள், இயந்திரத்தை நிறுவுதல் மற்றும் இயக்குதல் ஆகியவற்றைக் கையாண்டனர். புதிய Lithrone G40 அட்வான்ஸ் மாடலில் முதலீடு செய்வது ஜப்பானின் Komori உடன் கூட்டு முயற்சியில் பெறப்பட்ட வழக்கமான அச்சகங்களில் இருந்து ஒரு முக்கியமான மேம்படுத்தல் ஆகும்.",
        "இது 1982 ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து நிறுவப்பட்ட முதல் 4 வண்ணத் தாள் ஊட்டப்பட்ட ஆஃப்செட் அச்சிடும் இயந்திரம் SPC ஆகும். புதிய Lithrone G40 Advance இலங்கையில் பள்ளி புத்தக அச்சிடும் அரங்கில் மிகப் பெரிய தொழில்நுட்ப மாற்றமாகும். அப்ஸ்கேலிங் என்பது ஒரு நிலையான செயல்முறையாகும், இப்போது கோமோரியுடன், தரத்தில் எந்த சமரசமும் இல்லாமல் சரியான நேரத்தில் வழங்குவதற்கான கருவிகள் மற்றும் நுட்பங்களை SPC கொண்டுள்ளது. இந்த பத்திரிகையில் முதலீடு நிச்சயமாக தொழிற்சாலையின் நவீனமயமாக்கலுக்கு பங்களிக்கிறது மற்றும் SPC க்கு புதிய சந்தைகள் மற்றும் வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்குகிறது.",
        "நவலோக ஹோல்டிங்ஸின் துணை நிறுவனமான மற்றும் ரெட்லைன் கேப்பிட்டலின் உறுப்பினரான 1979 இல் இணைக்கப்பட்ட ஜே.டி.சி பிரின்டிங் டெக்னாலஜிஸ், இலங்கையில் அச்சிடும் மற்றும் பேக்கேஜிங் துறையில் நன்கு அறியப்பட்ட பெயராகும். முடிக்க அழுத்தவும். சந்துல பெரேரா, முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர், Redline Capital; Dinesh Mervyn, CEO, JDC Group of Companies; புத்திகே பெர்னாண்டோ, விற்பனைத் தலைவர்; சமிந்த டி சில்வா, தொழிநுட்ப முகாமையாளர் (ஆஃப்செட்) மற்றும் ஜே.டி.சி.யின் தொழில்நுட்பக் குழுவினர் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டதுடன், கல்வி அமைச்சின் அழைப்பாளர்களான எம்.என். ரணசிங்க, செயலாளர், டி.எஸ்.பத்மசிறி, பிரதம நிதி அதிகாரி.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோமோரி ஜிஎல்440",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில அச்சு கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேடிசி பிரிண்டிங் டெக்னாலஜிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொமோரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லித்ரோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொமோரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லித்ரோன் ஜி40 அட்வான்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொமோரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜேடிசி பிரிண்டிங் டெக்னாலஜிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவலோகா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெட்லைன் மூலதனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்துல பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெட்லைன் மூலதனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் மேர்வின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDC குழும நிறுவனங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்திகே பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த டி சில்வா, தொழில்நுட்ப",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழில்நுட்ப குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சிலிருந்து அழைக்கப்பட்டவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.என். ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எஸ்.பத்மசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}