{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83554/three-arrested-for-torching-pms-private-residence",
  "time_ut": 1657431240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three arrested for torching PM’s private residence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three arrested for torching PM’s private residence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Three people have been arrested for torching the private residence of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe located on the 5th Lane in Kollupitiya.",
        "Among the arrestees is a 19-year-old residing in Mount Lavinia. The other two suspects were identified as residents of Kadawatha and Galle areas.",
        "The police are probing the incident further to apprehend other suspects who are involved in the incident.",
        "During a protest staged outside the prime minister’s private residence, a group of people had stormed the premises and later set fire to the establishment last night (09).",
        "Meanwhile, several media persons on duty were brutally attacked by the STF officers at the scene.",
        "Island-wide mass public protests were organized yesterday, demanding President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to resign immediately.",
        "Tens of thousands of people thronged Colombo from various parts of the country to take part in the demonstrations.",
        "The protesters who advanced through police barricades had stormed the President’s House in Colombo Fort and occupied the premises."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mount Lavinia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැතිගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබූ තිදෙනෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොල්ලුපිටිය 5 වන පටුමගේ පිහිටි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබූ පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පිරිස අතර ගල්කිස්ස ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකු ද වනවා. අනෙක් සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා කඩවත සහ ගාල්ල ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන්.",
        "සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ තවත් සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පොලිසිය සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදු කරයි.",
        "ඊයේ (09) රාත්‍රියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ඉදිරිපිට පැවති විරෝධතාවක් අතරතුර කිසියම් පිරිසක් එම පරිශ්‍රයට කඩා වැදී පසුව එම ආයතනයට ගිනි තබා තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර එම ස්ථානයේ රාජකාරියේ නියුතු මාධ්‍යවේදීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දී ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් දීප ව්‍යාප්ත මහජන විරෝධතා ඊයේ දිනයේදී සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි.",
        "පෙළපාලිවලට සහභාගි වීම සඳහා දස දහස් ගණන් ජනතාව දිවයිනේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවලින් කොළඹට පැමිණ සිටියහ.",
        "පොලිස් බාධක මැදින් ඉදිරියට පැමිණි විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ කොටුවේ පිහිටි ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී එම පරිශ්‍රය අත්පත් කරගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமரின் இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த மூவர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி 5ம் பாதையில் அமைந்துள்ள பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் கல்கிசை பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் 19 வயது இளைஞனும் உள்ளான். மற்றைய இரு சந்தேக நபர்களும் கடவத்தை மற்றும் காலி பிரதேசங்களை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இச்சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய ஏனைய சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்ய பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே நேற்று (09) இரவு நடத்தப்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​ஒரு குழுவினர் வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து பின்னர் நிறுவனத்திற்கு தீ வைத்தனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், பணியில் இருந்த பல ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் சம்பவ இடத்தில் STF அதிகாரிகளால் கொடூரமான முறையில் தாக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் நேற்று பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "இந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களில் பங்கேற்பதற்காக நாட்டின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் இருந்தும் பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் கொழும்பில் குவிந்தனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் தடைகளை மீறி முன்னேறிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்டு, வளாகத்தை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}