{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/singapore-says-gotabaya-granted-short-term-visit-pass/",
  "time_ut": 1658407860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Singapore says Gotabaya granted short-term visit pass",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Singapore says Gotabaya granted short-term visit pass",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(THE HINDU); Former Sri Lanka President was issued a 14-day visit pass when he arrived in Singapore on July 14, reports the Hindu.",
        "Singapore has granted a 14-day short-term visit pass to former Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa as he entered the country on a “private visit” on July 14, according to immigration authorities in Singapore.",
        "Rajapaksa, 73, on July 13 left Sri Lanka to the Maldives and then Singapore and resigned after a popular uprising against his government for mismanaging the economy.",
        "In a statement released in response to media queries about Rajapaksa’s visit to Singapore, the Immigration and Checkpoints Authority (ICA) said that he was granted a short-term visit pass (STVP) on arrival, reported the Hindu.",
        "Rajapaksa was issued a 14-day visit pass when he arrived in Singapore on July 14, according to a report by The Straits Times newspaper.",
        "A Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesman said last week that Mr. Rajapaksa has not asked for asylum and neither has he been granted any asylum.",
        "The ICA said visitors from Sri Lanka who enter Singapore for social visits will generally be issued with an STVP with a duration of up to 30 days.",
        "Those who need to extend their stay here may apply online for an extension of their STVP.",
        "Applications will be assessed on a case-by-case basis, said the ICA.",
        "Attacks on President’s private residence: Police seek video & photos for probe"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "HINDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration and Checkpoints Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිංගප්පූරුව පවසන්නේ ගෝඨාභය කෙටි කාලීන සංචාර අවසර පත්‍රය ලබා දුන් බවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ද හින්දු); ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජූලි 14 වැනිදා සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේදී දින 14ක සංචාර බලපත්‍රයක් නිකුත් කර ඇති බව හින්දු පුවත්පත වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුවේ ආගමන බලධාරීන්ට අනුව, සිංගප්පූරුවේ \"පුද්ගලික සංචාරයක්\" සඳහා ජුලි 14 වන දින දිවයිනට පැමිණි හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සිංගප්පූරුව දින 14 ක කෙටි කාලීන සංචාර අවසර පත්‍රයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි රාජපක්ෂ, ජූලි 13 වන දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් මාලදිවයිනට සහ සිංගප්පූරුවට පිටත්ව ගොස් ආර්ථිකය වැරදි ලෙස කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහුගේ රජයට එරෙහිව මහජන නැගිටීමෙන් පසු ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂගේ සිංගප්පූරු සංචාරය පිළිබඳ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රශ්නවලට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් නිකුත් කළ ප්‍රකාශයක ආගමන හා මුරපොල අධිකාරිය (ICA) කියා සිටියේ ඔහුට පැමිණීමේදී කෙටි කාලීන සංචාර අවසර පත්‍රයක් (STVP) ලබා දුන් බවයි.",
        "ජුලි 14 වැනිදා සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණි රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට දින 14ක චාරිකා බලපත්‍රයක් නිකුත් කර ඇති බව ද ස්ට්‍රේට්ස් ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පතේ වාර්තාවක දැක්වේ.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු පසුගිය සතියේ කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සරණාගතභාවය ඉල්ලා නොමැති බවත් ඔහුට කිසිදු රැකවරණයක් ලබා දී නොමැති බවත්ය.",
        "සමාජ සංචාර සඳහා සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පැමිණෙන අමුත්තන්ට සාමාන්‍යයෙන් දින 30ක් දක්වා කාලයක් සහිත STVP එකක් නිකුත් කරන බව ICA පවසයි.",
        "මෙහි රැඳී සිටීමට අවශ්‍ය අයට ඔවුන්ගේ STVP දිගුවක් සඳහා මාර්ගගතව අයදුම් කළ හැකිය.",
        "අයදුම්පත් එක් එක් සිද්ධිය අනුව තක්සේරු කරනු ලබන බව ICA පවසයි.",
        "ජනපතිගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ප්‍රහාර: පොලිසිය පරීක්‍ෂණයට වීඩියෝ සහ ඡායාරූප සොයයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා මුරපොල අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Straits Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய குறுகிய கால பயண அனுமதியை வழங்கியதாக சிங்கப்பூர் கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(தி இந்து); இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஜூலை 14 ஆம் திகதி சிங்கப்பூர் வந்தடைந்தபோது 14 நாள் பயண அனுமதிச் சீட்டு வழங்கப்பட்டதாக இந்து செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகளின் கூற்றுப்படி, இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ஜூலை 14 அன்று \"தனிப்பட்ட பயணமாக\" நாட்டிற்கு வந்தபோது, ​​சிங்கப்பூர் 14 நாள் குறுகிய கால பயண அனுமதியை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "73 வயதான ராஜபக்சே, ஜூலை 13 அன்று இலங்கையை விட்டு மாலத்தீவுக்கும் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் சென்று பொருளாதாரத்தை தவறாக நிர்வகிப்பதற்காக தனது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான மக்கள் கிளர்ச்சிக்குப் பிறகு ராஜினாமா செய்தார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சவின் சிங்கப்பூர் பயணம் குறித்த ஊடகங்களின் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலடி கொடுக்கும் வகையில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கையில், குடிவரவு மற்றும் சோதனைச் சாவடிகள் ஆணையம் (ஐசிஏ) அவருக்கு வந்தவுடன் குறுகிய கால பயண அனுமதி (எஸ்டிவிபி) வழங்கப்பட்டதாக கூறியதாக தி ஹிந்து செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 14ஆம் தேதி சிங்கப்பூர் வந்தபோது ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு 14 நாள் பயண அனுமதிச் சீட்டு வழங்கப்பட்டதாக தி ஸ்ட்ரெய்ட்ஸ் டைம்ஸ் செய்தித்தாள் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்ச தஞ்சம் கோரவில்லை என்றும், அவருக்கு எந்த அடைக்கலமும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் கடந்த வாரம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சமூகப் பயணங்களுக்காக சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழையும் இலங்கையிலிருந்து வரும் பார்வையாளர்களுக்கு பொதுவாக 30 நாட்கள் வரையிலான கால அளவு கொண்ட STVP வழங்கப்படும் என்று ICA தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இங்கு தங்குவதை நீட்டிக்க விரும்புபவர்கள் தங்கள் STVP இன் நீட்டிப்புக்கு ஆன்லைனில் விண்ணப்பிக்கலாம்.",
        "விண்ணப்பங்கள் ஒவ்வொரு வழக்கின் அடிப்படையில் மதிப்பிடப்படும் என்று ICA தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல்: விசாரணைக்காக காணொளி மற்றும் புகைப்படங்களை பொலிஸார் நாடியுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் சோதனைச் சாவடிகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐசிஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ட்ரெய்ட்ஸ் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐசிஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐசிஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}