{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84737/staff-level-agreement-an-important-step-forward-for-sri-lanka-imf-chief",
  "time_ut": 1662273960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Staff-level agreement an important step forward for Sri Lanka - IMF chief",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Staff-level agreement an important step forward for Sri Lanka - IMF chief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Managing Director of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) Kristalina Georgieva says she is very pleased that IMF staff and Sri Lankan government officials have reached a staff-level agreement to support the country’s economic policies with a 48-month Extended Fund Facility of about US$2.9 billion.",
        "“This is an important step forward for Sri Lanka,” she said in a twitter message on Sunday.",
        "On Thursday, it was announced that IMF staff and the Sri Lankan authorities have reached a staff-level agreement to support Sri Lanka’s economic policies with a 48-month arrangement under the Extended Fund Facility (EFF) of about US$2.9 billion.",
        "This was at the end of an IMF mission led by Mr. Peter Breuer and Mr. Masahiro Nozaki who visited Colombo from August 24 to September 1, 2022 to continue discussions on IMF support for Sri Lanka and the authorities’ comprehensive economic reform program.",
        "The objectives of Sri Lanka’s new Fund-supported program are to restore macroeconomic stability and debt sustainability, while safeguarding financial stability, protecting the vulnerable, and stepping up structural reforms to address corruption vulnerabilities and unlock Sri Lanka’s growth potential, the IMF said.",
        "However, debt relief from Sri Lanka’s creditors and additional financing from multilateral partners will be required to help ensure debt sustainability and close financing gaps.",
        "Financing assurances to restore debt sustainability from Sri Lanka’s official creditors and making a good faith effort to reach a collaborative agreement with private creditors are crucial before the IMF can provide financial support to Sri Lanka, it said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kristalina Georgieva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US$2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Extended Fund Facility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US$2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24 to September 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැදගත් ඉදිරි පියවරක් - IMF ප්‍රධානියා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂිකා Kristalina Georgieva පවසන්නේ, IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ නිලධාරීන්, ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් 2.9ක පමණ විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමක් සමඟින් රටේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීම පිළිබඳව තමන් ඉතා සතුටට පත්වන බවයි. බිලියන.",
        "“මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා වැදගත් ඉදිරි පියවරක්,” ඇය ඉරිදා ට්විටර් පණිවිඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියාය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක පමණ විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) යටතේ මාස 48 ක විධිවිධානයක් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණ ඇති බව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා නිවේදනය කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහය සහ බලධාරීන්ගේ විස්තීරණ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ වැඩසටහන පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට 2022 අගෝස්තු 24 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 1 දක්වා කොළඹට පැමිණි පීටර් බෲවර් සහ මසාහිරෝ නොසාකි මහතාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් IMF මෙහෙයුමක් අවසානයේ මෙය සිදු විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව අරමුදල් අනුග්‍රහය සහිත වැඩසටහනේ අරමුණු වන්නේ සාර්ව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ණය තිරසාරභාවය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීම, මූල්‍ය ස්ථාවරත්වය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම, අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි අය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ දූෂණ අවදානම් විසඳීම සඳහා ව්‍යුහාත්මක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ වේගවත් කිරීම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්ධන විභවය විවෘත කිරීම බව IMF පවසයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් ණය සහන සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික හවුල්කරුවන්ගෙන් අතිරේක මූල්‍යකරණය ණය තිරසාර බව සහතික කිරීමට සහ මූල්‍ය පරතරය පියවීමට අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "IMF විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මූල්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීමට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිල ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් ණය තිරසාරභාවය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා මූල්‍ය සහතික කිරීම් සහ පෞද්ගලික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සහයෝගී ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීමට සද්භාවයෙන් උත්සාහයක් ගැනීම ඉතා වැදගත් බව එහි සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර්ජිවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 24 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 1 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கை இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான முன்னேற்றம் - IMF தலைவர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் Kristalina Georgieva கூறுகையில், IMF ஊழியர்களும் இலங்கை அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகளும் 48 மாத கால விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியுடன் சுமார் 2.9 அமெரிக்க டொலர்களுடன் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்பாட்டை எட்டியிருப்பது மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சி அளிக்கிறது. பில்லியன்.",
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தனது ட்விட்டர் செய்தியில், \"இது இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான முன்னேற்றம்\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று, IMF ஊழியர்களும் இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளும் சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களின் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியின் (EFF) கீழ் 48 மாத ஏற்பாட்டுடன் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கைகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான பணியாளர் அளவிலான உடன்பாட்டை எட்டியுள்ளதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவு மற்றும் அதிகாரிகளின் விரிவான பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தத் திட்டம் பற்றிய விவாதங்களைத் தொடர, ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 1, 2022 வரை கொழும்புக்கு விஜயம் செய்த திரு. பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் மற்றும் திரு. மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி தலைமையிலான IMF பணியின் முடிவில் இது நடந்தது.",
        "இலங்கையின் புதிய நிதி ஆதரவு திட்டத்தின் நோக்கங்கள், பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பது, அதே நேரத்தில் நிதி ஸ்திரத்தன்மையைப் பாதுகாத்தல், பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடியவர்களை பாதுகாத்தல் மற்றும் ஊழல் பாதிப்புகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கான கட்டமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்களை முடுக்கிவிடுவது மற்றும் இலங்கையின் வளர்ச்சி திறனை வெளிக்கொணர்வது என IMF தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து கடன் நிவாரணம் மற்றும் பலதரப்பு பங்காளிகளிடமிருந்து கூடுதல் நிதியுதவி ஆகியவை கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை மற்றும் நெருக்கமான நிதி இடைவெளிகளை உறுதிப்படுத்த உதவும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான நிதி உத்தரவாதங்கள் மற்றும் தனியார் கடனாளிகளுடன் கூட்டு ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவதற்கு நல்ல நம்பிக்கையுடன் முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வது, IMF இலங்கைக்கு நிதி உதவியை வழங்குவதற்கு முன், அது மிகவும் முக்கியமானது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜார்ஜீவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 1, 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}