{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84707/overseas-travel-ban-on-basil-temporarily-lifted",
  "time_ut": 1662105600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Overseas travel ban on Basil temporarily lifted",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Overseas travel ban on Basil temporarily lifted",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court today (Sep 02) temporarily lifted the overseas travel ban imposed on former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa.",
        "Accordingly, the former minister will be allowed to travel overseas until January 15.",
        "The travel ban was imposed after a motion was filed on July 13, seeking an order prohibiting former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, former Minister Basil Rajapaksa, former Central Bank Governor Ajith Nivard Cabraal and several others from leaving the country.",
        "The motion had been submitted in relation to a fundamental rights (FR) petition filed by the former Chairman of the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce (CCC) Chandra Jayaratne, requesting that an investigation be ordered against the individuals responsible for the current economic crisis.",
        "The FR petition is taken up before a five-member bench consisting of Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya and Supreme Court Justices L.T.B. Dehideniya and Buwaneka Aluwihare, Priyantha Jayawardena and Vijith Malalgoda."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Basil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "January 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard Cabraal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court Justices L.T.B. Dehideniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buwaneka Aluwihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijith Malalgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බැසිල්ට පනවා තිබූ විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම තාවකාලිකව ඉවතට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පනවා තිබූ විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම තාවකාලිකව ඉවත් කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද (සැප් 02) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජනවාරි 15 ​​වනදා දක්වා හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයාට විදෙස් ගතවීමට අවසර හිමිවනවා.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් ඇතුළු කිහිප දෙනෙකුට රටින් පිටවීම තහනම් කරමින් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා පසුගිය ජුලි 13 වනදා මෝසමක් ගොනු කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි මෙම සංචාරක තහනම පනවනු ලැබුවේ.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිව යුතු පුද්ගලයින් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ (CCC) හිටපු සභාපති චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න ගොනු කළ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමකට අදාළවයි මෙම මෝසම ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබුණේ.",
        "මෙම FR පෙත්සම අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය සහ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන් වන L.T.B. යන පංච පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ කැඳවනු ලැබේ. දෙහිදෙණිය සහ බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ, ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන සහ විජිත් මලල්ගොඩ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැසිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන් වන එල්.ටී.බී. දෙහිදෙණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත් මලල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பசிலின் வெளிநாட்டு பயணத்தடை தற்காலிகமாக நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு விதிக்கப்பட்ட வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணத் தடையை உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (செப். 02) தற்காலிகமாக நீக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, எதிர்வரும் ஜனவரி மாதம் 15ஆம் திகதி வரை முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் வெளிநாடு செல்ல அனுமதிக்கப்படுவார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச, மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால் மற்றும் பலர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதைத் தடைசெய்யும் உத்தரவைக் கோரி ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட பிரேரணையை அடுத்து இந்த பயணத் தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமான நபர்களுக்கு எதிராக விசாரணைக்கு உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரி இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் (CCC) முன்னாள் தலைவர் சந்திரா ஜயரத்னவினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் (FR) மனு தொடர்பில் இந்த பிரேரணை சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய மற்றும் உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதியரசர்களான எல்.டி.பி ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய ஐவர் அடங்கிய அமர்வு முன்னிலையில் இந்த மனு விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. தெஹிதெனிய மற்றும் புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே, பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன மற்றும் விஜித் மலல்கொட."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துளசி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள் எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித் மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}