{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84510/sanath-milan-dan-priyasad-ordered-to-hand-over-mobile-phones-to-cid",
  "time_ut": 1661336040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sanath, Milan & Dan Priyasad ordered to hand over mobile phones to CID",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sanath, Milan & Dan Priyasad ordered to hand over mobile phones to CID",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Social activist Dan Priyasad and MPs Sanath Nishantha and Milan Jayatilleke have been ordered to hand over their mobile phones to the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) for further investigations on violent incidents on May 09.",
        "The suspects, who are named as suspects in the brazen attacks on anti-government demonstrators outside Temple Trees in Kollupitiya and the ‘GotaGoGama’ protest site at Galle Face Geen, were produced before the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court earlier today.",
        "Magistrate Thilina Gamage ordered the suspects to be held in the custody of the court until their mobile phones are delivered to the CID."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Milan & Dan Priyasad",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dan Priyasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Milan Jayatilleke",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Geen",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සනත්, මිලාන් සහ ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්ට ජංගම දුරකථන රහස් පොලිසියට භාර දෙන ලෙසට නියෝග",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද් සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන සනත් නිශාන්ත සහ මිලාන් ජයතිලක යන අයගේ ජංගම දුරකථන ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සඳහා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (CID) මැයි 09 වනදා භාර දෙන ලෙස නියෝග කර තිබේ.",
        "කොල්ලුපිටියේ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයෙන් පිටත රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී පෙළපාලිකරුවන්ට සහ ගාලුමුවදොර ‘ගෝඨාගෝගම’ විරෝධතා භූමියේදී රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂකයන්ට එල්ල වූ නිර්ලජ්ජිත ප්‍රහාරයේ සැකකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කර ඇති සැකකරුවන් අද පෙරවරුවේ කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කෙරුණා.",
        "සැකකරුවන්ගේ ජංගම දුරකථන අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට භාරදෙන තුරු අධිකරණය භාරයේ තබන ලෙස මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිලාන් සහ ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලාන් ජයතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Geen",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சனத், மிலன் மற்றும் டான் பிரியசாத் ஆகியோர் மொபைல் போன்களை சிஐடியிடம் ஒப்படைக்க உத்தரவிட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமூக ஆர்வலர் டான் பிரியசாத் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான சனத் நிஷாந்த மற்றும் மிலன் ஜயதிலக்க ஆகியோரின் கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகளை மே 09 ஆம் திகதி வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்திடம் (CID) ஒப்படைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டியில் அலரிமாளிகைக்கு வெளியே அரச எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மீதும், காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள ‘கோட்டகோகம’ போராட்டத் தளத்துக்கும் எதிராக நடத்தப்பட்ட வெட்கக்கேடான தாக்குதல்களில் சந்தேகநபர்கள் என பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ள சந்தேகநபர்கள் இன்று கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்டனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களின் கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகள் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படும் வரை நீதிமன்றக் காவலில் வைக்குமாறு நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மிலன் & டான் பிரியசாத்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டான் பிரியசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிலன் ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Geen",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}