{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78660",
  "time_ut": 1658257560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "“My life has been in this Parliament for 45 years . Hence I like to extend a special gratitude to have been honoured with the Presidency by the very  same Parliament.” -President  Ranil Wickremesinghe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "“My life has been in this Parliament for 45 years . Hence I like to extend a special gratitude to have been honoured with the Presidency by the very  same Parliament.” -President  Ranil Wickremesinghe",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Perseverant Ranil Wickremesinghe yesterday reinforced his often underestimated prowess by becoming Sri Lanka’s 8th Executive President, comfortably winning a secret ballot from Parliamentarians with support mainly from colleagues loyal to ousted Rajapaksa regime.",
        "Of the 225-member Parliament, 223 voted with 2 MPs (MPs Selvaraja Gajendran and G.G. Ponnambalam) abstaining and 4 ballots rejected as invalid.",
        "Wickremesinghe received 134 votes against the 82 received by Dullas Alahapperuma. JVP Leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake managed only 3 votes.",
        "Though political activists questioned the legitimacy, the victory fulfils a long-cherished dream of the 73-year-old veteran who marks 45 years in Parliament and has served a record six times as Prime Minister.",
        "“My life has been in this Parliament,” said an enthusiastic Wickremesinghe in his brief address in the House after winning. Fittingly on his wishes, Wickremesinghe will be sworn in today at 10 a.m. in Parliament, a departure from his predecessors who opted for more grandiose or religiously important locations. He will serve the remainder of the term of the ousted President Gotabaya Rajapaksa till end 2024.",
        "Wickremesinghe unsuccessfully contested for Presidency twice before in 1999 and 2005 and his party UNP suffered a humiliating defeat at the 2020 General Elections, forcing it to secure only a national seat.",
        "It was ironic that President Rajapaksa who secured a record 6.9 million votes at November 2019 elections and his Sri Lanka Podujana Peruma won a near two-thirds majority at parliamentary elections had to turn to Wickremesinghe to become Prime Minister in May amidst political, economic and social chaos.",
        "Prior to yesterday’s vote, a close contest was anticipated with campaigners of the two leading contenders expressing confidence of securing the majority. The eventual 134 votes and the margin did surprise most analysts as Opposition’s coalition candidate Alahapperuma got widespread pledges of support from other MPs. The final count prompted some of the Opposition MPs to allege that cash deals were the deciding factor rather than conscience.",
        "The announcement of the outcome of the vote by Parliament Secretary General Dissanayake drew shouts of ‘Jayawewa’ amidst applause from Government benches. Dinesh Gunawardena who proposed Wickremesinghe and tipped to be the Prime Minister was seen thumping his desk.",
        "In a brief speech in the House after the victory, Wickremesinghe recalled that he and the Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena entered politics in 1973 and “it was a special happy occasion to have been voted in as President with Abeywardena at the chair”.",
        "Ranil stressed that he has spent 45 years in Parliament. “My life has been in this Parliament. Hence I like to extend a special gratitude to have been honoured with the Presidency by the very Parliament.”",
        "Wickremesinghe recalled that 31 years ago or in 1993, the Parliament undertook a similar exercise after President Premadasa was assassinated to elect a new President. D.B. Wijetunga won uncontested. “15 of those including me who participated in the vote still serve Parliament as of today,” Wickremesinghe said.",
        "It was pointed out in the second occasion yesterday, it was proved that the Parliament can elect a President via a vote. Therefore, Wickremesinghe said he has a responsibility to thank all those who ensured his victory.",
        "Focusing on grimmer issues, he also said: “We all know we are in a serious economic crisis at present with youth demanding change. People are not asking for old politics but want all parties to get together and initiate a new program to move forward.”",
        "“I request Dullas Alahapperuma and Anura Kumara Dissanayaka to work together for a new arrangement. I also request the Opposition leader and my friend Sajith Premadasa to join in,” Wickremesinghe said and also extended an invitation to former Presidents Mahinda Rajapaksa and Maithripala Sirisena and supportive Tamil MPs to come together with the Government.",
        "“We were divided for 48 hours and after today we must get together. I am prepared to discuss from tomorrow with all parties,” Wickremesinghe emphasised."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "45 years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 MPs",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvaraja Gajendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.G. Ponnambalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "end 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2020 General Elections",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peruma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "that 31 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.B. Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "“මගේ ජීවිතය අවුරුදු 45ක් මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ . එබැවින් එම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින්ම ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබීම පිළිබඳව විශේෂ කෘතඥතාව පළ කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමි.” -ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත්වෙමින්, ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන්ම බලයෙන් පහකළ රාජපක්ෂ පාලනයට පක්ෂපාතී සගයන්ගේ සහය ඇතිව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් රහසිගත ඡන්දයකින් පහසු ලෙස ජයග්‍රහණය කරමින්, බොහෝ විට අවතක්සේරු කරන ලද ඔහුගේ දස්කම් ස්ථීරසාර රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඊයේ ශක්තිමත් කළේය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් 223 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු (පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන සෙල්වරාජා ගජේන්ද්‍රන් සහ ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම්) ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටි අතර ඡන්ද පත්‍රිකා 4ක් වලංගු නොවන බවට ප්‍රතික්ෂේප විය.",
        "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ලැබූ ඡන්ද 82 ට එරෙහිව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඡන්ද 134 ක් ලබා ගත්තේය. ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට ලබාගත හැකි වූයේ ඡන්ද 3ක් පමණි.",
        "දේශපාලන ක්‍රියාකාරීන් නීත්‍යානුකූල භාවය පිළිබඳව ප්‍රශ්න කළද, මෙම ජයග්‍රහණය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට වසර 45ක් සපිරෙන සහ 6 වතාවක් අගමැති ධුරයට පත් වූ 73 හැවිරිදි ප්‍රවීණයාගේ දිගුකාලීන සිහිනයක් ඉටු කරයි.",
        "“මගේ ජීවිතය තිබුණේ මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ” යැයි උද්යෝගිමත් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජයග්‍රහණයෙන් පසු සභාව අමතා කළ කෙටි කතාවේදී පැවසීය. ඔහුගේ අභිමතය පරිදි, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පෙරවරු 10 ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී දිවුරුම් දෙනු ඇත, එය වඩා උත්කෘෂ්ට හෝ ආගමික වශයෙන් වැදගත් ස්ථාන තෝරා ගත් ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමීන්ගෙන් ඉවත්ව යයි. ඔහු 2024 අවසන් වනතුරු බලයෙන් පහකළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉතිරි ධූර කාලයද කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මීට පෙර 1999 සහ 2005 දී දෙවරක් ජනාධිපති ධුරයට අසාර්ථක වූ අතර 2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ඔහුගේ පක්ෂය එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට නින්දිත පරාජයක් අත්කර දුන්නේ ජාතික අසුනක් පමණක් ලබා ගැනීමටය.",
        "2019 නොවැම්බර් මැතිවරණයේදී වාර්තාගත ඡන්ද මිලියන 6.9ක් ලබා ගත් ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට සහ ඔහුගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරුමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේදී තුනෙන් දෙකක බලයක් ලබා ගත් ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට මැයි මාසයේදී අගමැති වීමට වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත හැරීමට සිදුවූයේ දේශපාලන, ආර්ථික හා සමාජීය වාතාවරණය මැදය. අවුල්.",
        "ඊයේ පැවති ඡන්ද විමසීමට පෙර, ප්‍රමුඛ තරඟකරුවන් දෙදෙනාගේ ප්‍රචාරකයින් බහුතරය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමේ විශ්වාසය පළ කිරීමත් සමඟ සමීප තරඟයක් අපේක්ෂා කරන ලදී. විපක්ෂයේ සන්ධාන අපේක්ෂක අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට අනෙකුත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් පුළුල් සහයෝගයක් ලැබුණු බැවින් අවසානයේ ඡන්ද 134 සහ පරතරය බොහෝ විශ්ලේෂකයින් මවිතයට පත් කළේය. අවසාන ගණන් කිරීම හෘද සාක්ෂියට වඩා මුදල් ගනුදෙනු තීරණාත්මක සාධකය බවට විපක්ෂයේ සමහර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් චෝදනා කිරීමට පෙලඹුණි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් දිසානායක විසින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමත් සමඟ රජයේ බංකුවල අත්පොලසන් හඬ මධ්‍යයේ ‘ජයවේවා’ ඝෝෂා නැගිණි. වික්‍රමසිංහට යෝජනා කර අගමැති වීමට ඔත්තු දුන් දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන ඔහුගේ මේසයට තට්ටු කරනු දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "ජයග්‍රහණයෙන් පසු සභාවේ පැවති කෙටි කතාවකදී වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තමන් සහ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා දේශපාලනයට පිවිසියේ 1973 දී බවත්, \"අබේවර්ධන මහතා මුලසුන තබාගෙන ජනාධිපති ලෙස ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ලැබීම විශේෂ සතුටක්\" බවත් සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "තමන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වසර 45ක් ගත කර ඇති බවද රනිල් අවධාරණය කළේය. “මගේ ජීවිතය තිබුණේ මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ. එබැවින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින්ම ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබීම ගැන මම විශේෂ කෘතඥතාව පුද කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමි.”",
        "මීට වසර 31 කට පෙර හෝ 1993 දී ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඝාතනය කිරීමෙන් පසු නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මෙවැනිම ව්‍යායාමයක නිරත වූ බව වික්‍රමසිංහ සිහිපත් කළේය. ඩී.බී. විජේතුංග නිතරගයෙන් ජය ගත්තේය. “ඡන්දයට සහභාගී වූ මා ඇතුළු 15 දෙනෙකු අද වන විටත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සේවය කරනවා,” වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඡන්දයකින් ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පත් කළ හැකි බව ඊයේ දෙවැනි වරටත් පෙන්වා දුන්නා. එම නිසා තම ජයග්‍රහණය තහවුරු කළ සියලු දෙනාටම ස්තුතිය පුද කිරීමට තමාට වගකීමක් ඇති බවද වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "දරුණු ප්‍රශ්න කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරමින් ඔහු මෙසේද පැවසීය: “තාරුණ්‍ය වෙනසක් ඉල්ලා සිටින අපි මේ වන විට බරපතල ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක සිටින බව අපි කවුරුත් දනිමු. ජනතාව ඉල්ලන්නේ පැරණි දේශපාලනයක් නොව සියලු පක්‍ෂ එකතු වී ඉදිරියට යාමට නව වැඩපිළිවෙළක් ආරම්භ කිරීමටයි.”",
        "“මම ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා අලුත් වැඩපිළිවෙලක් සඳහා එක්ව කටයුතු කරන්න. විපක්ෂ නායකතුමා සහ මගේ මිත්‍ර සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගෙන්ද මම ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා.",
        "“පැය 48ක් බෙදිලා හිටියා අදින් පස්සේ අපි එකතු වෙන්න ඕනේ. හෙට සිට සියලු පාර්ශ්ව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට මම සූදානම්” වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 45 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්ත්‍රීවරු 2යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වරාජා ගජේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 45 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 මහ මැතිවරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 45 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ අවුරුදු 31කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය 48 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "45 ஆண்டுகளாக இந்த நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எனது வாழ்க்கை இருக்கிறது. எனவே அதே பாராளுமன்றத்தால் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு கௌரவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமைக்கு நான் விசேட நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்ள விரும்புகிறேன்.” -ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "விடாமுயற்சியுள்ள ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே நேற்று இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றதன் மூலம் தனது அடிக்கடி குறைத்து மதிப்பிடப்பட்ட திறமையை வலுப்படுத்தினார், முக்கியமாக பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட ராஜபக்சே ஆட்சிக்கு விசுவாசமான சகாக்களின் ஆதரவுடன் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் வசதியாக வெற்றி பெற்றார்.",
        "225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்றத்தில், 223 பேர் வாக்களித்தனர், 2 எம்.பி.க்கள் (எம்.பி.க்கள் செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன் மற்றும் ஜி.ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம்) வாக்களிக்கவில்லை மற்றும் 4 வாக்குகள் செல்லாதவை என நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும பெற்ற 82 வாக்குகளுக்கு எதிராக விக்கிரமசிங்க 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார். ஜே.வி.பி.யின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 3 வாக்குகளை மாத்திரமே பெற்றிருந்தார்.",
        "அரசியல் ஆர்வலர்கள் நியாயத்தன்மையை கேள்விக்குள்ளாக்கினாலும், இந்த வெற்றியானது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 45 வருடங்களைக் குறிக்கும் மற்றும் 6 முறை பிரதமராகப் பணியாற்றி சாதனை படைத்த 73 வயது மூத்தவரின் நீண்டகால கனவை நிறைவேற்றுகிறது.",
        "\"எனது வாழ்க்கை இந்த பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்தது,\" என்று ஒரு உற்சாகமான விக்கிரமசிங்க வெற்றி பெற்ற பின்னர் சபையில் தனது சுருக்கமான உரையில் கூறினார். அவரது விருப்பத்தின் பேரில், விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று காலை 10 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்வார், இது அவரது முன்னோடிகளில் இருந்து மிகவும் பிரமாண்டமான அல்லது மத முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த இடங்களைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தது. பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக் காலத்தை 2024ஆம் ஆண்டு இறுதிவரை அவர் வகிப்பார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க 1999 மற்றும் 2005 க்கு முன்னர் இரண்டு முறை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தோல்வியுற்றார் மற்றும் அவரது கட்சியான UNP 2020 பொதுத் தேர்தலில் அவமானகரமான தோல்வியை சந்தித்தது, அது ஒரு தேசிய ஆசனத்தை மட்டுமே பெற வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் இருந்தது.",
        "நவம்பர் 2019 தேர்தலில் 6.9 மில்லியன் வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று சாதனை படைத்த ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவும், நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் அவரது ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெருமாவும் கிட்டத்தட்ட மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மையைப் பெற்றதன் மூலம் மே மாதம் அரசியல், பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் சமூகத்திற்கு மத்தியில் பிரதமராக விக்ரமசிங்கேவை நோக்கி திரும்ப வேண்டியிருந்தது. குழப்பம்.",
        "நேற்றைய வாக்கெடுப்புக்கு முன்னதாக, இரு முன்னணிப் போட்டியாளர்களின் பிரச்சாரகர்கள் பெரும்பான்மையைப் பெறுவோம் என்ற நம்பிக்கையை வெளிப்படுத்தியதில் ஒரு நெருக்கமான போட்டி எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டது. இறுதியில் 134 வாக்குகள் மற்றும் வித்தியாசம் என்பது பெரும்பாலான ஆய்வாளர்களை ஆச்சரியத்தில் ஆழ்த்தியது, ஏனெனில் எதிர்க்கட்சியின் கூட்டணி வேட்பாளர் அழகப்பெரும மற்ற பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து பரந்த ஆதரவைப் பெற்றார். இறுதி எண்ணிக்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் சிலரை மனசாட்சியை விட பண பேரங்கள் தீர்மானிக்கும் காரணி என்று குற்றம் சாட்ட தூண்டியது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் திஸாநாயக்கவின் வாக்கெடுப்பின் முடிவு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது அரசாங்க ஆசனங்களின் கரவொலிக்கு மத்தியில் ‘ஜயவேவா’ என்ற கூக்குரல்களை எழுப்பியது. விக்ரமசிங்கவை பிரேரித்து பிரதமராக வேண்டும் என்று கூறிய தினேஷ் குணவர்தன அவரது மேசையை தட்டிக் கொண்டிருந்தார்.",
        "வெற்றியின் பின்னர் சபையில் ஆற்றிய சுருக்கமான உரையில், தானும் சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவும் 1973 இல் அரசியலில் பிரவேசித்ததையும், “அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் ஜனாதிபதியாக வாக்களித்தமை விசேட மகிழ்ச்சியான சந்தர்ப்பம்” என்றும் விக்கிரமசிங்க நினைவு கூர்ந்தார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் 45 வருடங்களை கழித்துள்ளதாக ரணில் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார். “எனது வாழ்க்கை இந்த பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தான். எனவே பாராளுமன்றமே ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு கௌரவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமைக்கு விசேட நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்ள விரும்புகிறேன்.”",
        "31 வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் அல்லது 1993 இல் ஜனாதிபதி பிரேமதாச படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட பின்னர் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றம் இதேபோன்றதொரு செயற்பாட்டை மேற்கொண்டதை விக்ரமசிங்க நினைவு கூர்ந்தார். டி.பி. விஜேதுங்க போட்டியின்றி வெற்றி பெற்றார். “வாக்கெடுப்பில் கலந்து கொண்ட நான் உட்பட 15 பேர் இன்றுவரை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சேவையாற்றுகின்றனர்,” என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்ய முடியும் என நேற்று இரண்டாவது சந்தர்ப்பத்திலும் சுட்டிக்காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது. எனவே, தனது வெற்றியை உறுதி செய்த அனைவருக்கும் நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் பொறுப்பு தனக்கு இருப்பதாக விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடுமையான பிரச்சினைகளில் கவனம் செலுத்தி அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்: “இளைஞர்கள் மாற்றத்தை கோருவதால் தற்போது நாம் கடுமையான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருக்கிறோம் என்பதை நாம் அனைவரும் அறிவோம். மக்கள் பழைய அரசியலைக் கேட்கவில்லை, ஆனால் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளும் ஒன்றிணைந்து புதிய திட்டத்தை முன்னோக்கி நகர்த்த வேண்டும் என்று விரும்புகிறார்கள்.",
        "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் புதிய ஏற்பாட்டிற்காக இணைந்து செயற்படுமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கின்றேன். எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் எனது நண்பருமான சஜித் பிரேமதாசவையும் இதில் இணைந்து கொள்ளுமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்” என்று கூறிய விக்கிரமசிங்க, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிகளான மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் ஆதரவான தமிழ் எம்.பி.க்களுக்கும் அரசாங்கத்துடன் ஒன்றிணையுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் 48 மணி நேரம் பிரிந்தோம், இன்று நாங்கள் ஒன்றாக இருக்க வேண்டும். சகல தரப்பினருடனும் நாளை முதல் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கு நான் தயார்” என விக்ரமசிங்க வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "45 ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 எம்.பி.க்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 பொதுத் தேர்தல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெருமா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அது 31 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "48 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}