{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131359",
  "time_ut": 1657681613,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மாலைதீவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி செல்ல விமானத்தை வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் வெளியான தகவல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Information released regarding the provision of a plane for the President to go to the Maldives",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lankan Air Force said that the President was granted a flight to the Maldives with the permission of the Ministry of Defense under the authority of the Executive President.",
        "There were reports in the media and various social media regarding the departure of the President from the country early this morning via the Katunayake Airport to Malatipu by a Sri Lankan Air Force aircraft.",
        "Pursuant to the powers vested in the Executive President in the Constitution of Sri Lanka and at the request of the present Government, a flight has been provided by the Air Force on 13 July 2022 for the President and his wife and two bodyguards to travel to the Maldives at the Katunayake International Airport with the full approval of the Ministry of Defence, subject to all immigration, customs and other laws. Sri Lankan Air Force said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malatipu",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට මාලදිවයිනට යාමට ගුවන් යානයක් ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තොරතුරු නිකුත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල යටතේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අවසරය මත ජනාධිපතිවරයාට මාලදිවයින බලා යාමට ගුවන් යානයක් ලබාදුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා අද අලුයම කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් දිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව යාම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍ය සහ විවිධ සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ වාර්තා පළ වුණා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පැවරී ඇති බලතල ප්‍රකාරව සහ වත්මන් රජයේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳට සහ ආරක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනෙකුට 2022 ජූලි 13 වන දින ගුවන් හමුදාවෙන් ගුවන් යානයක් ලබා දී ඇත. සියලුම ආගමන විගමන, රේගු සහ අනෙකුත් නීතිවලට යටත්ව ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පූර්ණ අනුමැතිය ඇතිව මාලදිවයිනේ කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලතිපු",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாலைதீவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி செல்ல விமானத்தை வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் வெளியான தகவல்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரத்திற்கு அமைய பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் அனுமதியுடன் ஜனாதிபதி மாலைதீவிற்கு செல்ல விமானம் வழங்கப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை விமானப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இன்று அதிகாலை வேளையில் நாட்டில் இருந்து கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம் ஊடாக இலங்கை விமானப்படைக்குச் செந்தமான விமானத்தின் மூலம் மலைதீவிற்கு வெளியேறியமை தொடர்பாக ஊடகங்களிலும் பல்வேறு சமூக ஊடகங்களிலும் செய்திகள் வெளியாகியிருந்தன.",
        "இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பில் நிறைவேற்று அதிகார ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரங்களுக்கு இணங்க, தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு அமைய ,பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்தின் முழு அனுமதியின் கீழ் கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் அனைத்து குடிவரவு, சுங்க மற்றும் பிற சட்டங்களுக்கு உட்பட்டு, ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் அவரது துணைவியார் மேலும் இரு பாதுகாவலருடன் மாலைதீவிற்கு செல்ல 2022 ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி விமானப்படையினால்  ஒரு விமானம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என இலங்கை விமானப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலதிபு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}