{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83587/speaker-retracts-statement-on-president-leaving-country",
  "time_ut": 1657547520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Speaker retracts statement on President leaving country",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speaker retracts statement on President leaving country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker of Sri Lanka’s Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena on Monday clarified that Gotabaya Rajapaksa is still in the country, soon after reports emerged that President has left the island nation.",
        "Sri Lankan President, who announced his resignation on Saturday, was earlier said to have left the country and was in another country.",
        "“President of Sri Lanka Gotabaya Rajapaksa is still in the country, I made a mistake in the (BBC) interview,” Speaker Abeywardena told ANI in a telephone call.",
        "When asked further about the whereabouts of Sri Lankan Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and the Sri Lankan President, the speaker said that both of them are still in the country.",
        "The development comes after thousands of people stormed into the President’s House in Fort on Saturday. Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe also announced to step down from his posts amid the ongoing protests.",
        "However, the protesters who have occupied the residences of the President and Prime Minister have cleared that they will continue to occupy their houses until they resign from their posts.",
        "Earlier, on Saturday, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena announced in a press conference that the President will resign from his post on July 13. Rajapaksa officially informed PM Wickremesinghe that he is resigning from his post."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Gotabaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති රට හැර යාම ගැන කළ ප්‍රකාශය කථානායක ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා දිවයිනෙන් පිටව ගොස් ඇති බවට වාර්තා පළවීමත් සමඟ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තවමත් මෙරට සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා සඳුදා පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා මීට පෙර රට හැර ගොස් වෙනත් රටක සිටි බව පැවසේ.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තවමත් රටේ සිටින අතර, (බීබීසී) සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවේදී මට වැරදීමක් සිදු විය\" යනුවෙන් කථානායක අබේවර්ධන ANI වෙත දුරකථන ඇමතුමක් ලබා දෙමින් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිටින ස්ථානය පිළිබඳව වැඩිදුරටත් විමසූ විට කථානායකවරයා පැවසුවේ ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාම තවමත් මෙරට සිටින බවයි.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත ජනතාවක් කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසුව මෙම වර්ධනය සිදු විය. පවතින විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද සිය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ නිවෙස් අල්ලාගෙන සිටින විරෝධතාකරුවන් තමන් තනතුරුවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු සිය නිවෙස්වල රැඳී සිටින බව පවසති.",
        "මීට පෙර සෙනසුරාදා කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පවත්වමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා සිය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නිල වශයෙන් අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සිය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව දැනුම් දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவது குறித்த அறிக்கையை சபாநாயகர் வாபஸ் பெற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறியதாக தகவல்கள் வெளியாகிய நிலையில், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இன்னும் நாட்டிலேயே இருப்பதாக இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன திங்கட்கிழமை தெளிவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாக அறிவித்த இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி, நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி வேறு நாட்டில் இருப்பதாக முன்னர் கூறப்பட்டது.",
        "“இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச இன்னும் நாட்டில் இருக்கிறார், நான் (பிபிசி) நேர்காணலில் தவறு செய்துவிட்டேன்,” என்று சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன ANI க்கு தொலைபேசி அழைப்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சிறிலங்கா பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் சிறிலங்கா அதிபர் ஆகியோரின் இருப்பிடம் குறித்து மேலும் வினவியபோது, ​​அவர்கள் இருவரும் இன்னும் நாட்டில் இருப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் படையெடுத்ததை அடுத்து இந்த வளர்ச்சி ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. தொடர் போராட்டங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் தனது பதவிகளில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரின் இல்லங்களை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ள ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள், தமது பதவிகளை இராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை தமது வீடுகளை ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்போவதாக அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "முன்னதாக, சனிக்கிழமையன்று, சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதி தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் அறிவித்தார். ராஜபக்சே தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவிடம் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}