{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/putin-congratulates-sri-lanka-president-looks-to-foster-bilateral-cooperation-97881/",
  "time_ut": 1658740620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Putin congratulates Sri Lanka president; looks to foster bilateral cooperation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Putin congratulates Sri Lanka president; looks to foster bilateral cooperation",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Russian President Vladimir Putin writing to his Sri Lankan counterpart Ranil Wickremesinghe has said he is looking to foster bilateral cooperation and strengthen regional stability and security on the latter’s watch.",
        "On Monday July 25, President Wickremesinghe’s media division released a translation of a letter said to have been sent in by President Putin congratulating him for his victory on July 20.",
        "“The Russian-Sri Lankan relations are of traditionally friendly nature. I am counting on your activities as Head of State tofoster further development of the constructive bilateral cooperation in various spheres for the benefit of our peoples and in the interest of strengthening the regional stability and security.",
        "“I wish you every success as well as good health and prosperity,” the letter, bearing no signature or recognisable letterhead, said.",
        "Earlier Monday morning, Wickremesinghe had met Russia’s Ambassador to Sri Lanka Yury Materiy, who had extended Putin’s wishes, the president’s media division said.",
        "Sri Lanka’s relations with Russia were tested recently after a controversy surrounding a court case filed in Sri Lanka against Russia’s national carrier Aeorflot, which has now been resolved.",
        "Sri Lanka court suspends enjoining order issued against Russian Aeroflot flight",
        "Last month, independent MP Wimal Weerawansa told parliament that the island nation must not overlook “traditional ally” Russia in its efforts to overcome its worsening economic crisis, particularly with regard to ongoing negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF).",
        "Sri Lanka must not overlook Russia in favour of IMF, says MP Weerawansa"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Putin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday July 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Russian-Sri Lankan",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier Monday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yury Materiy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeorflot",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian Aeroflot",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පුටින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සුබ පතයි; ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව වර්ධනය කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් සිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහචර රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත ලිපියක් යවමින් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව වර්ධනය කිරීමටත් කලාපීය ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආරක්ෂාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීමටත් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ජූලි 25 සඳුදා, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහගේ මාධ්‍ය අංශය විසින් ජූලි 20 දින ඔහුගේ ජයග්‍රහණයට සුබ පතමින් ජනාධිපති පුටින් විසින් එවා ඇති බව කියන ලිපියක පරිවර්තනයක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "“රුසියානු-ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා සම්ප්‍රදායිකව මිත්‍රශීලී ස්වභාවයක් ගනී. අපගේ ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා සහ කලාපීය ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආරක්ෂාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සඳහා විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සාධනීය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස ඔබගේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් කෙරෙහි මම විශ්වාසය තබමි.",
        "“ඔබට සෑම සාර්ථකත්වයක් මෙන්ම හොඳ සෞඛ්‍යයක් සහ සමෘද්ධියක් ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරමි,” යනුවෙන් අත්සනක් හෝ හඳුනාගත හැකි ලිපි ශීර්ෂයක් නොමැති ලිපියේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "මීට පෙර සඳුදා උදෑසන වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුසියානු තානාපති යූරි මැටේරි හමුවී ඇති අතර ඔහු පුටින්ගේ කැමැත්ත පළ කර ඇති බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පැවසීය.",
        "රුසියාවේ ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය වන Aeorflot ට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධිකරණයේ ගොනු කර ඇති නඩුවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇති වූ මතභේදයකින් පසුව රුසියාව සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සබඳතා මෑතකදී පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් වූ අතර එය දැන් විසඳී ඇත.",
        "රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානයට එරෙහිව නිකුත් කර තිබූ වාරණ නියෝගය ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය විසින් අත්හිටුවයි",
        "පසුගිය මාසයේ ස්වාධීන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, විශේෂයෙන්ම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ පවතින සාකච්ඡා සම්බන්ධයෙන්, එහි නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට දරන උත්සාහයේදී දිවයින ජාතිය \"සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍ර\" රුසියාව නොසලකා හැරිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට පක්ෂව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාව නොසලකා හැරිය යුතු බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වීරවංශ පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පුටින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු-ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින් සඳුදා",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි මැටරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeorflot",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු Aeroflot",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය මාසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதிக்கு புட்டின் வாழ்த்து; இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை வளர்ப்பதாக தெரிகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் தனது இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளார், இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை வளர்ப்பதற்கும் பிராந்திய ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கும் தான் விரும்புவதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 25 திங்கட்கிழமை, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு, ஜூலை 20 அன்று வெற்றி பெற்றதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி புடின் அவருக்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்து அனுப்பியதாகக் கூறப்படும் கடிதத்தின் மொழிபெயர்ப்பை வெளியிட்டது.",
        "“ரஷ்ய-இலங்கை உறவுகள் பாரம்பரியமாக நட்புறவைக் கொண்டவை. நமது மக்களின் நலனுக்காகவும், பிராந்திய ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்தும் நலனுக்காகவும் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் ஆக்கபூர்வமான இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு மாநிலத் தலைவர் என்ற முறையில் உங்கள் செயல்பாடுகளை நான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன்.",
        "கையொப்பம் அல்லது அடையாளம் காணக்கூடிய லெட்டர்ஹெட் இல்லாத கடிதத்தில், \"உங்களுக்கு ஒவ்வொரு வெற்றியும், நல்ல ஆரோக்கியம் மற்றும் செழிப்பும் கிடைக்க வாழ்த்துகிறேன்\" என்று கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக திங்கட்கிழமை காலை, விக்கிரமசிங்க இலங்கைக்கான ரஷ்ய தூதுவர் Yury Materiy ஐ சந்தித்தார், அவர் புட்டினின் விருப்பத்தை நீட்டித்ததாக ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ரஷ்யாவின் தேசிய விமான நிறுவனமான Aeorflot க்கு எதிராக இலங்கை நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கு தொடர்பான சர்ச்சையின் பின்னர், ரஷ்யாவுடனான இலங்கையின் உறவுகள் சமீபத்தில் சோதிக்கப்பட்டன, அது இப்போது தீர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்திற்கு விதிக்கப்பட்ட தடை உத்தரவை இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம் இடைநிறுத்தியுள்ளது",
        "கடந்த மாதம், சுயேட்சை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்ச பாராளுமன்றத்தில், தீவு நாடு \"பாரம்பரிய நட்பு நாடான\" ரஷ்யாவை அதன் மோசமடைந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்கும் அதன் முயற்சிகளில், குறிப்பாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) நடந்து வரும் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை புறக்கணிக்கக் கூடாது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு ஆதரவாக ரஷ்யாவை இலங்கை புறக்கணிக்கக் கூடாது என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புடின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய-இலங்கை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்ஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}