{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/President-contacts-Gotabaya-about-his-return/108-243462",
  "time_ut": 1661135741,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President contacts Gotabaya about his return",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President contacts Gotabaya about his return",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe is reported to have contacted former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to discuss arrangements for his return to the country, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "This followed a request by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna ( SLPP ) National Organizer Basil Rajapaksa at a recent meeting with the president.",
        "Basil Rajapaksa called on the president in this regard and asked for the facilitation of early return of the former president who is currently in Thailand after fleeing the country in the face of public protests for his resignation from office on July 9, 2022.",
        "However, he will not return on August 24 despite speculation otherwise. The date of his arrival is not yet confirmed.(Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නැවත පැමිණීම ගැන ජනපති ගෝඨාභය අමතයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නැවත මෙරටට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අමතා ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ඒ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගියදා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුවයි.",
        "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවී 2022 ජූලි 9 වැනි දින ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට මහජන විරෝධය හමුවේ රටින් පැන ගොස් දැනට තායිලන්තයේ සිටින හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට කඩිනමින් ආපසු පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, වෙනත් ආකාරයකින් අනුමාන කළද ඔහු අගෝස්තු 24 වන දින ආපසු නොඑනු ඇත. ඔහු පැමිණි දිනය තවමත් තහවුරු කර නොමැත.(කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய நாடு திரும்புவது குறித்து ஜனாதிபதி தொடர்பு கொண்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாடு திரும்புவதற்கான ஏற்பாடுகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக அவரைத் தொடர்பு கொண்டுள்ளதாக டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ அண்மையில் ஜனாதிபதியுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து இது இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்த பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ, 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகியதற்காக மக்கள் எதிர்ப்புக்களை எதிர்கொண்டு நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி தற்போது தாய்லாந்தில் இருக்கும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை விரைவில் நாடு திரும்ப வசதி செய்யுமாறு கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "இருப்பினும், வேறுவிதமான ஊகங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், அவர் ஆகஸ்ட் 24 அன்று திரும்ப மாட்டார். அவர் வரும் தேதி இன்னும் உறுதி செய்யப்படவில்லை.(கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}