{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/the-land-may-divide-us-but-the-sky-and-the-ocean-unites-us-all-wimal-at-the-welcome-ceremony-for-yuan-wang-5/",
  "time_ut": 1660667400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "The land may divide us, but the sky and the ocean unites us all: Wimal at the welcome ceremony for Yuan Wang 5",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The land may divide us, but the sky and the ocean unites us all: Wimal at the welcome ceremony for Yuan Wang 5",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Although this land belongs to Sri Lanka, the sky and the ocean unites us all, said the Leader of the National Freedom Front, Wimal Weerawansa at the  welcome ceremony was organized at the Hambantota Port on Tuesday (16) morning, under the auspices of the Chinse Ambassador to Sri Lanka.",
        "MP Weerawansa, speaking further, said that there is an area of ocean and the skies which belongs to Sri Lanka, and as a state, bears responsibility for that area.",
        "\"The Indian Ocean Region must remain as Region of Peace. There can be NO conflict. It cannot be home to enemy camps. Even if we are strong or weak economically, we need to maintain the stance,\" he said.",
        "The MP further stated that although some call the vessel a Spy-Ship, it should be called a communication vessel.",
        "\"China has never told us what the structure of our Government  should be. China has never established NGOs in Sri Lanka, and funded them to destabilize the Government. Therefore, China is one of the few countries that extended assistance to Sri Lanka during these tough times. We hope China would help us more,\" he said.",
        "Speaking at the event, the Democratic Left Front Leader, Vasudeva Nanayakkara said that the presense of Yuan Wang 5 vessel itself is a symbol of the independence and sovereign power of Sri Lanka.",
        "An unnecessary controversy was raised about the arrival of the vessel, the MP said, adding that it was a machination of the western powers headed by the U.S.",
        "\"However the rightious decision prevailed, as Sri Lanka is glad we are to be able to have Yuan Wang 5 here in this port which contributes to the significance of this port and to the future importance of this port. We hope the long lasting friendship cannot be torpedoed by any kind of machinations of imperialism. We trust we will be able to keep our bonds firm and unbreakable and ensure the peace in the Indian Ocean and the freedom in the Indian Ocean\" MP Nanayakkara mentioned.",
        "Rear Admiral (Retd) Dr. Sarath Weerasekara, also speaking at the welcome ceremony said that the resolution of the issue with regard to the vessel further strengthens the relations between China and Sri Lanka, and visits such as these also strengthens the friendship between the countries.",
        "The land may divide us, but the sky and the ocean unites us all: Wimal at the welcome ceremony for Yuan Wang 5",
        "Polish man arrested with Rs. 245 Mn worth Cocaine by Customs"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinse",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Ocean Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Region of Peace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spy-Ship",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Left Front Leader",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cocaine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගොඩබිම අපිව බෙදන්න පුළුවන්, නමුත් අහසයි සාගරයයි අපි හැමෝම එකතු කරනවා: යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයේදී විමල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ භූමිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අයත් වුවත් අහසත් සාගරයත් අප සියල්ලන්ම එක්සේසත් කරන බව ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවය අඟහරුවාදා (16) පෙරවරුවේ හම්බන්තොට වරාය පරිශ්‍රයේදී සංවිධානය කර තිබිණි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති.",
        "මෙහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස්‌ දැක්‌වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වීරවංශ මහතා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අයත් සාගර ප්‍රදේශයක්‌ සහ අහස්‌ කලාපයක්‌ පවතින බවත්, එම ප්‍රදේශයේ රාජ්‍යයක්‌ වශයෙන් වගකීම දරණ බවත් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඉන්දියන් සාගර කලාපය සාම කලාපයක් ලෙස පැවතිය යුතුය. ගැටුමක් ඇති විය නොහැක. එය සතුරු කඳවුරුවල නිවහන විය නොහැක. ආර්ථික වශයෙන් අප ශක්තිමත් හෝ දුර්වල වුවද, අපි ස්ථාවරය පවත්වා ගත යුතුයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඇතැමුන් එම යාත්‍රාව Spy-Ship ලෙස හැඳින්වුවද එය සන්නිවේදන යාත්‍රාවක් ලෙස හැඳින්විය යුතු බවද මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"අපේ රජයේ ව්‍යුහය කුමක් විය යුතුද යන්න චීනය කිසි විටෙක අපට පවසා නැත. චීනය කිසි විටෙක ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ රාජ්‍ය නොවන සංවිධාන පිහිටුවා රජය අස්ථාවර කිරීමට ඔවුන්ට අරමුදල් සපයා නැත. එබැවින් මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර කළ රටවල් අතලොස්සෙන් එකකි චීනය. චීනය අපට තවත් උදව් කරනු ඇතැයි අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු, ”ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙහිදී අදහස් දැක්වූ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර කියා සිටියේ යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 යාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්වාධීනත්වයේ සහ ස්වෛරී බලයේ සංකේතයක් බවයි.",
        "යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අනවශ්‍ය ආන්දෝලනයක් ඇති වූ බවත්, එය එක්සත් ජනපදය ප්‍රමුඛ බටහිර බලවතුන්ගේ කූට උපායක් බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "\"කෙසේ වෙතත්, සාධාරණ තීරණය ජය ගත්තද, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සතුටු වන බැවින්, මෙම වරායේ වැදගත්කමට සහ මෙම වරායේ අනාගත වැදගත්කමට දායක වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 මෙම වරායේ මෙහි තබා ගැනීමට හැකිවීම ගැන අපට සතුටුයි. දිගුකාලීන මිත්‍රත්වයට නොහැකි වනු ඇතැයි අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු. අධිරාජ්‍යවාදයේ කුමන හෝ කූටෝපායන්වලට හසු විය යුතුයි.අපගේ බැඳීම් ස්ථිරව සහ නොබිඳිය හැකි ලෙස තබාගෙන ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ සාමය සහ ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ නිදහස තහවුරු කිරීමට අපට හැකිවනු ඇතැයි අපි විශ්වාස කරනවා\" යනුවෙන් නානායක්කාර මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රියර් අද්මිරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) ආචාර්ය සරත් වීරසේකර මහතා ද පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයට එක්වෙමින් කියා සිටියේ යාත්‍රාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් මතුව ඇති ගැටලුව විසඳීම චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කරන බවත් මෙවැනි සංචාරයන් දෙරට අතර මිත්‍රත්වය ද ශක්තිමත් කරන බවයි. .",
        "ගොඩබිම අපිව බෙදන්න පුළුවන්, නමුත් අහසයි සාගරයයි අපි හැමෝම එකතු කරනවා: යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයේදී විමල්",
        "රුපියල් කෝටි 1000ක් සමඟ පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට මිලියන 245ක් වටිනා කොකේන් රේගුවෙන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinse",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමයේ කලාපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔත්තු-නැව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායකයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොකේන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிலம் நம்மைப் பிரிக்கலாம், ஆனால் வானமும் கடலும் நம்மை ஒன்றிணைக்கிறது: யுவான் வாங் 5-க்கு வரவேற்பு விழாவில் விமல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இந்த நிலம் இலங்கைக்கு சொந்தமானது என்றாலும் வானமும் கடலும் எம்மை ஒன்றிணைக்கின்றன என தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் தலைவர் விமல் வீரவங்ச  அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (16) முற்பகல் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தின் ஏற்பாட்டில் வரவேற்பு வைபவத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர்.",
        "இங்கு தொடர்ந்தும் உரையாற்றிய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வீரவன்ச, இலங்கைக்கு சொந்தமான கடல் மற்றும் வான் பகுதி இருப்பதாகவும், அந்த பகுதிக்கு ஒரு அரசு என்ற வகையில் பொறுப்பு உள்ளது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பிராந்தியம் அமைதிப் பிரதேசமாக இருக்க வேண்டும். எந்த மோதலும் இருக்க முடியாது. அது எதிரி முகாம்களின் தாயகமாக இருக்க முடியாது. பொருளாதாரத்தில் நாம் பலமாக இருந்தாலும் அல்லது பலவீனமாக இருந்தாலும், நாம் நிலைப்பாட்டை பராமரிக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சிலர் இந்தக் கப்பலை ஸ்பை-ஷிப் என்று கூறினாலும், இதனை தகவல் தொடர்புக் கப்பல் என்றே அழைக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் எம்.பி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் அரசாங்கத்தின் கட்டமைப்பு என்னவாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பதை சீனா ஒருபோதும் எங்களிடம் கூறவில்லை. சீனா ஒருபோதும் இலங்கையில் அரச சார்பற்ற நிறுவனங்களை நிறுவவில்லை, அரசாங்கத்தை சீர்குலைக்க நிதியளித்தது இல்லை. எனவே, இந்த கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவிய சில நாடுகளில் சீனாவும் ஒன்று. சீனா எங்களுக்கு மேலும் உதவும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் உரையாற்றிய ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் தலைவர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, யுவான் வாங் 5 கப்பலின் இருப்பு இலங்கையின் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் இறையாண்மையின் அடையாளமாகும்.",
        "கப்பலின் வருகை குறித்து தேவையற்ற சர்ச்சை எழுப்பப்பட்டது, இது அமெரிக்க தலைமையிலான மேற்கத்திய சக்திகளின் சூழ்ச்சி என்று எம்.பி கூறினார்.",
        "\"எவ்வாறாயினும், நியாயமான முடிவு வெற்றிபெற்றது, இந்த துறைமுகத்தின் முக்கியத்துவத்திற்கும் இந்த துறைமுகத்தின் எதிர்கால முக்கியத்துவத்திற்கும் பங்களிக்கும் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஐ இந்த துறைமுகத்தில் வைத்திருப்பதில் இலங்கை மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம். நீண்ட கால நட்புடன் முடியாது என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். ஏகாதிபத்தியத்தின் எந்த விதமான சூழ்ச்சிகளாலும் சிதைக்கப்படுவோம்.எங்களுடைய பிணைப்புகளை உறுதியாகவும், உடைக்க முடியாததாகவும் வைத்து, இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் அமைதியையும், இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் சுதந்திரத்தையும் உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்\" என்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாணயக்கார குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ரியர் அட்மிரல் (ஓய்வு) கலாநிதி சரத் வீரசேகரவும் வரவேற்பு நிகழ்வில் பேசுகையில், கப்பல் தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு காணப்படுவது சீனாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதாகவும், இது போன்ற விஜயங்கள் இரு நாடுகளுக்கிடையிலான நட்புறவை வலுப்படுத்துவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "நிலம் நம்மைப் பிரிக்கலாம், ஆனால் வானமும் கடலும் நம்மை ஒன்றிணைக்கிறது: யுவான் வாங் 5-க்கு வரவேற்பு விழாவில் விமல்",
        "போலந்து நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த நபர் ரூ. சுங்கத்தால் 245 மில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள கோகோயின்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinse",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைதி மண்டலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உளவு-கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடது முன்னணி தலைவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போலிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகோயின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}