{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’’ඩග්ලස්-මුන්රෝ’’-කොළඹ-බලා-පිටත්-‌වෙයි/101-619334",
  "time_ut": 1662374305,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ’’ කොළඹ බලා පිටත් ‌වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Douglas Munro leaves for Colombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The P627 deep sea attack ship, which was officially handed over to the Sri Lanka Navy by the United States Coast Guard Department, left yesterday (03) from Seattle Port in America for its new home port, Colombo Port, the Navy said.",
        "The US Coast Guard Ship Douglas Munro, which belonged to the United States Coast Guard Department, was handed over to the Navy on October 26, 2021, and after being modernized to suit the operational needs of the Sri Lankan Navy, it has started traveling to Melesha Colombo. .",
        "After the official handover, this ship has joined the Sri Lanka Navy fleet under the pennant number P627, and it is scheduled to be assigned to the authority after its arrival in the country.",
        "According to the Navy, the second ship belonging to the Hamilton Class High Endurance Cutter class is 115 meters long and has a maximum speed of 29 nautical miles per hour.",
        "The Navy says that this ship is capable of carrying out invasion operations covering a distance of at least 14000 nautical miles at one time, and is equipped with modern technical devices and facilities that can carry out operations with a total of 187 ships.",
        "This ship P 627 is scheduled to arrive at the port of Colombo in the first week of November 2022 after a long voyage of nearly two months.",
        "In order to strengthen and develop the partnership in order to overcome the common maritime challenges in the ocean region, the deep sea surveillance ships Sri Lanka Naval Ship Samudura \"P 621\" and Sahigajabahu \"P 626\" have been given by the US Coast Guard Department to the Sri Lanka Navy. The Navy also says that this is the third ship given to the Sri Lankan Navy by the US Coast Guard Department with the aim of further developing that partnership.",
        "On that journey to Sri Lanka, to provide supplies and service needs, the ports of Honolulu in America, Apraga ports in Guam in America, Manila ports in the Philippines and Changi ports in Singapore are scheduled to be called."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Douglas Munro",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States Coast Guard Department",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seattle Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Port",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The US Coast Guard Ship",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Munro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States Coast Guard Department",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melesha Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P627",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hamilton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "115 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 nautical miles per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 14000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "187",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of November 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Naval Ship Samudura",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "621",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sahigajabahu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "626",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Coast Guard Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Coast Guard Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honolulu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apraga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manila",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ’’ කොළඹ බලා පිටත් ‌වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂයක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මඟින් ශ්‍රි  ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව වෙත නිල වශයෙන් භාර දෙන ලද පී 627 ගැඹුරු මුහුදු ආවේක්ෂණ නෞකාව  පෙරේදා (03) ඇමරිකාවේ සියැටෙල් වරායේ සිට එහි නව නිවහන වන කොළඹ වරාය බලා පිටත් වු බව නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂපක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට අයත්ව තිබූ ඇමෙරිකානු වෙරළාරක්ෂ ක නෞකා ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ’ නමැති මෙම  නෞකාව  පසු ගිය 2021 ඔක්තෝබර් මාස 26 දින  නාවික හමුදාව වෙත බාර දී තිබු අතර එය ලංකා නාවික හමුදා මෙහෙයුම් අවශ්යසතාවලට ගැලපෙන පරිදි නවීකරණ කිරීමෙන් පසු    මෙලෙෂ කොළඹ වරයා බලා ගමන් ආරම්භ කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම නෞකාව නිල වශයෙන් භාර දීමෙන් පසු පී 627 දරණ පෙනන්ට් අංකය යටතේ ශ්‍රි ලංකා නාවික හමුදා නෞකා සමූහයට එක්ව  ඇති අතර, එය මෙරටට  පැමිණීමෙන් පසු අධිකාරියට පත්කිරීමට නියමිතව ඇත.",
        "Hamilton Class High Endurance Cutter’  යන නෞකා පන්තියට අයත් දෙවන නෞකාව දිගින් මිටර 115ක්,  උපරිම වේගය පැයට නාවික සැතපුම් 29ක්  බව නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "මෙම නෞකාවට  එක් වරකදී අවම වශයෙන් නාවික සැතපුම් 14000ක දුරක් ආවරණය වන පරිදි ආවේක්ෂකණ කටයුතු සිදු කිරීමේ හැකියාවෙන් ඇති බවත්,  187ක පමණ නැව් මුළුවකින් මෙහෙයුම් කටයුතු සිදුකළ හැකි නවීන තාක්ෂිණික උපාංග හා පහසුකම් වලින් සමන්විත  බව නාවික හමුදාව කියයි.",
        "මෙම  පී 627 නෞකාව මාස දෙකකට ආසන්න දීර්ඝ මුහුදු ගමනකින් පසු 2022 නොවැම්බර් මස පළමු සතිය තුලදී කොළඹ වරායට සේන්දුවීමට නියමිතව ඇත.",
        "සාගර කාලාපයේ පොදු සමුද්රීකය අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම උදෙසා හවුල්කාරීත්වය ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේ සහ වර්ධනය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ශ්‍රි ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව වෙත මීට පෙර ශ්‍රි ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සමුදුර’ \"පි 621\" සහිගජබාහු’ \"පි 626\" යන ගැඹුරු මුහුදු අවේක්ෂණ නෞකා ඇමෙරිකානු වෙරළාරක්ෂයක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මගින් ලබා දී ඇති අැති  බවත්,  එම හවුල්කාරීත්වය තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කිරිමේ අරමුණින් ඇමෙරිකානු වෙරළාරක්ෂතක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ශ්‍රි ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව වෙත ලබා දුන් තෙවන නෞකාව  මෙය බවද නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකාව බලා  එම ගමන් මගේ  දී සැපයුම් හා සේවා අවශ්යාතා සපයා ගැනීම සඳහා ඇමරිකාවේ හවායි හී හොනොලුලූ වරායල ඇමරිකාවේ ගුවාම් හී අප්රාග වරායල පිලිපීනයේ මැනිලා වරාය හා සිංගප්පූරුවේ චැංගි යන වරායන් වෙත සේන්දුවීමට නියමිතව ඇතග"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැටල් වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක නෞකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙලේෂා කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P627",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැමිල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 115 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයට නාවික සැතපුම් 29ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 14000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "187",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 නොවැම්බර් පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සමුදුර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "621",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහිගජබාහු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "626",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොනොලුලු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රගා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවාම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැනිලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චංගි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ கொழும்பு செல்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவின் கடலோர பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களத்தினால் இலங்கை கடற்படையிடம் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக கையளிக்கப்பட்ட P627 ஆழ்கடல் தாக்குதல் கப்பல் நேற்று (03) அமெரிக்காவின் சியாட்டில் துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து அதன் புதிய உள்நாட்டு துறைமுகமான கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்திற்கு புறப்பட்டதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படை திணைக்களத்திற்கு சொந்தமான டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ என்ற அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படை கப்பல் 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஒக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் திகதி கடற்படையிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டதுடன், இலங்கை கடற்படையின் செயற்பாட்டுத் தேவைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப நவீனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பின்னர், அது பயணிக்கத் தொடங்கியது. மெலேஷா கொழும்பு..",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ கையளிப்பின் பின்னர், இந்த கப்பல் P627 என்ற இலக்கத்தின் கீழ் இலங்கை கடற்படையின் கடற்படையில் இணைந்துள்ளது, மேலும் இது நாட்டிற்கு வந்த பின்னர் அதிகாரசபைக்கு ஒதுக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "Hamilton Class High Endurance Cutter வகையைச் சேர்ந்த இரண்டாவது கப்பல் 115 மீற்றர் நீளமும், அதிகபட்சமாக மணிக்கு 29 கடல் மைல் வேகமும் கொண்டதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த கப்பல் ஒரே நேரத்தில் குறைந்தது 14000 கடல் மைல் தூரம் வரை ஆக்கிரமிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளும் திறன் கொண்டது என்றும், மொத்தம் 187 கப்பல்கள் மூலம் செயல்பாடுகளை மேற்கொள்ளக்கூடிய நவீன தொழில்நுட்ப சாதனங்கள் மற்றும் வசதிகள் கொண்டது என்றும் கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த P 627 கப்பல் ஏறக்குறைய இரண்டு மாத நீண்ட பயணத்தின் பின்னர் 2022 நவம்பர் முதல் வாரத்தில் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடைய உள்ளது.",
        "கடல் பிராந்தியத்தில் பொதுவான கடல்சார் சவால்களை முறியடிக்கும் வகையில் கூட்டாண்மையை வலுப்படுத்தவும் மேம்படுத்தவும், ஆழ்கடல் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல்களான இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல் சமுதுரா \"P 621\" மற்றும் Sahigajabahu \"P 626\" ஆகியவை அமெரிக்க கடலோர பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களத்தால் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இலங்கை கடற்படைக்கு.அந்த கூட்டுறவை மேலும் மேம்படுத்தும் நோக்கில் அமெரிக்க கடலோர பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களத்தினால் இலங்கை கடற்படைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட மூன்றாவது கப்பல் இது எனவும் கடற்படையினர் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அந்தப் பயணத்தில், விநியோகம் மற்றும் சேவைத் தேவைகளை வழங்க, அமெரிக்காவின் ஹொனலுலு துறைமுகங்கள், அமெரிக்காவின் குவாமில் உள்ள அப்ராகா துறைமுகங்கள், பிலிப்பைன்ஸில் உள்ள மணிலா துறைமுகங்கள் மற்றும் சிங்கப்பூரின் சாங்கி துறைமுகங்கள் அழைக்கப்பட உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்காவின் கடலோர காவல் துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாட்டில் துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படை கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்காவின் கடலோர காவல் துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெலேஷா கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P627",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "115 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 29 கடல் மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 14000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "187",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2022 முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல் சமுதுரா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "621",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹிகஜபாஹு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "626",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொனலுலு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்ரகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}