{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/22/yuan-wang-5-leaves-sri-lanka-after-6-day-replenishment/",
  "time_ut": 1661173620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Yuan Wang 5 leaves Sri Lanka after 6-day replenishment",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Yuan Wang 5 leaves Sri Lanka after 6-day replenishment",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Yuan Wang 5, China's missile and satellite tracking ship berthed at Hambantota port in Sri Lanka, departed today (22), confirmed the Harbour Master of the Hambantota Port Exclusively to News 1st.",
        "The Yuan Wang 5 is one of China's latest generation survey vessel officially entered Port of Hambantota in Sri Lanka on Tuesday 16th August 2022 replenishment purposes.",
        "Sri Lanka granted permission for the high-tech Chinese tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 to dock at the Hambantota Port in a backdrop marred with controversy.",
        "Diplomatic clearance for the Chinese vessel to make a port call at the Hambantota port from 11-17 August​,​ 2022 for replenishment purposes was granted by the Sri Lankan Ministry of Foreing Affairs, however due to concerns raised by various factions including India, the Ministry requested China to defer the visit of the said vessel to the Hambantota port.",
        "However, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs did not provide any reason for the request.",
        "When the request to defer the visit of the vessel was made, the Yuan Wang 5 had already set sail to Sri Lanka leaving its port of origin on the 14th of July, and it was already in the Indian Ocean.",
        "The vessel thereafter slowed down and moved over the Ninety East Ridge, a mid-ocean ridge on the Indian Ocean floor named for its near-parallel strike along the 90th meridian at the center of the Eastern Hemisphere.",
        "On 16th August 2022, Sri Lanka's Cabinet Spokesperson & Minister Bandula Gunawardena confirmed that the Chinese ballistic missiles and satellite tracking vessel was requested to delay their visit due to concerns voiced by India.",
        "He said that a request was made from China to defer the arrival until Sri Lanka cleared out the concerns of its neighbor India.",
        "Yuan Wang 5 is a third-generation tracking ship of the Yuan Wang Series. It has top-of-the-line antennas and electronic equipment to track ballistic missiles and satellite.",
        "The Chinese Reasearch Vessel fleet boats of twin vessels identified as Yuan Wang 5 and Yuan Wang 6.",
        "Suspects should not be wrongly treated as terrorists : Human Rights Commission",
        "Wasantha Mudalige, and two others to be held for 90-days under the PTA",
        "Sri Lanka has not approached creditors officially – CBSL Chief"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harbour",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Port of Hambantota",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday 16th August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11-17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Ministry of Foreing Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ninety East Ridge",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Hemisphere",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16th August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Spokesperson &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 දින 6ක නැවත පිරවීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටත් වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලා තිබූ චීනයේ මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා නිරීක්ෂණ නෞකාව වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 අද (22) පිටත්ව ගිය බව හම්බන්තොට වරායේ හාබර් මාස්ටර් නිවුස් 1st වෙත පමණක් තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 යනු චීනයේ නවතම පරම්පරාවේ සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් වන අතර එය 2022 අගෝස්තු 16 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා නැවත පිරවීමේ අරමුණු සඳහා නිල වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඇතුළු විය.",
        "මතභේදයට තුඩු දී ඇති පසුබිමක හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට අධි තාක්‍ෂණික චීන ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසර ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා නැවත පිරවීමේ අරමුණු සඳහා චීන යාත්‍රාවට හම්බන්තොට වරායට වරාය ඇමතීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික අවසරය ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් ලබා දී ඇත, කෙසේ වෙතත් ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු විවිධ පාර්ශවයන් විසින් මතු කරන ලද කනස්සල්ල හේතුවෙන්, එම යාත්‍රාව හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණීම කල් දමන ලෙස අමාත්‍යාංශය චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය මෙම ඉල්ලීම සඳහා කිසිදු හේතුවක් ඉදිරිපත් කර නොමැත.",
        "යාත්‍රාවේ සංචාරය කල්දැමීමට ඉල්ලීමක් කරන විට, යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ජූලි 14 වන දින එහි මූලාරම්භයේ වරායෙන් පිටත්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට යාත්‍රා කර තිබූ අතර එය ඒ වන විටත් ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ තිබුණි.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව යාත්‍රාව මන්දගාමී වී නැඟෙනහිර අර්ධගෝලයේ මධ්‍යයේ 90 වැනි මධ්‍යධර රේඛාව දිගේ සමාන්තර ප්‍රහාරයක් ලෙස නම් කරන ලද ඉන්දියන් සාගර පතුලේ මැද සාගර කඳු වැටියක් වන Ninety East Ridge හරහා ගමන් කළේය.",
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 16 වන දින, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක සහ අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන තහවුරු කළේ, ඉන්දියාව විසින් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද කරුණු හේතුවෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ සංචාරය ප්‍රමාද කරන ලෙස චීන බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අසල්වැසි ඉන්දියාවේ ප්‍රශ්න ඉවත් කරන තුරු පැමිණීම කල් දමන ලෙස චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 යනු යුවාන් වැන්ග් ශ්‍රේණියේ තුන්වන පරම්පරාවේ ලුහුබැඳීමේ නෞකාවකි. එය බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා ඉහළ පෙළේ ඇන්ටනා සහ ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උපකරණ ඇත.",
        "චීන රීසර්ච් යාත්‍රාව යුආන් වැන්ග් 5 සහ යුවාන් වැන්ග් 6 ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති ද්විත්ව යාත්‍රාවලින් සමන්විත යාත්‍රා.",
        "සැකකරුවන් ත්‍රස්තවාදීන් ලෙස වැරදි ලෙස සලකන්න එපා : මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
        "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ ඇතුළු තවත් දෙදෙනෙක් ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ දින 90ක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිල වශයෙන් ණය හිමියන්ට සම්බන්ධ වී නැත - මහ බැංකු ප්‍රධානියා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6-දින",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 16 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11-17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනූ නැගෙනහිර රිජ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර අර්ධගෝලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யுவான் வாங் 5 6 நாள் நிரப்பலுக்குப் பிறகு இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள சீனாவின் ஏவுகணை மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5, இன்று (22) புறப்பட்டதாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தின் ஹார்பர் மாஸ்டரை நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டுக்கு பிரத்தியேகமாக உறுதிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 என்பது சீனாவின் சமீபத்திய தலைமுறை ஆய்வுக் கப்பலானது, 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் தேதி செவ்வாய்க் கிழமை இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை நிரப்பும் நோக்கத்தில் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக நுழைந்தது.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 என்ற உயர் தொழில்நுட்ப சீன கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலுக்கு அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்துவதற்கு இலங்கை அனுமதி வழங்கியது.",
        "2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் துறைமுக அழைப்பை மேற்கொள்ள சீனக் கப்பலுக்கு இராஜதந்திர அனுமதி இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சினால் வழங்கப்பட்டது, எனினும் இந்தியா உட்பட பல்வேறு தரப்பினரால் எழுப்பப்பட்ட கவலைகள் காரணமாக, அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு மேற்படி கப்பலின் விஜயத்தை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு அமைச்சு சீனாவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "எனினும், இந்தக் கோரிக்கைக்கான காரணத்தை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் தெரிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "கப்பலின் வருகையை ஒத்திவைக்க கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டபோது, ​​யுவான் வாங் 5 ஏற்கனவே ஜூலை 14 ஆம் தேதி அதன் பிறப்பிடமான துறைமுகத்தை விட்டு இலங்கைக்கு புறப்பட்டது, அது ஏற்கனவே இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் இருந்தது.",
        "அதன்பிறகு கப்பல் வேகம் குறைந்து தொண்ணூறு கிழக்கு ரிட்ஜ் மீது நகர்ந்தது, இது இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் தரையில் உள்ள நடுக்கடல் முகடு, கிழக்கு அரைக்கோளத்தின் மையத்தில் உள்ள 90 வது மெரிடியனில் அதன் இணையான தாக்குதலுக்கு பெயரிடப்பட்டது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 16, 2022 அன்று, இலங்கையின் அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளரும் அமைச்சருமான பந்துல குணவர்தன, சீனாவின் பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணைகள் மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்புக் கப்பலானது, இந்தியா தெரிவித்த கவலைகள் காரணமாக தங்கள் வருகையை தாமதப்படுத்துமாறு கோரப்பட்டது என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "இலங்கை தனது அண்டை நாடுகளான இந்தியாவின் கவலைகளை நீக்கும் வரை வருகையை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு சீனாவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 என்பது யுவான் வாங் தொடரின் மூன்றாம் தலைமுறை கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் ஆகும். இது பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணைகள் மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள்களைக் கண்காணிக்கும் உயர்தர ஆண்டெனாக்கள் மற்றும் மின்னணு உபகரணங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 மற்றும் யுவான் வாங் 6 என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட இரட்டைக் கப்பல்களின் சீன ரீசர்ச் கப்பல் கடற்படை படகுகள்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர்களை பயங்கரவாதிகளாக தவறாக நடத்தக்கூடாது: மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
        "வசந்த முதலிகே மற்றும் இரண்டு பேர் பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் 90 நாட்களுக்கு நடத்தப்படவுள்ளனர்",
        "இலங்கை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக கடனாளிகளை அணுகவில்லை - CBSL தலைவர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6-நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16, 2022 செவ்வாய்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11-17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொண்ணூறு கிழக்கு ரிட்ஜ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு அரைக்கோளம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}