{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ජනාධිපති-අගමැති-සටනට-සමඟි-ජන-බලවේගයත්-එනවා/101-616484",
  "time_ut": 1657898199,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනාධිපති-අගමැති සටනට සමඟි ජන බලවේගයත් එනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Sami People's Force is also coming to the President-Prime Minister battle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Gayantha Karunathilaka, Member of Parliament of the Sami Jana Balavega, said today (15) afternoon that Sami Jana Balawegaya has decided to run for the post of President and Prime Minister and that the nominations will be handed over next Monday.",
        "Mr. Karunathilaka said that the MPs running for the post of President and Prime Minister will be revealed at the time of handing over the nominations.",
        "Member of Parliament Mr. Gayantha Karunathilaka said this after the discussion held today (15) at the office of the opposition leader in Colombo 7 with the participation of the members of the parliamentary group of the United People's Force."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The Sami People's Force",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gayantha Karunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sami Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Karunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayantha Karunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති-අගමැති සටනට සමඟි ජන බලවේගයත් එනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය තනතුරට කළින් ගත් තීරණයට අනුව සමඟි ජන බලවේගය ඉදිරිපත්වීමට තීරණය කළ බවත් නාමයෝජනා ලබන සඳුදා භාරදෙන බවත් සමඟි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ගයන්ත කරුණාතිලක මහතා අද (15) පස්වරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "නාමයෝජනා භාරදෙන අවස්ථාවේදී ජනාධිපති ධූරයට සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට ඉදිරිපත් වන මන්ත්‍රීවරු හෙළි කරන බව කී කරුණාතිලක මහතා විවිධ පාර්ශව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර යම් සම්මුතියකට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු සැකසීමට ද ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් සිටින බව ද වැඩි දුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සමඟි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායමේ සාමාජිකයන්ගේ සහභාගිත්වයෙන් කොළඹ 7 පිහිටි විපක්‍ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී අද (15) පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවෙන් පසුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ගයන්ත කරුණාතිලක මහතා එසේ පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සාමි ජනතා බලවේගය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගයන්ත කරුණාතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කරුණාතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයන්ත කරුණාතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி-பிரதமர் போருக்கு சாமி மக்கள் படையும் வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமி ஜன பலவேகய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு போட்டியிட தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாகவும் எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை வேட்புமனுக்கள் கையளிக்கப்படும் எனவும் சமி ஜன பலவேகவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.கயந்த கருணாதிலக்க இன்று (15) பிற்பகல் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு போட்டியிடும் எம்.பி.க்கள் யார் என்பது வேட்புமனுக்களை கையளிக்கும் போது வெளிப்படுத்தப்படும் என கருணாதிலக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு உறுப்பினர்களின் பங்குபற்றுதலுடன் கொழும்பு 7ல் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று (15) இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் பின்னர் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.கயந்த கருணாதிலக்க மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சாமி மக்கள் படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கயந்த கருணாதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாமி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருணாதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயந்த கருணாதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}