{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/birmingham_2022_cwg/Yupun-Abeykoon-qualifies-for-CWG-semis-fastest-in-100m-heats/488-242272",
  "time_ut": 1659438008,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Yupun Abeykoon qualifies for CWG semis, fastest in 100m heats",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Yupun Abeykoon qualifies for CWG semis, fastest in 100m heats",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan sprinter Yupun Abeykoon produced an excellent performance to win Heat 6 of the Men’s 100m event at the 22nd Commonwealth Games in Birmingham, England today.",
        "The fastest athlete in the South Asian region returned a superb time of 10.06s and qualified to compete in tomorrow’s semi-finals, scheduled for 11.40 p.m. Sri Lanka time with the fastest time in the Heats.",
        "Third placed Godson Oke Oghenebrume (10.36s) of Nigeria and second placed Kion Benjamin (10.34s) of the Trinidad and Tobago were the real threats for Abeykoon in this heat, but he managed to storm past them to secure the top spot.",
        "The top two athletes of each heat (10 heats) progressed to the semi-finals while the next seven semi-final spots were awarded to the fastest losers.",
        "Abeykoon said that now that he had cleared his initial hurdle, he would target a medal when he competes in the finals tomorrow.",
        "“I am happy to reach the semi-finals and my next goal is to reach the final and win a medal for Sri Lanka,” Abeykoon revealed soon after the event.",
        "Meanwhile, the other Sri Lankan athlete to take part today, Gayanthika Abeyratne clocked a Personal Best time of 2:01.20 secs in the Heats of the Women’s 800m but it was not enough to take her to the next round.",
        "Natoya Goule of Jamaica was placed first in the Heat, with a time of 1:58.39, ahead of Scotland’s Laura Muir, 1:58.84, and Alexandra Bell of England, who clocked 1:59.76."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yupun Abeykoon",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "100m heats",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yupun Abeykoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Men’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth Games",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Birmingham",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.40 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heats",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Godson Oke Oghenebrume",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nigeria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kion Benjamin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tobago",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeykoon",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 heats",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayanthika Abeyratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:01.20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Natoya Goule",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jamaica",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scotland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Laura Muir",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:58.84",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alexandra Bell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:59.76",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුපුන් අබේකෝන් මීටර් 100 උණුසුම් ඉසව්වේ වේගවත්ම CWG අවසන් පූර්ව වටයට සුදුසුකම් ලබයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එංගලන්තයේ බර්මින්හැම් හි පැවැත්වෙන 22 වැනි පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේ පිරිමි මීටර් 100 ඉසව්වේ හීට් 6 තරගය ජය ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා කෙටි දුර ධාවන ශූර යූපුන් අබේකෝන් අද විශිෂ්ට දස්කම් දැක්වූවා.",
        "දකුණු ආසියානු කලාපයේ වේගවත්ම ක්‍රීඩකයා තත්පර 10.06 ක විශිෂ්ට කාලයක් වාර්තා කළ අතර හෙට රාත්‍රී 11.40 ට නියමිත අවසන් පූර්ව තරගයට සහභාගි වීමට සුදුසුකම් ලබා ගත්තේය. හීට්ස් හි වේගවත්ම කාලය සමග ශ්‍රී ලංකා වේලාව.",
        "තෙවැනි ස්ථානය නයිජීරියාවේ Godson Oke Oghenebrume (තත්පර 10.36) සහ දෙවැනි ස්ථානය Trinidad and Tobago හි Kion Benjamin (තත්පර 10.34) මෙම උණුසුමේ දී අබේකෝන්ට සැබෑ තර්ජන වූ නමුත් ඔහු ඔවුන් පසුකර ගොස් ප්‍රමුඛ ස්ථානය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට සමත් විය.",
        "එක් එක් හීට් එකක (උණුසුම් තරග 10) ඉහළම ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් දෙදෙනා අවසන් පූර්ව වටයට පිවිසි අතර මීළඟ අවසන් පූර්ව වටයේ ස්ථාන හත වේගවත්ම පරාජිතයන්ට පිරිනැමිණි.",
        "අබේකෝන් පැවසුවේ මේ වන විට තම මූලික බාධකය ඉවත් කර ඇති බැවින් හෙට අවසන් මහා තරගයට ඉදිරිපත් වන විට පදක්කමක් ඉලක්ක කර ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "\"මම අවසන් පූර්ව වටයට පැමිණීම ගැන සතුටු වන අතර මගේ මීළඟ ඉලක්කය අවසන් මහා තරගයට පැමිණ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පදක්කමක් දිනා දීමයි\" යනුවෙන් ඉසව්වෙන් පසුව අබේකෝන් හෙළි කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, අද සහභාගි වන අනෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රීඩිකාව වන ගයන්තිකා අබේරත්න කාන්තා මීටර් 800 උණුසුම් ඉසව්වෙන් තත්පර 2:01.20 ක පෞද්ගලික හොඳම කාලය වාර්තා කළ නමුත් ඇයව මීළඟ වටයට රැගෙන යාමට එය ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවීය.",
        "ජැමෙයිකාවේ Natoya Goule හීට් හි ප්‍රථම ස්ථානයට පත් වූ අතර, 1:58.39 කාලයකින්, ස්කොට්ලන්තයේ Laura Muir, 1:58.84, සහ 1:59.76 නිමා කළ එංගලන්තයේ Alexandra Bell ඉදිරියෙන් සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුපුන් අබේකෝන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මීටර් 100 උණුසුම්",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුපුන් අබේකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමින්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බර්මින්හැම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.40 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උණුසුම් කරයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොඩ්සන් Oke Oghenebrume",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයිජීරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කියෝන් බෙන්ජමින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොබැගෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේකෝන්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාප 10 ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයන්තිකා අබේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:01.20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Natoya Goule",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැමෙයිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝරා මුයර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:58.84",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩ්‍රා බෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:59.76",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யூபுன் அபேகோன் CWG அரையிறுதிக்கு தகுதி பெற்றார், 100 மீ ஹீட்ஸில் வேகமாக",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இங்கிலாந்தின் பர்மிங்ஹாமில் இன்று நடைபெற்ற 22வது பொதுநலவாய விளையாட்டுப் போட்டியில், இலங்கையின் ஓட்டப்பந்தய வீரர் யுபுன் அபேகோன், ஆண்களுக்கான 100 மீற்றர் போட்டியின் ஹீட் 6 போட்டியில் வெற்றிபெற்றார்.",
        "தெற்காசிய பிராந்தியத்தில் அதிவேகமான தடகள வீரர் 10.06 வினாடிகளில் ஒரு சிறந்த நேரத்தைத் திருப்பி, நாளை இரவு 11.40 மணிக்குத் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட அரையிறுதிப் போட்டியில் பங்கேற்கத் தகுதி பெற்றார். ஹீட்ஸில் வேகமான நேரத்தைக் கொண்ட இலங்கை நேரம்.",
        "மூன்றாவது இடத்தில் நைஜீரியாவின் காட்சன் ஓகே ஓகெனெப்ரூம் (10.36 வி) மற்றும் டிரினிடாட் மற்றும் டொபாகோவின் கியோன் பெஞ்சமின் (10.34 வி) இந்த வெப்பத்தில் அபேகோனுக்கு உண்மையான அச்சுறுத்தலாக இருந்தனர், ஆனால் அவர் அவர்களைக் கடந்து முதலிடத்தைப் பெற முடிந்தது.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு வெப்பத்திலும் (10 ஹீட்ஸ்) முதல் இரண்டு தடகள வீரர்கள் அரையிறுதிக்கு முன்னேறினர், அடுத்த ஏழு அரையிறுதி இடங்கள் வேகமாக தோல்வியடைந்தவர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தற்போது தனது ஆரம்ப தடையை நீக்கியுள்ள நிலையில், நாளை இறுதிப் போட்டியில் பங்குபற்றும்போது பதக்கத்தை இலக்காகக் கொள்வதாக அபேகோன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நான் அரையிறுதிக்கு வருவதில் மகிழ்ச்சி அடைகிறேன், இறுதிப் போட்டிக்கு வந்து இலங்கைக்கு பதக்கம் வெல்வதே எனது அடுத்த இலக்காகும்\" என்று நிகழ்வு முடிந்தவுடன் அபேகோன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இன்று பங்குபற்றவுள்ள மற்றைய இலங்கை வீராங்கனையான கயந்திகா அபேரத்ன, பெண்களுக்கான 800 மீற்றர் ஹீட்ஸ் போட்டியில் தனிப்பட்ட சிறந்த நேரத்தை 2:01.20 வினாடிகளில் கடந்து, அடுத்த சுற்றுக்கு அழைத்துச் செல்ல போதுமானதாக இல்லை.",
        "ஹீட் பிரிவில் ஜமைக்காவின் நாடோயா கவுல் 1:58.39 வினாடிகளில் முதலிடம் பிடித்தார், ஸ்காட்லாந்தின் லாரா முயர், 1:58.84 மற்றும் இங்கிலாந்தின் அலெக்ஸாண்ட்ரா பெல், 1:59.76 வினாடிகளில் கடந்து சென்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யூபுன் அபேகோன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "100 மீ ஹீட்ஸ்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூபுன் அபேகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பர்மிங்காம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.40 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெப்பமடைகிறது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காட்சன் ஓகே ஓகெனெப்ரூம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நைஜீரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கியோன் பெஞ்சமின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொபாகோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேகோன்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 வெப்பங்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயந்திகா அபேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:01.20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடோயா கோலே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜமைக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாரா முயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:58.84",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்ஸாண்ட்ரா பெல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:59.76",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}