{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/India-responds-to-Chinese-Ambassadors-remarks-on-SL/155-243866",
  "time_ut": 1661620949,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India responds to Chinese Ambassador’s remarks on SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India responds to Chinese Ambassador’s remarks on SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Responding to recent remarks of Chinese Ambassador on Sri Lanka, Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka said Sri Lanka needs support, not unwanted pressure or unnecessary controversies to serve another country’s agenda.",
        "The High Commission said in a twitter post that \"We have noted the remarks of the Chinese Ambassador. His violation of basic diplomatic etiquette may be a personal trait or reflecting a larger national attitude\"",
        "\"His view of Sri Lanka's northern neighbour may be coloured by how his own country behaves. India, we assure him,is very different,\" the High Commission tweeted.",
        "\"His imputing a geopolitical context to the visit of a purported scientific research vessel is a giveaway.",
        "Opaqueness and debt driven agendas are now a major challenge, especially for smaller nations. Recent developments are a caution.",
        "Sri Lanka needs support, not unwanted pressure or unnecessary controversies to serve another country’s agenda,\" it tweeted."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශයට ඉන්දියාව ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ මෑත ප්‍රකාශවලට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෙනත් රටක න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට සේවය කිරීම සඳහා අනවශ්‍ය බලපෑම් හෝ අනවශ්‍ය මතභේද නොව සහය අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ට්විටර් සටහනක් තබමින් කියා සිටියේ \"චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශය අපි සටහන් කර ඇත්තෙමු. ඔහුගේ මූලික රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආචාර විධි කඩ කිරීම පුද්ගලික ලක්ෂණයක් හෝ විශාල ජාතික ආකල්පයක් පිළිබිඹු කිරීමක් විය හැකිය\"",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උතුරු අසල්වැසියා පිළිබඳ ඔහුගේ දැක්ම ඔහුගේම රට හැසිරෙන ආකාරය අනුව වර්ණවත් විය හැකිය. ඉන්දියාව, අපි ඔහුට සහතික වෙමු, ඔහු බෙහෙවින් වෙනස් ය,\" මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "\"ඔහු විසින් කියනු ලබන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක සංචාරයට භූ දේශපාලනික සන්දර්භයක් ආරෝපණය කිරීම දීමනාවකි.",
        "පාරාන්ධභාවය සහ ණය මත පදනම් වූ න්‍යාය පත්‍ර දැන් ප්‍රධාන අභියෝගයකි, විශේෂයෙන් කුඩා ජාතීන්ට. මෑත වර්ධනයන් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමකි.",
        "වෙනත් රටක න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට සේවය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය අවශ්‍ය මිස අනවශ්‍ය බලපෑම් හෝ අනවශ්‍ය මතභේද නොවේ, ”එය ට්වීට් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை குறித்த சீன தூதுவரின் கருத்துக்கு இந்தியா பதிலடி கொடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவரின் அண்மைக் கருத்துக்களுக்குப் பதிலளித்த இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம், இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவு தேவை, வேறொரு நாட்டின் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலுக்கு சேவை செய்வதற்கு தேவையற்ற அழுத்தங்கள் அல்லது தேவையற்ற சர்ச்சைகள் அல்ல.",
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தனது ட்விட்டர் பதிவில், \"சீன தூதரின் கருத்துக்களை நாங்கள் கவனித்துள்ளோம். அவர் அடிப்படை இராஜதந்திர ஆசாரங்களை மீறுவது தனிப்பட்ட பண்பாக இருக்கலாம் அல்லது ஒரு பெரிய தேசிய அணுகுமுறையை பிரதிபலிக்கும்\"",
        "\"இலங்கையின் வடக்கு அண்டை நாடு பற்றிய அவரது பார்வை அவரது சொந்த நாடு எவ்வாறு நடந்துகொள்கிறது என்பதன் வண்ணமாக இருக்கலாம். இந்தியா, அவருக்கு மிகவும் வித்தியாசமானது என்று நாங்கள் உறுதியளிக்கிறோம்,\" என்று உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ட்வீட் செய்தது.",
        "\"ஒரு விஞ்ஞான ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலின் வருகைக்கு அவர் புவிசார் அரசியல் சூழலைக் குறிப்பிடுவது ஒரு பரிசு.",
        "ஒளிவுமறைவு மற்றும் கடன் உந்துதல் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரல் இப்போது ஒரு பெரிய சவாலாக உள்ளது, குறிப்பாக சிறிய நாடுகளுக்கு. சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்கள் ஒரு எச்சரிக்கை.",
        "வேறொரு நாட்டின் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலுக்கு சேவை செய்ய இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவு தேவை, தேவையற்ற அழுத்தங்கள் அல்லது தேவையற்ற சர்ச்சைகள் அல்ல\" என்று அது ட்வீட் செய்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}