{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අරගලයේ-තරුණයන්ගේ-වෙනසක-ඉල්ලීම-අපි-පිළිගන්නවා/11-395798",
  "time_ut": 1658931770,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අරගලයේ තරුණයන්ගේ වෙනසක ඉල්ලීම අපි පිළිගන්නවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We accept the demand for change from the youth of the struggle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The demand of the youth who were engaged in the struggle was to change the system of the country. President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that we also accept it.",
        "The President mentioned this this afternoon (27th) while addressing the staff at the United National Party headquarters, Sirikota Mandir in Pitakotta.",
        "United National Party General Secretary Palitha Range Bandara, National Organizer Sagala Ratnayake and Party Chief Executive Officer Shamal Senarath welcomed the President who arrived at the party headquarters.",
        "The President mentioned that everyone is allowed to engage in peaceful protests according to the law of the country, those who were involved in the struggle also have the same right and he saw the participation of young people with various talents.",
        "Stating that he assumed the presidency at a time when the country was in a very difficult situation, the President also said that he has taken many steps to overcome the economic challenge and move the country forward."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirikota Mandir",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitakotta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Range",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Organizer Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලයේ තරුණයන්ගේ වෙනසක ඉල්ලීම අපි පිළිගන්නවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලයේ නිරතව සිටි තරුණයන්ගේ ඉල්ලීම වුයේ රටේ ක්‍රමය වෙනස් කිරීමයි. එය අපිත් පිළිගන්නවා යැයි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේ අද (27දා) පස්වරුවේ පිටකෝට්ටේ පිහිටි එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානය වන සිරිකොත මන්දිරයේ දී එහි කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අමතමිනි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මහ ලේකම් පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර, ජාතික සංවිධායක සාගල රත්නායක, පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී ශමල් සෙනරත් යන මහත්වරු විසින් පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානය වෙත පැමිණි  ජනාධිපතිවරයාව පිළි ගනු ලැබිණ.",
        "සියලුදෙනාට රටේ නීතියට අනුව  සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවල නිරතවීමට ඉඩ ඇති බවත්, අරගලයේ නිරත වූවන්ට ද එම අයිතිය ඇති අතර විවිධ දක්ෂතා ඇති තරුණ තරුණියන් ද  ඊට එක්ව සිටි අයුරු තමා දුටු බව  ජනාධිපතිතුමා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තමා ජනාධිපතිධූරය භාර ගත්තේ රට ඉතා අසීරු තත්ත්වයක පවතින අවස්ථාවේ බව සඳහන් කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ආර්ථික අභියෝගය ජය ගනිමින් රට ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට මේ වන විට පියවර රැසක් ගෙන ඇති බව ද කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිකොට මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටකෝට්ට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත රංගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සංවිධායක සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்ட இளைஞர்களின் மாற்றக் கோரிக்கையை ஏற்கிறோம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் அமைப்பை மாற்ற வேண்டும் என்பதே போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த இளைஞர்களின் கோரிக்கையாக இருந்தது. அதனை நாமும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்கிறோம் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று (27) பிற்பகல் பிட்டகொத்தவில் உள்ள ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைமையகமான சிறிகொத்த மன்றில் பணியாளர்கள் மத்தியில் உரையாற்றும் போதே ஜனாதிபதி இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் பாலித ரங்கே பண்டார, தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க மற்றும் கட்சியின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி ஷமல் செனரத் ஆகியோர் கட்சி தலைமையகத்திற்கு வருகை தந்த ஜனாதிபதியை வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "நாட்டின் சட்டத்திற்கு அமைவாக அமைதியான முறையில் போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுபடுவதற்கு அனைவருக்கும் அனுமதி உள்ளதாகவும், போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களுக்கும் அதே உரிமை உண்டு எனவும், பல்வேறு திறமைகளைக் கொண்ட இளைஞர்கள் கலந்துகொண்டதைக் கண்ட ஜனாதிபதி,",
        "நாடு மிகவும் இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்த வேளையில் தான் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றதாக தெரிவித்த ஜனாதிபதி, பொருளாதார சவாலை முறியடித்து நாட்டை முன்னோக்கி கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு பல நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிகோட்டா மந்திர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடகோட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித ரேஞ்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}