{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/record-run-chase-puts-sri-lanka-in-super-four-of-asia-cup-2022/",
  "time_ut": 1662090960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Record run chase puts Sri Lanka in Super Four of Asia Cup 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Record run chase puts Sri Lanka in Super Four of Asia Cup 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ICC: Sri Lanka chased down a target of 184 with four balls and two wickets to spare to qualify to the Super Four stage of Asia Cup 2022 in Dubai.",
        "In a game that swung back and forth, Sri Lanka held their nerve under pressure to sneak in a two-wicket win and qualify to the Super Four stage of Asia Cup 2022.",
        "Chasing 184, Sri Lanka started off well, but soon found themselves in trouble at 77/4 in the ninth over. Kusal Mendis, helped by a series of let-offs, compiled a half-century, and Dasun Shanaka added momentum to the innings to take Sri Lanka close.",
        "However, Bangladesh struck again in quick succession to come out on top.",
        "At 158/7 in the 18th over, Sri Lanka's hopes appeared done and dusted, but helped by a boundary off a no-ball in the penultimate over, Sri Lanka managed 17 runs off Ebadot Hossain's over to turn the game on its head.",
        "Asitha Fernando, on debut, hit 10 off three balls, including a crucial four off the second ball in the final over to help Sri Lanka complete their second-highest run chase in T20Is.",
        "It was also the highest-ever successful run chase in UAE in T20Is, beating Afghanistan's run chase of 180 against UAE in 2016.",
        "Japan calls for creditor nations’ talks on Sri Lanka debt restructuring",
        "Record run chase puts Sri Lanka in Super Four of Asia Cup 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Super Four of Asia Cup",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "184",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Super Four",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Cup 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Super Four",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Cup 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "184",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77/4 in the ninth",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusal Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a half-century",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dasun Shanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ebadot Hossain's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asitha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Super Four of Asia Cup",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වාර්තාගත ලකුණු හඹායාම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2022 ආසියානු කුසලානයේ සුපිරි හතරට ඇතුළත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ICC: ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2022 ඩුබායි හි පැවැත්වෙන ආසියානු කුසලානයේ සුපිරි හතර අදියරට සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමට තවත් පන්දු 4ක් සහ කඩුලු 2ක් ඉතිරිව තිබියදී ලකුණු 184ක ඉලක්කයක් හඹා ගියේය.",
        "එහාට මෙහාට පැද්දෙන තරගයකදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කඩුලු දෙකක ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබා 2022 ආසියානු කුසලානයේ සුපිරි හතරේ අදියරට සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමේ පීඩනය යටතේ ඔවුන්ගේ ස්නායුව රඳවාගෙන සිටියේය.",
        "ලකුණු 184ක් හඹා ගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හොඳින් ආරම්භ කළ නමුත් නවවැනි ඕවරයේදී ලකුණු 77/4ක් ලෙස ඉක්මනින්ම අසීරු තත්ත්වයකට පත්විය. දැවී ගිය අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදීම කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස් අර්ධ ශතකයක් රැස් කළ අතර, දසුන් ශානක ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමීප කරවීමට ඉනිමට ශක්තියක් එක් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, බංගලාදේශය ඉක්මනින්ම ඉදිරියට පැමිණීම සඳහා නැවත වරක් පහර දුන්නේය.",
        "18 වැනි ඕවරයේදී ලකුණු 158/7 ක් වූ විට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිලේ බලාපොරොත්තු සුන් වී ගිය බවක් පෙනෙන්නට තිබුණද, අවසන් ඕවරයේ දී නොබෝලයකින් හතරේ පහරක් එල්ල කළ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිල එබඩොට් හොසේන්ගේ ඕවරයේ දී ලකුණු 17 ක් ලබා ගනිමින් තරගය කණපිට හැරවිය.",
        "අසිත ප්‍රනාන්දු, මංගල තරගයේදී පන්දු තුනකින් ලකුණු 10ක් ලබා ගත් අතර, අවසන් ඕවරයේ දෙවැනි පන්දුවට තීරණාත්මක හතරේ පහරක් ඇතුළුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිලට T20I හි ඔවුන්ගේ දෙවැනි ඉහළම ලකුණු හඹායාම සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට උපකාර විය.",
        "එය 2016 දී එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට එරෙහිව ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ ලකුණු 180 ක ලකුණු හඹා යාමක් අභිබවා යමින් UAE හි T20I හි මෙතෙක් වාර්තා වූ ඉහළම සාර්ථක ලකුණු හඹා යාම ද විය.",
        "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ ණයහිමි ජාතීන්ගේ සාකච්ඡා ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "වාර්තාගත ලකුණු හඹායාම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2022 ආසියානු කුසලානයේ සුපිරි හතරට ඇතුළත් කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානයේ සුපිරි හතර",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "184",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුපිරි හතර",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුපිරි හතර",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "184",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77/4 නවවැනි ස්ථානයේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසල් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ධ ශතකයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දසුන් ශානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ebadot Hossain ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අසිත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානයේ සුපිරි හතර",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 ஆசியக் கோப்பையின் சூப்பர் 4 இல் இலங்கையை சாதனை ரன் சேஸ் சேர்த்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐசிசி: துபாயில் 2022 ஆசிய கோப்பையில் சூப்பர் 4 சுற்றுக்கு தகுதி பெற இலங்கை அணி 184 ரன்கள் இலக்கை 4 பந்துகள் மற்றும் 2 விக்கெட்டுகள் மீதமுள்ள நிலையில் துரத்தியது.",
        "முன்னும் பின்னுமாக நடந்த ஒரு ஆட்டத்தில், இலங்கை இரண்டு விக்கெட் வித்தியாசத்தில் வெற்றி பெற்று 2022 ஆசியக் கோப்பையின் சூப்பர் ஃபோர் நிலைக்குத் தகுதி பெறுவதற்கான அழுத்தத்தின் கீழ் இருந்தது.",
        "184 ரன்களைத் துரத்திய இலங்கை, நன்றாகத் தொடங்கியது, ஆனால் விரைவில் ஒன்பதாவது ஓவரில் 77/4 என்ற சிக்கலில் சிக்கியது. குசல் மெண்டிஸ், தொடர்ச்சியான லெட் ஆஃப்களால் உதவினார், அரை சதத்தை தொகுத்தார், மேலும் தசுன் ஷனக இன்னிங்ஸில் வேகத்தை சேர்த்து இலங்கையை நெருங்கினார்.",
        "இருப்பினும், வங்காளதேசம் மீண்டும் அடுத்தடுத்து வெற்றி பெற்று முதலிடம் பிடித்தது.",
        "18வது ஓவரில் 158/7 என்ற நிலையில், இலங்கையின் நம்பிக்கைகள் தூள்தூளாக்கப்பட்டதாகத் தோன்றியது, ஆனால் கடைசி ஓவரில் நோ-பாலில் ஒரு பவுண்டரி அடிக்க உதவியது, இலங்கை எபடோட் ஹொசைனின் ஓவரில் 17 ரன்கள் எடுத்து ஆட்டத்தை தலைகீழாக மாற்ற முடிந்தது.",
        "அசித பெர்னாண்டோ, தொடக்க ஆட்டத்தில், மூன்று பந்துகளில் 10 ரன்கள் எடுத்தார், இறுதி ஓவரில் இரண்டாவது பந்தில் ஒரு முக்கியமான பவுண்டரி உட்பட, இலங்கை T20I களில் இரண்டாவது அதிக ரன் சேஸை முடிக்க உதவியது.",
        "2016 இல் UAEக்கு எதிராக ஆப்கானிஸ்தானின் 180 ரன்களை முறியடித்து, T20I இல் UAE இல் இதுவரை இல்லாத வெற்றிகரமான ரன் சேஸ் இதுவாகும்.",
        "இலங்கை கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பாக கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு ஜப்பான் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
        "2022 ஆசியக் கோப்பையின் சூப்பர் 4 இல் இலங்கையை சாதனை ரன் சேஸ் சேர்த்தது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பையின் சூப்பர் ஃபோர்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "184",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர் நான்கு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர் நான்கு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை 2022",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "184",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது இடத்தில் 77/4",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசல் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு அரை சதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தசுன் ஷனக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எபடோட் ஹொசைனின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அசித்த பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பையின் சூப்பர் ஃபோர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}