{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/rs-3-4-bn-indian-aid-reaches-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1658832300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rs.3.4 Bn Indian Aid reaches Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rs.3.4 Bn Indian Aid reaches Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); High Commissioner Gopal Baglay handed over humanitarian supplies worth around Sri Lanka Rs. 3.4 billion donated by the people of India to Ali Sabry PC, Minister of Foreign Affairs, and Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Health and Water Supplies in Colombo on 26 July 2022.",
        "Member of Parliament Jeevan Thondaman and Ceylon Worker’s Congress leader Senthil Thondaman attended the event.",
        "The large humanitarian consignment consisting of 16,594 MT of rice, 200 MT of milk powder, and around 38 MT of medicines were donated by the Government of Tamil Nadu.",
        "This was the third such consignment from the Government of Tamil Nadu, which has donated a total of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder, and more than 100 MT of medicines whose total worth is more than USD 22 million. Critical medicines like 25,000 doses of anti-rabies vaccine formed a part of these supplies.",
        "These supplies are distributed among the beneficiaries by the Government of Sri Lanka and the humanitarian supplies which were handed over on 26 July 2022 are also expected to reach the beneficiaries in different parts of Sri Lanka in the coming days.",
        "The people of India have been complementing the Government of India’s efforts in standing with the people of Sri Lanka towards addressing their diverse needs. To this end, overwhelming and multi-pronged support of over USD 3.8 billion by the Government of India to the Sri Lankan people during the year was strengthened by independent initiatives of various hospitals, Indian community organizations in Sri Lanka, and several other entities based in India who donated generously for their brethren in Sri Lanka.",
        "The coming together of the people and Government of India towards the cause underscores the abiding people-to-people connection between India and Sri Lanka and the mutual care and concern for each other.",
        "Modi congratulates Ranil; says India will support Sri Lankan people"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Rs",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Worker",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senthil Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16,594",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over USD 3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය ආධාර රුපියල් බිලියන 3.4ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වටා රු. 2022 ජූලි 26 වන දින කොළඹදී විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි සහ සෞඛ්‍ය හා ජල සම්පාදන අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල වෙත ඉන්දීය ජනතාව විසින් රුපියල් බිලියන 3.4 පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් සහ ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක සෙන්දිල් තොණ්ඩමන් යන මහත්වරු සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 16,594 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 200 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත විශාල මානුෂීය තොගය තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලදී.",
        "සහල් මෙ.ටොන් 40,000ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් පරිත්‍යාග කර ඇති තමිල්නාඩු රජයෙන් එවැනි තුන්වන තොගය මෙය වන අතර එහි මුළු වටිනාකම ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 22කට වඩා වැඩිය. ජලභීතිකා නාශක එන්නත් මාත්‍රා 25,000ක් වැනි තීරණාත්මක ඖෂධ මෙම සැපයුම්වල කොටසක් විය.",
        "මෙම සැපයුම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් ප්‍රතිලාභීන් අතර බෙදා හරින අතර 2022 ජූලි 26 දින භාර දුන් මානුෂීය සැපයුම් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල ප්‍රතිලාභීන් වෙත ළඟා වීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ විවිධ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ සිට ඉන්දියානු රජය දරන ප්‍රයත්නයට ඉන්දීය ජනතාව අනුපූරකව සිටිති. මේ සඳහා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ රෝහල්, ඉන්දියානු ප්‍රජා සංවිධාන සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පදනම් වූ තවත් ආයතන කිහිපයක ස්වාධීන මුලපිරීම් මගින් වසර තුළ ඉන්දියානු රජය ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කට අධික අතිමහත් සහ බහුකාර්ය සහයෝගය ශක්තිමත් කරන ලදී. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින තම සහෝදරයන් වෙනුවෙන් නොමසුරුව පරිත්‍යාග කළ ඉන්දියාව.",
        "ඒ සඳහා ජනතාව සහ ඉන්දීය රජය එකමුතු වීම ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර පවතින මිනිසුන්-ජනතාව අතර සම්බන්ධය සහ එකිනෙකා කෙරෙහි ඇති අන්‍යෝන්‍ය සැලකිල්ල සහ සැලකිල්ල අවධාරනය කරයි.",
        "මෝදි රනිල්ට සුබ පතයි; ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට සහාය දෙන බව පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කම්කරුවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16,594 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD බිලියන 3.8 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரூ.3.4 பில்லியன் இந்திய உதவி இலங்கையை சென்றடைகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே இலங்கையைச் சுற்றி மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை கையளித்தார் ரூ. 26 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி பிசி மற்றும் சுகாதார மற்றும் நீர் வழங்கல் அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல ஆகியோருக்கு இந்திய மக்களால் 3.4 பில்லியன் நன்கொடை வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் மற்றும் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ் தலைவர் செந்தில் தொண்டமான் ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "16,594 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 200 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் சுமார் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய பெரிய மனிதாபிமான சரக்கு தமிழ்நாடு அரசால் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இது தமிழ்நாடு அரசாங்கத்தின் மூன்றாவது சரக்கு ஆகும், இது மொத்தம் 40,000 MT அரிசி, 500 MT பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 100 MT க்கும் அதிகமான மருந்துகளை நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியது, அதன் மொத்த மதிப்பு 22 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கும் அதிகமாகும். 25,000 டோஸ் ஆண்டி ரேபிஸ் தடுப்பூசி போன்ற முக்கியமான மருந்துகள் இந்த சப்ளைகளில் ஒரு பகுதியாக அமைந்தன.",
        "இந்த பொருட்கள் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தால் பயனாளிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படுகிறது மற்றும் 26 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று கையளிக்கப்பட்ட மனிதாபிமான பொருட்கள் எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் இலங்கையின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள பயனாளிகளை சென்றடையும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் பலதரப்பட்ட தேவைகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கு அவர்களுடன் இணைந்து இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் முயற்சிகளை இந்திய மக்கள் பூர்த்தி செய்து வருகின்றனர். இந்த நோக்கத்திற்காக, இலங்கையில் உள்ள பல்வேறு மருத்துவமனைகள், இந்திய சமூக அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் இலங்கையில் உள்ள பல நிறுவனங்களின் சுயாதீன முயற்சிகளால் இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தால் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்த ஆண்டில் 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேலான அபரிமிதமான மற்றும் பலதரப்பட்ட ஆதரவு பலப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. இலங்கையில் உள்ள தங்கள் சகோதரர்களுக்காக தாராளமாக நன்கொடை வழங்கிய இந்தியா.",
        "மக்களும் இந்திய அரசாங்கமும் இந்த நோக்கத்திற்காக ஒன்றிணைவது, இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான நிலையான மக்களிடையேயான தொடர்பையும் பரஸ்பர அக்கறையையும் பரஸ்பர அக்கறையையும் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "ரணிலுக்கு மோடி வாழ்த்து; இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியா ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று கூறினார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தொழிலாளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செந்தில் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16,594",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}