{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SLPP-Chairman-and-13-MPs-become-independent/56-739344",
  "time_ut": 1661976073,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP Chairman and 13 MPs become independent",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP Chairman and 13 MPs become independent",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prof. G.L Peiris announces decision to become independent during Parliamentary session",
        "Warns if social contract between people and MPs erode democratic way of life cannot be revived",
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) Chairman Prof. G.L. Peiris yesterday announced a group of MPs from the party has decided to sit with the Opposition in Parliament as an independent group. Accordingly, SLPP MPs Dullas Alahapperuma, Dilan Perera, Dr. Nalaka Godahewa, Prof. Charitha Herath, Prof. Channa Jayasumana, K.P.S. Kumarasiri, Dr. Gunapala Rathnasekara, Udayana Kirindigoda, Dr. Upul Galappatti, Dr. Thilak Rajapaksa, Wasantha Yapa, and Lalith Ellawala have now decided to cross over to the Opposition.",
        "Prof. G.L. Peiris made a special statement in Parliament on behalf of the group of MPs in Parliament yesterday.",
        "“Sri Lanka is facing a series of crises, including the economic, social, and political crises. This is nothing new to Sri Lanka. We have managed to face all including the civil conflict, the Tsunami, and the COVID-19 pandemic. But during these periods, Sri Lanka had the strength of a strong Parliament that represented the mandate of the people. Unfortunately, we do not have that strength today,” he told the house.",
        "The MP said there is a clear disparity between what the people want and the representation within the Parliament, adding that the promises and pledges made to the people back in 2020 ahead of the Parliamentary Elections, are not being fulfilled.",
        "“The SLPP supporters’ aspirations have been destroyed. The Government is doing the complete opposite of what it promised during the election campaign. The social contract between the people and their elected representatives is a core factor in Parliamentary democracy, and it is paramount that it must exist in Parliament. If that social contract is eroding or is destroyed, the democratic way of life cannot be revived,” he said.",
        "Peiris also said if the people want an election, that right must be ensured by calling for an election, adding that withholding that right in fear of defeat is unacceptable."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "13",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godahewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channa Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.P.S. Kumarasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunapala Rathnasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udayana Kirindigoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upul Galappatti",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilak Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Yapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalith Ellawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tsunami",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Elections",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති සහ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනෙකු ස්වාධීන වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසියේදී ස්වාධීන වීමේ තීරණය මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කරයි",
        "ජනතාව සහ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතර සමාජ ගිවිසුම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ජීවන රටාව ඛාදනය කළහොත් යළි පණ ගැන්විය නොහැකි බව අනතුරු අඟවයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විපක්ෂය සමඟ අසුන් ගැනීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව එම පක්ෂයේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා ඊයේ නිවේදනය කළේය. ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම, ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා, ආචාර්ය නාලක ගොඩහේවා, මහාචාර්ය චරිත හේරත්, මහාචාර්ය චන්න ජයසුමන, කේ.පී.එස්. කුමාරසිරි, වෛද්‍ය ගුණපාල රත්නසේකර, උදයන කිරිඳිගොඩ, වෛද්‍ය උපුල් ගලප්පත්ති, වෛද්‍ය තිලක් රාජපක්ෂ, වසන්ත යාපා, සහ ලලිත් එල්ලාවල දැන් විපක්ෂයට යාමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කළ මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආර්ථික, සමාජීය සහ දේශපාලන අර්බුද ඇතුළු අර්බුද රැසකට මුහුණ දී සිටී. මේක ලංකාවට අලුත් දෙයක් නෙවෙයි. සිවිල් ගැටුම, සුනාමිය සහ COVID-19 වසංගතය ඇතුළු සියල්ලට මුහුණ දීමට අපි සමත් වී සිටිමු. නමුත් මේ කාල සීමාවන් තුළ ජනවරම නියෝජනය කරන ශක්තිමත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක ශක්තිය ලංකාවට තිබුණා. අවාසනාවට අද අපිට ඒ ශක්තිය නැහැ.” ඔහු නිවසට කීවේය.",
        "ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය දේ සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නියෝජනය අතර පැහැදිලි විෂමතාවක් පවතින බව පැවසූ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා 2020 පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයට පෙර ජනතාවට ලබාදුන් පොරොන්දු හා ප්‍රතිඥාවන් ඉටු නොවන බවද පැවසීය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආධාරකරුවන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් විනාශ වී ඇත. ආණ්ඩුව මැතිවරණ ව්‍යාපාරයේ දී පොරොන්දු වූ දේට සම්පූර්ණයෙන් පටහැනිව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී. මහජනතාව සහ ඔවුන්ගේ තේරී පත් වූ නියෝජිතයන් අතර ඇති සමාජ ගිවිසුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයේ ප්‍රධාන සාධකයක් වන අතර එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ පැවතිය යුතු බව අතිශයින් වැදගත් වේ. එම සමාජ කොන්ත්‍රාත්තුව ඛාදනය වුවහොත් හෝ විනාශ වුවහොත් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ජීවන රටාව යළි පණ ගැන්විය නොහැක.",
        "ජනතාවට මැතිවරණයක් අවශ්‍ය නම් මැතිවරණයක් කැඳවීමෙන් එම අයිතිය තහවුරු කළ යුතු බව පැවසූ පීරිස්, පරාජයට බියෙන් එම අයිතිය අත්හිටුවීම පිළිගත නොහැකි බවද කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "13",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්න ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.පී.එස්. කුමාරසිරි ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණපාල රත්නසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදයන කිරිඳිගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපුල් ගලප්පත්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිලක් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත යාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලලිත් එල්ලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනාමිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLPP தலைவர் மற்றும் 13 எம்.பி.க்கள் சுயேச்சை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வின் போது பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ் சுயாதீனமாக மாறுவதற்கான தீர்மானத்தை அறிவித்தார்",
        "மக்களுக்கும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் இடையிலான சமூக ஒப்பந்தம் ஜனநாயக வாழ்க்கை முறையை சிதைத்தால் மீண்டும் உயிர்ப்பிக்க முடியாது என்று எச்சரிக்கிறது",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சியுடன் இணைந்து சுயேச்சைக் குழுவாக அமரத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அதன் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் நேற்று அறிவித்தார். அதன்படி, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, டிலான் பெரேரா, கலாநிதி நாலக கொடஹேவா, பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத், பேராசிரியர் சன்ன ஜயசுமன, கே.பி.எஸ். குமாரசிறி, கலாநிதி குணபால ரத்னசேகர, உதயன கிரிந்திகொட, கலாநிதி உபுல் கலப்பட்டி, கலாநிதி திலக் ராஜபக்ஷ, வசந்த யாப்பா, லலித் எல்லாவல ஆகியோர் தற்போது எதிர்க்கட்சியில் அமரத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழு சார்பில் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை விடுத்தார்.",
        "“பொருளாதார, சமூக மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடிகள் உட்பட தொடர்ச்சியான நெருக்கடிகளை இலங்கை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது. இது இலங்கைக்கு புதிதல்ல. உள்நாட்டு மோதல்கள், சுனாமி மற்றும் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் உட்பட அனைத்தையும் நாங்கள் சமாளித்துவிட்டோம். ஆனால் இந்தக் காலகட்டங்களில், மக்களின் ஆணையைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பலமான பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பலம் இலங்கைக்கு இருந்தது. துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, இன்று எங்களுக்கு அந்த வலிமை இல்லை, ”என்று அவர் வீட்டில் கூறினார்.",
        "மக்கள் விரும்புவதற்கும் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பிரதிநிதித்துவத்திற்கும் இடையில் தெளிவான வேறுபாடு காணப்படுவதாகவும், 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டு பாராளுமன்றத் தேர்தலுக்கு முன்னர் மக்களுக்கு வழங்கிய வாக்குறுதிகள் மற்றும் உறுதிமொழிகள் நிறைவேற்றப்படவில்லை என்றும் எம்.பி.",
        "“SLPP ஆதரவாளர்களின் அபிலாஷைகள் அழிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. தேர்தல் பிரசாரத்தின் போது வாக்குறுதி அளித்ததற்கு முற்றிலும் மாறாக அரசு செயல்படுகிறது. பாராளுமன்ற ஜனநாயகத்தில் மக்களுக்கும் அவர்களால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் இடையிலான சமூக ஒப்பந்தம் ஒரு முக்கிய காரணியாகும், மேலும் அது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டியது மிக முக்கியமானது. அந்தச் சமூக ஒப்பந்தம் அழிந்துகொண்டாலோ அல்லது அழிக்கப்பட்டாலோ, ஜனநாயக வாழ்க்கை முறையை மீட்டெடுக்க முடியாது,” என்றார்.",
        "மக்கள் தேர்தலை விரும்பினால், அந்த உரிமையை தேர்தலுக்கு அழைப்பதன் மூலம் உறுதிப்படுத்த வேண்டும் என்றும் கூறிய பீரிஸ், தோல்விக்கு பயந்து அந்த உரிமையை தடுப்பதை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாது என்றும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "13",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ன ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.பி.எஸ். குமாரசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணபால ரத்னசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதயன கிரிந்திகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உப்புல் கலப்பட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலக் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த யாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லலித் எல்லாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனாமி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}