{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/UK-Parliament-discusses-Sri-Lankas-Samurdhi-programme/108-240095",
  "time_ut": 1656561373,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UK Parliament discusses Sri Lanka’s Samurdhi programme",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UK Parliament discusses Sri Lanka’s Samurdhi programme",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Britain on Tuesday said that the existing social protection systems, including the Samurdhi programme, provide essential support to the most vulnerable communities in Sri Lanka and will be crucial at this difficult time.",
        "In response to a question by Conservative MP that what recent assessment that the State for Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Affairs has made of the effectiveness of the Samurdhi programme in Sri Lanka, Parliamentary Under-Secretary (Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office) Vicky Ford said that “The Sri Lankan authorities have taken a number of measures to help support the public, including an economic relief package of Rs. 200bn ($1bn) announced in January 2022.”",
        "“The UK recognises the economic challenges that Sri Lanka is facing. We continue to monitor the economic situation in Sri Lanka closely, including the impact economic issues are having on food security and livelihoods,” she said in a written answer to UK Parliament",
        "“This package includes a Rs. 5000 ($25) monthly allowance for public sector employees, pensioners and disabled soldiers. Under the scheme, Rs. 1000 ($5) has been allocated to the beneficiaries of the government's largest welfare programme 'Samurdhi', and a number of taxes and levies have been removed from essential foods and medicines. The Government of Sri Lanka agreed on May 2 to provide a special three-month cash allowance from May to July worth Rs. 13.36 billion to 3.34 million families affected by the current economic crisis, with funding from the World Bank of which the UK is a major donor.",
        "“We regularly discuss economic policy with the Sri Lankan Government and encourage efforts to improve economic growth and protect vital economic interests such as key industries, commodities, employment and livelihoods,” she added.",
        "In response to a question that the human development and social economic indicators of Sri Lanka in comparison to other South East Asian countries, Ms Ford “We continue to encourage a peaceful, democratic, and inclusive approach to resolving the current political and economic challenges.”",
        "She said that the most recent available data (2020) for Sri Lanka indicates that it performs well against South Asia neighbours on high-level human development and social economic indicators, particularly infant mortality rates.",
        "“However, the available data does not capture the severity of the current economic crisis and impact of recent economic shocks such as Covid-19, the Russia-Ukraine crisis, the floating of the Sri Lankan Rupee (LKR) and Sri Lanka's debt default in May 2022. We have not made a recent assessment comparing Sri Lankan indicators to those in South East Asian countries,” she added. (Sunil Jayasiri)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s Samurdhi",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samurdhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the State for Foreign",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth and Development Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samurdhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth and Development Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vicky Ford",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1bn",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May to July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13.36 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.34 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South East Asian",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ms Ford",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Rupee",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South East Asian",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Jayasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමෘද්ධි වැඩසටහන ගැන සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සමෘද්ධි වැඩසටහන ඇතුළු දැනට පවතින සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ ක්‍රම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත් අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ප්‍රජාවන්ට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සහය ලබා දෙන බවත් මෙම දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවේ එය තීරණාත්මක වනු ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමෘද්ධි වැඩසටහනේ සඵලතාවය පිළිබඳව විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කටයුතු පිළිබඳ රාජ්‍යය විසින් සිදු කර ඇති මෑතකාලීන තක්සේරුව කුමක් දැයි කොන්සර්වේටිව් මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු උප ලේකම් (විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය) විකී ෆෝඩ් පැවසීය. \"ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් මහජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා රු. 100 ක ආර්ථික සහන පැකේජයක් ඇතුළුව පියවර ගණනාවක් ගෙන ඇත. බිලියන 200 (ඩොලර් බිලියන 1) 2022 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දෙන ආර්ථික අභියෝග එක්සත් රාජධානිය පිළිගන්නවා. ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව සහ ජීවනෝපායන් කෙරෙහි ආර්ථික ගැටලු ඇති කරන බලපෑම ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය අපි සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටිමු.",
        "“මෙම පැකේජයට රු. රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයින්, විශ්‍රාමිකයින් සහ ආබාධිත සොල්දාදුවන් සඳහා රුපියල් 5000 ($25) මාසික දීමනාව. යෝජනා ක්රමය යටතේ රු. රජයේ විශාලතම සුබසාධන වැඩසටහන වන ‘සමෘද්ධි’ වැඩසටහනේ ප්‍රතිලාභීන්ට රුපියල් 1000ක් ($5) වෙන් කර ඇති අතර අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ආහාර සහ ඖෂධවලින් බදු සහ අයකිරීම් රැසක් ඉවත් කර ඇත. මැයි සිට ජූලි දක්වා මාස තුනක විශේෂ මුදල් දීමනාවක් ලබාදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය මැයි 2 වැනිදා එකඟ වූ අතර රු. එක්සත් රාජධානිය ප්‍රධාන පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන් වන ලෝක බැංකුවේ අරමුදල් සමඟ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් පවුල් මිලියන 13.36 සිට මිලියන 3.34 දක්වා.",
        "\"අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සමඟ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්ති පිළිබඳව නිතිපතා සාකච්ඡා කරන අතර ආර්ථික වර්ධනය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට සහ ප්‍රධාන කර්මාන්ත, වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ, රැකියා සහ ජීවනෝපාය වැනි අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට දරන ප්‍රයත්නයන් දිරිමත් කරන්නෙමු,\" ඇය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසුවාය.",
        "අනෙකුත් අග්නිදිග ආසියාතික රටවලට සාපේක්ෂව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව සංවර්ධන සහ සමාජ ආර්ථික දර්ශක යන ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් Ford මහත්මිය, “වර්තමාන දේශපාලන සහ ආර්ථික අභියෝග විසඳීම සඳහා සාමකාමී, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සහ සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් ප්‍රවේශයක් අපි දිගටම දිරිමත් කරනවා.”",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා දැනට පවතින නවතම දත්ත (2020) පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ එය ඉහළ මට්ටමේ මානව සංවර්ධන සහ සමාජ ආර්ථික දර්ශක, විශේෂයෙන්ම ළදරු මරණ අනුපාත සම්බන්ධයෙන් දකුණු ආසියාවේ අසල්වැසියන්ට එරෙහිව හොඳින් ක්‍රියා කරන බව ය.",
        "“කෙසේ වෙතත්, පවතින දත්ත මගින් වර්තමාන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ බරපතලකම සහ Covid-19, රුසියාව-යුක්රේන අර්බුදය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියලේ පාවෙන (LKR) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය පැහැර හැරීම වැනි මෑතකාලීන ආර්ථික කම්පනවල බලපෑම ග්‍රහණය කර නොගනී. 2022 මැයි. අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දර්ශක අග්නිදිග ආසියාතික රටවල ඇති දර්ශක සමඟ සංසන්දනය කරමින් මෑතකාලීන තක්සේරුවක් කර නැත. (සුනිල් ජයසිරි)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමෘද්ධිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමෘද්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ සඳහා රාජ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය හා සංවර්ධන කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමෘද්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය හා සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකී ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි සිට ජූලි දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 13.36 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.34 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෝඩ් මහත්මිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් ජයසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் சமுர்த்தி திட்டம் பற்றி இங்கிலாந்து பாராளுமன்றம் விவாதிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமுர்த்தி திட்டம் உட்பட தற்போதுள்ள சமூக பாதுகாப்பு அமைப்புகள் இலங்கையில் மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய சமூகங்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய ஆதரவை வழங்குவதாகவும், இந்த கடினமான நேரத்தில் இது முக்கியமானதாக இருக்கும் என்றும் பிரிட்டன் செவ்வாய்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் சமுர்த்தி வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் செயல்திறன் குறித்து வெளிவிவகார, பொதுநலவாய மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான அரசு என்ன சமீபத்திய மதிப்பீடு செய்துள்ளது என்று கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் எம்.பி.யின் கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த நாடாளுமன்ற துணைச் செயலாளர் (வெளிநாட்டு, பொதுநலவாய மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி அலுவலகம்) விக்கி ஃபோர்ட் கூறினார். \"இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் பொது மக்களுக்கு உதவ பல நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளனர், இதில் ரூ. பொருளாதார நிவாரணப் பொதி உட்பட. 200 பில்லியன் ($1 பில்லியன்) ஜனவரி 2022 இல் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "“இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பொருளாதார சவால்களை இங்கிலாந்து அங்கீகரிக்கிறது. உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வாழ்வாதாரத்தில் பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகள் ஏற்படுத்தும் தாக்கம் உட்பட இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நிலைமையை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து உன்னிப்பாகக் கண்காணித்து வருகிறோம், ”என்று அவர் இங்கிலாந்து பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு எழுத்துப்பூர்வமாக பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "“இந்த தொகுப்பில் ரூ. பொதுத்துறை ஊழியர்கள், ஓய்வூதியம் பெறுவோர் மற்றும் ஊனமுற்ற வீரர்களுக்கு 5000 ($25) மாதாந்திர கொடுப்பனவு. இத்திட்டத்தின் கீழ் ரூ. அரசாங்கத்தின் மிகப் பெரிய நலத்திட்டமான 'சமூர்த்தி'யின் பயனாளிகளுக்கு 1000 ($5) ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் அத்தியாவசிய உணவுகள் மற்றும் மருந்துகளில் இருந்து பல வரிகள் மற்றும் வரிகள் நீக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மே மாதம் முதல் ஜூலை மாதம் வரையிலான மூன்று மாத சிறப்பு பண கொடுப்பனவை வழங்குவதற்கு மே 2 அன்று ஒப்புக்கொண்டது. 13.36 பில்லியன் முதல் 3.34 மில்லியன் குடும்பங்கள் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, உலக வங்கியின் நிதியுதவியுடன், பிரிட்டன் ஒரு பெரிய நன்கொடை அளிக்கிறது.",
        "\"நாங்கள் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்துடன் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கை பற்றி தொடர்ந்து கலந்துரையாடுகிறோம் மற்றும் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான முயற்சிகளை ஊக்குவிக்கிறோம் மற்றும் முக்கிய தொழில்கள், பொருட்கள், வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் வாழ்வாதாரங்கள் போன்ற முக்கிய பொருளாதார நலன்களைப் பாதுகாப்போம்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஏனைய தென்கிழக்காசிய நாடுகளுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் இலங்கையின் மனித அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் சமூகப் பொருளாதாரக் குறிகாட்டிகள், தற்போதைய அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார சவால்களைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு அமைதியான, ஜனநாயக மற்றும் உள்ளடக்கிய அணுகுமுறையை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து ஊக்குவித்து வருகிறோம் என்ற கேள்விக்கு திருமதி ஃபோர்ட் பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான மிக சமீபத்திய தரவுகள் (2020) தெற்காசியாவின் அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு எதிராக உயர்மட்ட மனித மேம்பாடு மற்றும் சமூக பொருளாதார குறிகாட்டிகள், குறிப்பாக குழந்தை இறப்பு விகிதங்கள் ஆகியவற்றில் சிறப்பாக செயல்படுவதைக் குறிக்கிறது என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "“எனினும், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் தீவிரம் மற்றும் கொவிட்-19, ரஷ்யா-உக்ரைன் நெருக்கடி, இலங்கை ரூபாயின் மிதப்பு (LKR) மற்றும் இலங்கையின் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாதது போன்ற சமீபத்திய பொருளாதார அதிர்ச்சிகளின் தாக்கம் ஆகியவை கிடைக்கக்கூடிய தரவுகளால் பிடிக்கப்படவில்லை. மே 2022. இலங்கையின் குறிகாட்டிகளை தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய நாடுகளில் உள்ள குறிகாட்டிகளுடன் ஒப்பிடும் ஒரு சமீபத்திய மதிப்பீட்டை நாங்கள் செய்யவில்லை,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (சுனில் ஜெயசிறி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இங்கிலாந்து பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின் சமுர்த்தி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமுர்த்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டிற்கான மாநிலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமுர்த்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கி ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே முதல் ஜூலை வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13.36 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.34 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கிழக்கு ஆசியர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருமதி ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபாய்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கிழக்கு ஆசியர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் ஜயசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}