{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/03/sri-lanka-update-on-fuel-shipments/",
  "time_ut": 1656841080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka : Update on Fuel Shipments",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka : Update on Fuel Shipments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Minister of Power and Energy, Kanchana Wijesekera stated that two diesel ships will arrive in the island within the first two weeks of this month.",
        "Accordingly, two tankers with diesel shipments will reach Sri Lanka on 8th or 9th July and on 11th or 14th July.",
        "The minister also mentioned that a LIOC ship carrying petrol will arrive in Sri Lanka on the 22nd or 23rd July, which has already been paid for, while a third diesel shipment will arrive in the country on 15th – 17th July, upon advance payment.",
        "However, the Minister said that discussions have been initiated with Malaysia to obtain a Petrol shipment on or near 10th of July, and three new importers have been informed in this regard.",
        "Moreover, Minister Wijesekara added that the Government has also discussed with the Malaysian oil company ‘Petronas’ to supply the necessary crude oil required for Sri Lanka, and the Malaysian Government had responded positively.",
        "Minister, in a tweet said that the CPC is still awaiting confirmation of shipments upon advance payment, for 1 diesel shipment and 2 petrol shipments from LIOC, while LIOC has so far confirmed three cargo arrivals on 13-14th July, 30-31st July and 10-15th Aug, carrying both Petrol and diesel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first two weeks of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th or 9th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd or 23rd July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th – 17th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Malaysian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-31st July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-15th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් පිළිබඳ යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ මස මුල් සති දෙක තුළ ඩීසල් නෞකා දෙකක් දිවයිනට පැමිණෙන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් සහිත ටැංකි දෙකක් ජූලි 8 හෝ 9 සහ ජූලි 11 හෝ 14 යන දිනවල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ළඟා වනු ඇත.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් රැගත් LIOC නෞකාවක් දැනටමත් ගෙවා අවසන් ජූලි 22 හෝ 23 දිනවල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බවත්, අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීම මත තෙවැනි ඩීසල් තොගය ජූලි 15 - 17 දිනවල මෙරටට පැමිණෙන බවත් ඇමැතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජූලි මස 10 වැනි දින හෝ ඊට ආසන්න දිනකදී පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් ලබාගැනීම සඳහා මැලේසියාව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඇති බවත්, ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අලුතින් ආනයනය කරන්නන් තිදෙනෙකු දැනුවත් කර ඇති බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය බොරතෙල් සැපයීම සඳහා රජය මැලේසියානු තෙල් සමාගමක් වන ‘පෙට්‍රෝනාස්’ සමඟ ද සාකච්ඡා කර ඇති බවත්, මැලේසියානු රජය ඊට ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක් දක්වා ඇති බවත් අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "LIOC වෙතින් ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් 1 ක් සහ පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් 2 ක් සඳහා අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීමෙන් පසු නැව්ගත කිරීම් තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා CPC තවමත් බලා සිටින බව අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. 10-15 අගෝස්තු, පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් දෙකම රැගෙන."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ මුල් සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 8 හෝ 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22 හෝ 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15 - 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 30-31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி குறித்த புதுப்பிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இம்மாதம் முதல் இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் இரண்டு டீசல் கப்பல்கள் நாட்டை வந்தடையவுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி, டீசல் ஏற்றுமதியுடன் கூடிய இரண்டு டேங்கர் கப்பல்கள் ஜூலை 8 அல்லது 9 ஆம் தேதிகளிலும், ஜூலை 11 அல்லது 14 ஆம் தேதிகளிலும் இலங்கையை வந்தடையும்.",
        "பெற்றோலை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் LIOC கப்பலானது ஜூலை 22 அல்லது 23 ஆம் திகதிகளில் இலங்கைக்கு வரும் என்றும், அது ஏற்கனவே செலுத்தப்பட்டதாகவும், மூன்றாவது டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி ஜூலை 15 - 17 ஆம் திகதிகளில் முன்பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டதன் அடிப்படையில் நாட்டிற்கு வரும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜூலை 10 அல்லது அதற்கு அருகில் பெற்றோல் ஏற்றுமதியைப் பெறுவதற்கு மலேசியாவுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், இது தொடர்பாக மூன்று புதிய இறக்குமதியாளர்களுக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், இலங்கைக்குத் தேவையான கச்சா எண்ணெயை வழங்குவதற்கு மலேசிய எண்ணெய் நிறுவனமான ‘பெட்ரோனாஸ்’ நிறுவனத்துடனும் அரசாங்கம் கலந்துரையாடியதாகவும், அதற்கு மலேசிய அரசாங்கம் சாதகமாக பதிலளித்ததாகவும் அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமைச்சர், ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் CPC இன்னும் 1 டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் LIOC இலிருந்து 2 பெட்ரோல் ஷிப்மென்ட்களுக்கு முன்கூட்டியே பணம் செலுத்தியதன் மூலம் ஏற்றுமதிகளை உறுதிப்படுத்த காத்திருக்கிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் LIOC இதுவரை மூன்று சரக்கு வருகைகளை ஜூலை 13-14,  ஜூலை 30-31 மற்றும் 10-15 ஆகஸ்ட், பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசல் இரண்டையும் கொண்டு செல்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதத்தின் முதல் இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 8 அல்லது 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 அல்லது 23 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 - 17 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசிய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-31 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10-15 வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}