{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/columns/Sri-Lanka-s-list-of-designated-persons-and-organisations-violative-of-UN-Security-Council-resolution-2253-of-2015/4-739146",
  "time_ut": 1661537824,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s list of designated persons and organisations violative of UN Security Council resolution 2253 of 2015",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s list of designated persons and organisations violative of UN Security Council resolution 2253 of 2015",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is time that the President and his Government do not permit unacceptable and unauthorised procedures being adopted to marginalise and ostracise minority community institutions and individuals under cover of national security – Pic by Shehan Gunasekara",
        "While welcoming President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s statement at the recent annual conference of the Organisation of Professional Associations (OPA) on the need to “sort out the problems among the ethnic groups, as this has gone on for too long, as the war was over in 2009 and there is no need to fight again”, it is time that the President and his Government do not permit unacceptable and unauthorised procedures being adopted to marginalise and ostracise minority community institutions and individuals under cover of national security as we fear certain measures being unlawfully pursued will enhance radicalisation and counter radicalisation in the country leading to conflicts.",
        "At this time of dire economic crisis confronting the country attributed by some, to the ‘curse of all religious groups’, the urgent need is the unity of all the communities as well as the economic support of all countries!",
        "But why is the Foreign Ministry through its competent authority misusing, in its 1 August 2022 listing, the UN Security Council (SC) resolutions 1267 of 1999 and eight related subsequent SC resolutions including resolution 2253 of 2015, the last in the series as quoted by the Sri Lankan authorities? The clear purpose of the Security Council resolutions was to control funding the terrorist entities, originally the then Taliban and later the Al Qaida and the Islamic State of Iraq and Levant (ISIL). How can the 6 Sri Lankan organisations and 156 Sri Lankans be accused of funding any foreign terrorist entities or being associates of Al Qaida or ISIL?",
        "Surely the Foreign Ministry has no proof that any one of these Sri Lankan entities or persons had funded the Taliban, the Al Qaida or the ISIL at any time, even though these entities, as originally resolved by the Security Council, had ceased to exist!",
        "UN Security Council resolution 2253 of 2015 has unequivocally identified the target group of the resolution, in section 2 as the ‘ISIL’, ‘Al Qaida’ and associated individuals, groups, undertakings and entities’. The listing criteria are set out in section 3 and are far beyond any fisherman’s hook! Is it the position of the Sri Lankan Foreign Ministry that the 6 plus 156 Sri Lankan Muslim organisations and persons are associates of terror outfits, ISIL or AL Qaida, thereby exposing Sri Lanka wrongfully for actions including sanctions and damage claims by individuals, countries or the international community?",
        "Then DIG of the CID Ravi Seneviratne gave evidence before the Parliamentary Select Committee that probed Easter Sunday attacks of 21/04/2019 that there was no evidence of any links between Sri Lanka’s Easter Sunday suicide bombers and the ISIL or the Al Qaida. The Defence Ministry has on a number of instances refuted foreign media allegations and assumptions attempting such links with foreign terror outfits. The Catholic Church has time and again pointed to elements seeking to net in the ISIS to take responsibility for the Easter attacks, for days after 21/04. The attempt was to show a non-existing link.",
        "The 1 August 2022 listing of designated persons purportedly under Article 41 of the UN Charter is invalid and of no force or avail in law for several other reasons as well, including that Article 41 is entirely for the extraordinary UN objective of preventing wars and conflicts between nations and not to harass, humiliate or terrorise persons and organisations totally unconnected to ISIL or Al Qaida as defined in paragraph numbered 2 and the listing criteria in paragraph 3 of the Security Council resolution 2253 of 2015, not renewed thereafter because the two anti-Islamic entities have been killed and cremated.",
        "In addition, several provisions in the gazetted regulations are violative of international laws, the provisions of the Constitution of Sri Lanka and Security Council resolution 2253 of 2015. The violations may become issues in the International Court of Justice in Hague, the UN Human Rights Council in Geneva and the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka in Colombo, unless the listing of Muslim organisations and individuals are promptly reviewed and cancelled."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UN Security Council",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shehan Gunasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Organisation of Professional Associations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1267",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "resolution 2253 of 2015",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taliban",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Al Qaida",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Islamic State of Iraq",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Levant",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "156",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Al Qaida",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taliban",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Al Qaida",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2253 of 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 2 as the ‘ISIL’, ‘Al Qaida’",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 3",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "156",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AL Qaida",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Select Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter Sunday",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/04/2019",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter Sunday",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Al Qaida",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Catholic Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 1 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 41 of the UN Charter",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 41",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISIL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Al Qaida",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "anti-Islamic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Court of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hague",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2015 එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ 2253 යෝජනාව උල්ලංඝනය කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නම් කරන ලද පුද්ගලයින් සහ සංවිධාන ලැයිස්තුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාවට මුවා වී සුළුතර ප්‍රජා ආයතන සහ පුද්ගලයන් කොන් කිරීමට සහ කොන් කිරීමට පිළිගත නොහැකි සහ අනවසර ක්‍රියා පටිපාටි අනුගමනය කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ඔහුගේ රජය ඉඩ නොතැබිය යුතු කාලයයි - ෂෙහාන් ගුණසේකරගේ ඡායාරූපය",
        "2009 යුද්ධය අවසන් වූ බැවින් වාර්ගික කණ්ඩායම් අතර පවතින ගැටලු නිරාකරණය කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය පිළිබඳව පසුගියදා පැවති වෘත්තීය සමිති එකමුතුවේ (OPA) වාර්ෂික සමුළුවේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කළ ප්‍රකාශය පිළිගනිමින්. සහ නැවත සටන් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නැත”, ඇතැම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ග නීති විරෝධී ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ යැයි අප බිය වන බැවින් ජාතික ආරක්ෂාවට මුවා වී සුළුතර ප්‍රජා ආයතන සහ පුද්ගලයන් කොන් කිරීමට සහ කොන් කිරීමට පිළිගත නොහැකි සහ අනවසර ක්‍රියා පටිපාටි අනුගමනය කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ඔහුගේ රජය ඉඩ නොතැබිය යුතු කාලය මෙයයි රට තුළ රැඩිකල්කරණය වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සහ ගැටුම්වලට තුඩු දෙන රැඩිකල්කරණයට එරෙහිව කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "‘සියලු ආගමික කණ්ඩායම්වල ශාපය’ යැයි ඇතැමුන් විසින් ආරෝපණය කරන ලද දරුණු ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් රට මුහුණ දී ඇති මේ මොහොතේ හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාව වන්නේ සියලු ජන කොටස්වල එකමුතුකම මෙන්ම සියලු රටවල ආර්ථික සහයෝගයයි!",
        "නමුත් විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය එහි නිසි බලධාරියා හරහා 2022 අගෝස්තු 1 ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීමේදී, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ (SC) 1999 1267 යෝජනා සහ 2015 2253 යෝජනාව ඇතුළු ඊට අදාළ පසුකාලීන SC යෝජනා අටක් අනිසි ලෙස භාවිතා කරන්නේ ඇයි? ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන්? ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ යෝජනාවල පැහැදිලි අරමුණ වූයේ ත්‍රස්තවාදී ආයතනවලට අරමුදල් සැපයීම පාලනය කිරීමයි, මුලින් එවකට තලේබාන් සහ පසුව අල් කයිඩා සහ ඉරාක සහ ලෙවන්ට් ඉස්ලාමීය රාජ්‍යය (ISIL). කිසියම් විදේශීය ත්‍රස්තවාදී ආයතනයකට අරමුදල් සැපයූ බවට හෝ අල් කයිඩා හෝ අයිඑස්අයිඑල් හි හවුල්කරුවන් බවට ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සංවිධාන 6 සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් 156ට චෝදනා එල්ල වන්නේ කෙසේද?",
        "ආරක්‍ෂක කවුන්සිලය විසින් මුලින් විසඳන ලද පරිදි මෙම ආයතන නොපවතින නමුත්, මෙම කිසිදු ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ආයතනයක් හෝ පුද්ගලයන් ඕනෑම අවස්ථාවක තලේබාන්, අල් කයිඩා හෝ අයිඑස්අයිඑල් සංවිධානයට අරමුදල් සපයා ඇති බවට විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයට සාක්ෂි නැත!",
        "2015 එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ 2253 යෝජනාව මගින් යෝජනාවේ ඉලක්ක කණ්ඩායම 2 වන වගන්තියේ 'ISIL', 'Al Qaida' සහ ආශ්‍රිත පුද්ගලයින්, කණ්ඩායම්, ව්‍යාපාර සහ ආයතන' ලෙස අවිවාදයෙන් හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීමේ නිර්ණායක 3 වන කොටසේ දක්වා ඇති අතර ඒවා ඕනෑම ධීවරයෙකුගේ කොක්කෙන් ඔබ්බට ය! 6 ප්ලස් 156 ශ්‍රී ලාංකික මුස්ලිම් සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයින් ISIL හෝ AL Qaida ත්‍රස්තවාදී සංවිධානවල සහකරුවන් වන අතර එමඟින් පුද්ගලයන්, රටවල් හෝ රටවල් විසින් සම්බාධක සහ හානි හිමිකම් ඇතුළු ක්‍රියාවන් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැරදි ලෙස හෙළිදරව් කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ස්ථාවරයද? ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව?",
        "අනතුරුව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති රවී සෙනෙවිරත්න 2019/04/21 පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාව හමුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාස්කු ඉරිදා මරාගෙන මැරෙන බෝම්බකරුවන් සහ ISIL හෝ අල්කයිඩා අතර කිසිදු සම්බන්ධයක් නොමැති බවට සාක්ෂි ලබා දුන්නේය. විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය චෝදනා සහ විදේශ ත්‍රස්තවාදී සංවිධාන සමඟ එවැනි සබඳතා පැවැත්වීමට උත්සාහ කරන බවට එල්ල වන උපකල්පන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් අවස්ථා ගණනාවකදීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇත. කතෝලික පල්ලිය 21/04 න් පසු දින කිහිපයක් පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරයේ වගකීම භාර ගැනීම සඳහා ISIS තුළ දැල්වීමට උත්සාහ කරන කොටස් වෙත නැවත නැවතත් පෙන්වා දී ඇත. නොපවතින සබැඳියක් පෙන්වීමට උත්සාහ කරන ලදී.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ප්‍රඥප්තියේ 41 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ යැයි කියනු ලබන 2022 අගෝස්තු 1 වැනි දින නම් කරන ලද පුද්ගලයන් ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීම වලංගු නොවන අතර තවත් හේතු කිහිපයක් නිසා බලහත්කාරයෙන් හෝ නීතියෙන් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් නොලැබේ, 41 වැනි වගන්තිය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය අතර යුද්ධ සහ ගැටුම් වැලැක්වීමේ අසාමාන්‍ය අරමුණ සඳහා වේ. ජාතීන් සහ 2015 ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලයේ 2253 යෝජනාවේ 3 වැනි ඡේදයේ සහ ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීමේ නිර්ණායක අංක 2 හි නිර්වචනය කර ඇති පරිදි ISIL හෝ Al Qaida වෙත සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම සම්බන්ධ නොවූ පුද්ගලයින් සහ සංවිධානවලට හිරිහැර කිරීම, අවමන් කිරීම හෝ ත්‍රස්ත කිරීම නොකිරීමට, ඉස්ලාම් විරෝධී දෙක නිසා ඉන් පසුව අලුත් කර නැත. ආයතන ඝාතනය කර ආදාහනය කර ඇත.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ගැසට් කරන ලද රෙගුලාසි වල විධිවිධාන කිහිපයක් ජාත්‍යන්තර නීති, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධාන සහ 2015 ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ 2253 යෝජනාව උල්ලංඝනය කරයි. උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් හේග්හි ජාත්‍යන්තර අධිකරණයේ, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ ගැටළු බවට පත්විය හැකිය. ජිනීවාහි සහ කොළඹ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවේදී, මුස්ලිම් සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයන්ගේ ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීම කඩිනමින් සමාලෝචනය කර අවලංගු නොකළහොත් මිස."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහාන් ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෘත්තීය සංගම් සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 අගෝස්තු 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1267",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 2253 යෝජනාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලේබාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් කයිඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාකයේ ඉස්ලාමීය රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙවන්ට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "156",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් කයිඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.එස්.අයි.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලේබාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් කයිඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.එස්.අයි.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 2253",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 කොටස 'ISIL', 'Al Qaida' ලෙස",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 කොටස",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "156",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.එස්.අයි.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AL කයිඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/04/2019",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.එස්.අයි.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් කයිඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.එස්.අයි.එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ප්‍රඥප්තියේ 41 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "41 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.එස්.අයි.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් කයිඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාම් විරෝධී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේග්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2015 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானம் 2253 ஐ மீறும் இலங்கையின் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நபர்கள் மற்றும் அமைப்புகளின் பட்டியல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பின் கீழ் சிறுபான்மை சமூக நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களை ஓரங்கட்டுவதற்கும் ஒதுக்கி வைப்பதற்கும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாத மற்றும் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாத நடைமுறைகளை ஜனாதிபதியும் அவரது அரசாங்கமும் அனுமதிக்காத நேரமிது - புகைப்படம் ஷெஹான் குணசேகர",
        "கடந்த 2009ஆம் ஆண்டு யுத்தம் முடிவடைந்த நிலையில், இனக்குழுக்கள் மத்தியில் நிலவும் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்த்து வைப்பதன் அவசியம் குறித்து ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற வருடாந்த மாநாட்டில் தெரிவித்த கருத்தை வரவேற்றார். மேலும் மீண்டும் போராட வேண்டிய அவசியம் இல்லை”, சில நடவடிக்கைகள் சட்ட விரோதமாக பின்பற்றப்படும் என்று நாங்கள் அஞ்சுவதால், சிறுபான்மை சமூக நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களை சிறுபான்மை சமூக நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களை ஓரங்கட்டுவதற்கும் ஒதுக்கி வைப்பதற்கும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாத மற்றும் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாத நடைமுறைகளை ஜனாதிபதியும் அவரது அரசாங்கமும் அனுமதிக்காத நேரம் இது. நாட்டில் தீவிரமயமாக்கலை மேம்படுத்தி, மோதல்களுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும் தீவிரவாதத்தை எதிர்க்கும்.",
        "‘அனைத்து மதக் குழுக்களின் சாபமும்’ என்று சிலர் கூறும் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் இந்த நேரத்தில், அவசரத் தேவை அனைத்து சமூகங்களின் ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் அனைத்து நாடுகளின் பொருளாதார ஆதரவும்!",
        "ஆனால் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் அதன் தகுதிவாய்ந்த அதிகாரத்தின் மூலம் ஏன் தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது, அதன் 1 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 பட்டியலில், UN பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் (SC) 1999 இன் 1267 தீர்மானங்களையும், 2015 இன் 2253 தீர்மானம் உட்பட எட்டு தொடர்புடைய அடுத்தடுத்த SC தீர்மானங்களையும் மேற்கோள் காட்டியது. இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளா? பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானங்களின் தெளிவான நோக்கம் பயங்கரவாத அமைப்புகளுக்கு நிதியளிப்பதைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதாகும், முதலில் அப்போதைய தலிபான் மற்றும் பின்னர் அல்கொய்தா மற்றும் இஸ்லாமிய அரசு ஈராக் மற்றும் லெவன்ட் (ISIL). 6 இலங்கை அமைப்புகளும் 156 இலங்கையர்களும் எந்தவொரு வெளிநாட்டு பயங்கரவாத நிறுவனங்களுக்கும் நிதியுதவி செய்ததாக அல்லது அல்கொய்தா அல்லது ISIL இன் கூட்டாளிகளாக இருந்ததாக எப்படி குற்றம் சாட்ட முடியும்?",
        "தலிபான், அல்கொய்தா அல்லது ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எல் ஆகிய அமைப்புகளுக்கு எந்த நேரத்திலும் இலங்கையின் எந்தவொரு அமைப்பும் அல்லது நபர்களும் நிதியளித்தனர் என்பதற்கு நிச்சயமாக வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்திடம் ஆதாரம் இல்லை.",
        "ஐ.நா. பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானம் 2015 இன் 2253 தீர்மானத்தின் இலக்கு குழுவை, பிரிவு 2 இல் 'ISIL', 'Al Qaida' மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய நபர்கள், குழுக்கள், நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவனங்கள்' என சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமின்றி அடையாளம் கண்டுள்ளது. பட்டியலிடும் அளவுகோல்கள் பிரிவு 3 இல் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, மேலும் அவை எந்த மீனவரின் கொக்கிக்கும் அப்பாற்பட்டவை! இலங்கையின் 6 மற்றும் 156 முஸ்லிம் அமைப்புக்கள் மற்றும் நபர்கள், ISIL அல்லது AL Qaida என்ற பயங்கரவாத அமைப்புகளின் கூட்டாளிகள், இதன் மூலம் தனிநபர்கள், நாடுகள் அல்லது நாடுகளின் தடைகள் மற்றும் சேதக் கோரிக்கைகள் உள்ளிட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு இலங்கையை தவறாக அம்பலப்படுத்துவது இலங்கையின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சின் நிலையா? சர்வதேச சமூகம்?",
        "21/04/2019 ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்திய நாடாளுமன்றத் தெரிவுக்குழு முன் CID இன் பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் ரவி செனவிரத்ன, இலங்கையின் ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தற்கொலைக் குண்டுதாரிகளுக்கும் ISIL அல்லது அல்கொய்தாவுக்கும் இடையில் எந்தத் தொடர்பும் இருப்பதற்கான ஆதாரம் இல்லை என்று சாட்சியமளித்தார். பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்களின் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு பயங்கரவாத அமைப்புகளுடன் தொடர்பு கொள்ள முயற்சிக்கும் அனுமானங்களை பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் மறுத்துள்ளது. கத்தோலிக்க திருச்சபை 21/04 க்குப் பிறகு, ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பேற்க ஐஎஸ்ஐஎஸ்-ல் இணைய முயலும் கூறுகளை மீண்டும் மீண்டும் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது. இல்லாத இணைப்பைக் காட்ட முயற்சி.",
        "1 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 UN சாசனத்தின் 41 வது பிரிவின் கீழ் குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட நபர்களின் பட்டியலானது தவறானது மற்றும் பல காரணங்களுக்காக சட்டத்தில் எந்த பலமும் அல்லது பயனும் இல்லை, இதில் 41 வது பிரிவு முற்றிலும் போர்கள் மற்றும் மோதல்களைத் தடுக்கும் அசாதாரண ஐ.நா. நாடுகள் மற்றும் ISIL அல்லது அல்கொய்தாவுடன் முற்றிலும் தொடர்பில்லாத நபர்கள் மற்றும் அமைப்புகளை துன்புறுத்தவோ, அவமானப்படுத்தவோ அல்லது அச்சுறுத்தவோ கூடாது நிறுவனங்கள் கொல்லப்பட்டு தகனம் செய்யப்பட்டன.",
        "கூடுதலாக, வர்த்தமானி விதிமுறைகளில் உள்ள பல விதிகள் சர்வதேச சட்டங்கள், இலங்கை அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகள் மற்றும் 2015 இன் பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானம் 2253 ஆகியவற்றை மீறுகின்றன. மீறல்கள் ஹேக்கில் உள்ள சர்வதேச நீதிமன்றம், ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையில் பிரச்சினைகளாக மாறக்கூடும். ஜெனீவாவிலும், கொழும்பில் உள்ள இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையத்திலும், முஸ்லிம் அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களின் பட்டியல் உடனடியாக மதிப்பாய்வு செய்யப்பட்டு ரத்து செய்யப்படாவிட்டால்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐ.நா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹான் குணசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழில்முறை சங்கங்களின் அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1267",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 இன் தீர்மானம் 2253",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாலிபான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் கொய்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈராக் இஸ்லாமிய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமறைவாகி விடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "156",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் கொய்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாலிபான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் கொய்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 இன் 2253",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 2 'ஐஎஸ்ஐஎல்', 'அல் கொய்தா'",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 3",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "156",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.எல்.காய்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத் தெரிவுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/04/2019",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் கொய்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க திருச்சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21/04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா சாசனத்தின் பிரிவு 41",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 41",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.எஸ்.ஐ.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் கொய்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமிய எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}