{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/மேல்-மாகாணம்/ரணில்-கைது/95-303621",
  "time_ut": 1662383147,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரணில் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "On August 31, unknown persons who came on a motorcycle in front of the Negombo court fired a gun at a person who had come to hear the case and fled.",
        "Negombo Police said that two people have been arrested with weapons in connection with this incident.",
        "The police further said that they were arrested at around one o'clock in the afternoon today (05) in Kuttiduva area of ​​Negombo.",
        "Katwellekama Suresh was seriously injured in the firing by the suspects and was admitted to the intensive care unit of Negombo District Hospital. Due to this firing, a person who was walking on the street was also injured.",
        "The police said that a handgun, five cartridges, a hand grenade, a motorcycle used in the incident and two mobile phones were seized from the arrested suspects.",
        "Ranil Prabhat Roopa Singha is the main suspect arrested. He belongs to Minuangoda Unnarua region.",
        "The other suspect is Muthunayake Khedara Priyantha Sisira Kumara of Muthuwela Kalan Mithunuwewa area.",
        "Police said that the main reason for this shooting incident was love problem and drug problem.",
        "The police also said that the suspects will be produced in court tomorrow (06)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "August 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Negombo Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuttiduva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katwellekama Suresh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo District Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Unnarua",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Priyantha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisira Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muthuwela Kalan Mithunuwewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගෝස්තු 31 වැනිදා මීගමුව උසාවිය ඉදිරිපිටදී යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයන් නඩුව විභාග කිරීමට පැමිණි පුද්ගලයකුට තුවක්කුවකින් වෙඩි තබා පලා ගියහ.",
        "මීගමුව පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු ආයුධ සමඟ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "අද (05) දහවල් එකට පමණ මීගමුව කුට්ටිදූව ප්‍රදේශයේදී ඔවුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවයි පොලිසිය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසුවේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන් සිදුකළ වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් කත්වැල්ලේකම සුරේෂ් බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා මීගමුව දිසා රෝහලේ දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත. මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම හේතුවෙන් මාර්ගයේ ගමන් කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු ද තුවාල ලබා තිබෙනවා.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් සන්තකයේ තිබී අත්බෝම්බයක්, කාට්රිජ් පහක්, අත්බෝම්බයක්, සිද්ධියට යොදාගත් යතුරුපැදියක් සහ ජංගම දුරකථන දෙකක් ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ප්‍රධාන සැකකරු රනිල් ප්‍රභාත් රූපසිංහයි. ඔහු අයත් වන්නේ මිනුඅංගොඩ උන්නාරුව ප්‍රදේශයටය.",
        "අනෙක් සැකකරු මුතුවෙල කලං මිතුනුවැව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි මුතුනායක කේදර ප්‍රියන්ත සිසිර කුමාර නැමැත්තාය.",
        "මෙම වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියට ප්‍රධාන හේතුව ප්‍රේම සම්බන්ධ ගැටලුවක් සහ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ප්‍රශ්නයක් බවයි පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන් හෙට (06) අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව ද පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුට්ටිදූව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කත්වැල්ලේකම සුරේෂ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව දිසා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උන්නාරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිර කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුතුවෙල කලං මිතුණුවැව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் கைது",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீர்கொழும்பு நீதிமன்றம் முன்பாக ஓகஸ்ட்  31 ஆம் திகதி மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இனம் தெரியாத நபர்கள், வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு வந்திருந்த ஒருவர் மீது துப்பாக்கி பிரயோகம் செய்துவிட்டு தப்பி  தப்பியோடினர்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பாக இருவர் ஆயுதத்துடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார் என  நீர்கொழும்பு பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நீர்கொழும்பு குட்டிதூவ பிரதேசத்தில் இன்று (05) பிற்பகல் ஒரு மணியளவில் இவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர் என பொலிஸார் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர்களின் துப்பாக்கி சூட்டில் கட்டுவெல்லேகம சுரேஷ் என்பவர் படுகாயமடைந்து நீர்கொழும்பு மாவட்ட வைத்தியசாலையின் தீவிர சிகிச்சை பிரிவில்   அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார். இந்த துப்பாக்கிப் பிரயோகத்தால், வீதியில் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த ஒருவரும்  காயமடைந்தார்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர்களிடம் இருந்து கைத் துப்பாக்கி, ஐந்து ரவைகள், கைக்குண்டு ஒன்றும், சம்பவத்துக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட  மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் ஒன்றும், இரண்டு செல்லிடத் தொலைபேசிகளும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ரணில் பிரபாத் ரூப சிங்க  என்பவரே கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பிரதான சந்தேக நபர் ஆவார்.  இவர் மினுவாங்கொட உன்னாருவ பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர் ஆவார்.",
        "மற்றைய சந்தேக நபர் முத்துவெல கலன் மிதுனுவேவ பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த முத்துநாயக்க கெதர பிரியன்த்த சிசிர குமார என்பவராவார்.",
        "இந்த துப்பாக்கி சூட்டு சம்பவத்துக்கு பிரதான காரணம் காதல் பிரச்சினை மற்றும் போதை பொருள் பிரச்சினை என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர்களை நாளை (06) நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர் செய்ய உள்ளதாகவும் பொலிஸார் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குட்டிடுவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்வெல்லகம சுரேஷ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு மாவட்ட வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உன்னருவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிர குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முத்துவெல கலன் மிதுனுவெவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}