{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/basl-condemns-attacks-on-journalists-calls-for-action-against-police-officers-for-attacks/",
  "time_ut": 1657448340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "BASL condemns attacks on journalists, & calls for action against police officers for attacks",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "BASL condemns attacks on journalists, & calls for action against police officers for attacks",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Bar Association of Sri Lanka convening a special press conference on Sunday (10) afternoon has condemned the violence that broke out on Saturday (9) during the mass protest against the President, Prime Minister, and the Government.",
        "BASL President Saliya Pieris, PC told reporters that the Bar Association of Sri Lanka condemned the shooting at protestors on Saturday (9) morning, the attacks on News 1st journalists later in the day, and the torching of the Prime Minister’s residence on Saturday (9) night. The Bar Association President pointed out that disciplinary action must be taken against all police officers who attacked journalists following an impartial, and immediate investigation.",
        "“All acts of violence are condemned the should be investigated,” he told reporters adding that it is important to protect the rights of journalists to report on the news.",
        "The President of the Bar Association of Sri Lanka urged Sri Lankans who are occupying the President’s House and the President’s Office to refrain from causing any damage to the property, especially those items of historical importance.",
        "“We must all understand that all acts of violence by any party in any form will destabilize, worsen the country’s economy, and will worsen the plight of the people,” he said.",
        "For this reason all Sri Lankans must step back from violence and understand that violence does not benefit anyone.",
        "BASL condemns attacks on journalists, & calls for action against police officers for attacks",
        "What happens after the President resigns? BASL explains process to elect new President",
        "President & PM have no moral right to remain in power; Sirisena writes 10-point letter to build Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "later in the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the President’s Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "President & PM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "BASL මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම හෙළා දකින අතර ප්‍රහාර සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට එරෙහිව පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය ඉරිදා (10) පස්වරුවේ විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් කැදවමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට, අගමැතිට සහ රජයට එරෙහිව පැවති ජනතා විරෝධතාවයේ දී සෙනසුරාදා (9) ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හෙළා දකී.",
        "BASL සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ සෙනසුරාදා (9) උදෑසන විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට වෙඩි තැබීම, පසුවදා News 1st මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම සහ සෙනසුරාදා (9) අගමැති නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය හෙළා දකින බවයි. ) රෑ. මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදුන් සියලුම පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට එරෙහිව අපක්ෂපාතීව හා කඩිනම් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා විනය පියවර ගත යුතු බව නීතිඥ සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "“සියලු ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා හෙළා දකිනවා, එය විමර්ශනය කළ යුතුයි,” ඔහු වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසුවේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති වාර්තා කිරීමට මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ගේ අයිතිවාසිකම් ආරක්ෂා කිරීම වැදගත් බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ සහ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ රැඳී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ දේපළවලට, විශේෂයෙන් ඓතිහාසික වැදගත්කමක් ඇති භාණ්ඩවලට හානි සිදුකිරීමෙන් වළකින ලෙසයි.",
        "\"ඕනෑම ආකාරයකින් ඕනෑම පාර්ශවයක් විසින් සිදු කරනු ලබන සියලුම ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා රටේ ආර්ථිකය අස්ථාවර කිරීමට, නරක අතට හැරවීමට සහ ජනතාවගේ දුක්ඛිත තත්ත්වය නරක අතට හැරවීමට හේතු වන බව අප සියලු දෙනා තේරුම් ගත යුතුය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මේ හේතුව නිසා සියලු ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයෙන් ඉවත් විය යුතු අතර ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයෙන් කිසිවකුට යහපතක් නොවන බව වටහා ගත යුතුය.",
        "BASL මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම හෙළා දකින අතර ප්‍රහාර සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට එරෙහිව පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු කුමක් සිදුවේද? නව සභාපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය BASL පැහැදිලි කරයි",
        "ජනාධිපතිට සහ අගමැතිට බලයේ සිටීමට සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් නැත; සිරිසේන ලංකාව හදන්න කරුණු 10ක ලිපියක් ලියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුව දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "BASL பத்திரிகையாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்களை கண்டிக்கிறது, மேலும் தாக்குதல்களுக்கு காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகள் மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (10) பிற்பகல் விசேட செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டைக் கூட்டிய இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம், ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது சனிக்கிழமை (9) இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைகளைக் கண்டித்துள்ளது.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை (9) காலை ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டதையும், பின்னர் அன்று நியூஸ் 1ஸ்ட் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் தாக்கப்பட்டதையும், சனிக்கிழமை (9) பிரதமரின் இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்து எரிக்கப்பட்டதையும் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் கண்டிப்பதாக BASL தலைவர் சாலிய பீரிஸ் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார். ) இரவு. பக்கச்சார்பற்ற மற்றும் உடனடி விசாரணையின் பின்னர் ஊடகவியலாளர்களை தாக்கிய அனைத்து பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் எதிராக ஒழுக்காற்று நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "\"அனைத்து வன்முறைச் செயல்களும் கண்டிக்கப்பட வேண்டும், அது விசாரிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார், செய்திகளைப் புகாரளிக்கும் பத்திரிகையாளர்களின் உரிமைகளைப் பாதுகாப்பது முக்கியம்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ள இலங்கையர்கள், குறிப்பாக வரலாற்று முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த பொருட்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவிப்பதைத் தவிர்க்குமாறு இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "\"எந்தவொரு கட்சியினரும் எந்த வகையிலும் வன்முறைச் செயல்கள் செய்தாலும், அது நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை சீர்குலைக்கும், மேலும் மக்களின் அவலநிலையை மோசமாக்கும் என்பதை நாம் அனைவரும் புரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த காரணத்திற்காக அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களும் வன்முறையில் இருந்து பின்வாங்க வேண்டும் மற்றும் வன்முறை யாருக்கும் பயனளிக்காது என்பதை புரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "BASL பத்திரிகையாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்களை கண்டிக்கிறது, மேலும் தாக்குதல்களுக்கு காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகள் மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா செய்த பிறகு என்ன நடக்கும்? புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான செயல்முறையை BASL விளக்குகிறது",
        "ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் பிரதமருக்கும் அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்க தார்மீக உரிமை இல்லை; இலங்கையை கட்டியெழுப்ப 10 அம்ச கடிதம் எழுதுகிறார் சிறிசேனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி & பிரதமர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}