{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/leave-of-agri-ministry-employees-cancelled-to-distribute-fertilizer/",
  "time_ut": 1656062100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "\nLeave of Agri Ministry employees cancelled to distribute fertilizer",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Leave of Agri Ministry employees cancelled to distribute fertilizer",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The leave of all employees belonging to institutions under the Ministry of Agriculture has been suspended on 6th of July in order to facilitate the efficient distribution of urea fertilizer.",
        "The decision has been taken on the instructions of the Minister in charge of the subject, Mahinda Amaraweera.",
        "Accordingly, arrangements have been made to transport 65,000 metric tons of urea arriving in the country to the Agrarian Centers from 7th to 15th of July, and to eventually hand it over to farmers.",
        "Therefore, the leave of employees of the Ministry of Agriculture, Agrarian Services Department, National Fertilizer Secretariat, Ceylon Fertilizer Company and Commercial Fertilizer Company will be canceled during this period.",
        "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Agri Ministry",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Agrarian Centers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th to 15th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agrarian Services Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Fertilizer Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bribery Case",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොර බෙදා හැරීමට කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සේවකයන්ගේ නිවාඩු අවලංගු කෙරේ",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); යූරියා පොහොර කාර්යක්ෂමව බෙදා හැරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීම සඳහා කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ ඇති ආයතනවලට අයත් සියලුම සේවකයන්ගේ නිවාඩු ජූලි 6 වැනිදා අත්හිටුවා ඇත.",
        "විෂයභාර අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙරටට පැමිණෙන යූරියා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000ක් ජූලි මස 7 වැනිදා සිට 15 වැනිදා දක්වා ගොවිජන මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත ප්‍රවාහනය කර අවසානයේ ගොවීන් වෙත ලබාදීමට කටයුතු යොදා ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය, ගොවිජන සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය, ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම සහ කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම යන ආයතනවල සේවකයන්ගේ නිවාඩු මෙම කාලය තුළ අවලංගු කෙරෙනු ඇත.",
        "අල්ලස් නඩුවෙන් වෙල්ගම නිදහස් CIABOC පවසන්නේ නඩුව නැවත ගොනු කිරීමට තමන්ට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 6 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොවිජන මධ්යස්ථාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 7 සිට 15 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොවිජන සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් නඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உரம் விநியோகிக்க விவசாய அமைச்சு ஊழியர்களின் விடுமுறை ரத்து",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யூரியா உரத்தை திறம்பட விநியோகிப்பதை எளிதாக்கும் பொருட்டு வேளாண் அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள அனைத்து ஊழியர்களின் விடுப்பு ஜூலை 6 ஆம் தேதி இடைநீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாடத்திற்குப் பொறுப்பான அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீரவின் பணிப்புரைக்கு அமைய இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, நாட்டிற்கு வரும் 65,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியாவை ஜூலை 7ஆம் திகதி முதல் 15ஆம் திகதி வரை கமநல நிலையங்களுக்கு கொண்டு சென்று இறுதியில் விவசாயிகளிடம் கையளிக்க ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "எனவே விவசாய அமைச்சு, கமநல சேவைகள் திணைக்களம், தேசிய உர செயலகம், இலங்கை உர நிறுவனம் மற்றும் வர்த்தக உர கம்பனி ஆகிய நிறுவனங்களின் ஊழியர்களின் விடுமுறை இந்த காலப்பகுதியில் இரத்து செய்யப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "இலஞ்ச வழக்கில் இருந்து வெல்கம விடுதலை; CIABOC வழக்கை மீண்டும் தாக்கல் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வேளாண் அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 6 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய மையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 7 முதல் 15 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமநல சேவைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய உர செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச வழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "\nLeave of Agri Ministry employees cancelled to distribute fertilizer",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); The leave of all employees belonging to institutions under the Ministry of Agriculture has been suspended on 6th of July in order to facilitate the efficient distribution of urea fertilizer.",
    "The decision has been taken on the instructions of the Minister in charge of the subject, Mahinda Amaraweera.",
    "Accordingly, arrangements have been made to transport 65,000 metric tons of urea arriving in the country to the Agrarian Centers from 7th to 15th of July, and to eventually hand it over to farmers.",
    "Therefore, the leave of employees of the Ministry of Agriculture, Agrarian Services Department, National Fertilizer Secretariat, Ceylon Fertilizer Company and Commercial Fertilizer Company will be canceled during this period.",
    "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Leave of Agri Ministry employees cancelled to distribute fertilizer",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The leave of all employees belonging to institutions under the Ministry of Agriculture has been suspended on 6th of July in order to facilitate the efficient distribution of urea fertilizer.",
        "The decision has been taken on the instructions of the Minister in charge of the subject, Mahinda Amaraweera.",
        "Accordingly, arrangements have been made to transport 65,000 metric tons of urea arriving in the country to the Agrarian Centers from 7th to 15th of July, and to eventually hand it over to farmers.",
        "Therefore, the leave of employees of the Ministry of Agriculture, Agrarian Services Department, National Fertilizer Secretariat, Ceylon Fertilizer Company and Commercial Fertilizer Company will be canceled during this period.",
        "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Agri Ministry",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Agrarian Centers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th to 15th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agrarian Services Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Fertilizer Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bribery Case",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොර බෙදා හැරීමට කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සේවකයන්ගේ නිවාඩු අවලංගු කෙරේ",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); යූරියා පොහොර කාර්යක්ෂමව බෙදා හැරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීම සඳහා කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ ඇති ආයතනවලට අයත් සියලුම සේවකයන්ගේ නිවාඩු ජූලි 6 වැනිදා අත්හිටුවා ඇත.",
        "විෂයභාර අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙරටට පැමිණෙන යූරියා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000ක් ජූලි මස 7 වැනිදා සිට 15 වැනිදා දක්වා ගොවිජන මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත ප්‍රවාහනය කර අවසානයේ ගොවීන් වෙත ලබාදීමට කටයුතු යොදා ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය, ගොවිජන සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය, ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම සහ කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම යන ආයතනවල සේවකයන්ගේ නිවාඩු මෙම කාලය තුළ අවලංගු කෙරෙනු ඇත.",
        "අල්ලස් නඩුවෙන් වෙල්ගම නිදහස් CIABOC පවසන්නේ නඩුව නැවත ගොනු කිරීමට තමන්ට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 6 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොවිජන මධ්යස්ථාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 7 සිට 15 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොවිජන සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් නඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உரம் விநியோகிக்க விவசாய அமைச்சு ஊழியர்களின் விடுமுறை ரத்து",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யூரியா உரத்தை திறம்பட விநியோகிப்பதை எளிதாக்கும் பொருட்டு வேளாண் அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள அனைத்து ஊழியர்களின் விடுப்பு ஜூலை 6 ஆம் தேதி இடைநீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாடத்திற்குப் பொறுப்பான அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீரவின் பணிப்புரைக்கு அமைய இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, நாட்டிற்கு வரும் 65,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியாவை ஜூலை 7ஆம் திகதி முதல் 15ஆம் திகதி வரை கமநல நிலையங்களுக்கு கொண்டு சென்று இறுதியில் விவசாயிகளிடம் கையளிக்க ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "எனவே விவசாய அமைச்சு, கமநல சேவைகள் திணைக்களம், தேசிய உர செயலகம், இலங்கை உர நிறுவனம் மற்றும் வர்த்தக உர கம்பனி ஆகிய நிறுவனங்களின் ஊழியர்களின் விடுமுறை இந்த காலப்பகுதியில் இரத்து செய்யப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "இலஞ்ச வழக்கில் இருந்து வெல்கம விடுதலை; CIABOC வழக்கை மீண்டும் தாக்கல் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வேளாண் அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 6 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய மையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 7 முதல் 15 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமநல சேவைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய உர செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச வழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}