{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/picture_story/ශ්‍රී-ලංකන්-සේවකයන්ගේ-අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව-නිසා-තුර්කි-ගුවන්-සේවය-නවතින-ලකුණු/10-395102",
  "time_ut": 1656991115,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් සේවකයන්ගේ අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව නිසා තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය නවතින ලකුණු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Turkish Airlines ground to a halt due to inefficiency of Sri Lankan staff",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A cargo plane belonging to Turkish Airlines crashed at Katunayake Airport yesterday (03) while preparing to return.",
        "This is a Turkish Airlines A.-330-300 Airbus type cargo plane. This flight TK- 6050 had arrived at Katunayake Airport on 07/03 at around 09.00 pm carrying a load of goods from Istanbul, Turkey.",
        "After that, the plane was preparing to leave Katunayake Airport for Istanbul, Turkey, carrying a 45 metric ton load of clothes manufactured by \"Victoria's Secret Stores\".",
        "At that time, due to the strong wind condition in the Katunayake airport and its surrounding area (Esala storm situation), a container that was brought to be loaded on this aircraft, the Sri Lankan Airlines airport operators did not apply brakes properly and stopped near the relevant aircraft. After being placed, the container was blown towards the plane by the strong wind and collided with its engine.",
        "Due to this incident, the right side engine number 02 of this aircraft has been damaged.",
        "As such, the necessary steps have not been taken by the Turkish aviation authorities to restore the damaged engine of this plane or leave Katunayake airport.",
        "Katunayake Airport Sri Lankan Airline's inefficient and irresponsible action of the airport staff (Bad Ground Handling) and because it is no longer possible to get fuel for its planes from Katunayake Airport in Sri Lanka, Turkish Airlines to suspend flight operations with Sri Lanka. Airport sources have revealed that the aviation authorities are currently considering."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Turkish Airlines",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Turkish Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Turkish Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.-330-300",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airbus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6050",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "07/03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Istanbul",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Istanbul",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 metric ton",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Victoria's Secret Stores",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Esala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Turkish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport Sri Lankan Airline's",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bad Ground Handling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkish Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් සේවකයන්ගේ අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව නිසා තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය නවතින ලකුණු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගුවන් යානයක්, කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළේ දී පෙරේදා (03දා) දින රාත්‍රී ආපසු පිටත්ව යාමට සූදානම් වෙමින් සිටියදී අනතුරට පත් වී තිබේ.",
        "මෙය තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ඒ.- 330 - 300  එයා බස් වර්ගයේ භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගුවන් යානයකි. ටී.කේ.- 6050 දරන  මෙම ගුවන් යානය තුර්කියේ ඉස්තාන්බුල් නුවර සිට භාණ්ඩ තොගයක් රැගෙන  07/03 දින රාත්‍රී 09.00 ට පමණ කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත පැමිණ තිබුණි.",
        "ඉන්පසුව \" වික්ටෝරියා සීක්‍රට් ස්ටෝර්ස් \" නිෂ්පාදිත , මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 45 ක් බරැති ඇගලුම් තොගයක් රැගෙන, මෙම ගුවන් යානය රාත්‍රී 11.30 ට පමණ කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් තුර්කියේ ඉස්තාන්බුල් නුවර බලා පිටත්ව යාමට සූදානම් වෙමින් තිබුණි.",
        "ඒ වේලාව වනවිට කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවති දැඩි සුළං තත්වය ( ඇසළ කුණාටු තත්වය ) නිසා , මෙම ගුවන් යානයට පැටවීම සදහා රැගෙන විත් තිබූ බහාලුමක් , ශ්‍රී ලන්කන් ගුවන් සේවා ගුවන් අංගන මෙහෙයුම්  ක්‍රියාකරුවන් විසින් නිසි පරිදි  තිරිංග නොයොදා , අදාළ ගුවන් යානය අසළ නවතා තැබීමෙන් පසුව, එම බහාලුම ගුවන් යානය දෙසට හැමූ වේගවත්  සුළගට ගසා ගෙන ගොස් එහි ඇංජිමක ගැටීමෙන් මෙම අනතුර සිදු වී තිබේ.",
        "මෙම සිදුවීමෙන් මෙම ගුවන් යානයේ දකුණු පස අංක 02 දරන ඇංජිම අනතුරට පත් වී තිබේ.",
        "එනිසා මෙම ගුවන් යානය මෙසේ  අනතුරෙන් හානියට පත් වූ ඇංජිම යථා තත්වයට පත් කර ගැනීමට හෝ කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත්ව යාමට අවශ්‍ය  පියවර තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවා බලධාරීන් විසින් මේ වනතෙක් ගෙන නොමැත.",
        "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ ශ්‍රී ලන්කන් ගුවන් සේවා ගුවන් අංගන මෙහෙයුම් සේවකයින්ගේ අකාර්යක්ෂම වගකීම් විරහිත ක්‍රියාකළාපය (Bad Ground Handling )  සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් තම ගුවන් යානා සදහා තවදුරටත් ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි නිසා තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය , ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමග පවත්වනු ලබන ගුවන් ගමන් මෙහෙයුම් අත්හිටුවීමට තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවා බලධාරීන් මේ වනවිට සළකා බලමින් සිටින බවට ගුවන් තොටුපළ ආරංචි මාර්ග වලින් අනාවරණය  වී තිබේ ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.-330-300",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6050",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "07/03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්තාන්බුල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්තාන්බුල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 45 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටෝරියා රහස් වෙළඳසැල්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇසල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරක බිම් හැසිරවීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஊழியர்களின் திறமையின்மை காரணமாக துருக்கிய விமான சேவை நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "துருக்கி விமான சேவைக்கு சொந்தமான சரக்கு விமானமொன்று கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தில் நேற்று (03) நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு தயாரான நிலையில் விபத்துக்குள்ளானது.",
        "இது துருக்கிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ் ஏ.-330-300 ஏர்பஸ் வகை சரக்கு விமானம். TK- 6050 என்ற இந்த விமானம் துருக்கியின் இஸ்தான்புல்லில் இருந்து பொருட்களை ஏற்றிக்கொண்டு 07/03 இரவு 09.00 மணியளவில் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "அதன் பின்னர், \"விக்டோரியாஸ் சீக்ரெட் ஸ்டோர்ஸ்\" தயாரித்த 45 மெட்ரிக் தொன் ஆடைகளை ஏற்றிக்கொண்டு, கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து துருக்கியின் இஸ்தான்புல் நகருக்கு விமானம் புறப்படத் தயாராகிக் கொண்டிருந்தது.",
        "அப்போது கட்டுநாயக்கா விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் அதனை சூழவுள்ள பகுதியில் பலத்த காற்று வீசியதால் (எசல புயல் நிலை) இந்த விமானத்தில் ஏற்றுவதற்காக கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட கொள்கலனை ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் விமான நிலைய அதிகாரிகள் சரியாக பிரேக் போடாமல் அருகில் நிறுத்தினர். பொருத்தப்பட்ட விமானம் வைக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், பலத்த காற்றினால் கண்டெய்னர் விமானத்தை நோக்கி வீசப்பட்டு அதன் இயந்திரத்தில் மோதியது.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்தால் இந்த விமானத்தின் வலது பக்க எஞ்சின் எண் 02 சேதமடைந்துள்ளது.",
        "இவ்வாறான நிலையில், இந்த விமானத்தின் சேதமடைந்த இயந்திரத்தை மீட்பதற்கோ அல்லது கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கோ தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் துருக்கி விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அதிகாரிகளால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படவில்லை.",
        "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலைய ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமான நிலைய நடத்துனரின் திறமையற்ற மற்றும் பொறுப்பற்ற நடவடிக்கை (மோசமான தரை கையாளுதல்) மற்றும் இலங்கையின் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து தங்கள் விமானங்களுக்கு எரிபொருளைப் பெற முடியாது என்பதால், துருக்கிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ் இலங்கையுடனான விமான நடவடிக்கைகளை இடைநிறுத்தியுள்ளது. தற்போது பரிசீலித்து வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துருக்கி விமானம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.-330-300",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்பஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6050",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "07/03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 09.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்தான்புல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்தான்புல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டோரியா சீக்ரெட் ஸ்டோர்ஸ்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எசல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துருக்கிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோசமான தரை கையாளுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}