{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/05/video-school-boy-trapped-in-storm-drain-in-kurunegala-dies/",
  "time_ut": 1662378180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "(VIDEO) School boy trapped in storm drain in Kurunegala, dies",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "(VIDEO) School boy trapped in storm drain in Kurunegala, dies",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A major rescue operation got underway in Wehera, Kurunegala in the North-West of Sri Lanka after a 14-year-old school boy was found trapped in a drain. Unfortunately, the young boy died upon admission to hospital.",
        "Local joined hands with the authorities to move heavy machinery to site to dig open the drain that was gushing with flood waters.",
        "The boy was a grade 9 student from Maliyadeva College, Kurunegala and was washed away by flood waters into the drain when returning home from school.",
        "(VIDEO) School boy trapped in storm drain in Kurunegala, dies",
        "Sri Lanka appoints committee to facilitate return of Refugees in India",
        "President wants full implementation of 19th Amendment – Foreign Minister"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kurunegala",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wehera",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maliyadeva College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "(VIDEO) කුරුණෑගලදී වැසි කාණුවේ සිරවී පාසල් සිසුවා මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වයඹ ප්‍රදේශයේ කුරුණෑගල වෙහෙර ප්‍රදේශයේ 14 හැවිරිදි පාසල් සිසුවෙකු කාණුවක සිරවී සිටියදී සොයාගැනීමෙන් පසු විශාල මුදාගැනීමේ මෙහෙයුමක් ක්‍රියාත්මක විය. අවාසනාවන්ත ලෙස තරුණයා රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමේදී මිය ගියේය.",
        "ගංවතුරින් ගලා බසින කාණුව විවෘත කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් බලධාරීන් සමඟ අත්වැල් බැඳගෙන බර යන්ත්‍ර සූත්‍ර එම ස්ථානයට ගෙන ගියේය.",
        "මෙම පිරිමි ළමයා කුරුණෑගල මලියදේව විද්‍යාලයේ 9 වැනි ශ්‍රේණියේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන අතර පාසල නිමවී නිවස බලා එමින් සිටියදී ගංවතුරට ජලයෙන් ගසාගෙන ගොස් ඇත.",
        "(VIDEO) කුරුණෑගලදී වැසි කාණුවේ සිරවී පාසල් සිසුවා මරුට",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සිටින සරණාගතයින් ආපසු පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
        "19 වැනි සංශෝධනය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ජනපතිට අවශ්‍යයි – විදේශ ඇමැති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙහෙර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලියදේව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "(வீடியோ) குருநாகலில் புயல் வடிகாலில் சிக்கிய பாடசாலை மாணவன் மரணம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் வடமேற்கில் உள்ள குருநாகல் வெஹெராவில் 14 வயது பள்ளிச் சிறுவன் சாக்கடையில் சிக்கியதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஒரு பெரிய மீட்பு நடவடிக்கை தொடங்கியது. துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட சிறுவன் உயிரிழந்தான்.",
        "வெள்ள நீர் பெருக்கெடுத்து ஓடும் வடிகாலைத் திறப்பதற்காக கனரக இயந்திரங்களை இடத்துக்கு கொண்டு செல்ல அதிகாரிகளுடன் உள்ளூர்வாசிகள் கைகோர்த்தனர்.",
        "குருநாகல் மலியதேவ கல்லூரியில் தரம் 9 இல் கல்வி கற்கும் சிறுவன் பாடசாலை முடிந்து வீடு திரும்பும் போது வடிகாலில் வெள்ளத்தில் அடித்து செல்லப்பட்டான்.",
        "(வீடியோ) குருநாகலில் புயல் வடிகாலில் சிக்கிய பாடசாலை மாணவன் மரணம்",
        "இந்தியாவில் உள்ள அகதிகள் நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதியாக இலங்கை குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது",
        "19வது திருத்தத்தை முழுமையாக அமுல்படுத்த ஜனாதிபதி விரும்புகிறார் – வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "குருநாகல்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெஹெரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலியதேவ கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}