{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ආණ්ඩුකාරවරුන්-පත්-කිරීමට-එජාප-පොහොට්ටු-සීතල-යුද්ධයක්/1-618231",
  "time_ut": 1660660306,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආණ්ඩුකාරවරුන් පත් කිරීමට එජාප පොහොට්ටු සීතල යුද්ධයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNP budding cold war to appoint governors",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Political sources say that there are signs that the appointment of governors for the nine provinces of the island will become a big mess.",
        "According to the sources, President Ranil Wickremesinghe has already decided to appoint several people related to the United National Party as governors and the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has proposed separate names for the governorships.",
        "From the members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna in the appointment of the Governor for the Eastern Province",
        "It is reported that several MPs of the province, including former minister Mr. Wimalaweera Dissanayake, have already informed the government not to act illegally.",
        "The number of members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna representing the Eastern Province is 8.",
        "Former Minister Daya Gamage, John Amaratunga Naveen Dissanayake and former opposition leader Shamel Senarath of the North West Province have also proposed for the post of Governor.",
        "In the meantime, it has been learned that the party has requested the President to give three governors appointed by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna government the opportunity to continue in those governorships.",
        "The persons who Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has requested to be given the opportunity to continue working in the positions of governors are Lalith U Gamage, Willy Gamage and M. Messrs. J. Moosammil."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimalaweera Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daya Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Amaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shamel Senarath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North West Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J. Moosammil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආණ්ඩුකාරවරුන් පත් කිරීමට එජාප පොහොට්ටු සීතල යුද්ධයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ පළාත් නවය සඳහා   ආණ්ඩුකාරවරුන් පත්කිරීමද ලොකු අවුල් ජාලයක් බවට පත්වන  ලකුණු පහළව ඇතැයි  දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ගවලින් පැවසේ.",
        "ආණ්ඩුකාරවරුන් ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට සම්බන්ධ කිහිප දෙනකු පත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දැනටමත් තීරණය කර ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ආණ්ඩුකාර ධූරයන්  සඳහා වෙනම නම් යෝජනා  කිරීම  හේතුවෙන් මෙම අවුල් සහගත තත්වය ඇතිවී තිබෙන  බව  එම ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "නැගෙනහිර පළාත සඳහා ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා පත් කිරීමේදී  ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන්",
        "නොවීමසා කටයුතු නොකරන ලෙස  හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමලවීර දිසානායක මහතා ඇතුළු පළාතේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිපදෙනකු  රජයට දැනටමත් දැනුම්දී ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "නැගෙනහිර පළාත නියෝජනය කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සංඛ්‍යාව 8කි.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය දයා ගමගේ, ජෝන් අමරතුංග නවීන් දිසානායක සහ  වයඹ පළාත් හිටපු විපක්ෂ නායක ශමෙල් සෙනරත් යන මහත්වරුන්  ඇතුළු පිරිසක්ද ( එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ)  ආණ්ඩුකාර ධූර සඳහා  යෝජනාවී සිටිති.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණු  ආණ්ඩුවෙන් පත් කෙරුණු ආණ්ඩුකාර වරුන් තිදෙනකුට එම ආණ්ඩුකාර ධුරයන් හි ඉදිරියටද  කටයුතු කිරීමට  අවස්ථාව සලසන ලෙස එම පක්ෂය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීම් කර ඇතැයි  දැනගන්නට  ඇත.",
        "ආණ්ඩුකාර ධුරයන් හි  තවදුරටත් කටයුතු කිරීමට මෙලෙස අවස්ථාව දෙන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ  ඉල්ලා  ඇති පුද්ගලයන් වන්නේ  ලලිත් යූ ගමගේ, විලී ගමගේ සහ  එම්. ජේ මූසම්මිල් යන මහත්වරුන්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එජාප",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමලවීර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දයා ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් අමරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශමෙල් සෙනරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ. මූසම්මිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆளுநர்களை நியமிப்பதில் ஐ.தே.க பனிப்போர் வெடிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தீவின் ஒன்பது மாகாணங்களுக்கும் ஆளுநர் நியமனம் பெரும் குழப்பமாக மாறுவதற்கான அறிகுறிகள் தென்படுவதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியுடன் தொடர்புடைய பலரை ஆளுநர்களாக நியமிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஏற்கனவே தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாகவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ஆளுனர் பதவிகளுக்கு தனியான பெயர்களை முன்மொழிந்துள்ளதாகவும் அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "கிழக்கு மாகாண ஆளுநர் நியமனத்தில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் திரு.விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க உட்பட மாகாணத்தின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் பலர் சட்டவிரோதமாக செயற்பட வேண்டாம் என ஏற்கனவே அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "கிழக்கு மாகாணத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 8 ஆகும்.",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் தயா கமகே, ஜோன் அமரதுங்க நவீன் திசாநாயக்க மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாண முன்னாள் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஷமேல் செனரத் ஆகியோரும் ஆளுநர் பதவிக்கு முன்மொழிந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன அரசாங்கத்தினால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட மூன்று ஆளுநர்களுக்கு அந்த ஆளுநர் பதவிகளில் நீடிப்பதற்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அக்கட்சி கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக அறியமுடிகின்றது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஆளுநர் பதவிகளில் தொடர்ந்தும் பணியாற்ற வாய்ப்பு வழங்குமாறு கோரியவர்கள் லலித் யு கமகே, வில்லி கமகே மற்றும் எம். ஜே.மூசம்மில் அவர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தயா கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன் அமரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷமல் செனரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மேற்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.மூசம்மில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}