{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/8-වැනි-විධායක-ජනාධිපති-දිවුරුම්-දෙයි/1-616781",
  "time_ut": 1658378628,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපති දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "8th Executive President takes oath",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe was sworn in as the 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka at the Kotte Parliament premises.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who has held the office of Prime Minister six times, will be sworn in as the Executive President for the first time.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe requested to be given the opportunity to take oath at the Parliament premises after becoming the Executive President by parliamentary vote.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe is known as a leader who highly valued parliamentary democracy in his political career."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8th Executive",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotte Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපති දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපති ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කෝට්ටේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයේදී දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "හය වරක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙහි කටයුතු කර ඇති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විධායක ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙහි දිවුරුම් දෙන්නේ ප්‍රථම වතාවටයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයෙන් විධායක ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රයේදී ම දිවුරුම් දීමට අවස්ථාව ලබා දෙන ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තම දේශපාලන ජීවිතයේ දී පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ඉතා ඉහළින් අගය කළ නායකයෙකු ලෙස ප්‍රකටය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8 වැනි විධායක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝට්ටේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கோட்டே பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "6 முறை பிரதமர் பதவியை வகித்த திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக முதன்முறையாக பதவியேற்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்ய சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்குமாறு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது அரசியல் வாழ்வில் பாராளுமன்ற ஜனநாயகத்தை மிகவும் மதிப்பிட்ட தலைவராக அறியப்பட்டவர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8வது நிர்வாகி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டே பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}