{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/වෙන්ටියාන්-රසායනාගාර-මොඩියුලයට-ගගනගාමීන්-යයි/3-395718",
  "time_ut": 1658738069,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වෙන්ටියාන් රසායනාගාර මොඩියුලයට ගගනගාමීන් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Astronauts go to the Vientiane Laboratory Module",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The crew of China's Shenzhou-14 space mission entered the Wentian Laboratory Module this morning (25th), announced the China Manned Space Agency (CMS).",
        "This marks the first time that Chinese astronauts, or taikonauts, have entered a laboratory module in orbit.",
        "According to the plan, this would allow for joint control of China's space station and on-orbit work such as testing of Wentian's small robotic arm as well as the core module's large robotic arm.",
        "Launched on Sunday afternoon, the Wentian module has entered the planned orbit and docked with the main module's forward stand at China's Tianhe Space Center at 3:13 a.m. China time this morning, after completing setup.",
        "This is the first time that China's two 20-ton spacecraft have performed in-orbit rendezvous and docking, and the first time that astronauts have performed in-orbit rendezvous and docking while in orbit on the space station, CMS said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Vientiane Laboratory Module",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wentian Laboratory Module",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the China Manned Space Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wentian",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wentian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tianhe Space Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:13 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-ton",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෙන්ටියාන් රසායනාගාර මොඩියුලයට ගගනගාමීන් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ ෂෙන්ෂෝ-14 අභ්‍යවකාශ මෙහෙයුමේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අද (25දා) උදෑසන වෙන්ටියාන් රසායනාගාර මොඩියුලයට ඇතුළු වූ බව, චීන මිනිසුන් සහිත අභ්‍යවකාශ ඒජන්සිය (CMS) නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "චීන ගගනගාමීන් හෙවත් ටයිකොනෝට්වරු කක්ෂය තුළ විද්‍යාගාර මොඩියුලයකට ඇතුළු වූ පළමු වැනි අවස්ථාව එසේ සනිටුහන් වී තිබේ.",
        "මෙම සැලැස්මට අනුව, චීනය අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ ඒකාබද්ධ පාලනය සහ වෙන්ටියාන්ගේ කුඩා රොබෝ අත මෙන්ම මූලික මොඩියුලයේ විශාල රොබෝ අත පිළිබඳ පරීක්ෂණ වැනි කක්ෂයේ වැඩ සඳහා මෙමගින් අවස්ථාව සැලසෙයි.",
        "ඉරිදා පස්වරුවේ දියත් කරන ලද, වෙන්ටියාන් මොඩියුලය සැලසුම් කළ කක්ෂයට ඇතුළු වී සැකසුම සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමෙන් පසු අද අලුයම චීන වේලාවෙන් 3:13 ට චීනයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ ටියැන්හේ ප්‍රධාන මොඩියුලයේ ඉදිරිපස නැවතුම සමග සම්බන්ධ වී තිබේ.",
        "චීනයේ ටොන් 20 මට්ටමේ අභ්‍යවකාශ යානා දෙක කක්ෂයේ හමුවීම් සහ නැව්ගත කිරීම් සිදු කළ පළමු වැනි අවස්ථාව මෙය වන අතර, ගගනගාමීන් අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ කක්ෂගතව සිටින අතරතුර අභ්‍යවකාශ හමුවීම් සහ නැව්ගත කිරීම් සිදුකළ පළමු වැනි අවස්ථාව මෙය බව CMS පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vientian රසායනාගාර මොඩියුලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්ටියන් රසායනාගාර මොඩියුලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන මිනිසුන් සහිත අභ්‍යවකාශ ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wentian",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wentian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tianhe අභ්යවකාශ මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:13 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 20ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விண்வெளி வீரர்கள் Vientiane Laboratory Module க்கு செல்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் Shenzhou-14 விண்வெளிப் பயணத்தின் குழுவினர் இன்று (25ஆம் தேதி) காலை வென்டியன் ஆய்வக தொகுதிக்குள் நுழைந்ததாக சீன மனிதர்கள் கொண்ட விண்வெளி நிறுவனம் (CMS) அறிவித்தது.",
        "சீன விண்வெளி வீரர்கள் அல்லது டைகோனாட்கள், சுற்றுப்பாதையில் ஆய்வக தொகுதிக்குள் நுழைந்தது இதுவே முதல் முறை.",
        "திட்டத்தின் படி, இது சீனாவின் விண்வெளி நிலையத்தின் கூட்டுக் கட்டுப்பாட்டை அனுமதிக்கும் மற்றும் வென்டியனின் சிறிய ரோபோ கை மற்றும் முக்கிய தொகுதியின் பெரிய ரோபோ கையை சோதனை செய்வது போன்ற சுற்றுப்பாதையில் வேலை செய்யும்.",
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை பிற்பகலில் ஏவப்பட்ட, வென்டியன் தொகுதியானது, திட்டமிட்ட சுற்றுப்பாதையில் நுழைந்து, அமைவை முடித்த பிறகு, சீனாவின் தியான்ஹே விண்வெளி மையத்தில் இன்று அதிகாலை 3:13 மணிக்கு, சீனாவின் தியான்ஹே விண்வெளி மையத்தில் பிரதான தொகுதியின் முன்னோக்கி நிலைப்பாட்டுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சீனாவின் இரண்டு 20 டன் விண்கலங்கள் சுற்றுப்பாதையில் சந்திப்பு மற்றும் நறுக்குதல் ஆகியவற்றை நிகழ்த்துவது இதுவே முதல் முறையாகும், மேலும் விண்வெளி வீரர்கள் விண்வெளி நிலையத்தில் சுற்றுப்பாதையில் இருக்கும்போது சுற்றுப்பாதையில் சந்திப்பு மற்றும் நறுக்குதல் ஆகியவற்றைச் செய்வது இதுவே முதல் முறை என்று CMS தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vientiane ஆய்வக தொகுதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெண்டியன் ஆய்வக தொகுதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா மனிதர்கள் கொண்ட விண்வெளி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wentian",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wentian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tianhe விண்வெளி மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:13 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}