{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-says-local-fuel-crisis-purposely-created/108-240034",
  "time_ut": 1656494132,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB says local fuel crisis purposely created",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB says local fuel crisis purposely created",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Whilst alleging that liberalising Sri Lanka's fuel distribution will result in the closure of the Sapugaskanda refinery, Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa today said he together with other opposition political parties will launch a struggle to save it.",
        "\"Refinery is a national asset and we will do our utmost to save it,\" Premadasa told CPC trade unionists who met him yesterday.",
        "\"We will not allow the present government to destroy the refinery,\" he said.",
        "\"The refinery supplies 100 percent of Sri Lanka's kerosene need, 50 to 60 percent of aviation fuel need, 100 percent of Napta need, 30 to 100 percent of diesel and 75 percent to 100 percent of furnace oil at the moment,\" he said.",
        "MP Rajitha Senaratne who was also present at the meeting said the present fuel crisis has been deliberately created so that a conducive environment will prevail under which the local fuel market could be easily liberalised. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sapugaskanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 to 60 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Napta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 to 100 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශීය ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හිතාමතාම නිර්මාණය කළ බව SJB පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම ලිහිල් කිරීමෙන් සපුගස්කන්ද පිරිපහදුව වැසීයාමට සිදුවන බවට චෝදනා කරන අතරම විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ විපක්ෂයේ අනෙකුත් දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමඟ එක්ව එය බේරාගැනීම සඳහා අරගලයක් දියත් කරන බවයි.",
        "පිරිපහදුව යනු ජාතික සම්පතක් වන අතර එය සුරැකීමට අපි උපරිමයෙන් කටයුතු කරනවා යැයි ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඊයේ තමා හමුවූ CPC වෘත්තීය සමිති සාමාජිකයින්ට පැවසීය.",
        "වත්මන් රජයට පිරිපහදුව විනාශ කරන්න අපි ඉඩ තියන්නේ නැහැ යැයිද ඇමැතිවරයා කීය.",
        "\"මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ භූමිතෙල් අවශ්‍යතාවයෙන් සියයට 100ක්, ගුවන් ඉන්ධන අවශ්‍යතාවයෙන් සියයට 50 සිට 60 දක්වා, නැප්ටා අවශ්‍යතාවයෙන් සියයට 100ක්, ඩීසල් සියයට 30 සිට සියයට 100 දක්වා සහ ඌෂ්මක තෙල් සියයට 75 සිට සියයට 100 දක්වා පිරිපහදුව මගින් සපයනු ලැබේ,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම හමුවට එක්ව සිටි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රාජිත සේනාරත්න කියා සිටියේ දේශීය ඉන්ධන වෙළඳපොල පහසුවෙන් ලිහිල් කළ හැකි යහපත් පරිසරයක් පවතින පරිදි වත්මන් ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හිතාමතාම නිර්මාණය කර ඇති බවයි. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සපුගස්කන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට සියයක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 සිට 60 දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට සියයක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැප්ටා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 30 සිට 100 දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 75 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට සියයක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உள்ளூர் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி வேண்டுமென்றே உருவாக்கப்பட்டதாக SJB கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை தாராளமயமாக்கினால் சப்புகஸ்கந்த சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் மூடப்படும் என குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஏனைய எதிர்க்கட்சிகளுடன் இணைந்து அதனை காப்பாற்றுவதற்கான போராட்டத்தை முன்னெடுக்கவுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் ஒரு தேசிய சொத்து, அதை காப்பாற்ற நாங்கள் எங்களால் முடிந்த அனைத்தையும் செய்வோம்\" என்று நேற்று தன்னை சந்தித்த CPC தொழிற்சங்கவாதிகளிடம் பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய அரசு சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையத்தை அழிக்க அனுமதிக்க மாட்டோம் என்றார்.",
        "\"இந்த சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் இலங்கையின் மண்ணெண்ணெய் தேவையில் 100 சதவீதமும், விமான எரிபொருள் தேவையில் 50 முதல் 60 சதவீதமும், நாப்டா தேவையில் 100 சதவீதமும், டீசல் 30 முதல் 100 சதவீதமும், உலை எண்ணெய் 75 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 100 சதவீதமும் உள்ளது\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்தச் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ராஜித சேனாரத்ன, தற்போதைய எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி வேண்டுமென்றே உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, இதனால் உள்ளூர் எரிபொருள் சந்தையை இலகுவாக தாராளமயமாக்கக்கூடிய சாதகமான சூழல் உருவாகும். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபுகஸ்கந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 முதல் 60 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாப்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 முதல் 100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}