{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/india-urges-its-nationals-in-sri-lanka-to-exercise-caution/",
  "time_ut": 1661498520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India urges its nationals in Sri Lanka to exercise caution",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India urges its nationals in Sri Lanka to exercise caution",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); India has urged its nationals living in Sri Lanka to exercise caution and examine the currency convertibility and fuel situation in the island nation carefully.",
        "Indian Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Arindam Bagchi speaking to reporters on Thursday (26) said that India has been following the developments in Sri Lanka for some time, and it is understood that India is still the largest source of tourists for Sri Lanka.",
        "\"Our endeavour is to prevent any untoward incident involving Indians outside India. We would therefore encourage Indians to exercise all care and caution while in Sri Lanka. They should examine all relevant factors including currency convertibility and the fuel situation before undertaking any essential travel to Sri Lanka,\" he told the press briefing.",
        "He further assured that the Indian High Commission is in touch with local authorities over the safety of the Indian nationals in Sri Lanka.",
        "In reply to the queries about whether Indians should travel to Sri Lanka, MEA spokesperson pointed out, \"As regards to travel of Indians to Sri Lanka in the current situation, let me emphasize that the safety and well-being of Indian nationals during their stay outside India including in Sri Lanka, in this particular case, is always of prime importance,\" and added that Indians must exercise caution.",
        "Military should be ready for technological knowledge for cyber warfare – President",
        "Is Sri Lanka’s economic crisis spiraling into a humanitarian one?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින තම ජාතිකයන්ගෙන් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉන්දියාව ඉල්ලා සිටියි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන තම ජාතිකයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ප්‍රවේශම් වන ලෙසත්, දිවයිනේ මුදල් පරිවර්තන හැකියාව සහ ඉන්ධන තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ප්‍රවේශමෙන් පරීක්ෂා කරන ලෙසත්ය.",
        "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (26) මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ ඉන්දියාව කලක සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්ධනයන් අනුගමනය කරන බවත්, තවමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විශාලතම සංචාරක ප්‍රභවය ඉන්දියාව බව වටහා ගන්නා බවත්ය.",
        "\"අපගේ උත්සාහය ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත සිටින ඉන්දියානුවන් සම්බන්ධ කිසිදු අහිතකර සිදුවීමක් වැලැක්වීමයි. එබැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින විට සියලු සැලකිල්ලෙන් සහ ප්‍රවේශමෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස අපි ඉන්දියානුවන් දිරිමත් කරන්නෙමු. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සංචාරයක් කිරීමට පෙර ඔවුන් මුදල් පරිවර්තන හැකියාව සහ ඉන්ධන තත්ත්වය ඇතුළු අදාළ සියලු සාධක පරීක්ෂා කළ යුතුය. ලංකා,” ඔහු මාධ්‍ය හමුවට පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින ඉන්දීය ජාතිකයින්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය පළාත් පාලන ආයතන සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වී සිටින බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් සහතික කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දියානුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණිය යුතුද යන්න පිළිබඳව මතු වූ ප්‍රශ්නවලට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් MEA ප්‍රකාශකයා පෙන්වා දුන්නේ, “වර්තමාන තත්ත්වය තුළ ඉන්දියානුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්, ඔවුන් රැඳී සිටින කාලය තුළ ඉන්දියානු ජාතිකයින්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ යහපැවැත්ම පිළිබඳව මම අවධාරණය කරමි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළුව ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත, මෙම විශේෂිත අවස්ථාවෙහිදී, සෑම විටම ප්‍රමුඛ වැදගත්කමක් ඇති අතර, ඉන්දියානුවන් ප්‍රවේශම් විය යුතු බව පැවසීය.",
        "සයිබර් යුද්ධයට අවශ්‍ය තාක්ෂණික දැනුම සඳහා හමුදාව සූදානම් විය යුතුයි – ජනපති",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මානුෂීය අර්බුදයක් බවට පත්වෙමින් තිබේද?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் உள்ள தனது பிரஜைகள் எச்சரிக்கையுடன் இருக்குமாறு இந்தியா கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையில் வசிக்கும் தனது பிரஜைகள் எச்சரிக்கையுடன் செயற்படுமாறும், தீவு தேசத்தில் நாணய மாற்றம் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் நிலைமையை கவனமாக ஆராயுமாறும் இந்தியா வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி வியாழன் (26) செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசுகையில், இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள முன்னேற்றங்களை இந்தியா சில காலமாகப் பின்பற்றி வருவதாகவும், இலங்கைக்கான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் மிகப்பெரிய ஆதாரமாக இந்தியாவே இருந்து வருவதாகவும் புரிகிறது.",
        "\"எங்கள் முயற்சி இந்தியாவிற்கு வெளியே உள்ள இந்தியர்கள் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட எந்த விரும்பத்தகாத சம்பவத்தையும் தடுக்க வேண்டும். எனவே இலங்கையில் இருக்கும் போது அனைத்து கவனத்துடனும் எச்சரிக்கையுடனும் செயல்படுமாறு இந்தியர்களை ஊக்குவிப்போம். அவர்கள் இலங்கைக்கு எந்தவொரு அத்தியாவசிய பயணத்தையும் மேற்கொள்வதற்கு முன்னர் நாணய மாற்றம் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் நிலைமை உள்ளிட்ட அனைத்து தொடர்புடைய காரணிகளையும் ஆராய வேண்டும். லங்கா\" என்று அவர் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய பிரஜைகளின் பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பாக இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் உள்ளூர் அதிகாரிகளுடன் தொடர்பில் இருப்பதாக அவர் மேலும் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "இந்தியர்கள் இலங்கைக்கு செல்ல வேண்டுமா என்ற கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், \"தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் இந்தியர்கள் இலங்கைக்கு பயணம் செய்வது குறித்து, இந்திய பிரஜைகள் தங்கியிருக்கும் காலத்தில் அவர்களின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் நல்வாழ்வை வலியுறுத்துகிறேன். இலங்கை உட்பட இந்தியாவிற்கு வெளியே, இந்த குறிப்பிட்ட விஷயத்தில், எப்போதும் முக்கிய முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்தது, மேலும் இந்தியர்கள் எச்சரிக்கையுடன் இருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "சைபர் போருக்கான தொழில்நுட்ப அறிவுக்கு ராணுவம் தயாராக இருக்க வேண்டும் - ஜனாதிபதி",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மனிதாபிமானமாக மாறுகிறதா?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}