{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/හොර-අංකයකට-තෙල්-ගන්න-ඇවිත්-කූඩුවේ-ළගිති/1-617102",
  "time_ut": 1658893265,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හොර අංකයකට තෙල් ගන්න ඇවිත් කූඩුවේ ළගිති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "They come to get oil from a fake number and reach the cage",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Wayangoda Police say that a motorcyclist and a bus driver who came to get fuel from Sipetco filling station in Medagampitiya, Weyangoda with fake number plates were arrested along with the respective vehicles.",
        "Two residents of Divulapitiya and Hindenia-Pattigoda areas have been arrested.",
        "As fuel is dispensed according to the last number of the number plate, it was revealed that the number plates were changed to match the last numbers of the day and when the police officers checked the respective motorcycle and bus that came to the fuel station, it was revealed that fake number plates were installed.",
        "The motorcycle and the bus were seized on the instructions of Chief Inspector Channa Vathewa, Police Station Officer, Veyangoda."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sipetco",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Medagampitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divulapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindenia-Pattigoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Channa Vathewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veyangoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හොර අංකයකට තෙල් ගන්න ඇවිත් කූඩුවේ ළගිති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ව්‍යාජ අංක තහඩු සවිි කරගෙන වේයන්ගොඩ මැදගම්පිටිය සිපෙට්කෝ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම් හලෙන් ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට පැමිණි යතුරු පැදි කරුවකු සහ බස් රථ රියදුරකු අදාල වාහන සමග අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව වේයන්ගොඩ පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙසේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ දිවුලපිටිය සහ හීන්දෙනිය-පට්ටිගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකි.",
        "අංක තහඩුවේ අවසාන අංකය අනුව ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීමේ කටයුතු සිදු කෙරෙන බැවින් එදිනට නියමිත අවසාන අංකවලට ගැලපෙන පරිදි මෙසේ අංක තහඩු වෙනස් කර ඉන්දන පිරවුම් හලට පැමිණි අදාළ යතුරු පැදිය හා බස්රථය පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පරීක්ෂා කළ අවස්ථාවේ ව්‍යාජ අංක තහඩු සවිකර ඇති බව අනාවරණය වී තිබිණි.",
        "වේයන්ගොඩ පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක චන්න වෑත්තෑව මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත යතුරු පැදිය සහ බස්රථය අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබිණි ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදගම්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවුලපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දෙණිය-පට්ටිගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්න වතේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේයන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவர்கள் போலி எண்ணில் இருந்து எண்ணெய் பெற வந்து கூண்டுக்கு அடைகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெயங்கொடை மெதகம்பிட்டிய சிபெட்கோ எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் பெறுவதற்காக போலி இலக்கத் தகடுகளுடன் வந்த மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் சாரதியும் பஸ் சாரதியும் குறித்த வாகனங்களுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக வயங்கொடை பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "திவுலபிட்டிய மற்றும் ஹிந்தெனிய - பட்டிகொட பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த இருவரே இவ்வாறு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "நம்பர் பிளேட்டின் கடைசி எண்ணுக்கு ஏற்ப எரிபொருள் விநியோகிக்கப்படுவதால், அன்றைய கடைசி எண்களுக்கு ஏற்றவாறு நம்பர் பிளேட்டுகள் மாற்றப்பட்டிருப்பதும், எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு வந்த அந்தந்த மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் மற்றும் பேருந்தை போலீசார் சோதனையிட்டபோது, ​​அது தெரியவந்தது. போலி நம்பர் பிளேட் பொருத்தப்பட்டது தெரியவந்தது.",
        "வெயாங்கொட பொலிஸ் நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரி பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் சன்ன வத்தேவாவின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளும் பஸ்ஸும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெதகம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திவுலபிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிந்தெனிய-பட்டிகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சன்ன வதேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெயங்கொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}