{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83670/slpp-to-support-ranil-in-parliamentary-vote-for-president",
  "time_ut": 1657882500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP to support Ranil in parliamentary vote for president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP to support Ranil in parliamentary vote for president",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) has decided to support Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe in the parliamentary vote to elect the country’s next President, the party’s general-secretary Sagara Kariyawasam says.",
        "Wickremesinghe, who was appointed the Prime Minister after Mahinda Rajapaksa was forced to step down in early May amidst growing public agitations, was sworn in as the caretaker president today (July 15) soon after Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s resignation from the presidency was made official.",
        "Another frontrunner in the race to become the country’s president is MP Dullas Alahapperuma, who previously served as the Minister of Mass Media in the administration of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "The SLPP arrived at its decision to support Acting President Wickremesinghe after Alahapperuma announced his intention to contest for the presidency when the parliament calls nominations next week.",
        "As announced by Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena this morning, the parliament will elect a new President on July 20 and nominations will be called next Tuesday (July 19).",
        "Following the voting in the House, a Member of Parliament will be appointed for the presidency on July 20."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe after Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "(July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රනිල්ට සහය දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා පැවැත්වෙන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) තීරණය කර ඇති බව එම පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "වැඩෙන මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ මධ්‍යයේ මැයි මස මුලදී මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අගමැති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සිදුවීමෙන් පසු අගමැති ධූරයට පත් වූ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසු භාරකාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අද (ජූලි 15) දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ පාලනයේ ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ද කටයුතු කළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා රටේ ජනාධිපති වීමේ තරගයේ තවත් ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටින අයෙකි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ තීරණය කළේ ලබන සතියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නාමයෝජනා කැදවන අවස්ථාවේදී තමන් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කරන බව අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් අද පෙරවරුවේ ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ පරිදි, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු ජූලි 20 වැනිදා තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා අතර නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීම ලබන අඟහරුවාදා (ජූලි 19) සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "සභාවේ ඡන්ද විමසීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජූලි 20 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු පත් කිරීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලහප්පෙරුමගෙන් පසුව වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "(ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் SLPP ரணிலுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதிகரித்து வரும் மக்கள் போராட்டங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ மே மாத தொடக்கத்தில் பதவி விலக நிர்ப்பந்திக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் ராஜினாமா உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட உடனேயே இன்று (ஜூலை 15) தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் நிர்வாகத்தில் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சராக முன்னர் கடமையாற்றிய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான போட்டியில் மற்றுமொரு முன்னணி நபராவார்.",
        "அடுத்த வாரம் பாராளுமன்றம் வேட்புமனுக்களை கோரும் போது, ​​ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக அழகப்பெரும அறிவித்ததையடுத்து, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஆதரிக்கும் தீர்மானத்திற்கு SLPP வந்தது.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன இன்று காலை அறிவித்தபடி, ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் எனவும், எதிர்வரும் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (ஜூலை 19) வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்படும் எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சபையில் வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் நியமிக்கப்படுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரம்ப மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அழகப்பெருமவுக்குப் பிறகு விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "(ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}