{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/eggs-for-wholesale-traders-at-rs-46/",
  "time_ut": 1662179760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Eggs for wholesale traders at Rs. 46/-",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Eggs for wholesale traders at Rs. 46/-",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's Association says that it has decided to sell an egg for Rs.46/- for wholesale traders who visit Poultry Farms.",
        "The Chairman of the All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's Association Ajith Gunasekara said that the sale of eggs has dropped on recent weeks.",
        "He said that the government has been requested to provide benefits for the egg producers until the issued gazette is revised.",
        "China says it will support consultations for SL debt solution"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rs",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "46/-",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.46/-",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poultry Farms",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Association Ajith Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තොග වෙළෙඳුන්ට බිත්තර රු. 46/-",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කුකුළු ගොවිපළවලට පැමිණෙන තොග වෙළෙඳුන් සඳහා බිත්තරයක් රුපියල් 46/-කට අලෙවි කිරීමට තීරණය කළ බව සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති අජිත් ගුණසේකර මහතා පැවසුවේ පසුගිය සති කිහිපය තුළ බිත්තර අලෙවිය පහත වැටී ඇති බවයි.",
        "නිකුත් කර ඇති ගැසට් පත්‍රය ප්‍රතිශෝධනය කරන තුරු බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදකයින්ට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දෙන ලෙස රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය විසඳුම සඳහා උපදේශන සඳහා සහාය දෙන බව චීනය පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුපියල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "46/-",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.46/-",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුළු ගොවිපලවල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංගමය අජිත් ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෑත සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மொத்த வியாபாரிகளுக்கு முட்டை ரூ. 46/-",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கோழிப்பண்ணைகளுக்கு வருகை தரும் மொத்த வியாபாரிகளுக்கு ஒரு முட்டையை ரூ.46/-க்கு விற்பனை செய்ய தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை கோழி வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வாரங்களில் முட்டை விற்பனை குறைந்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை கோழி வியாபாரிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் அஜித் குணசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வெளியிடப்பட்ட வர்த்தமானியில் திருத்தம் செய்யப்படும் வரை முட்டை உற்பத்தியாளர்களுக்கான சலுகைகளை வழங்குமாறு அரசாங்கத்திடம் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை கடன் தீர்வுக்கான ஆலோசனைகளை ஆதரிப்பதாக சீனா கூறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரூ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "46/-",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.46/-",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழி பண்ணைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை கோழி வணிகர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கம் அஜித் குணசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}