{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/IMF-ප්‍රධානී-සතුටෙන්/11-396874",
  "time_ut": 1662281441,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "IMF ප්‍රධානී සතුටෙන්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF chief happy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "IMF staff and Sri Lankan government officials are very pleased to have reached a staff-level agreement to support the country's economic policies with an Extended Fund Facility of about US$2.9 billion, said Ms. Cristalina George Giova, head of the International Monetary Fund. She said on her Twitter account that this is an important step forward for Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US$2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cristalina George Giova",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF ප්‍රධානී සතුටෙන්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ නිලධාරීන්, ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9ක පමණ විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමක් සමඟින් රටේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීම පිළිබඳව තමන් ඉතා සතුටට පත්වන බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රධානී ක්‍රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර් ජියෝවා මහත්මිය  පැවැසුවාය. මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැදගත් ඉදිරි පියවරක් බව ඇය සිය ට්විටර් ගිණුමෙන් පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර්ජ් ජියෝවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF தலைவர் மகிழ்ச்சி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "IMF ஊழியர்களும் இலங்கை அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகளும் சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களின் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியுடன் நாட்டின் பொருளாதார கொள்கைகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்பாட்டை எட்டியதில் மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சியடைவதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் தலைவர் திருமதி கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜோர்ஜ் ஜியோவா தெரிவித்தார். இது இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான முன்னெடுப்பு என அவர் தனது டுவிட்டர் கணக்கில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜார்ஜ் ஜியோவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}