{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/if-dullas-wins-sajith-will-be-pm-in-all-party-govt-sri-lanka-opposition-mp-97644/",
  "time_ut": 1658221260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "If Dullas wins, Sajith will be PM in all-party govt: Sri Lanka opposition MP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "If Dullas wins, Sajith will be PM in all-party govt: Sri Lanka opposition MP",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – If Sri Lanka’s ruling party presidential candidate Dullas Alahapperuma wins an all-important election to be held in parliament, an all-party government will be formed with incumbent opposition leader Sajith Premadasa as prime minister, an opposition lawmaker said.",
        "“We’re forming an all-party government. We laid the foundations of this all-party government about two to three weeks ago. This is the beginning of the programme that people want to see, of everyone coming together to save the country,” main opposition Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) general secretary MP Ranjith Madduma Bandara said.",
        "According to Bandara, Premadasa made a sacrifice and took a decision with the country in mind when he backed out of the vote at the last minute.",
        "“People want a new political journey. At a time when sacrifices has to be made for the country, our leader sacrificed position and took a decision as a party for the country,”",
        "The MP confirmed agreement had “definitely” been reached to appoint Premadasa as prime minister under the interim presidency of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) MP Dullas Alahapperuma. Premadasa proposed Alahapperuma’s name in his place when parliament called nominations on Tuesday, which was then seconded by SLPP chairman G L Peiris.",
        "The MP added that SLPP members will likely be part of the next cabinet if Alahapperuma wins.",
        "Meanwhile, SLPP Chairman Peiris said the party is behind an Alahapperuma-Premadasa government. However, sections of the SLPP have expressed support for Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe who is also contesting.",
        "Sri Lanka ruling party majority behind Dullas; Sajith to be PM: G L"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about two to three weeks ago",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last minute",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G L Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G L",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස් දිනුවොත් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ අගමැති සජිත්: ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන ඉතා වැදගත් මැතිවරණයකින් ජයග්‍රහණය කළහොත් වත්මන් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අගමැති කර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන බව විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් හදනවා. අපි මේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවට අඩිතාලම දැම්මේ මීට සති දෙක තුනකට විතර කලින්. රට බේරාගැනීම සඳහා සියලු දෙනාම එකතුවීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළේ ආරම්භය මෙයයි” යැයි ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ (SJB) ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරට අනුව ප්‍රේමදාස අන්තිම මොහොතේ ඡන්දයෙන් ඉවත් වූ විට රට ගැන සිතා බලා කැපකිරීමක් කර තීන්දුවක් ගත්තේය.",
        "“මිනිසුන්ට අලුත් දේශපාලන ගමනක් අවශ්‍යයි. රට වෙනුවෙන් කැපකිරීම් කළ යුතු මොහොතක අපේ නායකයා තනතුර පූජා කරලා පක්ෂයක් විදියට රට වෙනුවෙන් තීන්දුවක් ගත්තා”",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාගේ අන්තර්වාර සභාපතිත්වය යටතේ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කිරීමට “අනිවාර්‍යෙන්ම” එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ ඇති බව මන්ත්‍රීවරයා තහවුරු කළේය. අඟහරුවාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නාමයෝජනා කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ප්‍රේමදාස ඔහු වෙනුවට අලහප්පෙරුමගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති ජී එල් පීරිස් විසින් ස්ථිර කරන ලදී.",
        "අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ජයග්‍රහණය කළහොත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් මීළඟ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඇතුළත් වීමට ඉඩ ඇති බවද මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති පීරිස් පැවසුවේ පක්ෂය අලහප්පෙරුම-ප්‍රේමදාස ආණ්ඩුවක් පිටුපස සිටින බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ කොටස් ද තරඟ වදින වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට සහය පළ කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඩලස් පිටුපස ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ බහුතරය; සජිත් අගමැති වෙයි: ජී එල්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති දෙක තුනකට විතර කලින්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන මිනිත්තුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸ் வெற்றி பெற்றால் அனைத்து கட்சி ஆட்சியில் சஜித் பிரதமராவார்: இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் ஆளும் கட்சி ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ள அனைத்து முக்கியமான தேர்தலில் வெற்றி பெற்றால், தற்போதைய எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச பிரதமராக சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படும் என்று எதிர்க்கட்சி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்குகிறோம். இந்த சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் அடித்தளத்தை இரண்டு மூன்று வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் நாங்கள் அமைத்தோம். நாட்டைக் காப்பாற்ற அனைவரும் ஒன்றிணைவதன் மூலம் மக்கள் பார்க்க விரும்பும் வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் ஆரம்பம் இதுவாகும் என பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பண்டாரவின் கூற்றுப்படி, பிரேமதாச ஒரு தியாகம் செய்து கடைசி நிமிடத்தில் வாக்களிப்பில் இருந்து பின்வாங்கிய போது நாட்டை மனதில் வைத்து ஒரு முடிவை எடுத்தார்.",
        "“மக்கள் புதிய அரசியல் பயணத்தை விரும்புகிறார்கள். நாட்டிற்காக தியாகம் செய்ய வேண்டிய நேரத்தில், எங்கள் தலைவர் பதவியை தியாகம் செய்து, நாட்டுக்காக கட்சி என்ற முடிவை எடுத்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியின் கீழ் பிரேமதாசவை பிரதமராக நியமிப்பதற்கு \"நிச்சயமாக\" உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார். செவ்வாய்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றம் வேட்புமனுக்களை அழைத்தபோது பிரேமதாச அவருக்கு பதிலாக அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயரை முன்மொழிந்தார், பின்னர் SLPP தலைவர் ஜி எல் பீரிஸ் அதை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "அழகப்பெரும வெற்றி பெற்றால் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்கள் அடுத்த அமைச்சரவையில் அங்கம் வகிப்பார்கள் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, அழகப்பெரும-பிரேமதாச அரசாங்கத்தின் பின்னணியில் கட்சி இருப்பதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். எவ்வாறாயினும், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சில பிரிவினர் போட்டியிடும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவை வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "டலஸ் பின்னால் இலங்கை ஆளும் கட்சி பெரும்பான்மை; சஜித் பிரதமராவார்: ஜி எல்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் இரண்டு மூன்று வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நிமிடம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}