{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/nsb-becomes-most-popular-banking-finance-website-for-second-consecutive-year/",
  "time_ut": 1662311400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NSB becomes Most Popular Banking & Finance Website for second consecutive year",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NSB becomes Most Popular Banking & Finance Website for second consecutive year",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "The corporate website of NSB (www.nsb.lk) was awarded the Most Popular Banking & Finance website along with the merit award for Best Banking & Finance website at BestWeb.lk awards ceremony organized by LK Domain Registry on 30th of August 2022 at the Cinnamon Grand.",
        "www.nsb.lk has been continuously recognized and rewarded for its performance and this is the second consecutive year of NSB being ranked the most popular Banking & Finance website. Further to that, the website has been recognized as the best Sri Lankan website in 2020.",
        "The award was received by the Chairperson of NSB Keasila Jayawardane, GM/CEO of NSB- Ajith Peiris, Directors- Jayantha Perera, Lakshman Gamini and the Senior DGM- K. Raveendran. The event was honored by the participation of members of the corporate management of NSB.",
        "A strong international support base for Sri Lanka to get assurances from its creditors",
        "JICA launches three-year technical cooperation project with SLCG on oil spill response capability improvement",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NSB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Popular Banking & Finance",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "second consecutive year",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Popular Banking & Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Best Banking & Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LK Domain Registry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th of August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Grand",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the second consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Banking & Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Keasila Jayawardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Gamini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Senior DGM- K. Raveendran",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "NSB අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර සඳහා වඩාත්ම ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය වෙබ් අඩවිය බවට පත් වේ",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "NSB හි ආයතනික වෙබ් අඩවිය (www.nsb.lk) 2022 අගෝස්තු 30 වන දින LK වසම් රෙජිස්ට්‍රි විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද BestWeb.lk සම්මාන උළෙලේදී හොඳම බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය වෙබ් අඩවිය සඳහා වන කුසලතා සම්මානය සමඟින් වඩාත් ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය වෙබ් අඩවියට හිමි සම්මානයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබීය. කුරුඳු ග්‍රෑන්ඩ්.",
        "www.nsb.lk එහි කාර්ය සාධනය සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව ඇගයීමට ලක්ව ත්‍යාග පිරිනමන ලද අතර NSB වඩාත් ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය වෙබ් අඩවිය ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර වේ. ඊට අමතරව, මෙම වෙබ් අඩවිය 2020 වසරේ හොඳම ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය වෙබ් අඩවිය ලෙසද පිළිගෙන ඇත.",
        "NSB හි සභාපතිනි කේසිලා ජයවර්ධන, NSB හි GM/CEO- අජිත් පීරිස්, අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන්- ජයන්ත පෙරේරා, ලක්ෂ්මන් ගාමිණී සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය GM- K. රවීන්ද්‍රන් විසින් මෙම සම්මානය ලබා ගන්නා ලදී. NSB හි ආයතනික කළමනාකාරීත්වයේ සාමාජිකයින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් මෙම අවස්ථාවට උපහාර දැක්වීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එහි ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් සහතික ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ශක්තිමත් ජාත්‍යන්තර ආධාරක පදනමක්",
        "JICA තෙල් කාන්දු ප්‍රතිචාර හැකියාව වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා SLCG සමඟ තෙවසරක තාක්ෂණික සහයෝගීතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය දියත් කරයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NSB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මුල්‍ය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මුල්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොඳම බැංකු සහ මුල්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LK වසම් රෙජිස්ට්රි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cinnamon Grand",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකු සහ මුල්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේසිල ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීඑම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් ගාමිණී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ DGM - K. රවීන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "NSB தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டாக மிகவும் பிரபலமான வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி இணையதளம் ஆகும்",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 30, 2022 அன்று LK டொமைன் ரெஜிஸ்ட்ரி ஏற்பாடு செய்த BestWeb.lk விருது வழங்கும் விழாவில், NSB இன் கார்ப்பரேட் இணையதளம் (www.nsb.lk) மிகவும் பிரபலமான வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி இணையதளம் மற்றும் சிறந்த வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி இணையதளத்திற்கான தகுதி விருது வழங்கப்பட்டது. இலவங்கப்பட்டை கிராண்ட்.",
        "www.nsb.lk ஆனது அதன் செயல்திறனுக்காக தொடர்ச்சியாக அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டு வெகுமதிகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளது. மேலும் NSB தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டாக மிகவும் பிரபலமான வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி இணையத்தளமாக தரவரிசைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. மேலும், இந்த இணையதளம் 2020ல் சிறந்த இலங்கை இணையதளமாக அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விருதை NSB இன் தலைவி கெசிலா ஜெயவர்தன, NSB இன் GM/CEO- அஜித் பீரிஸ், இயக்குநர்கள்- ஜெயந்த பெரேரா, லக்ஷ்மன் காமினி மற்றும் மூத்த DGM- K. ரவீந்திரன் ஆகியோர் பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர். இந்நிகழ்வில் NSB நிறுவன நிர்வாகத்தின் உறுப்பினர்கள் கலந்து கொண்டு கௌரவிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "கடனாளர்களிடமிருந்து உறுதிமொழிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கு இலங்கைக்கான வலுவான சர்வதேச ஆதரவு தளம்",
        "JICA எண்ணெய் கசிவு மறுமொழி திறன் மேம்பாட்டில் SLCG உடன் மூன்று ஆண்டு தொழில்நுட்ப ஒத்துழைப்பு திட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "என்.எஸ்.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிரபலமான வங்கி & நிதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டு",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபலமான வங்கி & நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறந்த வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LK டொமைன் ரெஜிஸ்ட்ரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலவங்கப்பட்டை கிராண்ட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி & நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேசிலா ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் காமினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூத்த டிஜிஎம்- கே. ரவீந்திரன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}