{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Two-suspects-wanted-for-gem-theft-worth-over-Rs-158Mn-arrested/108-242107",
  "time_ut": 1659242019,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two suspects wanted for gem theft worth over Rs. 158Mn arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two suspects wanted for gem theft worth over Rs. 158Mn arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two suspects have been arrested by the Colombo Crime Division (CCD) in connection with the theft of a safe containing precious gemstones worth over Rs. 158 million in Cinnamon Garden, Colombo.",
        "Police said the CCD launched investigations on a complaint received at the Cinnamon Garden  Police that a safe containing gemstones from a business place located in the Alexandra area was stolen.",
        "During the investigation, it was revealed that the value of stolen gems was Rs. 158,735,000.",
        "The CCD arrested two suspects involved in the theft on Saturday in the Grandpass area. The police also found 10 grams and 385 milligrams of heroin in suspects possession at the time of the arrest.",
        "During the questioning of the suspects, the safe with 16 stolen gems, a van used for the theft and two mobile phones were taken into police custody.",
        "Police said Investigations are underway to find the remaining suspects involved in the theft and the gemstones.",
        "The arrested suspects, aged 23 and 25, are residents of Welimada, Lunuwatta.",
        "They will be produced before the Maligakanda  Magistrate's Court.(Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "158 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cinnamon Garden",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Garden  Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alexandra",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "158,735,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16 stolen",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 and 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welimada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lunuwatta",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maligakanda  Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික මැණික් සොරකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු අවශ්‍යයි. මිලියන 158ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනා මැණික් ගල් සහිත සේප්පුවක් සොරකම් කිරීමේ සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය (CCD) විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ. මිලියන 158ක් කොළඹ කුරුඳුවත්තේ.",
        "පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩ්‍රා ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ව්‍යාපාරික ස්ථානයක මැණික් ගල් සහිත සේප්පුවක් සොරකම් කර ඇති බවට කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසියට ලැබුණු පැමිණිල්ලක් මත CCD විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කළ බවයි.",
        "විමර්ශනයේදී සොරාගත් මැණික් තොගයේ වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටි 1000 ක් බව අනාවරණය විය. 158,735,000 කි.",
        "මෙම සොරකමට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ග්‍රෑන්ඩ්පාස් ප්‍රදේශයේදී සීසීඩීය විසින් සෙනසුරාදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා. අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා අවස්ථාවේදී සැකකරුවන් සන්තකයේ තිබී හෙරොයින් ග්‍රෑම් 10 යි මිලිග්‍රෑම් 385 ක් ද පොලිසිය විසින් සොයාගෙන තිබේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන්ගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදී සොරාගත් මැණික් ගල් 16ක් සහිත සේප්පුව, සොරකම සඳහා යොදාගත් වෑන් රථයක් සහ ජංගම දුරකථන දෙකක් පොලිස් භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම සොරකමට සම්බන්ධ ඉතිරි සැකකරුවන් සහ මැණික් ගල් සොයා විමර්ශන ක්‍රියාත්මක බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් අවුරුදු 23 සහ 25 වයස්වල පසුවන වැලිමඩ, ලුණුවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන්.",
        "ඔවුන් මාලිගාකන්ද  මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.(දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 158 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩ්රා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "158,735,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 10 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16ක් සොරකම් කළා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 සහ 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිමඞ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුණුවත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාකන්ද  මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான இரத்தினக்கல் திருடப்பட்ட இரு சந்தேகநபர்கள் தேடப்பட்டு வருகின்றனர். 158 மில்லியன் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரண்டு இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான பெறுமதியான இரத்தினக் கற்கள் அடங்கிய பெட்டகத்தை திருடிய சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் இரண்டு சந்தேகநபர்கள் கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினரால் (CCD) கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். கொழும்பு கறுவாத்தோட்டத்தில் 158 மில்லியன்.",
        "அலெக்ஸாண்ட்ரா பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள வர்த்தக ஸ்தலமொன்றில் இருந்து இரத்தினக் கற்கள் அடங்கிய பெட்டகம் திருடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கறுவாத்தோட்டம் பொலிஸில் பெறப்பட்ட முறைப்பாட்டின் அடிப்படையில் CCD விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "விசாரணையில், திருடப்பட்ட ரத்தினக் கற்களின் மதிப்பு ரூ. 158,735,000.",
        "நேற்று சனிக்கிழமை கிராண்ட்பாஸ் பகுதியில் வைத்து திருட்டில் ஈடுபட்ட இரு சந்தேக நபர்களை சிசிடி அதிகாரிகள் கைது செய்துள்ளனர். கைது செய்யப்பட்ட போது சந்தேகநபர்கள் வைத்திருந்த 10 கிராம் 385 மில்லிகிராம் ஹெரோயின் போதைப் பொருளையும் பொலிஸார் கண்டுபிடித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களிடம் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசாரணைகளின் போது, ​​திருடப்பட்ட 16 மாணிக்கக் கற்கள் அடங்கிய பெட்டகம், திருடப் பயன்படுத்திய வேன் மற்றும் இரண்டு கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகள் பொலிஸாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "திருட்டு மற்றும் மாணிக்கக் கற்களுடன் தொடர்புடைய எஞ்சிய சந்தேக நபர்களைக் கண்டறிய விசாரணைகள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 23 மற்றும் 25 வயதுடைய வெலிமடை, லுனுவத்தை பகுதியை சேர்ந்தவர்கள்.",
        "அவர்கள் மாளிகாகந்த  நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளனர்.(தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "158 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலவங்கப்பட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிசிடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கறுவாத்தோட்டம்  போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்ஸாண்ட்ரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "158,735,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிசிடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16 திருடப்பட்டது",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 மற்றும் 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிமடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லுனுவத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாகந்த  நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}