{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මිලියන-9ක්-වටිනා-කේරළ-ගංජා-නාවික-හමුදා-භාරයට/11-395529",
  "time_ut": 1658209718,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මිලියන 9ක් වටිනා කේරළ ගංජා නාවික හමුදා භාරයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kerala Ganja worth 9 million in Navy custody",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In a special operation carried out by the Navy yesterday (18th) to chase away the Indian fishing vessels that carried out illegal fishing activities in the territorial waters belonging to Sri Lanka, the navy seized a stock of 30 kg (wet weight) of Kerala ganja floating in the sea near Kachchathivu Island. Worked out.",
        "In this special operation carried out yesterday (18th), 09 parcels floating near the island of Kachchativ were deployed to expel the Indian fishing boats that had illegally entered the territorial waters of the country by deploying the P412 fast fighter belonging to the fourth fast attack squadron attached to the Northern Naval Command. An amount of about 30 kg (wet weight) of Kerala ganja was taken into custody by the Navy.",
        "It is suspected that the smugglers may have abandoned this Kerala ganja without being able to bring it to the land due to the naval operations, and the gross street value of this stock of Kerala ganja is believed to be around 9 million rupees.",
        "Further, the Kerala Ganja stock seized by the Navy has been kept in the Navy's custody pending further legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerala Ganja",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kachchathivu Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kachchativ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 30 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිලියන 9ක් වටිනා කේරළ ගංජා නාවික හමුදා භාරයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අයත් මුහුදු සීමාව තුළ අනවසර ධීවර කටයුතු සිදු කල ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීම සඳහා ඊයේ (18දා)  නාවික හමුදාව විසින් සිදුකල විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී, කච්චතිව් දූපත අසල මුහුදේ පාවෙමින් තිබූ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 30 ක (තෙත බර සහිතව) පමණ තොගයක් නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත හතරවන වේග ප්‍රහාරක බලඝණයට අයත් පී 412 වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව යොදවා මෙරට මුහුදු සීමාව තුලට අනවසරයෙන් ඇතුළු වූ ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රා මෙරට මුහුදු සීමාවෙන් ඔබ්බට පළවා හැරීම සඳහා  ඊයේ (18දා) සිදුකල මෙම විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමේදී, කච්චතිව් දූපත අසල පාවෙමින් තිබූ පාර්සල් 09 ක අසුරන ලද කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 30 ක (තෙත බර සහිත) පමණ ප්‍රමාණයක් මෙලෙස නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙ‍රිණි",
        "නාවික හමුදා මෙහෙයුම් හමුවේ ගොඩබිමට රැගෙන ඒමට නොහැකිව ජාවාරම්කරුවන් විසින් මෙම කේරළ ගංජා මෙලෙස අතහැර දමන්නට ඇතැයි සැකකෙරෙන අතර, මෙම කේරළ ගංජා තොගයේ දළ වීථි වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 9 ක් පමණ වෙතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "තවද, නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගය ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා යොමු කරන තෙක් නාවික හමුදා භාරයේ තබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 9 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 30 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව් දූපත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 30 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "9 மில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள கேரள கஞ்சா கடற்படை காவலில் உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு சொந்தமான கடற்பரப்பில் அத்துமீறி மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்ட இந்திய மீன்பிடி படகுகளை விரட்டியடிப்பதற்காக கடற்படையினர் நேற்று (18) மேற்கொண்ட விசேட நடவடிக்கையில் 30 கிலோகிராம் (ஈரமான எடை) கொண்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர். கச்சத்தீவு அருகே கடலில் மிதக்கிறது.",
        "நேற்று (18ஆம் திகதி) மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இந்த விசேட நடவடிக்கையில் நான்காவது விரைவுப் போர்ப் படைக்கு சொந்தமான பி 412 விரைவுப் போர்க்கப்பலை நிலைநிறுத்தி நாட்டுக் கடற்பரப்பிற்குள் சட்டவிரோதமாக அத்துமீறி நுழைந்த இந்திய மீன்பிடி படகுகளை வெளியேற்றுவதற்காக கச்சத்தீவுக்கு அருகில் மிதக்கும் 09 பொதிகள் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டன. வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.சுமார் 30 கிலோ (ஈரமான எடை) கேரள கஞ்சா கடற்படையினரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "கடற்படை நடவடிக்கையின் காரணமாக இந்த கேரள கஞ்சாவை நிலத்திற்கு கொண்டு வர முடியாமல் கடத்தல்காரர்கள் கைவிட்டு சென்றிருக்கலாம் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது, மேலும் இந்த கேரளா கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த தெரு மதிப்பு சுமார் 9 மில்லியன் ரூபா என நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "மேலும், கடற்படையினரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சா கையிருப்பு மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக கடற்படையினரின் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 30 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}