{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Economic-hardships-could-persist-as-bridge-financing-remains-a-long-shot/108-241476",
  "time_ut": 1658357413,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Economic hardships could persist as bridge financing remains a long shot",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Economic hardships could persist as bridge financing remains a long shot",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Stalled IMF talks could resume with Parliament electing a new president yesterday",
        "“Until time we sign an agreement with IMF and restructure debt, it is going to be tough”- CB governor",
        "Lankan authorities expect more financing support from India and China",
        "The current economic conditions could grind on till Sri Lanka strikes an agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), which will unlock other sources of funding, as bridge financing, which the authorities were hoping for in the interim, remains hard to come by, according to Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe.",
        "The Sri Lankan economy came to an abrupt halt in mid-June after the bridge funding line from India to import fuel and other essentials came to an end, while attempts to obtain credit lines from elsewhere, including China, which was once a close bilateral ally of Sri Lanka, haven’t so far materialised.",
        "“If we get some assistance from either India or China in this interim, we can manage this period. We are discussing with them. What we think is, if we get (assistance), things could ease somewhat, if not we will have to continue like this,” Dr. Weerasinghe said.",
        "It was recently reported that both India and China may consider further financing to Sri Lanka. India has already extended US $ 3.8 billion worth of assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "Sri Lankan authorities remain hopeful of US $ 4 billion from China, of which the negotiations are ongoing.   Sri Lankans are still in miles-long queues for days for fuel and have been suffering from rolling power cuts for seven months. They have crippled enterprises and lifestyles, as the country doesn’t generate sufficient dollars to import fuel to keep its economy humming.   “Until the time we sign an agreement with the IMF and restructure debt, it is going to be tough,” Dr. Weerasinghe told reporters a few days ago after raising policy rates to further compress demand to rein in inflation.",
        "The only tool the central banks around the world have is the interest rates to ensure price stability and what they do is increase the cost of money through raising the interest rates to bring the demand in parity with the available supply.  Mirror Business last week showed that the imports are on course to fall in line with the export earnings after aggressive policy tightening since April by the Central Bank.  “What we can import is what we get from exports and what we collect from remittances. So, until that, we will have to import only the essentials and cut down on non-essentials and that adjustment is happening,” Dr. Weerasinghe said.  It is largely expected that Sri Lanka could resume its IMF talks following the election of Ranil Wicremesinghe as the President by Parliament, yesterday. Although Wickremesinghe’s Cabinet is still in the making, the immediate appointment of a finance minister will help Sri Lanka to reach a staff-level agreement with the IMF in the coming few weeks."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "mid-June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mirror Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wicremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාලම් මූල්‍යකරණය දිගු කාලයක් පවතින බැවින් ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා පැවතිය හැකිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමත් සමඟ ඇනහිට ඇති IMF සාකච්ඡා නැවත ආරම්භ විය හැකිය",
        "\"අපි IMF සමඟ ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කරන තුරු සහ ණය ප්රතිව්යුහගත කරන තුරු, එය දැඩි වනු ඇත\" - CB ආණ්ඩුකාර",
        "ලංකා බලධාරීන් ඉන්දියාවෙන් සහ චීනයෙන් වැඩි මූල්‍ය ආධාර අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹෙන තෙක් වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය ඇඹරීමට ඉඩ ඇති අතර එමඟින් අනෙකුත් අරමුදල් ප්‍රභවයන් අගුළු හරිනු ඇත, මන්ද බලධාරීන් තාවකාලිකව බලාපොරොත්තු වූ පාලම් මූල්‍යකරණය ලබා ගැනීම දුෂ්කර ය. මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහට අනුව.",
        "ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා පාලම් අරමුදල් මාර්ගය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය ජූනි මස මැද භාගයේදී හදිසියේම නතර වූ අතර, කලක් සමීප ද්විපාර්ශ්වික මිතුරෙකු වූ චීනය ඇතුළු වෙනත් තැන්වලින් ණය මාර්ග ලබා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ, මෙතෙක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වී නැත.",
        "“මේ අතරවාරයේදී අපට ඉන්දියාවෙන් හෝ චීනයෙන් යම් සහයක් ලැබුණොත් අපට මෙම කාලසීමාව කළමනාකරණය කරගත හැකියි. අපි ඔවුන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරනවා. අපි හිතන දේ තමයි අපිට (සහාය) ලැබුණොත් යම් තරමකට හෝ සහනයක් වෙන්න පුළුවන්, එහෙම නොවුණොත් අපිට මේ විදියටම කරගෙන යන්න වෙනවා,” වෛද්‍ය වීරසිංහ පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තවදුරටත් මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් සැලසීම පිළිබඳව සලකා බලනු ඇතැයි පසුගියදා වාර්තා විය. ඉන්දියාව දැනටමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8ක ආධාර ලබාදී ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් චීනයෙන් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 ක් බලාපොරොත්තු වන අතර, එයින් සාකච්ඡා සිදු වෙමින් පවතී. ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් තවමත් ඉන්ධන සඳහා දින ගණන් සැතපුම් ගණන් පෝලිම්වල සිටින අතර මාස හතක් තිස්සේ පෙරළෙන විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීමෙන් පීඩා විඳිති. රටේ ආර්ථිකය හූල්ලමින් තබා ගැනීම සඳහා ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඩොලර් උත්පාදනය නොකිරීම නිසා ඔවුන් ව්‍යවසායන් සහ ජීවන රටා අඩපණ කර ඇත. “අපි ජාමූඅ සමඟ ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කර ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරන තුරු එය දැඩි වනු ඇත,” ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ දින කිහිපයකට පෙර උද්ධමනය පාලනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉල්ලුම තවදුරටත් සංකෝචනය කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්ති අනුපාත ඉහළ නැංවීමෙන් පසු වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "ලොව පුරා මහ බැංකු සතුව ඇති එකම මෙවලම මිල ස්ථායිතාව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා පොලී අනුපාත වන අතර ඔවුන් කරන්නේ පවතින සැපයුමට සමාන ඉල්ලුමක් ගෙන ඒම සඳහා පොලී අනුපාත ඉහළ නැංවීම හරහා මුදල් පිරිවැය වැඩි කිරීමයි. පසුගිය සතියේ මිරර් බිස්නස් පෙන්වා දුන්නේ මහ බැංකුව විසින් අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ සිට ආක්‍රමණශීලී ප්‍රතිපත්ති දැඩි කිරීමෙන් පසු අපනයන ආදායමට අනුකූලව ආනයන පහත වැටෙනු ඇති බවයි. “අපට ආනයනය කළ හැක්කේ අපනයනයෙන් අපට ලැබෙන දේ සහ ප්‍රේෂණවලින් අප එකතු කරන දෙයයි. ඉතින් එතෙක් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය දේ පමණක් ආනයනය කර අත්‍යවශ්‍ය නොවන දේ කපා හැරීමට සිදු වන අතර එම ගැලපීම සිදුවෙමින් පවතින බවද ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය. ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා නැවත ආරම්භ කරනු ඇතැයි බොහෝ දුරට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය තවමත් සකස් වෙමින් පවතින නමුත්, වහාම මුදල් ඇමතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීම, ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය තුළ IMF සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාරී වනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැතපුම්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිරර් ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாலம் நிதியுதவி நீண்ட காலமாக இருப்பதால் பொருளாதார கஷ்டங்கள் நீடிக்கலாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை பாராளுமன்றம் நேற்று தெரிவு செய்வதன் மூலம் தடைப்பட்ட IMF பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் மீண்டும் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படலாம்",
        "\"நாங்கள் IMF உடன் ஒரு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திடும் வரை மற்றும் கடனை மறுசீரமைக்கும் வரை, அது கடினமாக இருக்கும்\" - சிபி கவர்னர்",
        "இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவிடம் இருந்து அதிக நிதி உதவியை எதிர்பார்க்கின்றனர்",
        "இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) உடன்படிக்கையை மேற்கொள்ளும் வரை தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமைகள் பாதிக்கப்படலாம், இது மற்ற நிதி ஆதாரங்களைத் திறக்கும், ஏனெனில் அதிகாரிகள் இடைக்காலமாக எதிர்பார்க்கும் பாலம் நிதியளிப்பது கடினமாக உள்ளது. என மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஒரு காலத்தில் நெருங்கிய இருதரப்பு நட்பு நாடாக இருந்த சீனா உட்பட பிற நாடுகளிலிருந்து கடன் பெறுவதற்கான முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட அதேவேளையில், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான பிரிட்ஜ் நிதி வரி இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து முடிவுக்கு வந்ததை அடுத்து, ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதியில் இலங்கைப் பொருளாதாரம் திடீரென நிறுத்தப்பட்டது. இலங்கையின், இதுவரை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படவில்லை.",
        "“இந்த இடைக்காலத்தில் இந்தியா அல்லது சீனாவிடம் இருந்து சில உதவிகளைப் பெற்றால், இந்தக் காலகட்டத்தை நாம் சமாளிக்க முடியும். அவர்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடி வருகிறோம். நாம் நினைப்பது என்னவென்றால், நமக்கு (உதவி) கிடைத்தால், விஷயங்கள் ஓரளவு எளிதாகிவிடும், இல்லையென்றால் நாங்கள் இப்படியே தொடர வேண்டியிருக்கும், ”என்று டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு மேலும் நிதியுதவி செய்வது குறித்து இந்தியாவும் சீனாவும் பரிசீலிக்கலாம் என்று சமீபத்தில் தகவல் வெளியானது. இந்தியா ஏற்கனவே 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான உதவிகளை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் சீனாவிடமிருந்து 4 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் பெறுவார்கள் என்ற நம்பிக்கையில் உள்ளனர், அதில் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் நடந்து வருகின்றன. இலங்கையர்கள் எரிபொருளுக்காக மைல்கள் நீண்ட வரிசையில் இன்னும் பல நாட்களாக நிற்கின்றனர் மற்றும் ஏழு மாதங்களாக உருட்டல் மின்வெட்டு காரணமாக அவதிப்படுகின்றனர். நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை முணுமுணுக்க எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய போதுமான டாலர்களை உற்பத்தி செய்யாததால், அவை நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் வாழ்க்கை முறைகளை முடக்கியுள்ளன. \"நாங்கள் IMF உடன் ஒரு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திடும் வரை மற்றும் கடனை மறுசீரமைக்கும் வரை, அது கடினமாக இருக்கும்,\" என்று டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு பணவீக்கத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த தேவையை மேலும் சுருக்க கொள்கை விகிதங்களை உயர்த்திய பின்னர் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள மத்திய வங்கிகளிடம் உள்ள ஒரே கருவி விலை ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை உறுதி செய்வதற்கான வட்டி விகிதங்கள் ஆகும், மேலும் அவை என்ன செய்வது, வட்டி விகிதங்களை உயர்த்துவதன் மூலம் பணச் செலவை அதிகரித்து, கிடைக்கக்கூடிய விநியோகத்திற்கு சமமான தேவையைக் கொண்டுவருகிறது. கடந்த வாரம் மிரர் பிசினஸ், மத்திய வங்கியால் ஏப்ரலில் இருந்து தீவிரமான கொள்கை இறுக்கத்திற்குப் பிறகு ஏற்றுமதி வருவாய்க்கு ஏற்ப இறக்குமதிகள் வீழ்ச்சியடையும் என்று காட்டியது. \"நாம் இறக்குமதி செய்யக்கூடியது, ஏற்றுமதியிலிருந்து நாம் பெறுவது மற்றும் பணம் அனுப்புவதில் இருந்து நாம் சேகரிப்பது. எனவே, அதுவரை அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களை மட்டும் இறக்குமதி செய்துவிட்டு, அத்தியாவசியமற்ற பொருட்களைக் குறைத்து, சரிசெய்தல் நடக்கிறது” என்று டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க கூறினார். ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாக நேற்று பாராளுமன்றம் தெரிவு செய்ததை அடுத்து இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மீண்டும் ஆரம்பிக்கலாம் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அமைச்சரவை இன்னும் உருவாக்கத்தில் இருந்தாலும், உடனடியாக நிதியமைச்சர் நியமிக்கப்படுவது, எதிர்வரும் சில வாரங்களில் IMF உடன் பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்பாட்டை எட்டுவதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு உதவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்ணாடி வணிகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அமைச்சரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் சில வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}