{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83281/top-us-officials-visiting-sri-lanka-meet-pm-for-talks",
  "time_ut": 1656313920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Top US officials visiting Sri Lanka meet PM for talks",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Top US officials visiting Sri Lanka meet PM for talks",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting high-level delegation of officials representing the US State Department and the Treasury Department met with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, a short while ago, for a discussion, the PM’s Office said.",
        "The delegation including officials from the U.S. Department of the Treasury and the U.S. Department of State had arrived in Sri Lanka yesterday morning for a three-day visit.",
        "Members of the delegation include Deputy Assistant Secretary of Treasury for Asia Robert Kaproth and Ambassador Kelly Keiderling, who is also the Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia.",
        "The visitors are expected to meet with a wide range of political representatives, economists, and international organizations in Sri Lanka from June 26 - 29, the U.S. Embassy in Colombo says.",
        "In all their meetings, they will explore the most effective ways for the U.S. to support Sri Lankans in need, Sri Lankans working to resolve the current economic crisis, and Sri Lankans planning for a sustainable and inclusive economy for the future, the U.S. Embassy said further.",
        "Over the past two weeks, the U.S. has announced $120 million in new financing for Sri Lankan small and medium-sized businesses, a $27 million contribution to Sri Lanka’s dairy industry and $5.75 million in humanitarian assistance to help those hit hardest by the economic crisis.",
        "The United States also committed $6 million in new grants to provide livelihood assistance to vulnerable populations, and technical assistance on financial reform that will help stabilize the economy.",
        "In the coming months, the U.S. will continue to support Sri Lankans as they revive their economy, combat food insecurity, and promote public health and education, the statement said.",
        "The United States said it also strongly supports Sri Lanka’s decision to seek assistance from the International Monetary Fund, which can provide the most durable resolution to the present crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the US State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Treasury Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM’s Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Department of the Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 26 - 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$120 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$27 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$5.75 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන අමෙරිකාවේ ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් සාකච්ඡා සඳහා අගමැති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරමින් පැමිණ සිටින ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවී සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වූ බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "ඇමෙරිකානු භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සහ ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් ඇතුළු දූත පිරිස තෙදින සංචාරයක් සඳහා ඊයේ පෙරවරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ තිබුණි.",
        "දූත පිරිසට ආසියාව සඳහා භාණ්ඩාගාර නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් රොබට් කප්‍රෝත් සහ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ද වන තානාපති කෙලී කීඩර්ලින් ද ඇතුළත් වෙති.",
        "මෙම අමුත්තන් ජුනි 26 සිට 29 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන නියෝජිතයන්, ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන රාශියක් හමුවීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කොළඹ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ සියලුම රැස්වීම් වලදී, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට සහාය වීමට එක්සත් ජනපදයට වඩාත් ඵලදායී ක්‍රම, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමට කටයුතු කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සහ අනාගතය සඳහා තිරසාර සහ සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් ආර්ථිකයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සැලසුම් කරන බව එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි. තව දුරටත්.",
        "පසුගිය සති දෙක තුළ, එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍යම ප්‍රමාණයේ ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා නව මූල්‍යකරණයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 120 ක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිරි කර්මාන්තයට ඩොලර් මිලියන 27 ක දායකත්වයක් සහ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 5.75 මානුෂීය ආධාර ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ජනගහනයට ජීවනෝපාය ආධාර සැපයීමට සහ ආර්ථිකය ස්ථාවර කිරීමට උපකාර වන මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා තාක්ෂණික ආධාර සැපයීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ඩොලර් මිලියන 6 ක නව ප්‍රදානයක් ද ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "ඉදිරි මාසවලදී, එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ආර්ථිකය පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීම, ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීම සහ මහජන සෞඛ්‍යය සහ අධ්‍යාපනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දක්වන බව එම ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "වත්මන් අර්බුදයට වඩාත්ම කල් පවතින විසඳුම සැපයිය හැකි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගත් තීරණයට තමන් දැඩි ලෙස සහාය දෙන බව එක්සත් ජනපදය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 26 - 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 120 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 27 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 5.75 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 6 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ள அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் பிரதமரை சந்தித்து பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க திணைக்களம் மற்றும் திறைசேரி திணைக்களத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழு சற்று முன்னர் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடியதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்க திறைசேரி மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க திணைக்கள அதிகாரிகள் உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் மூன்று நாள் விஜயமாக நேற்று காலை இலங்கை வந்திருந்தனர்.",
        "தூதுக்குழுவின் உறுப்பினர்களில் ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை கருவூலச் செயலர் ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை இராஜாங்கச் செயலாளரான தூதுவர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.",
        "வரும் ஜூன் 26 முதல் 29 வரை இலங்கையில் பல்வேறு அரசியல் பிரதிநிதிகள், பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளைச் சந்திப்பார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது என்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்கத் தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அவர்களின் அனைத்து சந்திப்புகளிலும், தேவையிலுள்ள இலங்கையர்களுக்கு அமெரிக்கா ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான மிகச் சிறந்த வழிகள், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு இலங்கையர்கள் பணியாற்றுவது மற்றும் எதிர்காலத்திற்கான நிலையான மற்றும் உள்ளடக்கிய பொருளாதாரத்திற்குத் திட்டமிடும் இலங்கையர்களை ஆராய்வார்கள் என்று அமெரிக்கத் தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. மேலும்.",
        "கடந்த இரண்டு வாரங்களில், இலங்கையின் சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர வணிகங்களுக்கு 120 மில்லியன் டாலர் புதிய நிதியுதவியையும், இலங்கையின் பால் உற்பத்தித் தொழிலுக்கு 27 மில்லியன் டாலர் பங்களிப்பையும், பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்காக 5.75 மில்லியன் டாலர் மனிதாபிமான உதவியையும் அமெரிக்கா அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மக்களுக்கு வாழ்வாதார உதவி மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத்தை ஸ்திரப்படுத்த உதவும் நிதி சீர்திருத்தத்திற்கான தொழில்நுட்ப உதவிகளை வழங்க அமெரிக்கா $6 மில்லியன் புதிய மானியங்களை வழங்கியது.",
        "எதிர்வரும் மாதங்களில், இலங்கையர்களின் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்டெடுக்கவும், உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையை எதிர்த்துப் போராடவும், பொது சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் கல்வியை மேம்படுத்தவும் அமெரிக்கா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு மிகவும் நீடித்த தீர்வை வழங்கக்கூடிய சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் இருந்து உதவி பெறுவதற்கான இலங்கையின் முடிவையும் வலுவாக ஆதரிப்பதாக அமெரிக்கா தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைய ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 26 - 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$120 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$27 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$5.75 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}