{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කොටිකාවත්ත-මුල්ලේරියාව-සභාවේ-හිටපු-උප--සභාපති-වෙඩි-පහරින්-මරුට/1-617474",
  "time_ut": 1659446782,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කොටිකාවත්ත-මුල්ලේරියාව සභාවේ හිටපු උප  සභාපති වෙඩි පහරින් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former Vice Chairman of Kotikawatta-Mulleria Assembly shot dead",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sumudu Rukshan (40), the former Vice Chairman of Kotikawatta Mulleriya Pradeshiya Sabha, was shot dead today (2) afternoon at Mulleriya Bank junction by two persons who came on a motorcycle, Police Media Spokesman Senior Superintendent of Police Mr. Nihal Talduwa said.",
        "Police also say that Mr. Rukshan, who served as a member of the local council until his death, is a nephew of Karate Dhammika, an underworld leader.",
        "It is said from police sources that information has been revealed to the police regarding an alleged incident where the district head, who is considered to be a follower of the underworld leader Angoda Lokka, has been threatened.",
        "Mulleriya police officers are conducting investigations to arrest the suspects involved in the incident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kotikawatta-Mulleria Assembly",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumudu Rukshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotikawatta Mulleriya Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mulleriya Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nihal Talduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rukshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karate Dhammika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Angoda Lokka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොටිකාවත්ත-මුල්ලේරියාව සභාවේ හිටපු උප  සභාපති වෙඩි පහරින් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොටිකාවත්ත මුල්ලේරියාව ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ හිටපු උප  සභාපති සුමුදු රුක්ෂාන් (40 ) මහතා මුල්ලේරියාව බැංකුව හන්දියේදී අද (2) පස්වරුවේ යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනකු විසින් කරන ලද වෙඩි තැබීමකින් ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇතැයි පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි  නිහාල් තල්දූව මහතා පැවැසීය.",
        "එම ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ලෙස මියයන තෙක්ම  කටයුතු කළ රුක්ෂාන් මහතා පාතාල නායකයකුවූ කරාටේ ධම්මික නමැත්තාගේ ඥාති පුත්‍රයකු බව ද  පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "අංගොඩ ලොක්කා නැමැති පාතාල නායකයාගේ ගෝලයකු ලෙස සැලකෙන ජිල්ලා නැමැත්තා මොහුට   මෑතකදී තර්ජනය කර ඇතැයි කියන සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලීසියට තොරතුරු අනාවරණයවී ඇති අතර ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන්  විමර්ශනයක් අරඹා ඇතැයි  පොලිස් ආරංචි මාර්ගවලින් පැවසේ.",
        "සිද්ධියට  සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට මුල්ලේරියාව පොලීසියේ නිලධාරීහු   පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොටිකාවත්ත - මුල්ලේරියාව සභාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමුදු රුක්ෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටිකාවත්ත මුල්ලේරිය ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුල්ලේරිය බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුක්ෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාටේ ධම්මික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අංගොඩ ලොක්කා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொட்டிகாவத்தை முல்லேரியா சபையின் முன்னாள் உப தலைவர் சுட்டுக்கொலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொட்டிகாவத்தை முல்லேரிய பிரதேச சபையின் முன்னாள் உப தலைவர் திரு.சுமுது ருக்ஷான் (வயது 40) இன்று (2) பிற்பகல் முல்லேரிய வங்கிச் சந்தியில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இருவரால் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிஹால் தல்துவா தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "உள்ளுராட்சி மன்ற உறுப்பினராக இறக்கும் வரை கடமையாற்றிய திரு.ருக்ஷான் பாதாள உலகத் தலைவரான கராத்தே தம்மிக்கவின் மருமகன் எனவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "பாதாள உலகக் குழுத் தலைவர் அங்கொட லொக்காவின் சீடராகக் கருதப்படும் மாவட்டத் தலைவருக்கு அச்சுறுத்தல் விடுக்கப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் பொலிஸாருக்குத் தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் வட்டாரங்களிலிருந்து தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்வதற்கான விசாரணைகளை முல்லேரிய பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொட்டிகாவத்தை-முல்லேரியா சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமுது ருக்ஷான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டிகாவத்தை முல்லேரிய பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லேரியா வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ருக்ஷான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராத்தே தம்மிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அங்கொட லொக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}