{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/08/bharat-petro-supports-refueling-ul-flights/",
  "time_ut": 1657279500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bharat Petro supports refueling UL flights",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bharat Petro supports refueling UL flights",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited has extended support to Sri Lankan Airlines, with the refueling of their long-haul flights at Indian airports.",
        "Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited said on its social media platforms that it is committed to supporting Sri Lankan Airlines, with the refueling of their long-haul flights at Indian airports, to overcome the Jet Fuel shortage in the country.",
        "So far, more than 100 flights have been refueled at Trivandrum, Chennai & Kochi airports, over the last fortnight by mobilising the assets and manpower for the ontime service, at a very short notice.",
        "Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited has been associated with SriLankan Airlines for over a decade, as their refueling partners at several Indian airports.",
        "SriLankan Airlines said that it continues to operate flight schedule close to 100% of efficiency despite any impediments and the operational implications of schedule revisions.",
        "SriLankan Airlines also reassured customers that the airline remains at their service and is making every reasonable effort to operate with minimum interruptions to scheduled flight operations at this critical juncture."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bharat Petro",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trivandrum",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai & Kochi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over a decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "close to 100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝ UL ගුවන් ගමන් සඳහා ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට සහාය දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් කෝපරේෂන් ලිමිටඩ් ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයට සහය ලබා දී ඇති අතර, ඔවුන්ගේ දිගු දුර ගුවන් ගමන් සඳහා ඉන්දියානු ගුවන් තොටුපලවල ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් කෝපරේෂන් ලිමිටඩ් සිය සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වේදිකාවල ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රට තුළ පවතින ජෙට් ඉන්ධන හිඟය මඟහරවා ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයට ඉන්දියානු ගුවන් තොටුපළවල දී ඔවුන්ගේ දිගු දුර ගුවන් ගමන් සඳහා ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට සහාය වීමට කැපවී සිටින බවයි.",
        "මේ වන විට, ත්‍රිවාන්ද්‍රම්, චෙන්නායි සහ කොචි ගුවන් තොටුපළවල, ඉතා කෙටි දැනුම්දීමකින්, වත්කම් සහ ශ්‍රම බලකාය ඔන් ටයිම් සේවාව සඳහා බලමුලු ගන්වමින් පසුගිය දෙසතිය තුළ ගුවන් ගමන් 100කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ඉන්ධන ලබාගෙන ඇත.",
        "භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් කෝපරේෂන් ලිමිටඩ් දශකයකට වැඩි කාලයක් ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වී ඇති අතර, ඉන්දියානු ගුවන් තොටුපළවල් කිහිපයක ඉන්ධන සැපයීමේ හවුල්කරුවන් ලෙස කටයුතු කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය පවසන්නේ කිසියම් බාධාවක් සහ කාලසටහන් සංශෝධනවල ක්‍රියාකාරී ඇඟවුම් නොතකා 100% ට ආසන්න කාර්යක්ෂමතාවයකින් ගුවන් ගමන් කාලසටහන අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට සහතික වූයේ ගුවන් සමාගම ඔවුන්ගේ සේවයේ දිගටම පවතින බවත් මෙම තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී නියමිත ගුවන් ගමන් මෙහෙයුම් සඳහා අවම බාධාවකින් තොරව ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට සෑම සාධාරණ උත්සාහයක්ම ගන්නා බවත්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "භාරත් පෙට්රෝ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "යූ.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් කෝපරේෂන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් කෝපරේෂන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිවන්ද්‍රම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai & Kochi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත භාරත් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් කෝපරේෂන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශකයකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100% ආසන්න",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UL விமானங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதை பாரத் பெட்ரோ ஆதரிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாரத் பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸுக்கு ஆதரவை நீட்டித்துள்ளது, அவர்களின் நீண்ட தூர விமானங்களுக்கு இந்திய விமான நிலையங்களில் எரிபொருள் நிரப்புகிறது.",
        "பாரத் பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட் அதன் சமூக ஊடக தளங்களில், நாட்டில் ஜெட் எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையை சமாளிக்க, இந்திய விமான நிலையங்களில் தங்கள் நீண்ட தூர விமானங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதன் மூலம், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க உறுதிபூண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதுவரை, திருவனந்தபுரம், சென்னை மற்றும் கொச்சி விமான நிலையங்களில், கடந்த பதினைந்து நாட்களில் 100க்கும் மேற்பட்ட விமானங்கள், மிகக் குறுகிய அறிவிப்பில், ஆன்டைம் சேவைக்கான சொத்துக்கள் மற்றும் மனிதவளத்தைத் திரட்டி எரிபொருள் நிரப்பப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பாரத் பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட் ஒரு தசாப்தத்திற்கும் மேலாக ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸுடன் பல இந்திய விமான நிலையங்களில் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் பங்காளியாக தொடர்பு கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "எந்தவொரு தடைகள் மற்றும் அட்டவணை திருத்தங்களின் செயல்பாட்டு தாக்கங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும் 100% செயல்திறனுக்கு அருகில் விமான அட்டவணையை தொடர்ந்து இயக்குவதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு உறுதியளித்தது, விமான நிறுவனம் தொடர்ந்து சேவையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளதுடன், இந்த நெருக்கடியான தருணத்தில் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட விமான நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு குறைந்தபட்ச இடையூறுகள் இல்லாமல் செயல்பட அனைத்து நியாயமான முயற்சிகளையும் மேற்கொண்டு வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாரத் பெட்ரோ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரத் பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரத் பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai & Kochi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரத் பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு தசாப்தத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100% அருகில்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}