{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/பட்டலந்த-ரணில்-நிரூபிக்க-தவறிவிட்டார்/175-301292",
  "time_ut": 1659016347,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "’பட்டலந்த ரணில் நிரூபிக்க தவறிவிட்டார்’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'Battalantha Ranil failed to prove'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Instead of using emergency law to quell the violence, the government is re-igniting violence in the country by launching mass protests, said ruling party MP Dylan Perera.",
        "He said the above while addressing a special press conference held in Colombo today (28).",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe got an opportunity in Parliament yesterday (27) to prove that he is not in Thailand by forming an all-party government that the people of the country demanded without using the emergency law, even though he came through the back door and became the president in the wrong way. However, he missed it.",
        "The protesters did not demand that the youth be arrested using the Emergency Act. There will be no shortage of fuel, fertilizer or queues in the country due to the declaration of Emergency. Can the international community help a country that has declared a state of emergency? Is IMF assistance available? Dylan Perera MP also raised a question.",
        "Legal action should be taken against those who set fire to the houses of the members of Parliament and those who attacked the empty-faced protestors on May 09. Normal laws in the country are enough for that. Punish those who entered the President's House and send the one who robbed the Central Bank to the President's House? He said that people are asking questions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Battalantha Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dylan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Emergency Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dylan Perera MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "'බත්තලන්ත රනිල්ට ඔප්පු කරන්න බැරි වුණා'",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා මැඩලීම සඳහා හදිසි නීතිය භාවිත කරනවා වෙනුවට ජනතා විරෝධතා දියත් කරමින් රජය යළිත් රට තුළ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය ඇවිලවීමට කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ අද (28) කොළඹ පැවති විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "පස්ස දොරෙන් ඇවිත් පත් වුණත් හදිසි නීතිය පාවිච්චි නොකර රටේ ජනතාව ඉල්ලපු සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් හදලා තමන් තායිලන්තයේ නැති බව ඔප්පු කරන්න රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමාට ඊයේ (27) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අවස්ථාවක් ලැබුණා. ජනාධිපති වැරදි විදියට. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහු එය මග හැරියේය.",
        "තරුණයා හදිසි නීතිය යොදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙස උද්ඝෝෂකයින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ නැත. හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම හේතුවෙන් රට තුළ ඉන්ධන, පොහොර හිඟයක් හෝ පෝලිම් හිඟයක් ඇති නොවේ. හදිසි තත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති රටකට ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවට උදව් කළ හැකිද? IMF ආධාර තිබේද? ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා මන්ත්‍රීවරයාද ප්‍රශ්නයක් මතු කළේය.",
        "මැයි 09 වැනි දින පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිවෙස්වලට ගිනි තැබූ පුද්ගලයන්ට සහ හිස් මුවාවෙන් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පහර දුන් අයට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගත යුතුයි. ඒ සඳහා රටේ පවතින සාමාන්‍ය නීති ප්‍රමාණවත්ය. ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වූවන්ට දඩුවම් දී මහ බැංකුව කොල්ලකෑ එකා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට යවනවද? ජනතාව ප්‍රශ්න කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බත්තලන්ත රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "’பட்டலந்த ரணில் நிரூபிக்க தவறிவிட்டார்’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவசரக்காலச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி வன்முறைகளை ஒடுக்குவதற்குப் பதிலாக, பலிவாங்கள் செயற்பாடுகளை ஆரம்பித்து வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களை அரசாங்கம் நாட்டில் மீண்டும் தூண்டுவதாக ஆளுங்கட்சி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டிலான் பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று (28) நடைபெற்ற விசேட ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துக்கொண்டு உரையாற்றும்போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பின் கதவு வழியாக வந்து தவறான வழியில் தான் ஜனாதிபதியாகிருந்தாலும், அவசரக்காலச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தாது நாட்டு மக்கள் கோரிய சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கம் ஒன்றை அமைத்து, நான் பட்டலந்த ரணில் இல்லை என்பதை நிருபிப்பதற்கான வாய்ப்பு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு நேற்று (27) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கிடைத்தது. எனினும் அதனை அவர் தவறவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவசரக்காலச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி இளைஞர்களைக் கைது செய்ய வேண்டும் என போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கோரவில்லை. அவசரக்காலச் சட்டம் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டதால் நாட்டுக்கு எரிபொருளோ, உரமோ நாட்டில் உள்ள வரிசைகளோ குறையப்போவது கிடையாது. அவசரக்காலச் சட்டம் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள நாட்டுக்கு சர்வதேசம் உதவுமா? சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் உதவிகள் கிடைக்குமா? எனவும் டிலான் பெரேரா எம்.பி கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வீடுகளைக் கொளுத்தியவர்களுக்கும், காலி முகத்திடல் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது மே 09ஆம் திகதி தாக்குதல் நடத்தியவர்கள் மீதும் சட்டநடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும். அதற்கு நாட்டில் உள்ள சாதாரண சட்டங்களே போதும். ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் சென்றவர்களை தண்டித்துவிட்டு மத்திய வங்கியில் கொள்ளையடித்தவரை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு அனுப்புவதா? என  மக்கள் கேள்வி எழுப்புவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பட்டாளந்த ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டிலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிலான் பெரேரா எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}