{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ධානිශ්-අලීට-ඇප/101-618122",
  "time_ut": 1660546174,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ධානිශ් අලීට ඇප",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhanish Ali granted bail",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe today (15) ordered that social activist Dhanish Ali, who was remanded in custody in connection with the alleged forced entry into the television corporation, be released on two sureties of 25000 rupees and 5 lakh rupees each.",
        "According to the Public Property Act related to this incident, the magistrate released the suspect on bail stating that there are not enough facts to keep the suspect in custody.",
        "The magistrate also ordered the suspect to go to the Kuruduwatta police and give a statement regarding this incident.",
        "The suspect was arrested by the police on the 26th while he was waiting in a plane to go abroad.",
        "On the 27th, the Fort Magistrate had ordered to remand the suspect, who was arrested according to a warrant issued by the court, after being brought back to court.",
        "Kurunduwatta police had reported the facts to the court regarding this incident.",
        "31-year-old Dhanish Ali, a resident of Kurunegala Webada area, was released on bail.",
        "Also, four suspects including Dhanish Ali have been remanded until the 26th by the Colombo Fort Magistrate's Court in relation to the alleged incident of trespassing into the Presidential Palace and damaging its property."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhanish Ali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanish Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Property Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuruduwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanish Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanish Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate's",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධානිශ් අලීට ඇප",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට අයුතු ලෙස ඇතුළු වී බලහත්කාරයෙන් කටයුතු කලැයි කියන සිද්ධියට අදාළව රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර සිටි  සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරී ධානිශ් අලී නැමැත්තා රුපියල් 25000 මුදල් සහ රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 5 බැගින් වූ ශරීර ඇප දෙකක් මත මුදා හැරීමට කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා අද (15) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළ පොදු දේපල දේපළ පනත ප්‍රකාරව සැකකරු තවදුරටත් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර සිටීමට තරම් ප්‍රමාණවත් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් නොවන බවට සඳහන් කරමින් මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා සැකකරු එලෙස ඇප මත මුදා හැරියේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කුරුදුවත්ත පොලීසියට ගොස් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදෙන ලෙසට ද මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා සැකකරුට නියම කළේය .",
        "මෙම සැකකරු විදේශගත වීමට සූදානම්ව සිටිමින් ගුවන් යානයක රැඳී සිටියදී පොලිසිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවේ ඉකුත් 26 වැනිදාය.",
        "අධිකරණයෙන් නිකුත් කළ වරෙන්තුවක් ප්‍රකාරව අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් මෙම සැකකරු නැවත අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා නියෝග කර තිබුණේ ඉකුත් 27 වැනිදාය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට කරුණු වාර්තා කර තිබුණේ කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය මගිනි.",
        "මෙලෙස ඇප මත මුදා හරිනු ලැබුවේ  ලැබුවේ කුරුණෑගල වෑබඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 31 හැවිරිදි ධානිශ් අලී නැමැත්තාය.",
        "එසේම, ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට අයුතු ලෙස ඇතුළු වී එහි දේපළවලට හානි කලැයි කියන සිද්ධියට අදාළව ධානිෂ් අලී ඇතුළු සැකකරුවන් හතර දෙනෙකු කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින්  ලබන 26 වන දා දක්වා  රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කරනු ලැබ ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදු දේපල පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuruduwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனிஷ் அலிக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தொலைக்காட்சி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் வலுக்கட்டாயமாக நுழைந்ததாக கூறப்படும் குற்றச்சாட்டில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த சமூக ஆர்வலர் தனிஷ் அலியை தலா 25000 ரூபா மற்றும் 5 இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான இரண்டு சரீரப் பிணைகளில் விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க இன்று (15) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் தொடர்பான பொதுச் சொத்து சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம், சந்தேகநபரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்க போதிய உண்மைகள் இல்லை என நீதவான் சந்தேக நபரை பிணையில் விடுவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் குருதுவத்தை பொலிஸாரிடம் சென்று வாக்குமூலம் வழங்குமாறும் சந்தேகநபரை நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் கடந்த 26ஆம் திகதி வெளிநாடு செல்வதற்காக விமானத்தில் காத்திருந்த போது பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தினால் பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட பிடியாணைக்கு அமைய கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபரை மீண்டும் நீதிமன்றில் முற்படுத்திய பின்னர் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கடந்த 27ஆம் திகதி கோட்டை நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் குருந்துவத்தை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் உண்மைகளை அறிக்கை செய்திருந்தனர்.",
        "குருநாகல் வெபட பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 31 வயதான தனிஷ் அலி என்பவரே இவ்வாறு பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அத்துடன், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் அத்துமீறி நுழைந்து அதன் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்ததாக கூறப்படும் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில், தனிஷ் அலி உள்ளிட்ட நான்கு சந்தேகநபர்களையும் எதிர்வரும் 26ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது சொத்து சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuruduwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}