{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/04/gl-assures-support-for-one-china-policy/",
  "time_ut": 1656912480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GL assures support for ‘One China policy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GL assures support for ‘One China policy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Foreign Affairs, Professor G.L. Peiris has assured the Chinese Ambassador that Sri Lanka will continue to stand by ‘one-China policy and pledged Sri Lanka’s unwavering support to protect China’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.",
        "The Foreign Minister met with the Ambassador of China, Qi Zhenhong, on 30th June 2022 at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.",
        "Minister Peiris appreciated China’s continued assistance to Sri Lanka. The Foreign Minister also apprised the Ambassador of the current situation in the country and the shortage of fuel, food and pharmaceutical equipment which have adversely affected the economy of Sri Lanka. The Minister added that bilateral partners and international agencies are in regular discussions to address these challenges.",
        "The Minister mentioned that he held discussions with the leaders of 12 countries on the current situation in terms of in Sri Lanka on the flanks of the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting (CHOGM) in Kigali, Rwanda and the assistance required by Sri Lanka at this critical juncture.",
        "He briefed the Ambassador on the ongoing discussion with the IMF for financial assistance as well as restructuring (reformulating) Sri Lanka’s debt. As well as the measures that are put in place by the Govt to address the most pressing issues.",
        "The Chinese Envoy appreciated the Government of Sri Lanka position and its consistent stance on ‘one China policy’.",
        "Ambassador Qi assured that the Chinese Government would remain engaged with Sri Lanka towards extending assistance to Sri Lanka in every possible manner.",
        "The Foreign Minister extended Sri Lanka’s profound gratitude to the Government of China for their unstinted support. Senior officials of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and officials of the Chinese Embassy were present at the meeting.",
        "We didn’t ask to evict fort protesters, say Australian Test stars"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kigali",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rwanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Govt",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘එක් චීනයක්’ ප්‍රතිපත්තියට සහය දක්වන බව ජී.එල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ‘එක්-චීන’ ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ අඛණ්ඩව පෙනී සිටින බවත් චීනයේ ස්වෛරීත්වය සහ භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාව ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නොසැලෙන සහය ලබා දෙන බවටත් විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය, මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා චීන තානාපතිවරයාට සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා 2022 ජුනි 30 වන දින විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong හමුවිය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය පීරිස් මහතා චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදෙන අඛණ්ඩ සහය අගය කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකයට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපා ඇති රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සහ ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ උපකරණ හිඟය පිළිබඳව ද විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා තානාපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කළේය. මෙම අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික හවුල්කරුවන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර නියෝජිතායතන නිරන්තරයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බව අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "රුවන්ඩාවේ කිගාලි හි පැවැත්වෙන පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍ය නායක සමුළුවේ දෙපස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සහ මෙම තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය සහය පිළිබඳව රටවල් 12 ක නායකයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළ බව අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේය. සන්ධිස්ථානය.",
        "මූල්‍ය ආධාර මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම (ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීම) සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සිදු කෙරෙන සාකච්ඡාව පිළිබඳව ඔහු තානාපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කළේය. වඩාත්ම දැවෙන ගැටළු විසඳීම සඳහා රජය විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ක්‍රියාමාර්ග මෙන්ම.",
        "චීන තානාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ස්ථාවරය සහ ‘එක් චීනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියක්’ පිළිබඳ එහි ස්ථාවර ස්ථාවරය අගය කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි සෑම ආකාරයකින්ම සහය ලබා දීම සඳහා චීන රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ දිගටම නිරත වන බව තානාපති Qi සහතික විය.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් චීන රජයට ඔවුන්ගේ නොමසුරු සහයෝගය වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගැඹුරු කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය. විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් සහ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ නිලධාරීන් මෙම හමුවට එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "බලකොටු විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කරන ලෙස අපි ඉල්ලා නොසිටි බව ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රීඩකයෝ පවසති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජුනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය රාජ්‍ය නායක සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෝගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිගාලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு சீனா கொள்கைக்கான ஆதரவை GL உறுதியளிக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ‘ஒரு சீனா’ கொள்கையில் இலங்கை தொடர்ந்து நிற்கும் என்றும், சீனாவின் இறையாண்மை மற்றும் ஆள்புல ஒருமைப்பாட்டைப் பாதுகாக்க இலங்கையின் அசைக்க முடியாத ஆதரவை உறுதி செய்வதாகவும் சீனத் தூதுவரிடம் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் 2022 ஜூன் 30 அன்று சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong ஐ வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தில் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு சீனாவின் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவிகளை அமைச்சர் பீரிஸ் பாராட்டினார். இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை மற்றும் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை மோசமாகப் பாதித்துள்ள எரிபொருள், உணவு மற்றும் மருந்து உபகரணங்களின் பற்றாக்குறை குறித்தும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் தூதுவருக்கு விளக்கமளித்தார். இந்த சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்ள இருதரப்பு பங்காளிகளும் சர்வதேச முகவர்களும் தொடர்ந்து கலந்துரையாடி வருவதாக அமைச்சர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ருவாண்டாவின் கிகாலியில் நடைபெற்ற பொதுநலவாய அரச தலைவர்கள் மாநாட்டின் பக்கவாட்டில் இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்தும் இலங்கைக்கு தேவையான உதவிகள் குறித்தும் 12 நாடுகளின் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடியதாக அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார். சந்திப்பு.",
        "நிதி உதவி மற்றும் இலங்கையின் கடனை மறுசீரமைத்தல் (சீர்திருத்தம் செய்தல்) தொடர்பாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் நடந்து வரும் கலந்துரையாடல் குறித்து அவர் தூதுவருக்கு விளக்கினார். அத்துடன் மிக அழுத்தமான பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண அரசாங்கத்தால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் நடவடிக்கைகள்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் நிலைப்பாடு மற்றும் ‘ஒரே சீனா கொள்கை’ தொடர்பான அதன் நிலையான நிலைப்பாட்டை சீனத் தூதுவர் பாராட்டினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு சாத்தியமான எல்லா வகையிலும் உதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்கு சீன அரசாங்கம் இலங்கையுடன் தொடர்ந்தும் ஈடுபடும் என்று தூதுவர் குய் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் அலாதியான ஆதரவிற்காக இலங்கையின் ஆழ்ந்த நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்தார். வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் உயர் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் சீன தூதரக அதிகாரிகள் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "கோட்டை எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை வெளியேற்ற நாங்கள் கேட்கவில்லை என ஆஸ்திரேலிய டெஸ்ட் நட்சத்திரங்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் அரசாங்கத் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CHOGM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிகாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவாண்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}