{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/permission-to-import-10-essentials-via-open-accounts/",
  "time_ut": 1656150780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Permission to import 10 essentials via open accounts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Permission to import 10 essentials via open accounts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Cabinet of Ministers have granted permission to import 10 essential items through open accounts from 1st of July, for a period of two months.",
        "The essential items include rice, flour, sugar, milk powder, dried chilli, dried sprats, potatoes, red Dhal, red onions and watana Dhal.",
        "Accordingly, these items will be imported through open accounts subject to limitations.",
        "The decision has been reached in view of the necessity to provide the people with essential food items without causing  shortage.",
        "Fuel protests continue today; Hatton residents allege no kerosene since 9th",
        "Prof. Rangita De Silva De Alwis elected as SL representative for CEDAW"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rangita De Silva De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විවෘත ගිණුම් හරහා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය 10ක් ආනයනය කිරීමට අවසර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජුලි 01 වැනිදා සිට මාස දෙකක කාලයක් සඳහා විවෘත ගිණුම් හරහා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය 10ක් ආනයනය කිරීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අවසර ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය අතර සහල්, පිටි, සීනි, කිරිපිටි, වියළි මිරිස්, වියළි හාල්මැස්සන්, අර්තාපල්, රතු පරිප්පු, රතු ළූණු සහ වටනා පරිප්පු ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව සීමාවන්ට යටත්ව විවෘත ගිණුම් හරහා මෙම භාණ්ඩ ආනයනය කෙරේ.",
        "ජනතාවට අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟයක් ඇති නොවන පරිදි ලබාදීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් මෙම තීරණයට එළඹ ඇත.",
        "අදත් ඉන්ධන විරෝධතා; හැටන් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් චෝදනා කරන්නේ පසුගිය 9 වැනිදා සිට භූමිතෙල් නොමැති බවයි",
        "CEDAW හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 1 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාල සීමාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරිප්පු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திறந்த கணக்குகள் மூலம் 10 அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்ய அனுமதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜூலை 1ஆம் திகதி முதல் இரண்டு மாத காலத்திற்கு 10 அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களை திறந்த கணக்குகள் மூலம் இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களில் அரிசி, மாவு, சர்க்கரை, பால் பவுடர், காய்ந்த மிளகாய், காய்ந்த ஸ்ப்ரேட்ஸ், உருளைக்கிழங்கு, சிவப்பு பருப்பு, சிவப்பு வெங்காயம் மற்றும் வதனா பருப்பு ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "அதன்படி, இந்த பொருட்கள் வரம்புகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு திறந்த கணக்குகள் மூலம் இறக்குமதி செய்யப்படும்.",
        "மக்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பொருட்களை தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்படாமல் வழங்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு இந்த முடிவு எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் எதிர்ப்பு போராட்டம் இன்றும் தொடர்கிறது; கடந்த 9ஆம் திகதி முதல் மண்ணெண்ணெய் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என ஹட்டன் பிரதேச மக்கள் குற்றம் சுமத்துகின்றனர்",
        "CEDAW இன் இலங்கைப் பிரதிநிதியாக பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பருப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}