{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/19/navy-rescues-distressed-fishermen/",
  "time_ut": 1660902660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy rescues distressed fishermen",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy rescues distressed fishermen",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Navy rescued 06 fishermen from a local multiday fishing trawler in distress about 18.5 nautical miles (34 km) off Dondra in southern waters and bring them ashore this morning (19th August 2022).",
        "Reportedly, the multiday fishing trawler ‘Dileesha Putha II’ (Reg. No. IMUL-A-1024 MTR) left the Kudawella fisheries harbour on a fishing voyage on 16th August 2022 and was at risk of sinking having collided with a ship plying in the sea area.",
        "Accordingly, the owner of the fishing trawler has reported the incident to the fishing monitoring point of SLCG at Kudawella fisheries harbour.",
        "Upon dissemination of the incident to the Maritime Rescue Coordination Centre (MRCC) Colombo at the Navy Headquarters by the Sri Lanka Coast Guard, the MRCC Colombo sent a distress signal to the ships in the sea area about the development.",
        "Subsequently, the Fast Attack Craft P 472 of the 4th Fast Attack Flotilla (4 FAF) in the Southern Naval Command was rushed to the sea area where the incident was reported to rescue the 06 fishermen on the distressed fishing trawler.",
        "Having located the distressed trawler, the Navy promptly rescued the 06 fishermen from the distressed trawler this morning and rushed them to the Tangalle Base Hospital after bringing them to the Tangalle Fisheries Harbour this morning (19th August).",
        "Meanwhile, the Navy remains on standby to assist naval and fishing communities around the clock in Sri Lanka's Search and Rescue Region.",
        "Photographed Horton Plains leopards not a threat, Visitor not allowed to enter said area"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 18.5 nautical miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kudawella",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16th August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kudawella",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Maritime Rescue Coordination Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Navy Headquarters",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "472",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Flotilla",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tangalle Base Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tangalle Fisheries Harbour",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Search and Rescue Region",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Photographed Horton Plains",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Visitor",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාවික හමුදාව විපතට පත් ධීවරයින් බේරා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නාවික හමුදාව විසින් දකුණු මුහුදු තීරයේ දෙවුන්දරට ​​නාවික සැතපුම් 18.5 (කිලෝමීටර 34) පමණ දුරින් විපතට පත් දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක සිටි ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු බේරාගෙන අද (2022 අගෝස්තු 19) උදෑසන ගොඩබිමට රැගෙන එනු ලැබීය.",
        "'දිලීෂ පුතා II' බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව 2022 අගෝස්තු 16 වන දින කුඩාවැල්ල ධීවර වරායෙන් ධීවර ගමනක් සඳහා පිටත්ව ගිය අතර, එහි යාත්‍රා කරමින් තිබූ නෞකාවක ගැටීමෙන් ගිලා බැසීමේ අවදානමක් පැවති බව වාර්තා වේ. මුහුදු ප්රදේශය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ධීවර යාත්‍රාවේ හිමිකරු සිද්ධිය කුඩාවැල්ල ධීවර වරායේ පිහිටි SLCG ධීවර නිරීක්ෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයට වාර්තා කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්‍ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ පිහිටි කොළඹ සමුද්‍ර ගලවා ගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයට (MRCC) ප්‍රචාරය කිරීමෙන් පසු, MRCC Colombo විසින් එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ නැව් වෙත සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳ ආපදා සංඥාවක් යවා ඇත.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව, විපතට පත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාවේ සිටි ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනා බේරා ගැනීම සඳහා සිද්ධිය වාර්තා වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයට දක්ෂිණ නාවික විධානයට අයත් 4 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක ෆ්ලෝටිලා (4 FAF) හි P 472 වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව කඩිනමින් රැගෙන යන ලදී.",
        "විපතට පත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාව සොයා ගත් නාවික හමුදාව අද අලුයම විපතට පත් ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනා බේරාගෙන අද (අගෝස්තු 19) උදෑසන තංගල්ල ධීවර වරාය වෙත රැගෙන ඒමෙන් පසු තංගල්ල මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෙවීම් සහ මුදාගැනීමේ කලාපයේ නාවික සහ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවන්ට පැය විසිහතර පුරාම සහය වීමට නාවික හමුදාව සූදානම්ව සිටියි.",
        "ඡායාරූපගත හෝර්ටන් තැන්න දිවියන් තර්ජනයක් නොවේ, එම ප්‍රදේශයට ඇතුළුවීමට අමුත්තන්ට අවසර නැත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික සැතපුම් 18.5ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝමීටර 34 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩාවැල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩාවැල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර ගලවා ගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "472",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්‍රහාර ෆ්ලෝටිලා",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල ධීවර වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙවීම සහ මුදාගැනීමේ කලාපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඡායාරූපගත කළේ හෝටන් තැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගන්තුකයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விபத்தில் சிக்கிய மீனவர்களை கடற்படையினர் மீட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தென் கடற்பரப்பில் டோண்ட்ராவிலிருந்து சுமார் 18.5 கடல் மைல் (34 கி.மீ) தொலைவில் ஆபத்தில் சிக்கிய உள்ளூர் பல நாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகில் இருந்து 06 மீனவர்களை கடற்படையினர் மீட்டு இன்று காலை (19 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022) கரைக்கு கொண்டு வந்தனர்.",
        "பல நாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு 'திலீஷா புத்தா II' (பதிவு எண். IMUL-A-1024 MTR) 16 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று மீன்பிடிப் பயணமாக குடவெல்ல மீன்பிடித் துறைமுகத்திலிருந்து புறப்பட்டு, அதில் பயணித்துக் கொண்டிருந்த கப்பலுடன் மோதி மூழ்கும் அபாயத்தில் இருந்தது. கடல் பகுதி.",
        "இதன்படி, மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகின் உரிமையாளர் குடாவெல்ல மீன்பிடி துறைமுகத்தில் உள்ள SLCG மீன்பிடி கண்காணிப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு சம்பவம் குறித்து அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படை மூலம் கடற்படைத் தலைமையகத்தில் உள்ள கடல்சார் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையத்திற்கு (MRCC) கொழும்பு இந்த சம்பவம் பரவியதும், MRCC கொழும்பு கடல் பகுதியில் உள்ள கப்பல்களுக்கு வளர்ச்சி குறித்து பேரிடர் சமிக்ஞையை அனுப்பியது.",
        "அதனையடுத்து, தென் கடற்படைக் கட்டளைக்கு உட்பட்ட 4 ஆவது Fast Attack Flotilla (4 FAF) இன் Fast Attack Craft P 472 கடற்பரப்புக்கு விரைந்த நிலையில், விபத்துக்குள்ளான மீன்பிடி படகில் இருந்த 06 மீனவர்களை மீட்பதற்காக சம்பவம் பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "ஆபத்தில் சிக்கிய இழுவைப் படகைக் கண்டறிந்த கடற்படையினர், இன்று காலை 06 மீனவர்களை உடனடியாக மீட்டு, இன்று காலை (ஆகஸ்ட் 19) தங்காலை மீன்பிடித் துறைமுகத்திற்குக் கொண்டு வந்து தங்காலை ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் சேர்த்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இலங்கையின் தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பிராந்தியத்தில் 24 மணிநேரமும் கடற்படை மற்றும் மீன்பிடி சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவ கடற்படை தயார் நிலையில் உள்ளது.",
        "புகைப்படம் எடுத்த ஹார்டன் சமவெளி சிறுத்தைகள் அச்சுறுத்தல் இல்லை, பார்வையாளர்கள் குறித்த பகுதிக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதி இல்லை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 18.5 கடல் மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடவெல்ல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடவெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "472",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் ஃப்ளோட்டிலா",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்காலை ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்காலை மீன்பிடி துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பகுதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புகைப்படம் எடுத்தது ஹார்டன் சமவெளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்வையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}