{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83916/showers-expected-in-most-parts-of-the-island-",
  "time_ut": 1658974560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Showers expected in most parts of the Island",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Showers expected in most parts of the Island",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at most parts of the Island during the evening or night, says the Department of Meteorology.",
        "Heavy showers about 100 mm can be expected at some places in Sabaragamuwa, Central, North-central, Uva and Southern provinces and in Ampara district.",
        "General public is kindly requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by temporary localized strong winds and lightning during thundershowers.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at several places in the sea areas around the island during the evening or night. Heavy showers may occur at several places in the sea area extending from Hambantota to Batticaloa via Pottuvil.",
        "Winds will be north-westerly or variable in direction and wind speed will be 20-30 kmph. Wind speed can increase up to 40 kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending fromGalle to Hambantota via Matara.",
        "The sea areas off the coast extending from Galle to Hambantota via Matara will be moderate. The other sea areas around the island will be slight to moderate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Island",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa, Central,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20-30 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coast extending fromGalle",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවලට වැසි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල සවස් කාලයේ හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුරු-මැද, ඌව සහ දකුණු පළාත්වලත් අම්පාර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේත් ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100ක පමණ තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කළ හැක.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "අපරභාගයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී දිවයින වටා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ. හම්බන්තොට සිට පොතුවිල් හරහා මඩකලපුව දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ස්ථාන කිහිපයක තද වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "සුළං වයඹ දෙසින් හෝ දිශාවෙන් විචල්‍ය විය හැකි අතර සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී. 20-30 පමණ වේ. ගාල්ල සිට මාතර හරහා හම්බන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.40 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "ගාල්ල සිට මාතර හරහා හම්බන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ මධ්‍යස්ථ වේ. දිවයින වටා වන අනෙකුත් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ තරමක් හෝ මධ්‍යස්ථ වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දිවයින",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20-30 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙරළ තීරය ගාල්ලේ සිට විහිදේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தீவின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகளில் மழை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகளில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமத்திய, ஊவா மற்றும் தென் மாகாணங்களிலும் அம்பாறை மாவட்டத்திலும் சில இடங்களில் சுமார் 100 மில்லிமீற்றர் அளவில் பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதுமான முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளையில் நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள கடற்பரப்புகளில் பல இடங்களில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும். ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் இருந்து பொத்துவில் ஊடாக மட்டக்களப்பு வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் பல இடங்களில் பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "காற்று வடமேற்கு அல்லது திசையில் மாறுபடும் மற்றும் காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 20-30 கி.மீ. காலியில் இருந்து மாத்தறை ஊடாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணிக்கு 40 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "காலியிலிருந்து மாத்தறை ஊடாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கரையோரத்திற்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகள் மிதமாக காணப்படும். நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புகள் சிறிதளவு முதல் மிதமானது வரை காணப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தீவு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 20-30 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடலோரம் காலியிலிருந்து நீண்டுள்ளது",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}