{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132181",
  "time_ut": 1658675406,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "காலிமுகத்திடல் தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றில் விவாதிக்க இடமளிக்க வேண்டும் - கிரியெல்ல வேண்டுகோள் !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There should be room for discussion in the Parliament regarding the attack on Khalimugatidal - Kiriella's request!",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Prime Minister of the Opposition, Korada Laxman Kiriella, said that we are demanding that there be room for a debate on the upcoming 27th in the Parliament regarding the attack on the Khalimugatidal protestors.",
        "Opposition Prime Minister Korda has requested the Prime Minister and the Speaker to convene Parliament tomorrow to discuss the attack on Khalimugatdal protesters.",
        "The government had attacked the protestors who were engaged in a peaceful protest in Kalimugat last Friday night in a very brutal manner. We have requested the Prime Minister and the Speaker to convene the Parliament on the 25th tomorrow to hold a discussion in this regard.",
        "However, as it is difficult to convene the parliament tomorrow and to call the members of parliament amid the fuel issue, we request the government to take up this discussion when the parliament meets on Wednesday 27th to approve the regular gazette notification.",
        "It is illegal and anti-democratic to attack and chase the protestors who were protesting peacefully. Therefore, it is necessary to establish a concept in this regard, he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Khalimugatidal - Kiriella's",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korada Laxman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Khalimugatidal",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalimugat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Friday night",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඛලිමුගටිඩාල්ට පහරදීම ගැන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සාකච්ඡාවට ඉඩක් තිබිය යුතුයි - කිරිඇල්ලගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක්!",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඛලිමුගටිඩාල් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පහරදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ලබන 27 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී විවාදයකට ඉඩ ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින බව විපක්ෂයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කෝරද ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඛලිමුගට්ඩාල් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවන ලෙස විපක්ෂ අගමැති කෝර්ඩා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගෙන් සහ කථානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබේ.",
        "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා රාත්‍රියේ කාලිමුගට් ප්‍රදේශයේ සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වූ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට රජය ඉතා ම්ලේච්ඡ ලෙස පහර දී තිබුණා. අපි අගමැතිතුමාගෙන් සහ කතානායකතුමාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කරලා තියෙනවා හෙට 25 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවලා ඒ ගැන සාකච්ඡාවක් කරන්න කියලා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඉන්ධන ප්‍රශ්නය මධ්‍යයේ හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීමටත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කැඳවීමටත් අපහසු බැවින් නිත්‍ය ගැසට් නිවේදනය අනුමත කිරීම සඳහා 27 බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වූ විට මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට ගන්නා ලෙස අපි රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා.",
        "සාමකාමීව විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පහරදීම සහ එළවා දැමීම නීති විරෝධී සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී ක්‍රියාවකි. ඒ නිසා මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සංකල්පයක් ඇතිකර ගැනීම අවශ්‍ය බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඛලිමුගටිදල් - කිරිඇල්ලගේ",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝරද ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛලිමුගටිඩාල්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝර්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලිමුගට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සිකුරාදා රාත්රියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට 25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காலிமுகத்திடல் தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றில் விவாதிக்க இடமளிக்க வேண்டும் - கிரியெல்ல வேண்டுகோள் !",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலிமுகத்திடல் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்வரும் 27 ஆம் திகதி விவாதத்துக்கு இடமளிக்கவேண்டும் என கோரி இருக்கின்றோம் என எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம கொரடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "காலிமுகத்திடல் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் விவாதிப்பதற்கு நாளை பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டுமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சி பிரதம கொரடா பிரதமர் மற்றும் சபாநாயகரை கோரி இருந்தார்.",
        "காலிமுகத்திடலில் அமைதியான போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுவந்த போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது அரசாங்கம் கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நள்ளிரவு மிகவும் மோசமான முறையில் தாக்குதல் நடத்தி இருந்தது. இதுதொடர்பில் விவாதம் ஒன்றை நடத்த நாளை 25 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டுமாறு பிரதமர் மற்றும் சபாநாயகரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்திருந்தோம்.",
        "இருந்தபோதும் பாராளுமன்றத்தை நாளைய தினம் கூட்டுவது மற்றும் எரிபொருள் பிரச்சினைக்கு மத்தியில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை அழைப்பது கடினமான விடயம் என்ற காரணத்தினால், அவரசகால சட்ட வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பை அனுமதித்துக்கொள்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றம் 27ஆம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை கூடும் சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் இந்த விவாதத்தையும் எடுத்துக்கொள்ள வேண்டும் என அரசாங்கத்திடம் கோர இருக்கின்றோம்.",
        "அமைதியான முறையில் போராட்டம் மேற்கொண்டுவந்த போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தாக்குதல் நடத்தி அவர்களை துரத்தி அடித்திருப்பது சட்ட விரோதம் என்பதுடன் ஜனநாயக விரோத செயலாகும். அதனால் இதுதொடர்பில் கருத்தாடல் ஒன்றை ஏற்படுத்திக்கொள்வது அவசியமாகும், எனக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கலிமுகடிடல் - கிரியெல்லாவின்",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொறடா லக்ஸ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலிமுகடிடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலிமுகத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இரவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை 25ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27ம் தேதி புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}