{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Facilitating-talks-with-IMF-creditors-my-priority-Foreign-Minister/108-241624",
  "time_ut": 1658509117,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Facilitating talks with IMF, creditors, my priority -  Foreign Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Facilitating talks with IMF, creditors, my priority -  Foreign Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Foreign Affairs Minister Ali Sabry said facilitation of talks with the International Monetary Fund ( IMF) and creditors is his priority in the new job .",
        "The Minister told Daily Mirror that he would first take stock of the situation.",
        "“Today, the first priority is to deal with the IMF and the creditors including bond holders,” he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF, ණයහිමියන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීම, මගේ ප්‍රමුඛතාවය - විදේශ අමාත්‍ය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි පැවසුවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සහ ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීම නව රැකියාවේදී ඔහුගේ ප්‍රමුඛතාවය බවයි.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් පළමුව තත්ත්වය සොයා බලන බවයි.",
        "“අද පළමු ප්‍රමුඛතාවය වන්නේ IMF සහ බැඳුම්කර හිමියන් ඇතුළු ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ගනුදෙනු කිරීමයි,” ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம், கடனாளிகளுடன் பேச்சு வார்த்தைகளை எளிதாக்குவது, எனது முன்னுரிமை - வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) மற்றும் கடனாளிகளுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை எளிதாக்குவதே புதிய வேலையில் தனது முன்னுரிமை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "முதலில் நிலைமையை ஆராய்வதாக அமைச்சர் டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இன்று, முதல் முன்னுரிமை IMF மற்றும் பத்திர வைத்திருப்பவர்கள் உட்பட கடன் வழங்குபவர்களுடன் கையாள்வதாகும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}