{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Colombo-allows-Pakistani-frigate-Taimur-to-dock-Dhaka-says-no/342-242642",
  "time_ut": 1659962140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Colombo allows Pakistani frigate Taimur to dock, Dhaka says no",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo allows Pakistani frigate Taimur to dock, Dhaka says no",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka has allowed permission to the Chinese built-Pakistani guided missile frigate PNS Taimur to make a port call at Colombo while on its way to join the Pakistan Navy in Karachi. Build by Hudong-Zhonghua shipyard in Shanghai, the warship is on its maiden voyage to Pakistan while exercising en-route with Cambodian and Malaysian navies. The ship is expected to be at Colombo port from August 12-15, 2022.",
        "While Sri Lanka gave permission to the Pakistani guided missile frigate to make a port call at Colombo, it is understood that the ship was denied a permission to make a port call at Chattogram port by the Sheikh Hasina government from August 7-10 after making a port call at Lumut port in Malaysia.",
        "According to diplomatic sources, India’s close ally Bangladesh denied permission to PNS Taimur as August is a month of mourning for Sheikh Hasina as her father, Sheikh Mujib-ur-Rehman also fondly called Bangabandhu, was assassinated by Pak instigated and Jamait-e-Islami inspired radical Islamist forces on August 15, 1975.",
        "The Sheikh Hasina government is close to Narendra Modi government with the Bangladesh Prime Minister clear that her father and family was done to death at the behest of Pakistan. The radical Islamist forces also made an assassination attempt on Sheikh Hasina in 2000 as Prime Minister and in 2004 as the Awami League President.",
        "Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina is scheduled to make a trip to India in the first week of September and along with PM Modi will launch the jointly developed 1320 Mega Watt Maitree Super Thermal Power Project at Rampal in Khulna sub-division.",
        "PNS Taimur, the second of the four Type 054 A/P frigates build in China, was commissioned on June 23, 2022. The lead ship of this class is PMNS Tughril and was commissioned on January 24, 2022. China is also building eight Yuan class -041 diesel attack submarines for Pakistan by 2028 with the objective to militarily flank India on high seas. (Hindustan Times)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pakistani",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhaka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pakistan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karachi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hudong-Zhonghua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanghai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cambodian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 12-15, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 7-10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sheikh Mujib-ur-Rehman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangabandhu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pak",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jamait",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 15, 1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sheikh Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMNS Tughril",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 24, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2028",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindustan Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ පකිස්තාන යාත්‍රා තයිමූර් නැව් තටාකාංගනය කිරීමට අවසර දෙයි, ඩකා පවසන්නේ නැත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කරච්චියේදී පාකිස්තාන නාවික හමුදාවට බැඳීමට යමින් සිටියදී කොළඹ වරායට ඇමතීමට චීනය විසින් සාදන ලද පකිස්තාන මාර්ගෝපදේශක මිසයිල නෞකාවක් වන PNS Taimur වෙත ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසර ලබා දී තිබේ. ෂැංහයි හි Hudong-Zhonghua නැව් තටාකාංගනය විසින් ඉදිකරන ලද මෙම යුධ නෞකාව කාම්බෝජ සහ මැලේසියානු නාවික හමුදා සමඟ අභ්‍යාස කරමින් පකිස්ථානය වෙත සිය මංගල ගමනේ යෙදී සිටී. නෞකාව 2022 අගෝස්තු 12 සිට 15 දක්වා කොළඹ වරායේ රැඳී සිටීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පකිස්තාන මගපෙන්වන මිසයිල නෞකාවට කොළඹ වරායට ඇමතුමක් ගැනීමට අවසර දුන් අතර, ෂෙයික් හසීනා රජය විසින් අගෝස්තු 7-10 දක්වා එම නෞකාවට චැටෝග්‍රම් වරායට වරාය ඇමතුමක් ගැනීමට අවසර දීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බව වැටහෙනවා. මැලේසියාවේ ලුමුට් වරායේ වරාය ඇමතුම.",
        "රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මූලාශ්‍රවලට අනුව, ඉන්දියාවේ සමීප මිතුරෙකු වන බංග්ලාදේශය PNS තයිමූර් වෙත අවසර ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේ අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී ෂෙයික් හසීනාගේ ශෝක මාසය වන බැවින් ඇගේ පියා වන ෂේක් මුජිබ්-උර්-රෙහ්මාන් ද බංගබන්ධු ලෙස ආදරයෙන් හඳුන්වනු ලබන අතර, පාකිස්තානය විසින් උසිගන්වන ලද සහ ජමයිට්-ඊ-ඉස්ලාමි විසින් ඝාතනය කරන ලදී. 1975 අගෝස්තු 15 වැනි දින රැඩිකල් ඉස්ලාම්වාදී බලවේග ආභාෂය ලැබීය.",
        "ෂීක් හසීනා රජය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි රජයට සමීපව සිටින්නේ ඇගේ පියා සහ පවුලේ අය ඝාතනය කර ඇත්තේ පකිස්ථානයේ අවශ්‍යතාවය මත බව බංග්ලාදේශ අගමැතිනිය පැහැදිලි කරමිනි. රැඩිකල් ඉස්ලාමීය බලවේග 2000 දී අගමැතිනිය ලෙස සහ 2004 දී අවාමි ලීගයේ සභාපති ලෙස ෂෙයික් හසීනා ඝාතනය කිරීමට තැත් කළේය.",
        "අගමැතිනි ෂීක් හසීනා සැප්තැම්බර් මුල් සතියේ ඉන්දියාවේ සංචාරයක නිරත වීමට නියමිත අතර අගමැති මෝදි සමග එක්ව ඒකාබද්ධව සංවර්ධනය කරන ලද මෙගා වොට් 1320 මෛත්‍රී සුපිරි තාප විදුලි ව්‍යාපෘතිය Khulna උප කොට්ඨාසයේ Rampal හි දියත් කරනු ඇත.",
        "චීනයේ සාදන ලද 054 A/P වර්ගයේ නෞකාවන් හතරෙන් දෙවැන්න වන PNS Taimur, 2022 ජූනි 23 දින ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. මෙම පන්තියේ ප්‍රධාන නෞකාව PMNS Tughril වන අතර එය 2022 ජනවාරි 24 වන දින ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. චීනය ද යුවාන් අටක් ඉදිකරමින් සිටී. පන්තිය -041 ඩීසල් ප්‍රහාරක සබ්මැරීන 2028 වන විට පකිස්තානය සඳහා යුධමය වශයෙන් ඉහළ මුහුදේ ඉන්දියාවට පැමිනීමේ අරමුණින්. (හින්දුස්ථාන් ටයිම්ස්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩකා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hudong-Zhonghua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂැංහයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාම්බෝජය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 12-15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 7-10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙයික් මුජිබ්-උර්-රෙහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංගබන්ධු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජමයිට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1975 අගෝස්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙයික් හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMNS Tughril",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2028",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දුස්ථාන් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தானின் தைமூர் போர்க்கப்பலை நிறுத்த கொழும்பு அனுமதிக்கிறது, இல்லை என்று டாக்கா கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கராச்சியில் பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படையில் இணைவதற்குச் செல்லும் வழியில் கொழும்பில் ஒரு துறைமுக அழைப்பை மேற்கொள்ள சீனக் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்ட பாகிஸ்தானின் வழிகாட்டுதல் ஏவுகணைப் போர்க்கப்பலான PNS Taimurக்கு இலங்கை அனுமதி அளித்துள்ளது. ஷாங்காயில் உள்ள Hudong-Zhonghua கப்பல் கட்டும் தளத்தால் கட்டப்பட்ட இந்த போர்க்கப்பல், கம்போடிய மற்றும் மலேசிய கடற்படைகளுடன் பயிற்சியில் ஈடுபடும் போது பாகிஸ்தானுக்கு தனது முதல் பயணத்தை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளது. இந்த கப்பல் 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 12-15 வரை கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தில் இருக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "பாகிஸ்தான் வழிகாட்டும் ஏவுகணை போர்க்கப்பலுக்கு கொழும்பில் துறைமுக அழைப்பை மேற்கொள்ள இலங்கை அனுமதி வழங்கியிருந்த நிலையில், ஷேக் ஹசீனா அரசாங்கத்தால் ஆகஸ்ட் 7-10 வரை கப்பலுக்கு சாட்டோகிராம் துறைமுகத்தில் துறைமுக அழைப்பை மேற்கொள்ள அனுமதி மறுக்கப்பட்டது. மலேசியாவில் உள்ள லுமுட் துறைமுகத்தில் துறைமுக அழைப்பு.",
        "ராஜதந்திர ஆதாரங்களின்படி, இந்தியாவின் நெருங்கிய நட்பு நாடான பங்களாதேஷ் PNS தைமூருக்கு அனுமதி மறுத்துள்ளது, ஆகஸ்ட் ஷேக் ஹசீனாவிற்கு துக்கம் அனுசரிக்கப்படும் அவரது தந்தை ஷேக் முஜிப்-உர்-ரஹ்மான் பங்கபந்து என்றும் அன்புடன் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். ஆகஸ்ட் 15, 1975 இல் தீவிர இஸ்லாமியவாத சக்திகளை தூண்டியது.",
        "ஷேக் ஹசீனா அரசாங்கம் நரேந்திர மோடி அரசாங்கத்துடன் நெருக்கமாக உள்ளது, அவரது தந்தை மற்றும் குடும்பத்தினர் பாகிஸ்தானின் உத்தரவின் பேரில் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக பங்களாதேஷ் பிரதமர் தெளிவாகத் தெரிவித்தார். 2000 ஆம் ஆண்டு பிரதமராகவும், 2004 ஆம் ஆண்டு அவாமி லீக் தலைவராகவும் இருந்த ஷேக் ஹசீனா மீது தீவிர இஸ்லாமிய சக்திகள் படுகொலை முயற்சியை மேற்கொண்டனர்.",
        "பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா செப்டம்பர் முதல் வாரத்தில் இந்தியாவுக்கு பயணம் மேற்கொள்ள உள்ளார், மேலும் பிரதமர் மோடியுடன் இணைந்து குல்னா துணைப்பிரிவில் உள்ள ராம்பாலில் கூட்டாக உருவாக்கப்பட்ட 1320 மெகா வாட் மைத்ரீ சூப்பர் தெர்மல் பவர் திட்டத்தை தொடங்கி வைக்கிறார்.",
        "சீனாவில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட நான்கு வகை 054 A/P போர்க்கப்பல்களில் இரண்டாவது PNS தைமூர், ஜூன் 23, 2022 அன்று இயக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த வகுப்பின் முன்னணிக் கப்பல் PMNS Tughril ஆகும், மேலும் இது ஜனவரி 24, 2022 அன்று இயக்கப்பட்டது. சீனாவும் எட்டு யுவான்களை உருவாக்குகிறது. 2028 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்குள் பாகிஸ்தானுக்கான வகுப்பு -041 டீசல் தாக்குதல் நீர்மூழ்கிக் கப்பல்கள் இந்தியாவை இராணுவ ரீதியாக உயர் கடலில் இணைக்கும் நோக்கத்துடன். (ஹிந்துஸ்தான் டைம்ஸ்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "டாக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hudong-Zhonghua",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷாங்காய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்போடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 12-15, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 7-10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷேக் முஜிப்-உர்-ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்கபந்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜமைத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15, 1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷேக் ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 23, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMNS துக்ரில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 24, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2028",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்துஸ்தான் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}