{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/විදේශීය-දුම්වැටි-සහ-මත්පැන්-සමග-02ක්-මාට්ටු/11-395194",
  "time_ut": 1657182487,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විදේශීය දුම්වැටි සහ මත්පැන් සමග 02ක් මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "02 caught with foreign cigarettes and alcohol",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two persons were arrested by the Special Task Force officers along with a stock of foreign cigarettes, liquor and dried turmeric worth more than one crore rupees that were illegally imported into Sri Lanka.",
        "Two persons aged 32 and 44, residents of Pussellawa and Kotmale, have been arrested.",
        "According to the information received by the officers of Organized Crime Unit 11 of the Special Task Force, a team of officers including Inspector P.W.A.J.P.K.Wanniarachchi conducted a three-wheeler raid near the Kiribathgoda fuel station as per the instructions of the Special Task Force Commander DIG Varuna Jayasundara. The two suspects were arrested along with a stock of illegally imported foreign cigarettes that were being transported in a vehicle and during further questioning, a stock of illegally imported foreign liquor and dried turmeric hidden in a house located on Wevelduwa Road, Wattala, Hunupitiya was arrested.",
        "During this raid, 40000 foreign cigarettes, 720 bottles of foreign liquor, 4700 kg of dry turmeric and the three-wheeler used to transport them were arrested.",
        "The arrested suspects have been handed over to the Kiribathgoda police to be produced in court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pussellawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotmale",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Organized Crime Unit 11",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P.W.A.J.P.K.Wanniarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiribathgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Varuna Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wevelduwa Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hunupitiya",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "720",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4700 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiribathgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදේශීය දුම්වැටි සහ මත්පැන් සමග 02ක් මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතිවිරෝධීව මෙරටට ගෙන්වන ලද රුපියල් කෝටියකට වැඩි වටිනාකමකින් යුත් විදේශීය දුම්වැටි ,මත්පැන් සහ වියලි කහ තොගයක් සමග පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකායේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "පුස්සැල්ලාව සහ කොත්මලේ යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි කරුවන් වන 32 සහ 44 වියැති පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු මෙසේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකායේ සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ මර්ධන ඒකකය 11 නිලධාරීන්ට ලද තොරතුරකට අනුව විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකායේ අණදෙන නිලධාරී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති වරුණ ජයසුන්දර මහතාගේ උපදෙස් අනුව පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක පී.ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ.ජේ.පී.කේ.වන්නිආරච්චි ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් කිරිබත්ගොඩ ඉන්ධන හල අසල සිදුකල වැටලීමකදී ත්‍රී රෝද රථයකින් ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් සිටි නීති විරෝධීව මෙරටට ආනයනය කල විදේශීය දුම්වැටි තොගයක් සමග සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන වැඩිදුර ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදී වත්තල,හුණුපිටිය ,වේවැල්දුව පාරේ පිහිටි නිවසක් තුල සඟවා තිබු නීති විරෝධීව මෙරටට ගෙන්වන ලද විදේශීය මත්පැන් සහ වියලි කහ තොගයක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම වැටලීමේදී විදේශීය දුම්වැටි 40000 ක් ,විදේශීය මත්පැන් බෝතල් 720ක්,වියලි කහ කිලෝ 4700 ක් සමග ඒවා ප්‍රවාහනයට යොදාගත් ත්‍රී රෝද රථය අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා කිරිබත්ගොඩ පොලිසියට භාරදී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුස්සැල්ලාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොත්මලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ ඒකකය 11",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P.W.A.J.P.K. වන්නිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිබත්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරුණ ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේවැල්දූව පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුණුපිටිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "720",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 4700 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිබත්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெளிநாட்டு சிகரெட் மற்றும் மதுபானங்களுடன் 02 பேர் பிடிபட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் இலங்கைக்கு இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு கோடி ரூபாவிற்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான வெளிநாட்டு சிகரட்கள், மதுபானம் மற்றும் உலர் மஞ்சள் என்பனவற்றுடன் இருவர் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "புஸ்ஸல்லாவ மற்றும் கொத்மலை பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 32 மற்றும் 44 வயதுடைய இருவரே இவ்வாறு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு 11 இன் அதிகாரிகளுக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் பிரகாரம், விசேட அதிரடிப்படை தளபதி பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் வருணவின் பணிப்புரைக்கமைய கிரிபத்கொட எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் பீ.டபிள்யூ.ஏ.ஜே.பி.கே.வன்னியாராச்சி உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகள் அடங்கிய குழுவினர் முச்சக்கரவண்டி சோதனையை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர். ஜயசுந்தர, வத்தளை, வத்தளை, வெவெல்துவ வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள வீடொன்றில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட வெளிநாட்டு சிகரெட்டுகள் மற்றும் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளின் போது, ​​சந்தேக நபர்கள் இருவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "இந்தச் சுற்றிவளைப்பின் போது 40000 வெளிநாட்டு சிகரெட்டுகள், 720 வெளிநாட்டு மதுபான போத்தல்கள், 4700 கிலோகிராம் உலர் மஞ்சள் மற்றும் அவற்றை எடுத்துச் செல்ல பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட முச்சக்கர வண்டி என்பன கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர்கள் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்துவதற்காக கிரிபத்கொட பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஸ்ஸல்லாவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொத்மலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றப் பிரிவு 11",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P.W.A.J.P.K.வன்னியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரிபத்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருண ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெவெல்துவ வீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹுனுப்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "720",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4700 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரிபத்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}