{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/PUCSL-to-probe-power-cut-on-5th-Lane-last-night/108-240748",
  "time_ut": 1657431010,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PUCSL to probe power cut on 5th Lane last night",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PUCSL to probe power cut on 5th Lane last night",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The PUCSL said today an investigation will be launched over the power outage around 5th Lane, where the private residence of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe is located, at the time it was attacked last night.",
        "PUCSL said there was no scheduled power cuts at that time and they will probe as to how the power was out at that time."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ 5 වන මංතීරුවේ විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීම ගැන සොයා බැලීමට මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස පිහිටි 5 වන පටුමගට ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල වූ අවස්ථාවේදී එම ප්‍රදේශයේ විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කරන බව මහජන කොමිසන් සභාව පවසයි.",
        "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම ප්‍රකාශ කළේ එම අවස්ථාවේ නියමිත පරිදි විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සිදු නොවූ අතර එම අවස්ථාවේ විදුලිය විසන්ධි වූයේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நேற்று இரவு 5வது பாதையில் ஏற்பட்ட மின்வெட்டு குறித்து ஆய்வு செய்ய PUCSL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் அமைந்துள்ள 5 வது பாதையை சுற்றி நேற்று இரவு தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்ட நேரத்தில் மின்சாரம் தடைப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் என PUCSL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட மின்வெட்டு எதுவும் இல்லை என்றும், அந்த நேரத்தில் மின்சாரம் எப்படி இருந்தது என்பது குறித்து ஆய்வு செய்யப்படும் என்றும் PUCSL தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}