{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’’නන්දලාල්-වෙනුවෙන්-මම-ගෙදර-යන්නම්’’/101-619174",
  "time_ut": 1662098745,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’නන්දලාල් වෙනුවෙන් මම ගෙදර යන්නම්’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"I will go home for Nandalal\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Foreign Affairs and President's Attorney Mr. Ali Sabri said in Parliament today (2) that he is ready to step down on behalf of the Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe.",
        "Mr. Ali Sabri said this during the second reading debate on the Budget Appropriation Bill.",
        "The Minister of Foreign Affairs who said that he would make a request to everyone not to jump after the Governor of the Central Bank, said that he is a person who has fulfilled what he said.",
        "He said that this is a good budget and the first step in building the country has been taken.",
        "Mr. Ali Sabri also said that all parties are requested to support the implementation of the budget proposals.",
        "The Minister of Foreign Affairs said that since Sri Lanka has gone to the blacklist for non-payment of debt, no one will give loans to the country today and also stated that the country's economic crisis is not the result of what happened yesterday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nandalal",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Budget Appropriation Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’නන්දලාල් වෙනුවෙන් මම ගෙදර යන්නම්’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා ඉවත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නම්  ඔහු  වෙනුවෙන් තමා ඉවත්වීමට සූදානම් බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ  අලි සබ්‍රි මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී  අද (2)  පැවසීය.",
        "අලි සබ්‍රි  මහතා මෙසේ පැවසූවේ අයවැය විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත පිළිබඳ දෙවැනි වර කියවීමේ විවාදයේදීය.",
        "මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා පස්සේ පැන්නීමෙන් වළකින්නැයි  තමා සියලු දෙනාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කරන බව පැවසූ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ඔහු කියූ දේ ඉටු කළ පුද්ගලයකු බවද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මෙය හොඳ අය වැයක් බවත් රට  ගොඩනැගීමේ පළමු පියවර මින් තැබූ බවත්  හෙතෙම  සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අයවැය යෝජනා ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහාය දෙන ලෙස සියලූ පාර්ශවවලින්  ඉල්ලීමක්  කරන බවද අලි සබ්‍රි මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය නොගෙවීම පිළිබඳ  අසාදු ලේඛනයට ගොස් ඇති හෙයින්  රටට අද  කිසිවකුත් ණය ලබා නොදෙන බව පැවසූ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා  රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය අද ඊයේ සිදුවූ දේ වල ප්‍රතිඵලයක් නොවේ යැයිද  ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නන්දලාල්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයවැය විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"நான் நந்தலாலுக்காக வீட்டுக்குப் போறேன்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவின் சார்பில் பதவி விலகத் தயார் என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சரும் ஜனாதிபதியின் சட்டத்தரணியுமான திரு.அலி சப்ரி இன்று (2) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலம் மீதான இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு விவாதத்தின் போதே திரு.அலி சப்ரி இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநரின் பின்னால் குதிக்க வேண்டாம் என அனைவரிடமும் கோரிக்கை விடுப்பதாக தெரிவித்த வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், தான் சொன்னதை நிறைவேற்றியவர்.",
        "இது நல்ல பட்ஜெட் என்றும், நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான முதல் அடி எடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட முன்மொழிவுகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கு அனைத்துத் தரப்பினரும் ஆதரவளிக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுவதாகவும் திரு.அலி சப்ரி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடனை செலுத்தாத காரணத்தினால் இலங்கை கறுப்புப் பட்டியலில் சிக்கியுள்ளதால், இன்று யாரும் நாட்டுக்கு கடன் வழங்க மாட்டார்கள் என தெரிவித்த வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி நேற்று நேற்றைய தினம் ஏற்பட்டதல்ல எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நந்தலால்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட் ஒதுக்கீட்டு மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}