{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/all-bark-and-no-bite/",
  "time_ut": 1657029660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All bark and no bite",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All bark and no bite",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliament was thrown into turmoil once again yesterday, when a group of Opposition MPs staged a boisterous protest against President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s presence in the House. They shouted themselves hoarse, asking the President to step down. The whole country has been asking the President to go home, but he carries on regardless. Politicians who savour power never give it up of their own volition; they are like limpets. So, no amount of shouting will help the SJB, the other Opposition parties in Parliament, and the public see the back of the President, as it stands. It looks as if the Opposition had to change its strategy.",
        "The government still has a working majority in Parliament; it therefore has the edge in shouting matches in the House and can secure the passage of bad laws. Yesterday, there were dozens of government MPs shouting in support of the President. The Opposition has its work cut out as regards its plan to topple the government by mustering enough numbers in Parliament, and this may be the reason why it has taken its battle to the streets. A similar situation arose towards the latter stages of the yahapalana government. The UNP-led UNF retained an absolute majority in the House with the help of the JVP and the TNA although it was losing popular support rapidly. The SLPP intensified its campaign outside Parliament and turned the tables on the  yahapalana regime; it won the presidential and parliamentary polls with huge majorities. But this time around, there is neither an election in sight nor a guarantee that the next government to be elected would be a stable one, and the present crisis would go away even if Parliament resolved to dissolve itself and a snap general election was held anytime soon. There’s the rub. The SJB, other anti-government forces, and the country will stand to gain only if all parties get together to break the back of the crisis before the next general election.",
        "It has been reported that the Opposition is planning to launch a continuous protest soon to pressure the President to resign. The President is not likely to step down due to protests, but if he happens to find himself in a situation where he is left with no alternative but to sacrifice Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and appoint a new government with someone else as the PM, to save his skin, he will not scruple to do so. After all, he had his own brother, Mahinda, step down as the PM, didn’t he? In fact, he offered the premiership to SJB leader Sajith Premadasa before appointing Wickremesinghe PM. Anything is possible in politics.",
        "The Opposition may have thought yesterday’s protest against the President would go down well with the irate public, languishing in queues and skipping meals, but such gimmicks will not help solve their problems. People are so indignant that they may love to see the President and other government grandees being ridiculed, but that does not serve their purpose. The interests of the public will be served only if all political parties, which are responsible for the mess the country has got into over the years, albeit to varying degrees, speak with one voice and act unitedly to resolve the crisis.",
        "President Rajapaksa may have sought to prove MP Wimal Weerawansa wrong by attending Parliament yesterday. The latter said on Monday that the President was nowhere to be seen, the implication being that he was in hiding. But the President’s presence only led to a serious disruption to parliamentary proceedings in a time when the national legislature should remain maniacally focused on how to contain the crisis. The IMF and foreign governments have told Sri Lanka with one voice that it has to get its act together to qualify for financial assistance, but its political leaders are jousting for supremacy instead of sinking their differences and working out a common agenda to save the economy.",
        "Meanwhile, Prime Minister Wickremesinghe threw down a challenge to JVP leader, Anura Kumara Dissanayake, who claims to be able to revive the economy in six months. He said he would resign, allowing Dissanayake to take over as the PM if the latter could present to Parliament a workable plan to resolve the crisis so fast. Will Dissanayake take up the challenge or continue to protest? The SJB also can reveal to the House how it intends to sort out the economy, and thereafter ask for the reins of government to implement its economic recovery programme. Such a course of action will be much more effective, and beneficial to the country than shouting.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "dozens",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe PM",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සියලුම පොත්ත සහ කටගැස්මක් නැත",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සභා ගැබට පැමිණීමට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් ඊයේ දැඩි විරෝධතාවයක් පැවැත්වීමත් සමඟ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව යළිත් නොසන්සුන්තාවකට පත් විය. ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉවත් වන ලෙස කියමින් ඔවුහු ඝෝෂා කළහ. මුළු රටම ජනාධිපතිතුමාට ගෙදර යන්න කියලා ඉල්ලුවත් ඔහු එය නොතකා ඉදිරියට යනවා. බලය රසවිඳින දේශපාලකයින් කිසිවිටෙක එය තම කැමැත්තෙන් අත් නොහරිති. ඔවුන් දෙපා වාගේ ය. ඉතින් කොච්චර කෑ ගැහුවත් SJB එකටයි, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඉන්න අනිත් විරුද්ධ පක්ෂවලටයි, මහජනතාවටයි ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ පස්ස පැත්ත පෙනෙන්නේ නැහැ. විපක්ෂයට තම උපාය මාර්ගය වෙනස් කිරීමට සිදු වූ බව පෙනේ.",
        "ආණ්ඩුවට තවමත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වැඩකරන බහුතරයක් ඇත; එබැවින් එය සභාව තුළ කෑගැසීමේ තරඟවල කෙළවරක් ඇති අතර නරක නීති සම්මත කිරීම සුරක්ෂිත කළ හැකිය. ඊයේ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු දුසිම් ගනනක් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහය පළ කරමින් කෑ ගසමින් සිටියහ. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රමාණවත් සංඛ්‍යාවක් රැස්කරගෙන ආන්ඩුව පෙරලීමේ සැලැස්ම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විපක්ෂයේ වැඩකටයුතු කපා හැර ඇති අතර, ඔවුන් තම සටන පාරට බැසීමට හේතුව එය විය හැකිය. යහපාලන ආණ්‌ඩුවේ අවසාන අදියරේදී ද එවැනිම තත්ත්වයක්‌ ඇති විය. එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය ප්‍රමුඛ එක්සත් ජාතික පෙරමුණ ජනතා සහය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් ගිලිහී යමින් තිබුණද ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ සහ දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සහාය ඇතිව සභාවේ නිරපේක්ෂ බහුතරයක් රඳවා ගත්තේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටත සිය ප්‍රචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය තීව්‍ර කර යහපාලන තන්ත්‍රය දෙසට මේසය හැරෙව්වා. එය අතිවිශාල බහුතර බලයකින් ජනාධිපතිවරණ සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය. නමුත් මෙවර මැතිවරණයක් හෝ ඉදිරියෙන් පත්වන ආණ්ඩුව ස්ථාවර එකක් බවට සහතිකයක් නොමැති අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැර ඕනෑම වේලාවක හදිසි මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වුවද වත්මන් අර්බුදය පහව යනු ඇත. ඉක්මනින්. අඹරන එක තියෙනවා. SJB, අනෙකුත් ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී බලවේග සහ රටට වාසි අත්වන්නේ ඉදිරි මහ මැතිවරණයට පෙර අර්බුදයේ කොන්ද කඩන්නට සියලු පක්ෂ එකතු වුවහොත් පමණි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලපෑම් කිරීම සඳහා විපක්ෂය නුදුරේදීම අඛණ්ඩ විරෝධතාවක් දියත් කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ. විරෝධතා නිසා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉවත් වීමට ඉඩක් නැති නමුත් අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ බිල්ලට දී වෙනත් අයෙකු අගමැති කර අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවක් පත් කිරීම හැර වෙනත් විකල්පයක් නැති තත්ත්වයකට පත් වුවහොත් එය බේරා ගැනීමටය. ඔහුගේ සම, එසේ කිරීමට ඔහු නොසැලී සිටියි. කොහොමටත් ඔහුට ඔහුගේම සහෝදරයා වූ මහින්ද අගමැතිකමෙන් ඉවත් විය, නේද? ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, ඔහු වික්‍රමසිංහ අගමැති කිරීමට පෙර SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාසට අගමැතිකම පිරිනැමුවේය. දේශපාලනයේ ඕනෑම දෙයක් කරන්න පුළුවන්.",
        "පෝලිම්වල රස්තියාදු වෙමින්, ආහාර වේල් මඟහරිමින්, කුපිත වූ මහජනතාව අතරට ඊයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට එරෙහි විරෝධතාව හොඳින් යයි යැයි විපක්ෂය සිතන්නට ඇතත්, එවැනි ජිමික්ස්වලින් ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇත. ජනතාව කොතරම් කෝපයට පත් වී ඇත්ද යත්, ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අනෙකුත් රජයේ ලොක්කන් විහිළුවට ලක් කරනු දැකීමට ඔවුන් කැමති විය හැකි නමුත් එය ඔවුන්ගේ අරමුණ ඉටු නොවේ. වසර ගණනාවක් මුළුල්ලේ රට පත්වී ඇති ව්‍යාකූලත්වයට වගකිව යුතු සියලු දේශපාලන පක්‍ෂ විවිධ මට්ටම්වලින් වුවද එක හඬින් කතාකර අර්බුදය විසඳීමට එකමුතුව ක්‍රියා කළහොත් පමණක් මහජනතාවගේ අවශ්‍යතා ඉටුවනු ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණ විමල් වීරවංශ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා වැරදි බව ඔප්පු කිරීමට රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයා උත්සාහ කරන්නට ඇත. දෙවැන්නා සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොතැනකවත් පෙනෙන්නට නැති බවත්, එයින් ගම්‍ය වන්නේ ඔහු සැඟවී සිටින බවයි. එහෙත් ජාතික ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය අර්බුදය පාලනය කරන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව උමතු ලෙස අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතු මොහොතක ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පැමිණීම පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතුවලට බරපතල බාධාවක් ඇති කිරීමට හේතු විය. මූල්‍ය ආධාර සඳහා සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමට එක්ව ක්‍රියා කළ යුතු බව IMF සහ විදේශ ආන්ඩු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එක හඬින් පවසා ඇතත්, එහි දේශපාලන නායකයින් තම මතභේද ගිල්වා ආර්ථිකය බේරා ගැනීම සඳහා පොදු න්‍යාය පත්‍රයක් සකස් කිරීම වෙනුවට ආධිපත්‍යය සඳහා දඟලමින් සිටිති.",
        "මේ අතර, මාස හයකින් ආර්ථිකය පණ ගැන්වීමට හැකි බව කියන ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකට අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ අභියෝගයක් එල්ල කළේය. දිසානායක මහතාට මේ තරම් ඉක්මනින් අර්බුදය විසඳා ගැනීමට හැකි වැඩපිළිවෙළක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකි නම් දිසානායක මහතාට අගමැති ධූරයේ වැඩ භාර ගැනීමට ඉඩ ලබා දෙමින් තමා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. දිසානායක එම අභියෝගය භාර ගනීද නැතිනම් දිගටම විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වෙයිද? SJB ද ආර්ථිකය නිරාකරණය කිරීමට අදහස් කරන ආකාරය සභාවට හෙළි කළ හැකි අතර, ඉන් පසුව එහි ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසාධන වැඩසටහන ක්‍රියාවට නැංවීම සඳහා ආණ්ඩු බලය ඉල්ලා සිටිය හැකිය. එවැනි ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් කෑගැසීමට වඩා බෙහෙවින් ඵලදායී වනු ඇත, රටට වාසිදායක වනු ඇත.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුසිම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑන්එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ පී.එම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்து பட்டை மற்றும் கடி இல்லை",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பிரசன்னத்திற்கு எதிராக எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் குழு நேற்று கடும் எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதையடுத்து, பாராளுமன்றம் மீண்டும் குழப்பமடைந்தது. குடியரசுத் தலைவரை பதவி விலகச் சொல்லி உரக்கக் குரல் எழுப்பினர். ஜனாதிபதியை வீட்டுக்குச் செல்லுமாறு நாடு முழுவதும் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தும் அவர் அதனைப் பொருட்படுத்தாமல் தொடர்கிறார். அதிகாரத்தை ருசிக்கும் அரசியல்வாதிகள் தங்கள் சொந்த விருப்பத்தின் பேரில் அதை ஒருபோதும் கைவிட மாட்டார்கள்; அவை முட்டுக்கட்டைகள் போன்றவை. எனவே, SJB, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள மற்ற எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் மற்றும் பொதுமக்கள் ஜனாதிபதியின் முதுகில் இருப்பதைப் பார்க்க எவ்வளவு கூச்சலிட்டாலும் உதவாது. எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தங்களின் வியூகத்தை மாற்றிக் கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்று தோன்றுகிறது.",
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இன்னும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை பலம் உள்ளது; எனவே அது ஹவுஸில் கூச்சலிடுவதில் விளிம்பைக் கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் மோசமான சட்டங்களை நிறைவேற்றுவதைப் பாதுகாக்க முடியும். நேற்று, ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஆதரவாக டஜன் கணக்கான அரசாங்க எம்.பி.க்கள் முழக்கமிட்டனர். பாராளுமன்றத்தில் போதிய எண்ணிக்கையை திரட்டி அரசாங்கத்தை கவிழ்க்கும் திட்டத்தை எதிர்கொள்வது குறித்து எதிர்கட்சி தனது வேலைகளை வெட்டியுள்ளது, மேலும் அது தனது போராட்டத்தை வீதிக்கு எடுத்ததற்கு இதுவே காரணமாக இருக்கலாம். யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தின் இறுதிக் கட்டங்களிலும் இதே போன்றதொரு நிலைமை ஏற்பட்டது. UNP தலைமையிலான UNF மக்கள் ஆதரவை விரைவாக இழந்த போதிலும் ஜேவிபி மற்றும் TNA உதவியுடன் சபையில் அறுதிப் பெரும்பான்மையை தக்கவைத்துக் கொண்டது. SLPP பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வெளியே தனது பிரச்சாரத்தை தீவிரப்படுத்தியது மற்றும் யஹபாலன ஆட்சியின் மீது மேசைகளைத் திருப்பியது; ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்களில் பெரும் பெரும்பான்மையுடன் வெற்றி பெற்றது. ஆனால், இம்முறை, தேர்தலோ, அடுத்ததாக அமையும் அரசாங்கம் நிலையானதாக அமையும் என்பதற்கான உத்திரவாதமோ தெரிவதில்லை, நாடாளுமன்றம் கலைக்கப்பட்டு, பொதுத் தேர்தல் எப்போது வந்தாலும் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடி நீங்கும். விரைவில். தேய்த்தல் இருக்கிறது. அடுத்த பொதுத் தேர்தலுக்கு முன்னர் நெருக்கடியின் முதுகை உடைக்க அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளும் ஒன்றிணைந்தால் மட்டுமே எஸ்.ஜே.பி., மற்ற அரசாங்க விரோத சக்திகள் மற்றும் நாட்டுக்கு லாபம் கிடைக்கும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய வலியுறுத்தி எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் விரைவில் தொடர் போராட்டத்தை நடத்த திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளது. எதிர்ப்புகள் காரணமாக ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலக வாய்ப்பில்லை, ஆனால் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பலிகொடுத்து வேறு ஒருவரை பிரதமராகக் கொண்டு புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை நியமிப்பதைத் தவிர வேறு வழியில்லை என்ற நிலைமை அவருக்கு ஏற்பட்டால் காப்பாற்றும். அவரது தோல், அவர் அவ்வாறு செய்ய மாட்டார். எல்லாவற்றிற்கும் மேலாக, அவர் தனது சொந்த சகோதரரான மஹிந்தவை பிரதமர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகினார், இல்லையா? உண்மையில், விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக நியமிப்பதற்கு முன்னர் அவர் SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவுக்கு பிரதமர் பதவியை வழங்கினார். அரசியலில் எதுவும் சாத்தியம்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எதிரான நேற்றைய போராட்டம் ஆத்திரமடைந்த பொதுமக்கள், வரிசையில் நின்று உணவைத் தவிர்த்துவிட்டுச் செல்லும் என்று எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் நினைத்திருக்கலாம், ஆனால் இதுபோன்ற வித்தைகள் அவர்களின் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தீர்க்க உதவாது. ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிற அரசாங்கப் பிரபுக்கள் கேலி செய்யப்படுவதைக் கண்டு மக்கள் மிகவும் கோபமடைந்துள்ளனர், ஆனால் அது அவர்களின் நோக்கத்தை நிறைவேற்றவில்லை. நாடு கடந்த பல ஆண்டுகளாக ஏற்பட்டுள்ள குழப்பங்களுக்குக் காரணமான அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் ஒரே குரலில் பேசி, ஒற்றுமையாகச் செயல்பட்டு நெருக்கடிகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்குப் போராடினால் மட்டுமே பொதுமக்களின் நலன்கள் மேம்படும்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்சவை தவறு என்று நிரூபிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு சென்றிருக்கலாம். பிந்தையவர் திங்களன்று ஜனாதிபதியை எங்கும் காணவில்லை என்று கூறினார், அவர் தலைமறைவாக இருக்கிறார். ஆனால் தேசிய சட்டமன்றம் நெருக்கடியை எவ்வாறு கட்டுப்படுத்துவது என்பதில் வெறித்தனமாக கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டிய நேரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரசன்னம் பாராளுமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு கடுமையான இடையூறுக்கு வழிவகுத்தது. சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு அரசாங்கங்கள் நிதி உதவிக்கு தகுதி பெறுவதற்கு ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்பட வேண்டும் என்று இலங்கையிடம் ஒரே குரலில் கூறியுள்ளன, ஆனால் அதன் அரசியல் தலைவர்கள் தங்கள் கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை மூழ்கடித்து பொருளாதாரத்தை காப்பாற்ற ஒரு பொதுவான நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலை உருவாக்குவதற்கு பதிலாக மேலாதிக்கத்திற்காக துடிக்கிறார்கள்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஆறு மாதங்களில் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்டெடுக்க முடியும் என்று கூறும் ஜே.வி.பி தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திசாநாயக்கவுக்கு பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க சவால் ஒன்றை விடுத்தார். நெருக்கடியை மிக விரைவாக தீர்க்கும் செயற்திட்டத்தை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்வைக்க முடியுமென்றால் திஸாநாயக்க பிரதமராக பதவியேற்க அனுமதித்து தான் பதவி விலகுவதாக அவர் கூறினார். திஸாநாயக்க இந்த சவாலை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வாரா அல்லது தொடர்ந்து ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுவாரா? SJB பொருளாதாரத்தை எவ்வாறு வரிசைப்படுத்த உத்தேசித்துள்ளது என்பதையும் சபைக்கு வெளிப்படுத்த முடியும், அதன் பின்னர் அதன் பொருளாதார மீட்சித் திட்டத்தைச் செயல்படுத்த அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆட்சியைக் கேட்க வேண்டும். கூச்சலிடுவதை விட, இத்தகைய நடவடிக்கை மிகவும் பயனுள்ளதாகவும், நாட்டுக்கு பயனுள்ளதாகவும் இருக்கும்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டஜன் கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க பி.எம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}