{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/05/verstappen-wins-dramatic-dutch-gp/",
  "time_ut": 1662355380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Verstappen wins dramatic Dutch GP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Verstappen wins dramatic Dutch GP",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Max Verstappen held onto victory in a captivating 2022 Dutch Grand Prix amid a strong showing from the Mercedes and late Safety Car drama at Zandvoort, as George Russell and Charles Leclerc completed the podium.",
        "Verstappen seemed to be assured of victory having taken a second pit stop during a Virtual Safety Car on Lap 48, with Hamilton second and Russell third as both had extended their opening stint on medium tyres (their rivals having started on softs) to pit for hards, on which they were rapid. The events after a Lap 55 Safety Car dashed any hopes of victory that Hamilton harboured, however.",
        "The seven-time champion stayed out on mediums to inherit the lead while Verstappen came in for softs, followed by Russell and Leclerc, for the restart on Lap 61. In that restart, Verstappen swept past the Mercedes for the lead, with Russell and Leclerc following suit to pry Hamilton away from the podium.",
        "Hamilton ended up fourth at the flag as Carlos Sainz and Sergio Perez – the former held back by a calamitous Ferrari pit stop earlier on, before a five-second penalty for an unsafe release in a later stop – battled late on for P5. That allowed Alonso and Norris to close in too, and when the penalty kicked in Sainz was dropped to eighth, promoting Perez to fifth, Alonso to sixth, and Norris to seventh.",
        "Esteban Ocon finished ninth, just ahead of Lance Stroll – who started and finished 10th for Aston Martin. Pierre Gasly missed out on the points in P11 for AlphaTauri while Alex Albon finished 12th from 15th on the grid.",
        "Sebastian Vettel started 19th and finished 14th, losing out to Mick Schumacher – who lost out due to a pair of slow pit stops. The four-time champion was given a five-second penalty for ignoring blue flags earlier in the race.",
        "Kevin Magnussen hit the barriers on Lap 2 but continued to finish 15th, behind his Haas team mate. Daniel Ricciardo pitted first out of the pack and couldn’t make up ground, finishing 17th for McLaren behind Zhou Guanyu, who served a five-second penalty for speeding in the pit lane.",
        "Valtteri Bottas was classified 19th for Alfa Romeo, his car stopping on track to bring out the late Safety Car.",
        "Yuki Tsunoda stopped on track on Lap 48 after reporting a driveshaft issue, the AlphaTauri driver having previously reported that his tyres were incorrectly fitted before a lengthy pit stop."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dutch",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Max Verstappen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dutch Grand Prix",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Safety Car",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zandvoort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "George Russell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charles Leclerc",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hamilton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Lap 55 Safety Car",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hamilton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leclerc",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 61",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercedes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leclerc",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hamilton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hamilton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carlos Sainz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sergio Perez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ferrari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-second",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "P5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sainz",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alonso",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seventh",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Esteban Ocon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ninth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lance Stroll",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aston Martin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pierre Gasly",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P11",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "AlphaTauri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alex Albon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sebastian Vettel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th and finished 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mick Schumacher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-second",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kevin Magnussen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 2",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "finish 15th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daniel Ricciardo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "McLaren",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhou Guanyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-second",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Valtteri Bottas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alfa Romeo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Safety Car",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuki Tsunoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 48",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "AlphaTauri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Verstappen නාට්‍යමය ලන්දේසි GP දිනා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජෝර්ජ් රසල් සහ චාල්ස් ලෙක්ලර්ක් වේදිකාව සම්පූර්ණ කරන විට, සැන්ඩ්වෝර්ට් හි මර්සිඩීස් සහ ප්‍රමාද වූ සේෆ්ටි කාර් නාට්‍යයේ ප්‍රබල දර්ශනයක් මධ්‍යයේ මැක්ස් වර්ස්ටැපන් ආකර්ශනීය 2022 ලන්දේසි ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී තරගයේ ජයග්‍රහණය අත්කර ගත්තේය.",
        "48 වන වටයේ අතථ්‍ය ආරක්‍ෂිත මෝටර් රථයක් අතරතුර දෙවන පිට නැවතුමට යාමෙන් Verstappen ජයග්‍රහණය සහතික කර ඇති බවක් පෙනෙන්නට තිබුණි, හැමිල්ටන් දෙවනුව සහ රසල් තෙවන ස්ථානයට පත් වූ අතර දෙදෙනාම මධ්‍යම ටයර් (ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රතිවාදීන් මෘදු මත ආරම්භ කර ඇත) ඔවුන්ගේ ආරම්භක කාලය දීර්ඝ කර ඇත. , ඔවුන් වේගවත් වූ මත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ලැප් 55 ආරක්ෂිත මෝටර් රථයකින් පසු සිදුවීම් හැමිල්ටන්ගේ ජයග්‍රහණය පිළිබඳ බලාපොරොත්තු බිඳ දැමීය.",
        "හත් වරක් ශූරයා පෙරමුණට උරුමකම් කියන මාධ්‍යවලින් ඈත් වූ අතර වර්ස්ටැපන් මෘදු ක්‍රීඩා සඳහා පැමිණි අතර පසුව රසල් සහ ලෙක්ලර්ක් 61 ලැප්හි නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා පැමිණියහ. එම නැවත ආරම්භයේදී වර්ස්ටැපන් මර්සිඩීස් ඉදිරියෙන් සිටි අතර රසල් සහ ලෙක්ලර්ක් සමඟින් පෙරමුණ ගත්තේය. හැමිල්ටන් වේදිකාවෙන් ඉවතට තල්ලු කිරීමට අනුගමනය",
        "කාලෝස් සයින්ස් සහ සර්ජියෝ පෙරෙස් ධජයේ සිවුවැනි ස්ථානයට පත් වූ අතර, පෙර නැවතුමකදී අනාරක්ෂිත ලෙස මුදා හැරීම සඳහා තත්පර පහක දඩුවමකට පෙර විපත්තිදායක ෆෙරාරි නැවැත්වීමකින් පෙරට ගිය හැමිල්ටන් P5 සඳහා ප්‍රමාද වී සටන් කළේය. එය ඇලොන්සෝ සහ නොරිස්ට ද වසා දැමීමට ඉඩ සැලසූ අතර, සයින්ස් හි පයින් ගැසූ දඩුවම අටවැනි ස්ථානයට වැටුණු විට, පෙරෙස් පස්වන ස්ථානයට, ඇලොන්සෝ හයවැනි ස්ථානයට සහ නොරිස් හත්වැනි ස්ථානයට උසස් කරන ලදී.",
        "Esteban Ocon නවවන ස්ථානයට පත් විය, ලාන්ස් ස්ට්‍රෝල්ට වඩා ඉදිරියෙන් - ඇස්ටන් මාටින් සඳහා ආරම්භ කර 10 වැනි ස්ථානය අවසන් කළේය. AlphaTauri වෙනුවෙන් Pierre Gasly හට P11 හි ලකුණු අහිමි වූ අතර Alex Albon 15 වැනි ස්ථානයේ සිට 12 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත්විය.",
        "සෙබස්තියන් වෙටෙල් 19 වැනි ස්ථානය ආරම්භ කර 14 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත් වූ අතර, මන්දගාමී පිට් නැවතුම් යුගලයක් හේතුවෙන් මික් ෂූමාකර්ට අහිමි විය. සිව් වතාවක් ශූරයා වූ ඔහුට තරඟයේ කලින් නිල් කොඩි නොසලකා හැරීම හේතුවෙන් තත්පර පහක දඩයක් ලබා දෙන ලදී.",
        "Kevin Magnussen 2 වටයේ බාධකවලට පහර දුන් නමුත් ඔහුගේ Haas කණ්ඩායමේ සහකරුට පිටුපසින් 15 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත්විය. Daniel Ricciardo ප්‍රථමයෙන් පිටියෙන් ඉවත් වූ අතර බිම සකස් කිරීමට නොහැකි වූ අතර, වළේ මංතීරුවේ වේගයෙන් ධාවනය කිරීම සඳහා තත්පර පහක දඬුවමක් ලබා දුන් Zhou Guanyu පිටුපසින් McLaren සඳහා 17 වන ස්ථානය ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "Valtteri Bottas Alfa Romeo සඳහා 19 වැනි ලෙස වර්ග කරන ලදී, ඔහුගේ මෝටර් රථය ප්‍රමාද වූ ආරක්ෂිත මෝටර් රථය පිටතට ගෙන ඒම සඳහා මාර්ගයේ නතර විය.",
        "ඩ්‍රයිව් ෂාෆ්ට් ගැටළුවක් වාර්තා කිරීමෙන් පසු යුකී ට්සුනෝඩා 48 ලැප් එකේදී නතර විය, ඇල්ෆා ටවුරි රියදුරු දිගු වළක් නැවැත්වීමට පෙර ඔහුගේ ටයර් වැරදි ලෙස සවි කර ඇති බව කලින් වාර්තා කර තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලන්දේසි",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැක්ස් වර්ස්ටැපන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්දේසි ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මර්සිඩීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂිත මෝටර් රථය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zandvoort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝර්ජ් රසල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාල්ස් ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැමිල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රසල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lap 55 ආරක්ෂිත මෝටර් රථයක්",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැමිල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රසල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61 වටය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මර්සිඩීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රසල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැමිල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැමිල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carlos Sainz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ජියෝ පෙරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර පහක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "P5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සයින්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරෙස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලොන්සෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Esteban Ocon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාන්ස් ස්ට්‍රෝල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇස්ටන් මාටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියරේ ගෑස්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P11",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "AlphaTauri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්ස් ඇල්බන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙබස්තියන් වෙටෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි ස්ථානය සහ 14 වැනි ස්ථානය අවසන් විය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මික් ෂූමාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර පහක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙවින් මැග්නුසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උකුල 2",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 අවසන් කරන්න",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daniel Ricciardo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැක්ලරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhou Guanyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර පහක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Valtteri Bottas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ෆා රෝමියෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂිත මෝටර් රථය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuki Tsunoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වටය 48",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "AlphaTauri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் வியத்தகு டச்சு ஜிபியை வென்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜார்ஜ் ரஸ்ஸல் மற்றும் சார்லஸ் லெக்லெர்க் ஆகியோர் மேடையை நிறைவு செய்ததால், மெர்சிடிஸ் மற்றும் ஜான்ட்வோர்ட்டில் தாமதமான பாதுகாப்பு கார் நாடகத்தின் வலுவான காட்சிக்கு மத்தியில், 2022 டச்சு கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸில் மேக்ஸ் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் வெற்றியைத் தக்க வைத்துக் கொண்டார்.",
        "லேப் 48 இல் விர்ச்சுவல் சேஃப்டி காரின் போது வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் இரண்டாவது பிட் ஸ்டாப் எடுத்ததால் வெற்றி பெறுவது உறுதி என்று தோன்றியது, ஹாமில்டன் இரண்டாவது மற்றும் ரசல் மூன்றாவது இடம், நடுத்தர டயர்களில் (அவர்களது போட்டியாளர்கள் சாஃப்ட்களில் ஆரம்பித்துவிட்டார்கள்) தங்கள் தொடக்க காலத்தை நீட்டித்ததால் கடினமானது. , அதில் அவர்கள் வேகமாக இருந்தனர். எவ்வாறாயினும், ஒரு லேப் 55 பாதுகாப்பு காருக்குப் பிறகு நடந்த நிகழ்வுகள், ஹாமில்டன் வைத்திருந்த வெற்றியின் எந்த நம்பிக்கையையும் சிதைத்துவிட்டன.",
        "ஏழு முறை சாம்பியனான மீடியம்களில் முன்னணியில் இருந்து வெளியேறினார், அதே நேரத்தில் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் சாஃப்ட்களுக்கு வந்தார், அதைத் தொடர்ந்து ரஸ்ஸல் மற்றும் லெக்லெர்க், லேப் 61 இல் மறுதொடக்கம் செய்தார். அந்த மறுதொடக்கத்தில், ரஸ்ஸல் மற்றும் லெக்லெர்க்குடன் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் மெர்சிடஸைக் கடந்தார். ஹாமில்டனை மேடையில் இருந்து விலக்கி வைப்பதைத் தொடர்ந்து.",
        "ஹாமில்டன் கார்லோஸ் சைன்ஸ் மற்றும் செர்ஜியோ பெரெஸ் ஆகியோர் கொடியில் நான்காவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தனர் - முந்தைய ஃபெராரி பிட் ஸ்டாப்பால் முன்பு ஒரு பேரழிவு தரும் ஃபெராரி பிட் ஸ்டாப்பால் தடுத்து நிறுத்தப்பட்டார், பின்னர் நிறுத்தத்தில் பாதுகாப்பற்ற ரிலீஸுக்கு ஐந்து வினாடிகள் பெனால்டி - P5 க்கு தாமதமாகப் போராடினார். அது அலோன்சோ மற்றும் நோரிஸையும் நெருங்க அனுமதித்தது, மேலும் சைன்ஸில் உதைக்கப்பட்ட பெனால்டி எட்டாவது இடத்திற்கு கைவிடப்பட்டது, பெரெஸை ஐந்தாவது இடத்திற்கும், அலோன்சோ ஆறாவது இடத்திற்கும், நோரிஸை ஏழாவது இடத்திற்கும் உயர்த்தியது.",
        "ஆஸ்டன் மார்ட்டினுக்கு 10வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்த லான்ஸ் ஸ்ட்ரோலுக்கு சற்று முன்னதாக எஸ்டெபன் ஓகான் ஒன்பதாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார். AlphaTauriக்கான P11 புள்ளிகளை Pierre Gasly தவறவிட்டார், அதே நேரத்தில் Alex Albon 15வது இடத்தில் இருந்து 12வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார்.",
        "செபாஸ்டியன் வெட்டல் 19வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்து 14வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார், மிக் ஷூமேக்கரிடம் தோற்றார் - ஒரு ஜோடி மெதுவாக பிட் ஸ்டாப்புகளால் தோற்றார். நான்கு முறை சாம்பியனானவருக்கு முன்னதாக பந்தயத்தில் நீலக் கொடிகளை புறக்கணித்ததற்காக ஐந்து வினாடிகள் அபராதம் விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கெவின் மேக்னுசென் லேப் 2 இல் தடைகளைத் தாக்கினார், ஆனால் அவரது ஹாஸ் அணியின் துணைக்கு பின்னால் 15 வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார். Daniel Ricciardo முதலில் பேக்கிற்கு வெளியே களமிறங்கினார், மேலும் மெக்லாரனுக்கு 17 வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார், Zhou Guanyu க்கு பின்னால் இருந்தார், அவர் பிட் லேனில் வேகமாகச் சென்றதற்காக ஐந்து-வினாடி பெனால்டியைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "வால்டேரி போட்டாஸ், ஆல்ஃபா ரோமியோவிற்காக 19வது தரப்படுத்தப்பட்டார், அவரது கார் தாமதமான பாதுகாப்பு காரை வெளியே கொண்டு வர பாதையில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "டிரைவ்ஷாஃப்ட் சிக்கலைப் புகாரளித்த பின்னர், யுகி சுனோடா லேப் 48 இல் பாதையில் நின்றார், நீண்ட பிட் ஸ்டாப்புக்கு முன் அவரது டயர்கள் தவறாகப் பொருத்தப்பட்டதாக ஆல்பாடாரி டிரைவர் முன்பு தெரிவித்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டச்சு",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேக்ஸ் வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டச்சு கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெர்சிடிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கார்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்ட்வூர்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்ஜ் ரஸ்ஸல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சார்லஸ் லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஸ்ஸல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு லேப் 55 பாதுகாப்பு கார்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஸ்ஸல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடி 61",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெர்சிடிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஸ்ஸல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்லோஸ் சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செர்ஜியோ பெரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபெராரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து-வினாடி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "P5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலோன்சோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்டெபன் ஓகான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லான்ஸ் உலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்டன் மார்ட்டின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியர் கேஸ்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி11",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "AlphaTauri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்ஸ் அல்பன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செபாஸ்டியன் வெட்டல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது இடத்தையும், 14வது இடத்தையும் பிடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிக் ஷூமேக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து-வினாடி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெவின் மாக்னுசென்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடி 2",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஆம் தேதி முடிக்க",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேனியல் ரிச்சியார்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெக்லாரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhou Guanyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து-வினாடி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வால்டேரி போட்டாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆல்ஃபா ரோமியோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கார்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuki Tsunoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மடி 48",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "AlphaTauri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}