{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/25/private-buses-to-cater-to-school-students-today-25/",
  "time_ut": 1658726040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Private Buses to cater to school students today (25)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Private Buses to cater to school students today (25)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association says that despite the lack of fuel, a sufficient number of buses were deployed for school children today (25).",
        "The Chairman of Lanka Private Bus Owners Association Gemunu Wijeratne said that fuel was received from several places in the last two days.",
        "The Director General of the National Transport Commission Nilan Miranda said that according to the quantity of fuel received, steps have been taken to deploy Sisusariya buses for the students.",
        "The Chairman of All Ceylon School Child Transport Association Malshree Silva said that more vans have been deployed for the transportation of school students today (25) due to sufficient fuel being received through SLTB Depots.",
        "F1: Verstappen wins French Grand Prix after Leclerc crashes out"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka Private Bus Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Transport Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilan Miranda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisusariya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malshree Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "French Grand Prix",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leclerc",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද (25) පාසල් සිසුන් සඳහා පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ ධාවනයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන හිඟය මධ්‍යයේ වුවද පාසල් සිසුන් සඳහා ප්‍රමාණවත් බස් රථ සංඛ්‍යාවක් අද (25) යෙදවූ බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා පැවසුවේ පසුගිය දින දෙක තුළ ස්ථාන කිහිපයකින් ඉන්ධන ලැබුණු බවයි.",
        "ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් නිලාන් මිරැන්ඩා මහතා පැවසුවේ, ලැබුණු ඉන්ධන ප්‍රමාණය අනුව සිසුන් සඳහා සිසුසැරිය බස් රථ යෙදවීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංගම ඩිපෝ හරහා ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ලැබෙන නිසා අද (25) පාසල් සිසුන් ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා වෑන් රථ වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් යොදවා ඇති බව සමස්ත ලංකා පාසල් ළමා ප්‍රවාහන සංගමයේ සභාපති මල්ශ්‍රී සිල්වා මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "F1: Leclerc බිඳ වැටීමෙන් පසු Verstappen ප්‍රංශ ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී දිනා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලාන් මිරැන්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසුසැරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්ශ්‍රී සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රංශ ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රී",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙක්ලර්ක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனியார் பேருந்துகள் இன்று (25) பாடசாலை மாணவர்களின் சேவையை வழங்குகின்றன.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறை இருந்தபோதிலும், பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்காக போதிய எண்ணிக்கையிலான பஸ்கள் இன்று (25) சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்களில் பல இடங்களில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் பெறப்பட்டதாக லங்கா தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பெறப்பட்ட எரிபொருளின் அளவுக்கேற்ப மாணவர்களுக்காக சிசுசரிய பஸ்களை சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணைக்குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் நிலான் மிரண்டா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை டிப்போக்கள் மூலம் போதியளவு எரிபொருள் கிடைக்கப்பெறுவதால் இன்று (25) பாடசாலை மாணவர்களின் போக்குவரத்துக்காக அதிகளவான வான்கள் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பாடசாலை சிறுவர் போக்குவரத்து சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் மல்ஸ்ரீ சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "F1: லெக்லெர்க் தோல்வியடைந்த பிறகு வெர்ஸ்டாப்பன் பிரெஞ்சு கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸை வென்றார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலன் மிராண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசுசாரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மல்ஸ்ரீ சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரெஞ்சு கிராண்ட் பிரிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெக்லெர்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}