{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/19/additional-25-mn-from-australia-to-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1660892460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Additional $ 25 Mn from Australia to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Additional $ 25 Mn from Australia to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Australia will provide an additional $25 million to help Sri Lanka meet urgent food and healthcare needs, as it confronts its worst economic crisis in 70 years.",
        "During this challenging period, Australia stands with the people of Sri Lanka, especially those experiencing severe hardship, said Pat Conroy MP, Australian Minister for International Development and the Pacific.",
        "This additional support brings Australia’s Official Development Assistance response to $75 million.",
        "\"Our support will be delivered through UN agencies to provide food, health and nutrition services, access to safe water and essential support for those at risk, including women and children,\" said Pat Conroy MP, Australian Minister for International Development and the Pacific.",
        "Australia’s continued assistance to Sri Lanka supports our mutual interest in a secure and resilient Indian Ocean and reinforces our 75 year-strong relationship built on cooperation and community connection.",
        "The extra humanitarian assistance is in addition to the $23 million in ongoing development assistance to Sri Lanka in 2022-23."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "an additional $25 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Conroy MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$75 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Conroy MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$23 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අමතර ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): වසර 70කට පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හදිසි ආහාර සහ සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව අමතර ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක් ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ, විශේෂයෙන්ම දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ දෙන ජනතාව සමඟ සිටින බව, ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධන සහ පැසිෆික් පිළිබඳ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු අමාත්‍ය පැට් කොන්රෝයි මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම අතිරේක සහාය ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ නිල සංවර්ධන ආධාර ප්‍රතිචාරය ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 දක්වා ගෙන එයි.",
        "\"ආහාර, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ පෝෂණ සේවා, ආරක්ෂිත ජලය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය සහ කාන්තාවන් සහ ළමුන් ඇතුළු අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටින අයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීම සඳහා අපගේ සහයෝගය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන හරහා ලබා දෙනු ඇත,\" ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධන සහ පැසිෆික් අමාත්‍ය පැට් කොන්රෝයි එම්පී පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ අඛණ්ඩ සහාය ආරක්‍ෂිත සහ ඔරොත්තු දෙන ඉන්දියන් සාගරයක් සඳහා අපගේ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය උනන්දුවට සහාය වන අතර සහයෝගීතාවය සහ ප්‍රජා සම්බන්ධතාවය මත ගොඩනගා ඇති අපගේ 75 වසරක ශක්තිමත් සබඳතාව ශක්තිමත් කරයි.",
        "අතිරේක මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022-23 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැනට පවතින සංවර්ධන ආධාර සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 23 ට අමතරව වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 70 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැට් කොන්රෝයි මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර සංවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැට් කොන්රෝයි මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර සංවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 23 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆஸ்திரேலியாவில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கூடுதல் $25 Mn",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): 70 வருடங்களில் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கையின் அவசர உணவு மற்றும் சுகாதாரத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய ஆஸ்திரேலியா கூடுதல் $25 மில்லியன் வழங்கவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த சவாலான காலகட்டத்தில், அவுஸ்திரேலியா இலங்கை மக்களுடன், குறிப்பாக கடும் இன்னல்களை அனுபவிக்கும் மக்களுடன் நிற்கிறது என அவுஸ்திரேலிய சர்வதேச அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் பசுபிக் அமைச்சர் பாட் கொன்ரோய் எம்.பி.",
        "இந்த கூடுதல் ஆதரவு ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ மேம்பாட்டு உதவிக்கான பதிலை $75 மில்லியனாகக் கொண்டு வருகிறது.",
        "\"உணவு, சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து சேவைகள், பாதுகாப்பான நீர் அணுகல் மற்றும் பெண்கள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகள் உட்பட ஆபத்தில் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய ஆதரவை வழங்குவதற்கு ஐ.நா. ஏஜென்சிகள் மூலம் எங்களது ஆதரவு வழங்கப்படும்\" என்று ஆஸ்திரேலிய சர்வதேச வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் பசிபிக் அமைச்சர் பாட் கான்ராய் எம்.பி கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவியானது, பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் மீள்தன்மையுடைய இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் எங்களின் பரஸ்பர ஆர்வத்தை ஆதரிக்கிறது மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் சமூக இணைப்பில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்ட 75 வருட வலுவான உறவை வலுப்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "2022-23 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டு வரும் 23 மில்லியன் டொலர்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் $25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாட் கான்ராய் எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வளர்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$75 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாட் கான்ராய் எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வளர்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$23 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}