{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84437/navy-seizes-petrol-stock-worth-over-rs-900000-in-kalpitiya",
  "time_ut": 1661076360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy seizes petrol stock worth over Rs. 900,000 in Kalpitiya",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy seizes petrol stock worth over Rs. 900,000 in Kalpitiya",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Navy seized about 2,030 liters of petrol, made ready to be transported by illegal means during a special operation carried out in Sengumalawatta area in Kalpitiya in the evening of August 20.",
        "Three suspects and two lorries were also taken into custody along with the seized fuel volumes.",
        "In this special operation, SLNS Vijaya in the Northwestern Naval Command had searched 02 suspicious lorries in Sengumalawatta area in Kalpitiya and the operation led to the seizure of about 2030 liters of petrol made ready to be transported by illegal means.",
        "The apprehended suspects were identified as residents of Kalpitiya, Wariyapola and Rathnapura, who are from 28 to 48 years of age.",
        "Meanwhile, the market value of the stock of seized petrol has been estimated over Rs. 900,000. The suspects along with petrol and the vehicles used for the illegal act were handed over to the Kalpitiya Police for onward legal action."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "900,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kalpitiya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2,030",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sengumalawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Vijaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northwestern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sengumalawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 2030",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wariyapola",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 to 48 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalpitiya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් නාවික හමුදා භාරයට කල්පිටියේ 900,000 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අගෝස්තු 20 වැනිදා සවස කල්පිටිය, සෙංගුමලවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට සූදානම් කර තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 2,030ක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ඉන්ධන තොග සමඟ සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු සහ ලොරි රථ දෙකක් ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "මෙම විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමේදී වයඹ නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා විජය නෞකාව කල්පිටිය, සෙංගුමලවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේදී සැකකටයුතු ලොරි රථ 02ක් සෝදිසි කර ඇති අතර, එම මෙහෙයුමේදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට සූදානම් කර තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 2030ක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් කල්පිටිය, වාරියපොළ සහ රත්නපුර ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි අවුරුදු 28 සිට 48 දක්වා වයස්වල පසුවන්නන් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පෙට්‍රල් තොගයේ වෙළඳපල වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධිකයි. 900,000 කි. සැකකරුවන් සහ පෙට්‍රල් තොගය සහ නීති විරෝධී ක්‍රියාව සඳහා යොදාගත් වාහන ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා කල්පිටිය පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "900,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කල්පිටිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,030 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙංගුමලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා විජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙංගුමලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරියපොළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 28 සිට 48 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "900,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්පිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரூபாவிற்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான பெற்றோல் பங்குகளை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர். கல்பிட்டியில் 900,000",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 20 ஆம் திகதி மாலை கல்பிட்டி செங்குமலவத்தை பகுதியில் இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் மேற்கொண்ட விசேட சுற்றிவளைப்பின் போது சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கொண்டு செல்ல தயாரான சுமார் 2030 லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட எரிபொருளுடன் மூன்று சந்தேக நபர்களும் இரண்டு லொறிகளும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த விசேட நடவடிக்கையில், வடமேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையின் SLNS விஜயா கல்பிட்டி, செங்குமலவத்தை பகுதியில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான 02 லொறிகளை சோதனையிட்டதுடன், சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கொண்டு செல்ல தயார் செய்யப்பட்ட சுமார் 2030 லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் கல்பிட்டி, வாரியபொல மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் எனவும், அவர்கள் 28 முதல் 48 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்கள் எனவும் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட பெட்ரோலின் சந்தை மதிப்பு ரூ. 900,000. சந்தேகநபர்கள் பெற்றோல் மற்றும் சட்டவிரோத செயலுக்கு பயன்படுத்திய வாகனங்கள் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக கல்பிட்டி பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "900,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கல்பிட்டி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2,030",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செங்குமலவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS விஜயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செங்குமலவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2030",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரியபொல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 முதல் 48 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்பிட்டி பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}