{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලොරි-ලොරි-ගැටී-දෙකක්-මරු-දකිති/101-619003",
  "time_ut": 1661845004,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලොරි-ලොරි ගැටී දෙකක් මරු දකිති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two are killed in a lorry-lorry collision",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tissamaharama police said that a small lorry traveling on Hambantota Tissamaharama road to Weerawila Tissamaharama collided with a lorry stopped in Tissapura area on the 30th at around 5.00 am. .",
        "W., a resident of Senapura, Tissamaharama, who was traveling in the small lorry, died. S. Ranjani (58) and K.M. who resided in Gagasiripura in Tissamaharama. Asela Lakmal (33) is the two. The injured Ranjith Udayakumara, a resident of Gagasiripura, has been taken to hospital with serious injuries.",
        "The dead body has been kept at Debarawewa Base Hospital mortuary. Magistrate examination is scheduled to be held today on 30th.",
        "The lorry involved in the accident and Ridurat's small lorry were also arrested and Tissamaharama police station chief police investigation A.D. A team of officers including Mr. Kariyawasam and Police Investigation Officer Pushpakumara of the Traffic Division are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawila Tissamaharama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Senapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Ranjani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.M.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissamaharama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asela Lakmal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Udayakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gagasiripura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ridurat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Traffic Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලොරි-ලොරි ගැටී දෙකක් මරු දකිති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හම්බන්තොට තිස්සමහාරාම පාරේ වීරවිල තිස්සමහාරාමය දක්වා දාවනය වූ කුඩා ලොරි රථයක් අද 30 වන දින උදේ 5.00 පමණ තිස්සපුර ප්‍රෙද්ශයේදී නතරකර තිබූ ලොරි රථයක ගැටීමෙන් කුඩා ලොරි රථයේ ගමන්ගත් රියදුරා හා කාන්තාවක එම ස්ථානයේම මියගොස් බරපතළ තුවාල ලැබූ තවත් අයෙකු දෙබරවැව මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති බව තිස්සමහාරාම පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ කුඩා ලොරි රථයේ ගමන්ගත් තිස්සමහාරාමයේ සේනපුර පදිංචිව සිටි ඩබ්ලිව්. එස්. රංජනී (58) හා තිස්සමහාරාමයේ ගගසිරිපුර පදිංචිව සිටි කේ.එම්. අසේල ලක්මාල් (33) යන දෙදෙනාය. බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගත කර ඇත්තේ ගගසිරිපුර පදිංචි රංජිත් උදයකුමාර යන තුවාලකරුය.",
        "මළ සිරුර දෙබරවැව මූලික රෝහලේ මෘත ශරීරාගාරයේ තබා ඇත. මහේස්ත්‍රාත් පරීක්ෂණ  අද 30 වන දින පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "අනතුරට සම්බන්ධ ලොරි රථය හා රිදුරාත් කුඩා ලොරි රථයත් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිස්සමහාරාම පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස පරීක්ෂණ ඒ.ඩී. කාරියවසම් මහතා හා රථවාහන අංශයේ ස්ථානාධිපති පොලිස් පරීක්ෂණ පුෂ්පකුමාර මහතා ඇතුලු නිලධාරීහු කණ්ඩායමක් වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවිල තිස්සමහාරාමය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්සපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සේනපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.රංජනී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.එම්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්සමහාරාම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසේල ලක්මාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් උදයකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගගසිරිපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිදුරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රථවාහන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லாரியும் லாரியும் மோதிக் கொண்டதில் இருவர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அம்பாந்தோட்டை திஸ்ஸமஹாராம வீதியில் வீரவில திஸ்ஸமஹாராம நோக்கிச் சென்ற சிறிய லொறி ஒன்று திஸ்ஸபுர பகுதியில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருந்த லொறியுடன் 30ஆம் திகதி அதிகாலை 5.00 மணியளவில் மோதியதாக திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சிறிய லொறியில் பயணித்த திஸ்ஸமஹாராம சேனபுர பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த டபிள்யூ. எஸ். ரஞ்சனி (வயது 58) மற்றும் திஸ்ஸமஹாராம, ககசிரிபுரவில் வசித்து வந்த கே.எம். அசேல லக்மால் (33) ஆகிய இருவரும். படுகாயமடைந்த காகசிரிபுர பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ரஞ்சித் உதயகுமார என்பவர் படுகாயமடைந்த நிலையில் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சடலம் தெபரவெவ ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையின் பிரேத அறையில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. மாஜிஸ்திரேட் தேர்வு இன்று 30ம் தேதி நடைபெற உள்ளது.",
        "விபத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய லொறி மற்றும் ரிதுரத்தின் சிறிய லொறியும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸ் நிலையப் பிரதான பொலிஸ் விசாரணை ஏ.டி. திரு. காரியவசம், போக்குவரத்துப் பிரிவின் பொலிஸ் புலனாய்வு அதிகாரி புஷ்பகுமார உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழு மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவில திஸ்ஸமஹாராம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சேனாபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ரஞ்சனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.எம்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸமஹாராம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசேல லக்மால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் உதயகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ககாசிரிபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிதுரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}