{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78650",
  "time_ut": 1658258640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Six-time Prime Minister and acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe elected President by the  Sri Lanka Parliament on July 20; Defeats  Dullas Alahapperuma by 134 Votes to 82 While Anura Kumara Dissanayake gets 3 Votes",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Six-time Prime Minister and acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe elected President by the  Sri Lanka Parliament on July 20; Defeats  Dullas Alahapperuma by 134 Votes to 82 While Anura Kumara Dissanayake gets 3 Votes",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Six-time Prime Minister and acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe was on July 20 elected President of Sri Lanka — a post that has eluded him despite a near-half century political career — in extraordinary circumstances of a political crisis triggered by the island’s economic crash.",
        "Mr. Wickremesinghe won 134 votes in the 225-member Parliament, securing a comfortable victory margin in a three-way contest. Dullas Alahapperuma, a formerly Rajapaksa-aligned, now independent MP, won 82 votes, despite several independent lawmakers, the main opposition, and most minority parties pledging to back him on Tuesday. The leftist Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna’s candidate Anura Kumara Dissanayake won just three votes. Two MPs abstained from the vote.",
        "“The time for division is over,” Mr. Wickremesinghe said in his first remarks after clinching Presidency. He urged all political parties to come together to take the country on the path of economic recovery.",
        "This is the third unlikely elevation this year for Mr. Wickremesinghe, 73, since Sri Lanka’s economic crisis worsened. The sole member of his United National Party (UNP) in Parliament, Mr. Wickremesinghe entered the current Parliament not through a poll victory in his constituency, but through the national list, based on the party’s total vote share in the 2020 general elections.",
        "On May 12, recently ousted President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appointed him as Prime Minister, replacing Mahinda Rajapaksa, who had resigned days earlier, in the wake of violence triggered by his protesters who assaulted peaceful anti-government protesters. On July 13, Mr. Wickremesinghe was appointed Acting President, just ahead of Mr. Gotabaya’s resignation after he fled the island and took refuge in the Maldives, and later Singapore, after protesters stormed his office and home in an escalation of mass resistance to his government.",
        "Mr. Wickremesinghe will helm the country during its worst economic crisis since Independence, which has put citizens amidst crippling shortages and soaring living costs. However, his election comes amid enduring public protests from citizens’ groups that accuse him of being a Rajapaksa “enabler”.",
        "Mr. Wickremesinghe has denied the charge, and said he took the PM’s post only to set the country’s economy in order. In a Twitter thread on Monday, Mr. Wickremesinghe claimed power cuts and fuel distribution had improved since he took charge as Premier in May, although thousands of citizens are still braving long queues for days together to purchase fuel.",
        "“I call upon all political parties in the country to put aside their differences and come together. I urge everyone to help form an All-Party Government which would allow the country to recover from the economic crisis,” he had said.",
        "Following the passage of the 20th Amendment by the Rajapaksa government in 2020, Sri Lanka’s President enjoys unbridled powers and greater immunity. Mr. Wickremesinghe has pledged to bring about constitutional changes to clip the Executive’s powers and in turn empower the Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "82",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Votes",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a near-half century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "days earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 20th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හය වතාවක් අගමැති සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජූලි 20 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය. ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ඡන්ද 134 ට 82 කින් පරාජය කළ අතර අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකට ඡන්ද 3 ක්",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "හය වතාවක් අගමැති සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජූලි 20 වන දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් විය - අඩ සියවසකට ආසන්න දේශපාලන ජීවිතයක් තිබියදීත් ඔහුට මග හැරුණු තනතුරක් - දිවයිනේ ආර්ථික බිඳවැටීම මගින් අවුලුවන ලද දේශපාලන අර්බුදයක අසාමාන්‍ය තත්වයන් තුළ.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225කින් සමන්විත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඡන්ද 134ක් ලබා ගනිමින් තුන්කොන් තරගයකින් පහසු ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබා ගත්තේය. ස්වාධීන නීති සම්පාදකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු, ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය සහ බොහෝ සුළු පක්ෂ අඟහරුවාදා ඔහුට සහාය දෙන බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දී තිබියදීත්, කලින් රාජපක්ෂ-පක්ෂගත, දැන් ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ඡන්ද 82 ක් ලබා ගත්තේය. වාමාංශික ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ අපේක්ෂක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට හිමිවූයේ ඡන්ද තුනක් පමණි. මන්ත්‍රීවරු දෙදෙනෙක් ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියහ.",
        "\"බෙදීමේ කාලය අවසන්\" යැයි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු සිය පළමු ප්‍රකාශයේදී පැවසීය. රට ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිමත් කිරීමේ මාවතට ගෙනයාමට සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ එක්වන ලෙස ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය නරක අතට හැරීමෙන් පසු, 73 හැවිරිදි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට මේ වසරේ සිදු විය නොහැකි තුන්වන ඉහළ යාම මෙයයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තම එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ (එජාප) එකම මන්ත්‍රීවරයා වන වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේ ඔහුගේ මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාශයේ ඡන්ද ජයග්‍රහණයකින් නොව, 2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී පක්ෂයේ මුළු ඡන්ද ප්‍රමාණය මත පදනම්ව ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ය.",
        "සාමකාමී රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පහර දුන් ඔහුගේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ඇති කරන ලද ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හමුවේ, දින කිහිපයකට පෙර ඉල්ලා අස් වූ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ වෙනුවට මැයි 12 දින, මෑතකදී නෙරපා හරින ලද ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඔහුව අගමැති ලෙස පත් කළේය. ජුලි 13 දින, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබුවේ, ගෝඨාභය මහතා දිවයිනෙන් පලා ගොස් මාලදිවයිනේ සහ පසුව සිංගප්පූරුවේ සරණාගත වීමෙන් පසුව, විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලයට සහ නිවසට කඩා වැදී ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට මොහොතකට පෙරය. ආණ්ඩුව.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු රට අත්විඳින දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නායකත්වය දෙනු ඇත, එය පුරවැසියන් අබලන් වූ හිඟයන් සහ ඉහළ යන ජීවන වියදම් මධ්‍යයේ තබා ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහුගේ තේරී පත්වීම සිදුවන්නේ ඔහු රාජපක්ෂ \"සක්‍රීය කරන්නෙකු\" බවට චෝදනා කරන පුරවැසි කණ්ඩායම්වල මහජන විරෝධතා විඳදරාගැනීම මධ්‍යයේ ය.",
        "එම චෝදනාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, තමන් අගමැති ධූරයට පත්වූයේ රටේ ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට පමණක් බව කියා සිටියේය. සඳුදා ට්විටර් ත්‍රෙඩ් එකක වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කියා සිටියේ තමා මැයි මාසයේ අගමැති ලෙස පත්වීමෙන් පසු විදුලි කප්පාදුව සහ ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම වැඩිදියුණු වී ඇති නමුත් දහස් ගණනක් පුරවැසියන් තවමත් ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා දිගු පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටින බවයි.",
        "“රටේ සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්‍ෂවලින් මම ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ මතභේද පසෙකලා එකට එකතු වන ලෙසයි. ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් රට ගොඩ ගැනීමට හැකි වන පරිදි සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට උදව් කරන ලෙස මම සියලු දෙනාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමි.",
        "2020 දී රාජපක්ෂ රජය විසින් 20 වැනි සංශෝධනය සම්මත කිරීමෙන් පසුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා අසීමිත බලතල සහ වැඩි මුක්තියක් භුක්ති විඳියි. විධායකයේ බලතල කපා හැර පාර්ලිමේන්තුව බල ගැන්වීම සඳහා ව්‍යවස්ථාමය වෙනස්කම් ගෙන එන බවට වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "82",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඡන්ද",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩ සියවසකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆறு முறை பிரதமராகவும், தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் இருந்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜூலை 20 அன்று இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றத்தால் ஜனாதிபதியாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்; 82க்கு எதிராக 134 வாக்குகள் வித்தியாசத்தில் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை தோற்கடித்த அதேவேளை அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 3 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆறு முறை பிரதமராகவும், தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் இருந்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இலங்கையின் அதிபராக ஜூலை 20 அன்று தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார் - கிட்டத்தட்ட அரை நூற்றாண்டு அரசியல் வாழ்க்கை இருந்தபோதிலும், தீவின் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியால் தூண்டப்பட்ட ஒரு அரசியல் நெருக்கடியின் அசாதாரண சூழ்நிலையில்.",
        "225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட பாராளுமன்றத்தில் திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று, மும்முனைப் போட்டியில் வசதியான வெற்றி வித்தியாசத்தைப் பெற்றார். செவ்வாய்க்கிழமையன்று பல சுயேச்சை சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள், பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் பெரும்பாலான சிறுபான்மைக் கட்சிகள் அவருக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்த போதிலும், முன்னர் ராஜபக்சேவுடன் இணைந்த, இப்போது சுயேச்சையான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரான டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும 82 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார். இடதுசாரி ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனவின் வேட்பாளர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க வெறும் மூன்று வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளார். இரண்டு எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்கெடுப்பில் கலந்து கொள்ளவில்லை.",
        "“பிரிவுக்கான காலம் முடிந்துவிட்டது,” என்று திரு. நாட்டைப் பொருளாதார மீட்சிப் பாதையில் கொண்டு செல்ல அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் ஒன்றிணைய வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "73 வயதான திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மோசமடைந்ததன் பின்னர், இந்த வருடத்தில் சாத்தியமில்லாத மூன்றாவது உயர்வு இதுவாகும். பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் (UNP) ஏக உறுப்பினரான திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு தனது தொகுதியில் கிடைத்த வாக்கெடுப்பு வெற்றியின் மூலம் அல்ல, மாறாக 2020 பொதுத் தேர்தலில் கட்சியின் மொத்த வாக்குகளின் அடிப்படையில் தேசியப் பட்டியல் மூலம் நுழைந்தார்.",
        "மே 12 அன்று, சமீபத்தில் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, அமைதியான அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டக்காரர்களைத் தாக்கிய அவரது எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் தூண்டப்பட்ட வன்முறையைத் தொடர்ந்து, சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்னர் ராஜினாமா செய்த மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவுக்குப் பதிலாக அவரைப் பிரதமராக நியமித்தார். ஜூலை 13 அன்று, திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, தீவை விட்டு வெளியேறி மாலத்தீவிலும், பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூரிலும் தஞ்சம் புகுந்த திரு. கோட்டாபய ராஜினாமா செய்வதற்கு சற்று முன்னதாக, அவரது அலுவலகத்தையும் வீட்டையும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டு வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்பை அதிகரித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, செயல் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். அரசாங்கம்.",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் போது திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமை தாங்குவார், இது குடிமக்களை முடமான பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் உயரும் வாழ்க்கைச் செலவுகளுக்கு மத்தியில் வைத்துள்ளது. எவ்வாறாயினும், அவர் ஒரு ராஜபக்ச \"செயல்படுத்துபவர்\" என்று குற்றம் சாட்டும் குடிமக்களின் குழுக்களின் சகிப்புத்தன்மையின் பொது எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு மத்தியில் அவரது தேர்தல் வந்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் குற்றச்சாட்டை மறுத்துள்ள திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை சீரமைப்பதற்காகவே பிரதமர் பதவியை எடுத்ததாகக் கூறினார். திங்கட்கிழமை ட்விட்டர் இழையில், திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, மே மாதம் பிரதமராகப் பொறுப்பேற்றதில் இருந்து மின்வெட்டு மற்றும் எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் மேம்பட்டுள்ளதாகக் கூறினார், இருப்பினும் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான குடிமக்கள் எரிபொருளை வாங்குவதற்காக நீண்ட வரிசையில் நீண்ட வரிசையில் நிற்கின்றனர்.",
        "“நாட்டில் உள்ள அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் தங்கள் கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை ஒதுக்கி வைத்துவிட்டு ஒன்று சேருமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன். பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுக்க அனுமதிக்கும் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க உதவுமாறு அனைவரையும் நான் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "2020 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ராஜபக்சே அரசாங்கத்தால் 20 வது திருத்தம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கட்டுப்பாடற்ற அதிகாரங்களையும் அதிக நோய் எதிர்ப்பு சக்தியையும் அனுபவித்து வருகிறார். திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரங்களை குறைக்கவும், அதையொட்டி பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அதிகாரம் அளிக்கவும் அரசியலமைப்பு மாற்றங்களை கொண்டு வர உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "82",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "வாக்குகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட அரை நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனாவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}