{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/under-22-a-president-can-hold-ministerial-positions/",
  "time_ut": 1659431820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Under 22-A President can hold ministerial positions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Under 22-A President can hold ministerial positions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Justice, President's Counsel Dr. Wijeyadasa Rajapapkshe says under the 22nd Amendment Bill approved by the Cabinet, the President can hold ministerial positions.",
        "Addressing the Cabinet Press Briefing today, Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe said under the 22nd Amendment, the President will continue to hold the powers and privileges of the Defence Minister.",
        "He added that under the 22nd Amendment, it has been proposed to increase the time allocated to challenge a bill submitted to the Parliament before the Supreme Court, up to 14-days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapapkshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amendment Bill",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet Press Briefing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22-A යටතේ ජනාධිපතිට ඇමති ධුර දැරිය හැකිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද 22 වන සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අමාත්‍ය ධූර දැරිය හැකි බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය, ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අද පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ කියා සිටියේ 22 වන ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය යටතේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ බලතල සහ වරප්‍රසාද තවදුරටත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සතුවන බවයි.",
        "22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය යටතේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් අභියෝගයට ලක් කිරීමට ලබාදී ඇති කාලය දින 14 දක්වා වැඩි කිරීමට යෝජනා කර ඇති බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22-ஏ கீழ் ஜனாதிபதி அமைச்சர் பதவிகளை வகிக்க முடியும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அமைச்சரவையினால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட 22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்தின் கீழ் ஜனாதிபதி அமைச்சர் பதவிகளை வகிக்க முடியும் என நீதியமைச்சர் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று இடம்பெற்ற அமைச்சரவை செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் உரையாற்றிய அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ, 22வது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சருக்கான அதிகாரங்கள் மற்றும் சிறப்புரிமைகளை ஜனாதிபதி தொடர்ந்து வைத்திருப்பார் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ், உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட சட்டமூலத்தை சவால் செய்ய ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட நேரத்தை 14 நாட்களாக அதிகரிக்க முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருத்த மசோதா",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14-நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}