{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sajith-says-people-s-emergencies-are-a-far-cry-from-that-of-Govt/56-738001",
  "time_ut": 1658951721,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith says people’s emergencies are a far cry from that of Govt.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith says people’s emergencies are a far cry from that of Govt.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Alleges State emergency to unleash brutality and terrorism on the people",
        "Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa says the real emergencies of the people are a far cry from that of the Government’s. “The people are always facing emergencies today as they have no fuel, gas",
        "or milk powder for children. They are unable to buy a bag of cement, build a home or even secure a housing loan. The people are dying in fuel queues, and they are even unable to take a patient to a hospital.” he said listing out the many problems faced by the Sri Lankan people today. “They are facing many emergencies in their struggle to simply live. These are the true emergencies on the ground,” he noted.",
        "However, Premadasa said the Government’s emergencies appear to be far different. “This debate is being held in a hurry because it appears the Government’s emergencies are to do with issuing threats and unleashing brutality as well as state terrorism on the people,” he said. Premadasa made these comments during the debate on the continuation of the emergency laws held yesterday. The Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) led by Premadasa voted against the continuity of the state of emergency declared by the President on 18 July.",
        "Premadasa said there were only peaceful protests till the acts of violence against these protestors were perpetrated by former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa on 9 May.  Premadasa called on Government MPs connected to the political group involved in the 9 May incidents to not mislead the Parliament by giving a different narrative on the acts of terrorism they were referring to."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් පවසන්නේ ජනතාවගේ හදිසි අවස්ථා රජයට වඩා බොහෝ දුරස්ථ බවයි.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතාව මත ම්ලේච්ඡත්වය සහ ත්‍රස්තවාදය මුදා හැරීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථාවක් චෝදනා කරයි",
        "ජනතාවගේ සැබෑ හදිසි තත්ත්වය ආණ්ඩුවේ තත්ත්වයට වඩා බොහෝ දුරස් බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසයි. “ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් නොමැති නිසා ජනතාව අද සෑම විටම හදිසි අනතුරුවලට මුහුණ දෙනවා",
        "හෝ දරුවන්ට කිරිපිටි. සිමෙන්ති කොට්ටයක් මිලදී ගැනීමට, නිවසක් සාදා ගැනීමට හෝ නිවාස ණයක් ලබා ගැනීමට පවා ඔවුන්ට හැකියාවක් නැත. ජනතාව ඉන්ධන පෝලිම්වල මිය යමින් සිටින අතර ඔවුන්ට රෝගියෙකු රෝහලකට ගෙන යාමට පවා නොහැකි වී තිබේ. අද ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ගැටලු රාශියක් ලැයිස්තුගත කරමින් ඔහු පැවසීය. “සරලව ජීවත් වීමේ අරගලයේදී ඔවුන් බොහෝ හදිසි අවස්ථා වලට මුහුණ දී සිටිති. මේවා තමයි භූමියේ සැබෑ හදිසි අවස්ථා,” ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසුවේ රජයේ හදිසි අවස්ථා ඊට හාත්පසින්ම වෙනස් බව පෙනේ. \"මෙම විවාදය කඩිමුඩියේ පවත්වනු ලබන්නේ රජයේ හදිසි අවස්ථා තර්ජන නිකුත් කිරීම සහ ම්ලේච්ඡත්වය මෙන්ම රාජ්‍ය ත්‍රස්තවාදය ජනතාව මත මුදා හැරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බව පෙනෙන නිසා\" ඔහු පැවසීය. ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ ඊයේ පැවති හදිසි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම පිළිබඳ විවාදයේදීය. ප්‍රේමදාසගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ජූලි 18 වැනි දින ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීතිය අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මැයි 9 වැනිදා හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් මෙම විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහි ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා සිදු කරන තෙක් පැවතියේ සාමකාමී විරෝධතා පමණක් බව ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය. ඔවුන් සඳහන් කරන ත්‍රස්තවාදී ක්‍රියාවන් පිළිබඳව වෙනස් ආඛ්‍යානයක් ලබා දෙමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොමඟ යවන ලෙස ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මැයි 9 වැනිදා සිදුවීම්වලට සම්බන්ධ දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායමට සම්බන්ධ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மக்களின் அவசரநிலைகள் அரசாங்கத்தின் நிலையிலிருந்து வெகு தொலைவில் இருப்பதாக சஜித் கூறுகிறார்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்கள் மீது மிருகத்தனத்தையும் பயங்கரவாதத்தையும் கட்டவிழ்த்து விடுவதற்காக மாநில அவசரநிலையை குற்றம் சாட்டுகிறது",
        "மக்களின் உண்மையான அவசரநிலை அரசாங்கத்தின் நிலையிலிருந்து வெகு தொலைவில் இருப்பதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார். \"எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயு இல்லாததால் மக்கள் இன்று எப்போதும் அவசரநிலைகளை எதிர்கொள்கிறார்கள்",
        "அல்லது குழந்தைகளுக்கு பால் பவுடர். அவர்களால் ஒரு மூட்டை சிமென்ட் வாங்கவோ, வீடு கட்டவோ, வீட்டுக் கடனைப் பெறவோ முடியவில்லை. மக்கள் எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் இறந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறார்கள், மேலும் அவர்களால் ஒரு நோயாளியை மருத்துவமனைக்கு அழைத்துச் செல்ல முடியவில்லை. இன்று இலங்கை மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பல பிரச்சினைகளை பட்டியலிட்டார். \"அவர்கள் எளிமையாக வாழ்வதற்கான போராட்டத்தில் பல அவசரநிலைகளை எதிர்கொள்கிறார்கள். இவைதான் தரையில் உண்மையான அவசரநிலைகள்” என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அரசாங்கத்தின் அவசரநிலைகள் மிகவும் வேறுபட்டதாகத் தோன்றுவதாக பிரேமதாச கூறினார். \"இந்த விவாதம் அவசரமாக நடத்தப்படுகிறது, ஏனெனில் அரசாங்கத்தின் அவசரநிலைகள் அச்சுறுத்தல்களை வெளியிடுவது மற்றும் மிருகத்தனத்தை கட்டவிழ்த்துவிடுவது மற்றும் மக்கள் மீது அரச பயங்கரவாதத்தை கட்டவிழ்த்துவிடுவது என்று தோன்றுகிறது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தின் தொடர்ச்சி விவாதத்தின் போதே பிரேமதாச மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். பிரேமதாச தலைமையிலான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) ஜனாதிபதியால் ஜூலை 18 அன்று பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அவசரகால நிலை தொடர்வதற்கு எதிராக வாக்களித்தது.",
        "மே 9ஆம் திகதி முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவினால் இந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிரான வன்முறைச் செயல்கள் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் வரை அமைதியான போராட்டங்கள் மாத்திரமே இடம்பெற்றதாக பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்தார். மே 9 சம்பவங்களுடன் தொடர்புடைய அரசியல் குழுவுடன் தொடர்புடைய அரசாங்க எம்.பி.க்கள் அவர்கள் குறிப்பிடும் பயங்கரவாதச் செயல்கள் குறித்து வேறுவிதமான கதைகளை வழங்கி நாடாளுமன்றத்தை தவறாக வழிநடத்த வேண்டாம் என்று பிரேமதாச கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}