{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/හදිසිනීතිය-පොහොට්ටුවේ-ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට-විරුද්ධයි/101-617177",
  "time_ut": 1658996672,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හදිසිනීතිය පොහොට්ටුවේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට විරුද්ධයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Emergency law is against the policies of Potottuwa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Its Founding President, Member of Parliament Professor G.L Peiris said that the imposition of Emergency Law is against the policies and constitution of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna.",
        "Mr. GL Peiris said that it may adversely affect Sri Lanka at the Human Rights Commission, which will be held in Geneva next month, and it may also lead to the loss of the GSP Plus concession.",
        "He said that according to the current situation in Sri Lanka, the existing general law is sufficient to protect people's lives and property, and there is no need to impose the emergency law.",
        "Professor GL Peiris said this while addressing a press conference held today (28) in Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Potottuwa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emergency Law",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හදිසිනීතිය පොහොට්ටුවේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට විරුද්ධයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති හා ව්‍යවස්ථාවට විරුද්ධ බව එහි ආරම්භක සභාපති, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එය ජිනීවාහිදී තවත් මසකින් පැවැත්වෙන මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපෑ හැකි බව කී ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා ජී.එස්.පී ප්ලස් සහනය අහිමිවීමට ද හේතු විය හැකි බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින තත්වය අනුව මහජන ජීවිත හා දේපල ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීමට පවතින සාමාන්‍ය නීතිය ප්‍රමාණවත් බවත්, හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීමේ කිසිඳු අවශ්‍යතාවයක් නැති බවත් හෙතෙම කීවේය.",
        "මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් මහතා මේ බව පැවසුවේ කොළඹ දී අද (28) පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් අමතමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොටොට්ටුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவசர சட்டம் பொதொட்டுவவின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு எதிரானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்படுவது ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்புக்கு எதிரானது என அதன் ஸ்தாபகத் தலைவர், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அடுத்த மாதம் ஜெனீவாவில் நடைபெறவுள்ள மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவில் அது இலங்கைக்கு பாதகமான பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தலாம் என்றும், அது ஜிஎஸ்பி பிளஸ் சலுகையை இழக்க வழிவகுக்கும் என்றும் திரு.ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலவரப்படி மக்களின் உயிர் மற்றும் உடைமைகளைப் பாதுகாக்க தற்போதுள்ள பொதுச் சட்டமே போதுமானது எனவும் அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்த வேண்டிய அவசியமில்லை எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று (28) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொதொட்டுவ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}