{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130403",
  "time_ut": 1656498094,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பொருளாதார சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் அமெரிக்காவின் ஆதரவு குறித்து இரு தரப்பு கலந்துரையாடல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bilateral discussion on US support in tackling economic challenges",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Sri Lankan-US bilateral discussion has taken place on the potential areas of US support in tackling the many challenges posed by the country's economic crisis.",
        "The meeting was held on Tuesday (28) in connection with a meeting between Robert Cabrot, Under Secretary of State for the Treasury of Asia and senior officials representing the US Treasury and State Department, led by Deputy Secretary of State for South and Central Asia Kelly Geiterling, and Foreign Secretary Aruni Wijewardene.",
        "Foreign Secretary Wijewardene welcomed the strong and diversified bilateral partnership between the two countries which is mutually beneficial and contributes towards the well-being of the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "The meeting was also attended by US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Sung and officials from the US Treasury Department, the US Embassy and the US Embassy in Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan-",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Cabrot",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Geiterling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Sung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Treasury Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සහාය පිළිබඳ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාව",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් මතුව ඇති අභියෝග රැසකට මුහුණදීම සඳහා අමෙරිකාවේ සහාය ලැබිය හැකි ක්ෂේත්‍ර පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ඇමරිකා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවක් පවත්වා තිබේ.",
        "ආසියානු භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ නියෝජ්‍ය ලේකම් රොබට් කැබ්‍රොට් සහ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාව භාර නියෝජ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් කෙලී ගයිටර්ලින් ප්‍රමුඛ එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය සහ රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජිතයින් සමඟ මෙම හමුව අඟහරුවාදා (28) පැවැත්විණි. ලේකම් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන.",
        "දෙරට අතර අන්‍යෝන්‍ය වශයෙන් වාසිදායක සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා දායක වන ශක්තිමත් සහ විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික හවුල්කාරිත්වය විදේශ ලේකම් විජේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "මෙම හමුවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී සුං මහත්මිය සහ ඇමෙරිකානු භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ, ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ සහ කොළඹ පිහිටි ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ නිලධාරීන්ද සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික -",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කැබ්රොට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී ගයිටර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි සන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் அமெரிக்காவின் ஆதரவு குறித்து இரு தரப்பு கலந்துரையாடல்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பல சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் அமெரிக்க ஆதரவின் சாத்தியமான பகுதிகள் குறித்து இலங்கை - அமெரிக்க இரு தரப்பு கலந்துரையாடலொன்று இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "ஆசியாவிற்கான திறைசேரி துணைச் செயலாளர் ரொபர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவிற்கான துணை இராஜாங்கச் செயலாளர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் தலைமையிலான அமெரிக்காவின் திறைசேரித் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் , வெளிவிவகார  செயலாளர் அருணி விஜேவர்தன ஆகியோருக்கும் (28) செவ்வாய்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே இவ்விடயம் தொடர்பில் அவதானம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "பரஸ்பரம் நன்மை பயக்கும் மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களின் நல்வாழ்வை நோக்கி பங்களிக்கின்ற இரு நாடுகளுக்குமிடையிலான வலுவான மற்றும் பன்முகத்தன்மை கொண்ட இருதரப்பு பங்காளித்துவத்தை வெளிவிவகாரச் செயலாளர் விஜேவர்தன வரவேற்றார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சங் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க திறைசேரித் திணைக்களம், அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்கத் தூதரகம் ஆகியவற்றின் அதிகாரிகளும் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை -",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கீட்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}