{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/දියේ-ගිලීම්-හේතුවෙන්-මරණ-හා-අතුරුදන්වීම්-6ක්/11-395944",
  "time_ut": 1659411778,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දියේ ගිලීම් හේතුවෙන් මරණ හා අතුරුදන්වීම් 6ක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "6 deaths and disappearances due to drowning",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "03 deaths and missing persons have been reported due to drowning accidents in three places of the island.",
        "Thus, a woman and a girl who were returning home from pre-school in Polpitiya, Hitinegama area had drowned and disappeared. Later, during a joint search operation by the police and local residents, the 5-year-old granddaughter and the 62-year-old grandmother were found and they died when they were admitted to Ginigathhena Hospital.",
        "Two people and a woman have gone missing after crossing the Kambulawa Oya in Akkarawatta, Nawalapitiya. The people who have drowned and disappeared are the residents of Katambulawa area, aged 36, 46, and 47 years.",
        "Meanwhile, police say that one of the three people who were walking home in the Hatton Montafair area slipped and fell into the Panmure lake and went missing. A resident of Hatton, Abosliwatta, has been missing for 24 years."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hitinegama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ginigathhena Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kambulawa Oya",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akkarawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nawalapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katambulawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36, 46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton Montafair",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abosliwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දියේ ගිලීම් හේතුවෙන් මරණ හා අතුරුදන්වීම් 6ක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ ස්ථාන තුනකදි දියේ ගිලීම් හේතුවෙන් සිදුවූ අනතුරු හේතවෙන් පුද්ගල මරණ හා අතුරුදන්විම් 03ක් වාර්තා වී තිබේ.",
        "මේ අනුව පොල්පිටිය, හිටිනේගම ප්‍රෙද්ශයේදී පෙර පාසලේ සිට නිවසට පැමිණෙමින් සිටි කාන්තාවක් හා දැරියක් දියේ ගිලී අතුරුදන්ව තිබුණි. පසුව පොලීසිය හා ප්‍ර දේශවාසීන් එක්ව කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී අවුරුදු 5ක් වන මිණිබිරිය හා අවුරුදු 62ක් වන මිත්තනිය සොයාගෙන ගිනිගත්හේන රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කරන විටත් මියගොස් තිබුණි.",
        "නාවලපිටිය, අක්කරවත්ත ප්‍ර දේශයේදි කැඹුලාව ඔයෙන් එතෙරවීමට ගිය පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙක් හා කාන්තාවක් දියේ ගිලි අතුරුදන්ව තිබේ. මෙසේ දියේ ගිලී අතුරුදන්ව ඇත්තේ කැටඹුලාව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි අවුරුදු 36,46, හා 47 වැනි වියේ පසුවන අයයි.",
        "මේ අතර හැටන් මොන්ටෆෙයාර් කොටස ප්‍රදේශයේදී නිවෙස් වෙත ගමන් කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනෙකුගෙන් එක් පුද්ගලයෙක් ලිස්සා ගොස් පැන්මූර් වැවට වැටි දියේ ගිලී අතුරුදන්ව ඇතැයි පොලීසිය පවසයි. මෙසේ අතුරුදන්ව ඇත්තේ අවුරුදු 24ක් ඇබෝස්ලිවත්ත, හැටන් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිටිනේගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5 ක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිගත්හේන රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඹුලාව ඔය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akkarawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවලපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටඹුලාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36, 46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 47 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන් මොන්ටෆෙයාර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබොස්ලිවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 24 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீரில் மூழ்கி 6 பேர் பலி மற்றும் காணாமல் போனவர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தீவின் மூன்று இடங்களில் நீரில் மூழ்கி விபத்துக்கள் காரணமாக 03 இறப்புகள் மற்றும் காணாமல் போனவர்கள் பதிவாகியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இவ்வாறு, பொல்பிட்டிய, ஹிதினேகம பிரதேசத்தில் முன்பள்ளியிலிருந்து வீடு திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்த பெண்ணொருவரும் சிறுமியும் நீரில் மூழ்கி காணாமல் போயுள்ளனர். பின்னர், பொலிஸாரும் பிரதேசவாசிகளும் இணைந்து மேற்கொண்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது 5 வயது பேத்தியும் 62 வயதுடைய பாட்டியும் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டு கினிகத்தேன வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட போது உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நாவலப்பிட்டி அக்கரவத்தையில் கம்புலாவ ஓயாவைக் கடந்த இருவர் மற்றும் பெண் ஒருவர் காணாமல் போயுள்ளனர். 36, 46 மற்றும் 47 வயதுடைய கடம்புலவ பிரதேசத்தில் வசிப்பவர்களே நீரில் மூழ்கி காணாமல் போயுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஹட்டன் மொன்டபேர் பகுதியில் வீட்டுக்கு நடந்து சென்று கொண்டிருந்த மூவரில் ஒருவர் வழுக்கி பன்முரே ஏரியில் விழுந்து காணாமல் போயுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர். ஹட்டன், அபோஸ்லிவத்தையில் வசிக்கும் ஒருவர் 24 வருடங்களாக காணாமல் போயுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொல்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிட்டிநேகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கினிகத்தேன வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்புலாவ ஓயா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akkarawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாவலப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடம்புலாவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36, 46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன் மொன்டஃபேர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபோஸ்லிவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}