{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-will-force-a-general-election-soon-Kiriella/108-241887",
  "time_ut": 1658908564,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB will force a general election soon: Kiriella",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB will force a general election soon: Kiriella",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) will start up a program to force a general election shortly, Chief Opposition Whip Lakshman Kiriella told Parliament today.",
        "Mr. Kiriella who was speaking during the emergency debate in Parliament said people should be given the opportunity to elect the new government of their choice as they want it. “Also the ruling party has lost its mandate as the President, Prime Minister and the cabinet had resigned. Those in the ruling party had appointed their own people to the government. This is nothing, but old wine in new bottles,” he said.",
        "“No foreign country will support a government which is formed by changing heads of the government. Some of the heads of foreign missions in Sri Lanka had informed us that they would not support Sri Lanka anymore. How are you going to get bridging finances in this situation? We have been informed that the staff level agreement which was to be signed with IMF has been delayed by few months. It is not likely that IMF assistance will come until middle of 2023,” he added.",
        "“We will move towards forcing a general election shortly, as international assistance will come only for a new government elected by the people,” he also said.",
        "Mr. Kiriella said the regulations imposed under emergency laws are draconian pieces of legislation. “Anyone can be  arrested without a warrant under these laws while anyone who are arrested can be kept in jail without producing him/her before courts,” he said. (Yohan Perera and Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB ළඟදීම මහ මැතිවරණයකට බලකරනවා: කිරිඇල්ල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය නුදුරේදීම මහ මැතිවරණයකට බලකිරීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් ආරම්භ කරන බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ හදිසි අවස්ථා විවාදයේදී අදහස් දක්වමින් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා කියා සිටියේ ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය පරිදි තමන් කැමති ආණ්ඩුවක් පත්කර ගැනීමට අවස්ථාව ලබාදිය යුතු බවයි. “ඒ වගේම ජනාධිපතිතුමා, අගමැතිතුමා ඇතුළු කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිසා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයට ජනවරම අහිමි වෙලා. ආණ්‌ඩු පක්‍ෂයේ අය තමන්ගේ අයව ආණ්‌ඩුවට පත්කරගෙන තිබුණා. මේ කිසිවක් නොව අලුත් බෝතල්වල පරණ වයින්” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“ආණ්ඩුවේ ප්‍රධානීන් වෙනස් කරලා හදන ආණ්ඩුවකට කිසිම විදේශ රටක් සහාය දෙන්නේ නැහැ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින ඇතැම් විදේශ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානීන් මින් ඉදිරියට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය නොදෙන බව අපට දන්වා තිබුණා. මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ ඔබ පාලම් මූල්ය ලබා ගැනීමට යන්නේ කෙසේද? IMF සමඟ අත්සන් කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබූ මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම මාස කිහිපයකින් ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති බව අපට දන්වා ඇත. 2023 මැද භාගය වන තෙක් IMF ආධාර ලැබෙනු ඇතැයි සිතිය නොහැක, ”ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ජාත්‍යන්තර ආධාර ලැබෙන්නේ මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් පත්වන නව රජයකට පමණක් බැවින් අපි ඉක්මනින්ම මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට කටයුතු කරනවා\" යැයිද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හදිසි නීති යටතේ පනවා ඇති රෙගුලාසි කුරිරු නීති සම්පාදනය කරන බව කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසීය. \"මෙම නීති යටතේ ඕනෑම අයෙකු වරෙන්තුවක් නොමැතිව අත්අඩංගුවට ගත හැකි අතර අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ඕනෑම අයෙකු ඔහු/ඇය අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකර සිරගත කළ හැක,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා සහ අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB விரைவில் பொதுத் தேர்தலை கட்டாயப்படுத்தும்: கிரியெல்ல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) விரைவில் பொதுத் தேர்தலை நடத்துவதற்கான வேலைத்திட்டத்தை ஆரம்பிக்கும் என எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற அவசரகால விவாதத்தின் போது உரையாற்றிய திரு.கிரியெல்ல, மக்கள் விரும்பியவாறு புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டுமென தெரிவித்தார். “அத்துடன் ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் மற்றும் அமைச்சரவை இராஜினாமா செய்ததால் ஆளும் கட்சி தனது ஆணையை இழந்துள்ளது. ஆளும் கட்சியில் இருப்பவர்கள் தங்கள் சொந்த ஆட்களையே அரசாங்கத்தில் நியமித்திருந்தனர். இது ஒன்றும் இல்லை, புதிய பாட்டில்களில் உள்ள பழைய மது,” என்றார்.",
        "“அரசாங்கத்தின் தலைவர்களை மாற்றி அமைக்கப்படும் அரசாங்கத்தை எந்த வெளி நாடும் ஆதரிக்காது. இலங்கையில் உள்ள வெளிநாட்டு தூதரகங்களின் தலைவர்கள் சிலர் இனி இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கப்போவதில்லை என எமக்கு அறிவித்திருந்தனர். இந்தச் சூழ்நிலையில் நீங்கள் எப்படிப் பிரிட்ஜிங் நிதியைப் பெறப் போகிறீர்கள்? சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் கைச்சாத்திடப்படவிருந்த பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தம் சில மாதங்கள் தாமதமாகியுள்ளதாக எங்களுக்குத் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நடுப்பகுதி வரை IMF உதவி வர வாய்ப்பில்லை,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"மக்களால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட புதிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கு மட்டுமே சர்வதேச உதவி கிடைக்கும் என்பதால், விரைவில் பொதுத் தேர்தலை கட்டாயப்படுத்துவதை நோக்கி நகர்வோம்\" என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவசரகாலச் சட்டங்களின் கீழ் விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள விதிமுறைகள் கொடூரமான சட்டதிட்டங்கள் என்று திரு.கிரியெல்ல கூறினார். \"இந்தச் சட்டங்களின் கீழ் பிடிவாரண்ட் இல்லாமல் எவரும் கைது செய்யப்படலாம், அதே நேரத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட எவரும் அவரை/அவளை நீதிமன்றங்களில் ஆஜர்படுத்தாமல் சிறையில் அடைக்கலாம்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா மற்றும் அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}