{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83465/sl-president-calls-russian-counterpart-seeks-credit-support-to-import-fuel",
  "time_ut": 1657103160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL President calls Russian counterpart, seeks credit support to import fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL President calls Russian counterpart, seeks credit support to import fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has sought an offer of credit support from Russian President Vladimir Putin to import fuel to Sri Lanka to ride out the current economic challenges.",
        "Taking to his official Twitter account, the Head of State said he had a very productive telephone conversation with his Russian counterpart today (July 06).",
        "The two leaders have unanimously agreed that strengthening bilateral relations in sectors such as tourism, trade and culture is paramount in reinforcing the friendship between the two nations.",
        "During their conversation, President Rajapaksa has appealed to President Putin to resume Russian airline Aeroflot’s flight operations to Sri Lanka.",
        "He also thanked President Putin for the support extended by the Russian government to overcome the challenges Sri Lanka faced in the past.",
        "1/2Had a very productive telecon with the #Russia President, Vladimir Putin. While thanking him for all the support extended by his gvt to overcome the challenges of the past, I requested an offer of credit support to import fuel to #lka in defeating the current econ challenges.— Gotabaya Rajapaksa (@GotabayaR) July 6, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1/2Had",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "#",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 6, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා රුසියානු සහකරු අමතා ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ණය ආධාර ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝගවලින් මිදීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්ගෙන් ණය ආධාර ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "සිය නිල ට්විටර් ගිණුමට සටහනක් තබමින් රාජ්‍ය නායකයා කියා සිටියේ අද (ජුලි 06) තම රුසියානු සහචරයා සමඟ ඉතා ඵලදායී දුරකථන සංවාදයක නිරත වූ බවයි.",
        "දෙරට අතර මිත්‍රත්වය තර කර ගැනීමේදී සංචාරක, වෙළෙඳ සහ සංස්කෘතික වැනි ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීම ප්‍රමුඛ වන බවට නායක දෙපළ ඒකමතිකව එකඟ වී ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ සංවාදය අතරතුර, රුසියානු ගුවන් සමාගමක් වන Aeroflot හි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගුවන් ගමන් නැවත ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපති පුටින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පසුගිය කාලයේ මුහුණ දුන් අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා රුසියානු රජය ලබාදුන් සහය පිළිබඳව ද ඔහු ජනාධිපති පුටින්ට ස්තුතිය පළ කළේය.",
        "1/2රුසියාවේ ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් සමඟ ඉතා ඵලදායී ටෙලිකොන් එකක් තිබුණා. අතීත අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා ඔහුගේ gvt ​​විසින් ලබා දුන් සියලු සහයෝගයට ස්තූති කරන අතරම, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝග පරාජය කිරීම සඳහා # lka වෙත ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ණය ආධාරයක් ලබා දෙන ලෙස මම ඉල්ලා සිටියෙමි.— ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ (@GotabayaR) 2022 ජූලි 6"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1/2 තිබුනා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": null,
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 6, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL ஜனாதிபதி ரஷியப் பிரதிநிதிக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார், எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதிக்கு கடன் உதவி கோருகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சவால்களை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினிடம் கடன் உதவி கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ ட்விட்டர் கணக்கில் எடுத்துக்கொண்ட அரச தலைவர், இன்று (ஜூலை 06) தனது ரஷ்யப் பிரதிநிதியுடன் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள தொலைபேசி உரையாடலை மேற்கொண்டதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "சுற்றுலா, வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம் போன்ற துறைகளில் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையேயான நட்புறவை வலுப்படுத்துவதில் மிக முக்கியமானது என்பதை இரு தலைவர்களும் ஒருமனதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "அவர்களின் உரையாடலின் போது, ​​ரஷ்ய விமான நிறுவனமான ஏரோஃப்ளோட்டின் இலங்கைக்கான விமான நடவடிக்கைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி புட்டினிடம் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த காலங்களில் இலங்கை எதிர்கொண்ட சவால்களை வெற்றிகொள்வதற்கு ரஷ்ய அரசாங்கம் வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்காக ஜனாதிபதி புட்டினுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "1/2 #ரஷ்யா ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடினுடன் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள தொலைத்தொடர்பு இருந்தது. கடந்த கால சவால்களை முறியடிக்க அவரது அரசாங்கம் வழங்கிய அனைத்து ஆதரவிற்கும் நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், தற்போதைய சுற்றுச்சூழல் சவால்களை தோற்கடிப்பதற்காக #lka க்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய கடன் உதவியை வழங்குமாறு கோரினேன்.— கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச (@GotabayaR) ஜூலை 6, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1/2 இருந்தது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": null,
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 6, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}