{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131850",
  "time_ut": 1658291514,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரணிலுக்கு ஆதரவு வழங்குவதாக விக்னேஸ்வரன் அறிவிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Wigneswaran announced that he would support Ranil",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil People's National Alliance will give its support to President Ranil Wickremesinghe in return, the party's president CV Wigneswaran has said.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe and Member of Parliament Dalus Alagaperuma are vying for the presidential election.",
        "It is noteworthy that while the Tamil National Alliance has extended its support to Dallas Beauty, the Tamil People's National Alliance has announced that it will extend its support to President Ranil Wickremesinghe in return.",
        "Meanwhile, it is noted that Vikineswaran handed over a letter containing 6 demands on behalf of the Tamil people to the Acting President and new presidential candidate Ranil Wickramasinghe on Tuesday 19th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wigneswaran",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil People's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dalus Alagaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Beauty",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil People's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vikineswaran",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විග්නේෂ්වරන් රනිල්ට සහාය දෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සහය ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ලබා දෙන බව එම පක්ෂයේ සභාපති සී.වී.විග්නේෂ්වරන් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා තරග වදියි.",
        "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය ඩලස් බියුටිට සහාය පළ කරද්දී දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානය ඊට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය පළ කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "මේ අතර දෙමළ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් ඉල්ලීම් 6ක් ඇතුළත් ලිපියක් විකිනේෂ්වරන් මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ නව ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට 19 අඟහරුවාදා භාරදුන් බවද සටහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී.වී.විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලංකාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකිනේශ්වරන්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலுக்கு ஆதரவு வழங்குவதாக விக்னேஸ்வரன் அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய கூட்டணி தனது ஆதரவை பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வழங்குவதாக அக்கட்சியின் தலைவர் சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்காக பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவும் போட்டியிடுகின்றனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையிலேயே தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ள நிலையில், தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய கூட்டணி தனது ஆதரவை பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வழங்குவதாக அறிவித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "இதேவேளை, தமிழ் மக்கள் சார்பில் 6 கோரிக்கைகள் அடங்கிய கடிதமொன்றை கடந்த 19 ஆம் திகதி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம்  விக்கினேஸ்வரன் கையளித்திருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ் அழகு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்களின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கினேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}