{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Music-teacher-arrested-for-harassing-schoolgirls/108-243438",
  "time_ut": 1661072227,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Music teacher arrested for harassing schoolgirls",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Music teacher arrested for harassing schoolgirls",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The teacher who teaches music as a subject in a government school in Dickwella was arrested on suspicion of harassing three grade-ten schoolgirls.",
        "Police said the suspect was arrested during investigations upon complaints that he had hugged and kissed the three girls attending music classes.",
        "The parents had raised complained to the Child Care Officers and on their information the police had initiated investigations.",
        "The three schoolgirls aged 14 and 15 years were to be referred to JMO for medical examination.",
        "The 38-year-old suspect was to be produced before Matara Magistrate.(Krishan Jeewaka Jayaruk)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dickwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Child Care Officers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 and 15 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeewaka Jayaruk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාසල් සිසුවියන්ට හිරිහැර කළ සංගීත ගුරුවරයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දික්වැල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ රජයේ පාසලක සංගීතය විෂයක් ලෙස උගන්වන ගුරුවරයා දහයේ ශ්‍රේණියේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන පාසල් සිසුවියන් තිදෙනෙකුට හිරිහැර කළ බවට සැකපිට අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනුණා.",
        "සංගීත පන්තිවලට සහභාගි වෙමින් සිටි දැරියන් තිදෙනා බදාගෙන සිපගත් බවට ලැබුණු පැමිණිලි මත සිදුකළ විමර්ශනවලදී සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙමාපියන් ළමාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන්ට පැමිණිලි කර ඇති අතර ඔවුන්ගේ තොරතුරු මත පොලිසිය පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ කර තිබුණා.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 14 සහ 15 යන වයස්වල පසුවන පාසල් සිසුවියන් තිදෙනා වෛද්‍ය පරීක්‍ෂණය සඳහා අධිකරණ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරිවරයා වෙත යොමු කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබිණි.",
        "38 හැවිරිදි සැකකරු මාතර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි.(ක්‍රිෂාන් ජීවක ජයරුක්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ළමාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 14 සහ 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවක ජයරුක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பள்ளி மாணவிகளை துன்புறுத்திய இசை ஆசிரியர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "டிக்வெல்ல அரச பாடசாலையில் பாடமாக இசை கற்பிக்கும் ஆசிரியர், தரம் 10ல் கல்வி கற்கும் மூன்று பாடசாலை மாணவிகளை துன்புறுத்தியதாக சந்தேகத்தின் பேரில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இசை வகுப்புகளுக்குச் சென்ற மூன்று சிறுமிகளை கட்டிப்பிடித்து முத்தமிட்டதாக கிடைத்த முறைப்பாடுகளின் அடிப்படையில் விசாரணைகளின் போது சந்தேக நபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பெற்றோர்கள் குழந்தை பராமரிப்பு அதிகாரிகளிடம் புகார் அளித்ததையடுத்து, அவர்களின் தகவலின் பேரில் போலீசார் விசாரணைகளை தொடங்கினர்.",
        "14 மற்றும் 15 வயதுடைய மூன்று பள்ளி மாணவிகள் மருத்துவப் பரிசோதனைக்காக ஜே.எம்.ஓ.வுக்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "38 வயதான சந்தேகநபர் மாத்தறை நீதவான் முன்னிலையில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளார்.(கிரிஷான் ஜீவக ஜயருக்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டிக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழந்தை பராமரிப்பு அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 மற்றும் 15 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்ஓ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவக ஜயருக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}