{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Weerawansa-Gammanpila-and-group-to-back-Dullas-for-President/56-737697",
  "time_ut": 1658261000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Weerawansa, Gammanpila and group to back Dullas for President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Weerawansa, Gammanpila and group to back Dullas for President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "People’s insecurities will disappear through the forming of a new Government",
        "The Union of Independent Parties led by MPs Wimal Weerawansa, Udaya Gammanpila and Vasudeva Nanayakkara said it will back Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) MP Dullas Alahapperuma in the election in parliament to elect a new President today.",
        "“We know that victory is certain. This is the only way to create political stability,” Weerawansa said. “The People’s insecurities will disappear with the appointment of this new Government,” Weerawansa claimed. “This will create a country that moves forward with friendship and unity,” he added.",
        "The entry of Ranil Wickremesinghe as Prime Minister and the appointment of a traditional Cabinet was not able to elicit the trust of the public, Weerawansa pointed out. “Instead, the calls for Gota to go home only intensified,” he said.",
        "According to Weerawansa, public trust is key to surviving this current crisis. “Without public trust, even the appointment of the world’s best economist to resolve the issue will be to no avail,” he said, adding that therefore an All-Party Government is the only way to regain the trust of the general public.",
        "Weerawansa noted that independent parties to the Government had warned of impending disaster through a series of seminars it commenced on 2 March and raised their voice against the then Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa. Weerawansa said he and former Minister Udaya Gammanpila were removed from their ministerial positions as a result."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gammanpila",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Union of Independent Parties",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gota",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වීරවංශ, ගම්මන්පිල ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම ඩලස්ට ජනපති අපේක්ෂකත්වයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව රජයක් පිහිටුවීම හරහා ජනතාවගේ අනාරක්ෂිත භාවය පහව යනු ඇත",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන විමල් වීරවංශ, උදය ගම්මන්පිල සහ වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ප්‍රමුඛ නිදහස් පක්ෂ එකමුතුව අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරාපත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පැවැත්වෙන මැතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දක්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“ජයග්‍රහණය ස්ථිර බව අපි දන්නවා. දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ඇති කළ හැකි එකම මාර්ගය මෙයයි” වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය. “මේ නව රජය පත්වීමත් සමඟම ජනතාවගේ අනාරක්ෂිතභාවය පහව යනු ඇත,” වීරවංශ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. \"මෙමගින් මිත්‍රත්වයෙන් සහ සමගියෙන් ඉදිරියට යන රටක් නිර්මාණය වනු ඇත\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පැමිණීම සහ සම්ප්‍රදායික අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් පත් කිරීම තුළින් ජනතා විශ්වාසය දිනා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ බවද වීරවංශ මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. \"ඒ වෙනුවට, ගෝඨා ගෙදර යන ලෙස කරන ලද ඉල්ලීම් උත්සන්න විය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "වීරවංශට අනුව මෙම වත්මන් අර්බුදයෙන් බේරීමට මහජන විශ්වාසය ප්‍රධාන වේ. \"මහජන විශ්වාසය නොමැතිව, ගැටලුව විසඳීම සඳහා ලෝකයේ හොඳම ආර්ථික විද්යාඥයා පත් කිරීම පවා ඵලක් නොවනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය, එබැවින් පොදු ජනතාවගේ විශ්වාසය නැවත ලබා ගත හැකි එකම මාර්ගය සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාර්තු 2 වැනිදා ආරම්භ වූ සම්මන්ත්‍රණ මාලාවක් මගින් ආණ්ඩුවේ ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ විසින් ඉදිරියේදී සිදුවිය හැකි ව්‍යසනය පිළිබඳව අනතුරු අඟවා තිබූ බවත් එවකට මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂට එරෙහිව හඬ නැගූ බවත් වීරවංශ සඳහන් කළේය. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස තමන් සහ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය උදය ගම්මන්පිල අමාත්‍ය ධුරවලින් ඉවත් කළ බව වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගම්මන්පිල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வீரவன்ச, கம்மன்பில மற்றும் குழு ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு டலஸை ஆதரிக்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய அரசு அமைவதன் மூலம் மக்களின் பாதுகாப்பின்மை மறைந்துவிடும்",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவுசெய்வதற்காக இன்று நடைபெறவுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தலில் ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான விமல் வீரவன்ச, உதய கம்மன்பில மற்றும் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தலைமையிலான சுயேட்சைக் கட்சிகளின் ஒன்றியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“வெற்றி நிச்சயம் என்பதை நாங்கள் அறிவோம். அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை உருவாக்குவதற்கான ஒரே வழி இதுதான்” என்று வீரவன்ச கூறினார். \"இந்த புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் நியமனத்துடன் மக்களின் பாதுகாப்பின்மை மறைந்துவிடும்\" என வீரவன்ச கூறினார். இது நட்புறவு மற்றும் ஒற்றுமையுடன் முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும் ஒரு நாட்டை உருவாக்கும் என அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பிரதமராக பிரவேசித்து, பாரம்பரிய அமைச்சரவையை நியமித்ததன் மூலம் பொதுமக்களின் நம்பிக்கையை பெற முடியவில்லை என வீரவன்ச சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். \"மாறாக, கோட்டா வீட்டிற்கு செல்ல வேண்டும் என்ற அழைப்பு தீவிரமடைந்தது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "வீரவன்சவின் கூற்றுப்படி, தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து தப்பிப்பதற்கு மக்களின் நம்பிக்கையே முக்கியமாகும். \"பொது நம்பிக்கை இல்லாமல், பிரச்சினையைத் தீர்க்க உலகின் சிறந்த பொருளாதார நிபுணரை நியமித்தாலும் எந்தப் பயனும் இல்லை,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், எனவே பொது மக்களின் நம்பிக்கையை மீண்டும் பெற அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கமே ஒரே வழி.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் சுயாதீனக் கட்சிகள் எதிர்வரும் மார்ச் மாதம் 2 ஆம் திகதி ஆரம்பமான கருத்தரங்குகள் மூலம் அன்றைய நிதியமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு எதிராக குரல் எழுப்பியதன் மூலம் வரவிருக்கும் அனர்த்தம் குறித்து எச்சரித்ததாக வீரவன்ச குறிப்பிட்டார். இதனால் தானும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் உதய கம்மன்பிலவும் அமைச்சர் பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்டதாக வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கம்மன்பில",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சிகளின் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}