{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-farmers-showing-stronger-than-expected-interest-to-grow-maize-minister-98993/",
  "time_ut": 1661394900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka farmers showing stronger than expected interest to grow maize: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka farmers showing stronger than expected interest to grow maize: Minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka is planning to increase maize cultivation to 50,000 to 60,000 hactares from the 20,000 last year by making more fertilizer available Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said while market prices for maize has soared amid import controls and a collapse of the currency.",
        "In 2021 Sri Lanka had produced about 90,000 metric tonnes of maize with farmers cultivating only 20,000 hactares.",
        "“We were planning to increase it to 50,000 to 60,000 hectares,” Minister Gunawardene said. “But we now seeing that farmer are ready to cultivate 110,000 hectares.",
        "“If they do cultivate this area, in about two seasons we will be able to produce the entire requirement.”",
        "The Ministry of Agriculture had called farmers to register on their website to get subsidized fertilizer which had drawn a stronger than expected response, the said.",
        "Sri Lanka is expecting to give fertilizer for rice 10,000 rupees, which is below the market price of around 40,000 rupees a metric tonne he said.",
        "More than 46,000 farmers have registered through the agrarian.lk website to get fertilizer, Minister Gunewardene said. (Colombo/Aug25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 to 60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 90,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50,000 to 60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "110,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "More than 46,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගොවීන් බඩඉරිඟු වගා කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වූවාට වඩා ප්‍රබල උනන්දුවක් දක්වයි: ඇමති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථීකය - ආනයන පාලනයන් සහ මුදල් කඩාවැටීම මධ්‍යයේ බඩඉරිඟු සඳහා වෙළඳපොල මිල ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර, පසුගිය වසරේ බඩඉරිඟු වගාව වැඩි පොහොර ලබා දීමෙන් 20,000 සිට හෙක්ටයාර 50,000 සිට 60,000 දක්වා වැඩි කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "2021 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බඩඉරිඟු මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 90,000ක් පමණ නිෂ්පාදනය කර ඇති අතර ගොවීන් වගා කළේ හෙක්ටයාර් 20,000ක් පමණි.",
        "\"අපි එය හෙක්ටයාර 50,000 සිට 60,000 දක්වා වැඩි කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබෙනවා,\" ගුණවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. “නමුත් අපි දැන් දකිනවා ගොවියා හෙක්ටයාර් 110,000ක් වගා කරන්න සූදානම්.",
        "\"ඔවුන් මෙම ප්‍රදේශය වගා කළහොත්, කන්න දෙකකින් පමණ අපට සම්පූර්ණ අවශ්‍යතාවය නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට හැකි වනු ඇත.\"",
        "සහනාධාර පොහොර ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා තම වෙබ් අඩවියේ ලියාපදිංචි වන ලෙස කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය ගොවීන් කැඳවා තිබූ අතර ඒ සඳහා බලාපොරොත්තු වූවාට වඩා ප්‍රබල ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබී ඇති බව ද එම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහල් සඳහා රුපියල් 10,000ක පොහොර ලබාදීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත් එය වෙළෙඳපොළ මිලට වඩා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකක් රුපියල් 40,000ක් පමණ අඩු බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පොහොර ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ගොවීන් 46,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසක් agrarian.lk වෙබ් අඩවිය හරහා ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති බව අමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 සිට 60,000 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 90,000ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50,000 සිට 60,000 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "110,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46,000 කට වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மக்காச்சோளத்தை பயிரிட இலங்கை விவசாயிகள் எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட அதிக ஆர்வம் காட்டுகின்றனர்: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இறக்குமதி கட்டுப்பாடுகள் மற்றும் நாணய சரிவு ஆகியவற்றுக்கு மத்தியில் மக்காச்சோளத்திற்கான சந்தை விலைகள் உயர்ந்துள்ள நிலையில், கடந்த ஆண்டு 20,000 மக்காச்சோள சாகுபடியை 50,000 முதல் 60,000 ஹெக்டேர்களாக அதிகரிக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கை 90,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் சோளத்தை உற்பத்தி செய்தது, விவசாயிகள் 20,000 ஹெக்டேர்களில் மட்டுமே பயிரிட்டனர்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் அதை 50,000 முதல் 60,000 ஹெக்டேர்களாக அதிகரிக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளோம்\" என்று அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன கூறினார். “ஆனால், 110,000 ஹெக்டேரில் விவசாயம் செய்ய விவசாயி தயாராக இருப்பதைக் காண்கிறோம்.",
        "\"அவர்கள் இந்தப் பகுதியில் பயிரிட்டால், இரண்டு பருவங்களில் நாங்கள் முழுத் தேவையையும் உற்பத்தி செய்ய முடியும்.\"",
        "மானிய விலையில் உரத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கு விவசாயிகள் தங்கள் இணையதளத்தில் பதிவு செய்யுமாறு வேளாண் அமைச்சகம் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது, இது எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட வலுவான வரவேற்பைப் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் அரிசிக்கான உரம் 10,000 ரூபாவை வழங்க எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாகவும், இது சந்தை விலையில் ஒரு மெட்ரிக் தொன் சுமார் 40,000 ரூபாவுக்கும் குறைவாக இருப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "உரத்தைப் பெறுவதற்காக 46,000 இற்கும் அதிகமான விவசாயிகள் agrarian.lk இணையத்தளத்தின் ஊடாக பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 முதல் 60,000 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 90,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50,000 முதல் 60,000 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "110,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}