{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83570/high-commission-denies-reports-of-india-sending-troops-to-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1657506240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "High Commission denies reports of India sending troops to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "High Commission denies reports of India sending troops to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian High Commission in Colombo has categorically denied speculative reports in sections of media and social media about India sending troops to Sri Lanka.",
        "These reports and such views are also not in keeping with the position of the Government of India, the High Commission said in a statement.",
        "The Spokesperson of Ministry of External Affairs of India clearly stated today that India stands with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realize their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values, established institutions and constitutional framework, it said.",
        "Meanwhile the Chief of Defence Staff General Shavendra Silva says that social media reports claiming that a large number of troops are heading to the Galle Face protest site are false.",
        "He says this is a fake video which has been created by someone to achieve different motives."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "High Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Spokesperson of Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හමුදා එවූ බවට පළවන වාර්තා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හමුදා එවන බවට මාධ්‍ය සහ සමාජ මාධ්‍ය අංශවල පළවන සමපේක්ෂන වාර්තා කොළඹ පිහිටි ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම වාර්තා සහ එවැනි අදහස් ඉන්දීය රජයේ ස්ථාවරයට නොගැලපෙන බවද මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව තුළින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමෘද්ධිය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ අපේක්ෂාවන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන විට ඉන්දියාව ඔවුන් සමඟ සිටින බව ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක අද පැහැදිලිව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා පවසන්නේ ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියට හමුදා භට පිරිසක් ගමන් කරන බවට සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ පළවන වාර්තා අසත්‍ය බවයි.",
        "ඔහු පවසන්නේ මෙය කිසියම් අයකු විසින් විවිධ අරමුණු ඉටුකර ගැනීම සඳහා නිර්මාණය කර ඇති ව්‍යාජ වීඩියෝවක් බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா படைகளை அனுப்பியதாக வெளியான தகவலை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் மறுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா படைகளை அனுப்புவது குறித்து ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் ஊகச் செய்திகளை திட்டவட்டமாக மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த அறிக்கைகள் மற்றும் இதுபோன்ற கருத்துக்கள் இந்திய அரசின் நிலைப்பாட்டுடன் ஒத்துப்போகவில்லை என்று உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள், நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க முயலும் இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியா நிற்கிறது என்று இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் இன்று தெளிவாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, காலி முகத்திடலில் பெரும் எண்ணிக்கையிலான இராணுவத்தினர் போராட்டம் நடத்துவதாக சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியாகும் செய்திகள் பொய்யானவை என பாதுகாப்பு படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இது யாரோ ஒருவரால் வெவ்வேறு நோக்கங்களை அடைவதற்காக உருவாக்கப்பட்ட போலி வீடியோ என்று அவர் கூறுகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}