{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131839",
  "time_ut": 1658244468,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி, ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ், இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ் ஆகியன டலஸுக்கு ஆதரவு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tamil Progressive Alliance, Sri Lanka Muslim Congress and Sri Lanka People's Congress supported Dulles",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil Progressive Alliance will support Dulles Alagaperuma, who has agreed to act as a coalition with the United People's Alliance, in the presidential polls to be held tomorrow, its president Mano Ganesan said.",
        "The decision to this effect was taken by the leadership committee of the Tamil Progressive Alliance today at the Colombo Nugegodai party secretariat under the leadership of the alliance leader Mano Ganesan.",
        "Meanwhile, Sri Lanka Muslim Congress General Secretary Nizam Kariapar has announced that the Sri Lanka Muslim Congress has decided to vote for Member of Parliament Dalus Alagaperuma in the referendum to elect the President.",
        "Also, it is noteworthy that the All Sri Lankan People's Congress has also decided to vote for Member of Parliament Dulles Alagaperuma in the referendum to elect the President."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "People's Congress",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dulles",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Nugegodai",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nizam Kariapar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All Sri Lankan People's Congress",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන කොංග්‍රසය ඩලස්ට සහාය පළ කළා",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය හෙට පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී එක්සත් ජනතා සන්ධානය සමඟ සභාගයක් ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීමට එකඟ වූ ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාට සහය පළ කරන බව එහි සභාපති මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායක මනෝ ගනේෂන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කොළඹ නුගේගොඩ පක්ෂ ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේදී අද රැස්වූ එම පක්ෂයේ නායකත්ව කමිටුව මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසයේ මහලේකම් නිසාම් කාරියපර් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පැවැත්වෙන ජනමත විචාරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාට ඡන්දය දීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "එමෙන්ම සමස්ත ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන කොංග්‍රසය ද ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ජනමත විචාරණයේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට තීරණය කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මහජන කොංග්‍රසය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ නුගේගොඩයි",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිසාම් කාරියපර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி, ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ், இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ் ஆகியன டலஸுக்கு ஆதரவு",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாளை நடைபெறவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி, ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கூட்டணியுடன் இணைந்து கூட்டரசங்கமாக செயற்பட இணங்கியுள்ள டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்ககும் என அதன் தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்கான தீர்மானத்தை தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் தலைமைக்குழு இன்று கொழும்பு நுகேகொடை  கட்சி செயலகத்தில், கூட்டணி தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன் தலைமையில்  கூடி முடிவெடுத்தது.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கும் வாக்களிக்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் நிசாம் காரியப்பர் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு வாக்களிக்க அகில இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸும் தீர்மானித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு நுகேகொடை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஜாம் காரியப்பர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}