{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SL-to-pay-colossal-prices-plus-commissions-for-40k-MT-of-fuel-Harsha/342-240466",
  "time_ut": 1657094454,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL to pay colossal prices plus commissions for 40k MT of fuel: Harsha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL to pay colossal prices plus commissions for 40k MT of fuel: Harsha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka is agreeing to pay crazy prices plus commissions for a 40k MT of fuel, SJB MP Dr.  Harsha de Silva alledged today.",
        "\"We hear numerous ‘local agents’ are crawling out of the woodwork for ‘emergency procurements’. As oil prices are crashing, Sri Lanka is agreeing to pay colossal prices plus LKR 700 million ‘commissions’ per 40k MT shipment to crooks and thieves\" Dr. de Silva said in his Twitter.",
        "The issue was raised in Parliament yesterday where Dr. de Silva said CPC officials were summoned before Committe on Public Enterprises (COPE) to discuss matters pertaing to oil, but they have refused to be present yesterday.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe who responded said, adjust times, so that COPE could meet CPC officials. \"It was me who wanted COPE to look into these matters,\" the PM said.(Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40k",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "700 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40ක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැවැන්ත මිලක් සහ කොමිස් මුදලක් ගෙවයි: හර්ෂ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40ක ඉන්ධන සඳහා උමතු මිල ගණන් සහ කොමිස් ගෙවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එකඟ වන බව SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා අද චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "\"හදිසි ප්‍රසම්පාදන' සඳහා 'දේශීය නියෝජිතයින්' බොහෝ දෙනෙක් ලී වැඩවලින් බඩගාගෙන යන බව අපට අසන්නට ලැබේ. තෙල් මිල කඩා වැටෙන විට, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැවැන්ත මිල ගණන් සහ වංචනිකයින්ට සහ හොරුන්ට නැව්ගත කිරීම සඳහා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000කට රුපියල් මිලියන 700 'කොමිස්' ගෙවීමට එකඟ වේ\" ආචාර්ය ද සිල්වා මහතා සිය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී මෙම ප්‍රශ්නය මතු වූ අතර එහිදී ආචාර්ය ද සිල්වා කියා සිටියේ තෙල් සම්බන්ධ කරුණු සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ නිලධාරීන් පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (කෝප්) හමුවට කැඳවූ නමුත් ඔවුන් ඊයේ පැමිණීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බවයි.",
        "ඊට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ කියා සිටියේ කෝප් කමිටුවට ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ නිලධාරීන් හමුවිය හැකි පරිදි වේලාවන් සකස් කරන්න. කෝප් කමිටුවට අවශ්‍ය වුණේ මේ කරුණු ගැන සොයා බලන ලෙසයි” අගමැතිවරයා පැවසීය.(යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40k",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிபொருளுக்கு மகத்தான விலைகளையும் கமிஷன்களையும் கொடுக்க வேண்டும்: ஹர்ஷா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிபொருளுக்கான விலையும், கொமிஷனும் கொடுக்க இலங்கை ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறது என்று SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டாக்டர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா இன்று குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "\"அவசர கொள்முதல்'களுக்காக பல 'உள்ளூர் முகவர்கள்' மரவேலைகளில் இருந்து வலம் வருவதை நாங்கள் கேள்விப்படுகிறோம். எண்ணெய் விலைகள் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து வருவதால், இலங்கை 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் கப்பலுக்கு 700 மில்லியன் 'கமிஷன்' மற்றும் மோசடி செய்பவர்கள் மற்றும் திருடர்களுக்கு மகத்தான விலைகளை வழங்க ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறது\" டி சில்வா தனது டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எண்ணெய் தொடர்பான விடயங்கள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான குழுவின் (கோப்) முன் CPC அதிகாரிகள் அழைக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், ஆனால் அவர்கள் நேற்றைய தினம் பிரசன்னமாக இருக்க மறுத்ததாகவும் கலாநிதி டி சில்வா நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரச்சினை எழுப்பினார்.",
        "இதற்கு பதிலளித்த பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, கோப் குழுவானது இ.தொ.கா அதிகாரிகளை சந்திக்கும் வகையில் நேரத்தை மாற்றியமைக்கவும். \"கோப் இந்த விடயங்களை ஆராய வேண்டும் என்று நான் விரும்பினேன்\" என்று பிரதமர் கூறினார்.(யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40k",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}