{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Sri-Lanka-beat-Australia-by-an-innings-in-second-Test-to-draw-series/342-240898",
  "time_ut": 1657585975,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka beat Australia by an innings in second Test to draw series",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka beat Australia by an innings in second Test to draw series",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka crushed Australia by an innings and 39 runs inside four days of the second Test to draw the series 1-1.",
        "Dinesh Chandimal hit a sublime unbeaten 206 as the hosts made 554 in Galle to take a first innings lead of 190.",
        "Australia reached 52-1 at tea but then crumbled to 151 all out as Sri Lanka spinner Prabath Jayasuriya took 6-59 to finish with match figures of 12-177.",
        "It is Sri Lanka head coach Chris Silverwood's second Test series in charge since taking over in April.",
        "Silverwood left his role as England head coach in February after the heavy Ashes defeat in Australia.",
        "Chandimal was on 118 not out overnight, with Sri Lanka 431-6, leading by 67.",
        "He batted expertly with the tail on day four to add another 123 runs to his side's total and finish with his career-best score, giving Sri Lanka a big enough lead that they could push for an innings victory.",
        "Australia posted 364 in the first innings following an unbeaten 145 from Steve Smith and 104 from Marnus Labuschagne.",
        "But this time the tourists' batting failed, with Smith falling for a duck to slow-left armer Prabath and Australia losing their final six wickets for only 39 runs, leading to joyous celebrations among the Sri Lanka staff and fans.",
        "The match took place amid ongoing financial crisis and political unrest in Sri Lanka.",
        "Hundreds of protestors marched around the Galle International Stadium on day two of the match, demanding the resignation of president Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Rajapaksa has subsequently confirmed he will resign after tens of thousands of protestors stormed his official residence in Colombo on Saturday.",
        "\"We are here to bring smiles on people's faces,\" said Sri Lanka captain Dimuth Karunaratne.",
        "\"I don't want to mention what we are going through. Unfortunately it's what we are going through.\"",
        "Australia won the first Test by 10 wickets, after a 3-2 defeat in the one-day international series and a 2-1 win in the Twenty20 series.",
        "Australia Test skipper Pat Cummins said the tour and their previous tour of Pakistan had given his players a new perspective.",
        "\"We spent two years basically stuck at home during Covid and our last two tours had been to Pakistan where we hadn't toured for 20-odd years, and now Sri Lanka in the middle of a country in crisis,\" said Cummins.",
        "\"We've got protests round the ground, it really hits home how lucky we are to be travelling the world but also in some ways it's more than just being here to play cricket, you can see the impact it can have.",
        "\"You could hear when it changed from protests into a party.\" (BBC)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "206",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "554",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "151",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-59",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chris Silverwood's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "118",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "overnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "431",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "day four",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "123",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "364",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Steve Smith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "104",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marnus Labuschagne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Smith",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabath",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle International Stadium",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "day two",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dimuth Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twenty20",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia Test",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pat Cummins",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-odd years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cummins",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව අතර පැවැති දෙවැනි ටෙස්ට් තරගයෙන් ඉනිමක ජයක් අත්කර ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව අතර පැවැති දෙවැනි ටෙස්ට් තරගයේ දින හතරක් ඇතුළත ඉනිමකින් සහ ලකුණු 39කින් පරාජය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමත් වූයේ තරගාවලිය 1-1ක් ලෙස සම කරමිනි.",
        "දිනේෂ් චන්දිමාල් නොදැවී ලකුණු 206ක් ලබා ගත් අතර, සත්කාරක කණ්ඩායම ගාල්ලේදී ලකුණු 554ක් ලබා ගනිමින් පළමු ඉනිමේ ලකුණු 190ක වාසියක් ලබා ගැනීමට සමත් විය.",
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව තේ පානය වන විට ලකුණු 52-1ක් ලබා ගත් නමුත් පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දඟපන්දු යවන ක්‍රීඩක ප්‍රභාත් ජයසූරිය ලකුණු 6-59ක් ​​ලබා ගනිමින් තරගයේ ලකුණු 12-177ක් ලෙස තරගය නිමා කිරීමත් සමඟ සියල්ලන්ම දැවී ලකුණු 151කට බිඳ වැටුණි.",
        "එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රධාන පුහුණුකරු ක්‍රිස් සිල්වර්වුඩ් අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී වැඩ භාර ගැනීමෙන් පසු භාරව සිටින දෙවන ටෙස්ට් තරඟාවලියයි.",
        "සිල්වර්වුඩ් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ පැවති දරුණු අළු බඳුන පරාජයෙන් පසු පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී එංගලන්ත ප්‍රධාන පුහුණුකරු තනතුරෙන් ඉවත් විය.",
        "චන්දිමාල් එක රැයකින් නොදැවී ලකුණු 118ක් ලබා සිටි අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලකුණු 431-6ක් ලෙසින් ලකුණු 67කින් ඉදිරියෙන් සිටියේය.",
        "ඔහු සිව්වන දිනයේ දී වලිගය සමඟ දක්ෂ ලෙස පන්දුවට පහර දුන් අතර ඔහුගේ කණ්ඩායමේ මුළු ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාවට තවත් ලකුණු 123 ක් එකතු කර ඔහුගේ වෘත්තීය ජීවිතයට හොඳම ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාව සමඟ අවසන් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉනිමක ජයග්‍රහණයක් කරා තල්ලු කළ හැකි තරම් විශාල ඉදිරියක් ලබා දෙමිනි.",
        "ස්ටීව් ස්මිත් නොදැවී ලකුණු 145ක් සහ මාර්නස් ලැබුස්චේන් ලකුණු 104ක් ලබා ගනිමින් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව පළමු ඉනිමට ලකුණු 364ක් රැස් කළේය.",
        "එහෙත් මෙවර සංචාරකයින්ගේ පිතිකරණය අසාර්ථක වූ අතර, මන්දගාමී වමත් පිතිකරු ප්‍රභාත්ගේ පන්දුවකට ස්මිත් දැවී ගිය අතර ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ අවසන් කඩුලු 6 ලකුණු 39කට පමණක් දැවී යාම ශ්‍රී ලංකා කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ක්‍රීඩා ලෝලීන් අතර ප්‍රීති උත්සවවලට තුඩු දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය සහ දේශපාලන නොසන්සුන්තාව මධ්‍යයේ මෙම තරගය පැවැත්විණි.",
        "තරගයේ දෙවැනි දිනයේ දී සිය ගණනක් විරෝධතා පාගමනින් ගාලු ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රීඩාංගණය වටා ගමන් කළේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමිනි.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා දස දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ පිහිටි ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු රාජපක්ෂ පසුව තමා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව තහවුරු කර තිබේ.",
        "මිනිසුන්ගේ මුහුණුවල සිනහවක් ගෙන ඒමට අපි මෙහි පැමිණ සිටිමු යැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායක දිමුත් කරුණාරත්න පැවසීය.",
        "\"අපි අත්විඳින දේ ගැන සඳහන් කිරීමට මට අවශ්‍ය නැත. අවාසනාවකට අප අත්විඳින්නේ එයයි.\"",
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව පළමු ටෙස්ට් තරගය කඩුලු 10කින් ජයගත් අතර, එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරගාවලිය 3-2කින් පරාජයට පත් වූ අතර විස්සයි20 තරගාවලිය 2-1ක් ලෙස ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය.",
        "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ටෙස්ට් නායක පැට් කමින්ස් පැවසුවේ මෙම සංචාරය සහ ඔවුන්ගේ පෙර පාකිස්ථාන සංචාරය තම ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට නව ඉදිරිදර්ශනයක් ලබා දුන් බවයි.",
        "“අපි මූලික වශයෙන් Covid කාලය තුළ නිවසේ සිරවී වසර දෙකක් ගත කළ අතර අපගේ අවසන් සංචාර දෙක පාකිස්තානයට ගොස් ඇති අතර එහිදී අපි වසර 20 ක් තිස්සේ සංචාරය නොකළෙමු, දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අර්බුදයක රටක් මැදයි,” කමින්ස් පැවසීය.",
        "“අපට ක්‍රීඩාංගණය වටේ විරෝධතා ඇත, එය සැබවින්ම අප ලොව පුරා සංචාරය කිරීමට කොතරම් වාසනාවන්තද යන්න ගෙදරට පහර දෙයි, නමුත් සමහර ආකාරවලින් එය ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමට මෙහි සිටීම වඩා වැඩි ය, එයින් ඇති කළ හැකි බලපෑම ඔබට දැක ගත හැකිය.",
        "\"එය විරෝධතා වලින් පක්ෂයක් බවට පත් වූ විට ඔබට ඇසෙනු ඇත.\" (බීබීසී)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "206",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "554",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "151",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-59",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිස් සිල්වර්වුඩ්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "118",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක රැයකින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "431",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "123",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "364",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටීව් ස්මිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "104",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marnus Labuschagne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්මිත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාත්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "39 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිමුත් කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්සයි20",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ටෙස්ට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැට් කමින්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 20 - ඔත්තේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමින්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான இரண்டாவது டெஸ்ட் போட்டியில் இன்னிங்ஸ் வித்தியாசத்தில் இலங்கை அணி வெற்றி பெற்று தொடரை சமன் செய்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான இரண்டாவது டெஸ்ட் போட்டியின் நான்கு நாட்களுக்குள் இலங்கை அணி இன்னிங்ஸ் மற்றும் 39 ஓட்டங்களால் வெற்றிபெற்று தொடரை 1-1 என சமன் செய்தது.",
        "தினேஷ் சண்டிமால் ஆட்டமிழக்காமல் 206 ரன்கள் எடுத்தார், இதனால் புரவலன்கள் காலியில் 554 ரன்கள் எடுத்து முதல் இன்னிங்ஸில் 190 முன்னிலை பெற்றனர்.",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலியா 52-1 டீயை எட்டியது, ஆனால் பின்னர் இலங்கை சுழற்பந்து வீச்சாளர் பிரபாத் ஜெயசூர்யா 6-59 எடுத்ததால் 12-177 என்ற போட்டியின் எண்ணிக்கையுடன் முடிவடைய 151 ரன்களுக்கு ஆல் அவுட் ஆனது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தலைமைப் பயிற்றுவிப்பாளராக கிறிஸ் சில்வர்வுட் ஏப்ரல் மாதம் பொறுப்பேற்ற பின்னர் பொறுப்பேற்ற இரண்டாவது டெஸ்ட் தொடர் இதுவாகும்.",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலியாவில் நடந்த ஆஷஸ் தொடரின் கடும் தோல்விக்குப் பிறகு பிப்ரவரியில் இங்கிலாந்து தலைமைப் பயிற்சியாளர் பொறுப்பில் இருந்து சில்வர்வுட் விலகினார்.",
        "சண்டிமால் ஒரே இரவில் ஆட்டமிழக்காமல் 118 ரன்களில் இருந்தார், இலங்கை 431-6, 67 முன்னிலையில் இருந்தது.",
        "நான்காவது நாளில் அவர் திறமையாக பேட்டிங் செய்தார், மேலும் 123 ரன்களை தனது பக்கத்தின் மொத்தத்தில் சேர்த்தார் மற்றும் அவரது வாழ்க்கையின் சிறந்த ஸ்கோரை முடித்தார், இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு இன்னிங்ஸ் வெற்றிக்கு தள்ளக்கூடிய அளவுக்கு பெரிய முன்னிலையை வழங்கினார்.",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலியா முதல் இன்னிங்ஸில் ஸ்டீவ் ஸ்மித்தின் ஆட்டமிழக்காமல் 145 ரன்களும், மார்னஸ் லாபுசாக்னேவின் 104 ரன்களும் எடுத்தது.",
        "ஆனால் இம்முறை சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் பேட்டிங் தோல்வியடைந்தது, ஸ்மித், ஸ்மித், ஸ்லோ-லெஃப்ட் ஆர்மர் பிரபாத் ஆகியோரிடம் ஆட்டமிழக்க, ஆஸ்திரேலியா 39 ரன்களுக்கு இறுதி ஆறு விக்கெட்டுகளை இழந்தது, இலங்கை ஊழியர்கள் மற்றும் ரசிகர்களிடையே மகிழ்ச்சியான கொண்டாட்டங்களுக்கு வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நிதி நெருக்கடி மற்றும் அரசியல் அமைதியின்மைக்கு மத்தியில் இந்தப் போட்டி நடைபெற்றது.",
        "போட்டியின் இரண்டாம் நாளான இன்று நூற்றுக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் காலி சர்வதேச மைதானத்தை சுற்றி அணிவகுத்து, ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் சனிக்கிழமை கொழும்பில் உள்ள அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்வதை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "மக்கள் முகத்தில் புன்னகையை வரவழைப்பதற்காக நாங்கள் இங்கு வந்துள்ளோம் என இலங்கை அணியின் தலைவர் திமுத் கருணாரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் என்ன செய்கிறோம் என்பதை நான் குறிப்பிட விரும்பவில்லை. துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக நாங்கள் என்ன செய்கிறோம்.\"",
        "ஒரு நாள் சர்வதேச தொடரில் 3-2 என்ற கணக்கில் தோல்வியையும், இருபதுக்கு 20 தொடரை 2-1 என்ற கணக்கில் கைப்பற்றிய ஆஸ்திரேலியா முதல் டெஸ்டில் 10 விக்கெட் வித்தியாசத்தில் வெற்றி பெற்றது.",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலியா டெஸ்ட் கேப்டன் பாட் கம்மின்ஸ், சுற்றுப்பயணம் மற்றும் அவர்களின் முந்தைய பாகிஸ்தான் சுற்றுப்பயணம் தனது வீரர்களுக்கு ஒரு புதிய பார்வையை அளித்துள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் இரண்டு வருடங்கள் கோவிட் சமயத்தில் வீட்டிலேயே இருந்தோம், எங்கள் கடைசி இரண்டு சுற்றுப்பயணங்கள் பாகிஸ்தானுக்குச் சென்றிருந்தோம், அங்கு நாங்கள் 20-ஒற்றைப்படை ஆண்டுகளாக சுற்றுப்பயணம் செய்யவில்லை, இப்போது இலங்கை நெருக்கடியில் உள்ள ஒரு நாட்டின் நடுவில் உள்ளது\" என்று கம்மின்ஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எங்களுக்கு மைதானம் முழுவதும் எதிர்ப்புகள் வந்துள்ளன, உலகம் முழுவதும் பயணம் செய்வது எவ்வளவு அதிர்ஷ்டம் என்பதை இது உண்மையில் வீட்டிற்குத் தாக்குகிறது, ஆனால் சில வழிகளில் கிரிக்கெட் விளையாடுவதற்கு இங்கு இருப்பதை விட, அது ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடிய தாக்கத்தை நீங்கள் காணலாம்.",
        "\"எப்போது எதிர்ப்புகளிலிருந்து கட்சியாக மாறியது என்பதை நீங்கள் கேட்கலாம்.\" (பிபிசி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "206",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "554",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "151",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-59",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ் சில்வர்வுட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "118",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரே இரவில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "431",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாள் நான்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "123",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "364",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டீவ் ஸ்மித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "104",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்னஸ் லாபுசாக்னே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்மித்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "39 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி சர்வதேச மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாள் இரண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திமுத் கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபது20",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா டெஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாட் கம்மின்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-ஒற்றைப்படை ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்மின்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}