{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/speaker-as-acting-president-pending-all-party-govt-sri-lanka-party-leaders-agree-97192/",
  "time_ut": 1657375140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Speaker as acting president pending all-party govt, Sri Lanka party leaders agree",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speaker as acting president pending all-party govt, Sri Lanka party leaders agree",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Leaders of political parties that represent Sri Lanka’s parliament have agreed that both President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe must resign immediately, making the way for Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena to become acting president, MP Dullas Alahapperuma said.",
        "Alahapperuma tweeted Saturday July 09 evening that the party leaders agreed that parliament must be convened within a week to elect a new president by parliamentary majority.",
        "In the same week, he said, a coalition government must be formed representing all parties.",
        "Participated in the Party Leaders meeting, presided by the Speaker. An overwhelming majority agreed to the following.",
        "1. The President @GotabayaR & the Prime Minister @RW_UNP must resign immediately.",
        "The meeting followed a massive popular uprising in the heart of the island nation’s capital Colombo that saw people storm the official residence of the president, demanding his resignation.",
        "President Rajapaksa has said he will respect any decision reached by the party leaders, reports said. Prime Minister Wickremesinghe has also said he is willing to step down to make way for an all-party government.",
        "To ensure the continuation of the Government including  the safety of all citizens I accept the best recommendation of the Party Leaders today, to make way for an All-Party Government.",
        "Sri Lanka party leaders call for President to resign, PM agrees to step down"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the same week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The President @GotabayaR & the Prime",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කතානායක සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් එනතුරු වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂ නායකයෝ එකඟ වෙති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති වීමට මග සලසමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් එකඟ වූ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජුලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා සවස අලහප්පෙරුම ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරයෙන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා සතියක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවිය යුතු බවට පක්ෂ නායකයින් එකඟ වූ බවයි.",
        "එම සතිය තුළම සියලු පක්ෂ නියෝජනය වන පරිදි සභාග ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කථානායකවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමට එක්වෙමින්. අතිමහත් බහුතරයක් පහත සඳහන් දේට එකඟ විය.",
        "1. ජනාධිපති @GotabayaR සහ අගමැති @RW_UNP වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුය.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීම දිවයිනේ අගනුවර වන කොළඹ හදවතේ දැවැන්ත මහජන නැගිටීමකින් පසුව, ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කරමින් ජනතාව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදුණු අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "පක්‍ෂ නායකයින් ගන්නා ඕනෑම තීරණයකට ගරු කරන බව ජනාධිපතිතුමා පවසා ඇතැයි වාර්තාවේ. අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහ ද පවසා ඇත්තේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා තමා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සූදානම් බවයි.",
        "සියලුම පුරවැසියන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව ඇතුළුව රජයේ අඛණ්ඩ පැවැත්ම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් සඳහා මග සලසා දීම සඳහා අද පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ හොඳම නිර්දේශය මම පිළිගනිමි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂ නායකයින් ජනපතිට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව කියයි, අගමැති ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට එකඟ වෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම සතියේම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති @GotabayaR සහ අගමැති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சபாநாயகர் தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கம் நிலுவையில் உள்ளது, இலங்கை கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறார்கள்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இருவரும் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் இணங்கியுள்ளதாகவும், இதனால் சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக வருவதற்கு வழிவகுத்துள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 09 சனிக்கிழமை மாலை ட்வீட் செய்த அழகப்பெரும, பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையுடன் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு ஒரு வாரத்திற்குள் பாராளுமன்றம் கூட்டப்பட வேண்டும் என்று கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "ஒரே வாரத்தில் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கூட்டணி ஆட்சி அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் தலைமையில் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் பங்கேற்றார். பெரும்பான்மையானவர்கள் பின்வருவனவற்றை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "1. ஜனாதிபதி @GotabayaR & பிரதமர் @RW_UNP உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும்.",
        "தீவு நாட்டின் தலைநகர் கொழும்பின் மையத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற பாரிய மக்கள் எழுச்சியைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகக் கோரி அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை மக்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டனர்.",
        "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் எடுக்கும் எந்த முடிவுக்கும் மதிப்பளிப்பதாக அதிபர் ராஜபக்ஷ கூறியதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்காக பதவி விலக தயாராக இருப்பதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அனைத்துக் குடிமக்களின் பாதுகாப்பு உட்பட அரசாங்கத்தின் தொடர்ச்சியை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக, அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வழி வகுக்கும் இன்றைய கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் சிறந்த பரிந்துரையை நான் ஏற்றுக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என இலங்கை கட்சி தலைவர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர், பிரதமர் பதவி விலக ஒப்புக்கொண்டார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதே வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி @GotabayaR & பிரதமர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}