{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජාතික-ආපදා-තත්වයක්-ප්‍රකාශ-කරන්න/1-615812",
  "time_ut": 1656908179,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජාතික ආපදා තත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශ කරන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Declare a state of national emergency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Administrative Services Association of Sri Lanka says that a competent authority should establish a proper mechanism to maintain essential services by declaring a state of national calamity and that the current situation in the country cannot be managed under normal conditions.",
        "The government is protesting against the non-interference of the government to enforce the law regarding the persecution of government officials who intervene regardless of the risk of life to maintain essential services and the law has not been implemented against the employees of the Matara General Hospital who inconvenienced the Matara Divisional Secretary and the Kurunegala Mayor who obstructed the duties of the Secretary to the Governor of the North West Province. The association is mentioned.",
        "The Sri Lanka Administrative Services Association also says that if the law is not implemented in these cases, they will take strict professional action."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Declare",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Administrative Services Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Matara General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North West Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Administrative Services Association",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික ආපදා තත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශ කරන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ආපදා තත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කර අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා පවත්වාගෙන යෑමට නිසි බලධාරියෙක් පක්තර නිසි යාන්ත්‍රණයක් ස්ථාපිත කළ යුතු බවත් වර්තමානයේ රට තුළ පවතින තත්වය සාමාන්‍ය තත්වය යටතේ කළමනාකරණය කළ නොහැකි බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවා සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා පවත්වාගෙන යෑම සඳහා ජීවිත අවදානම නොතකා මැදිහත් වන රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට වන පීඩා පිළිබඳව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට රජය මැදිහත්නොවීමට විරෝධය දක්වන බවත් මාතර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම්වරිය අපහසුතාවට පත්කළ මාතර මහ රෝහලේ සේවකයින් පිරිසට සහ වයඹ පළාත් ආණ්ඩුකාර ලේකම්වරයාගේ රාජකාරියට බාධා කළ කුරුණෑගල නගරාධිපතිවරයාට එරෙහිව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක වී නොමැති බවත් එම සංගමය සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකරන්නේ නම් දැඩි වෘත්තීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයකට අවතීර්ණ වන බව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවා සංගමය කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්රකාශ කරන්න",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවා සංගමය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசிய அவசர நிலையை அறிவிக்கவும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய அனர்த்த நிலையைப் பிரகடனப்படுத்தி அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளைப் பேணுவதற்கான முறையான பொறிமுறையொன்றை உரிய அதிகார சபை ஸ்தாபிக்க வேண்டுமெனவும், நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையை சாதாரண நிலைமைகளின் கீழ் நிர்வகிக்க முடியாது எனவும் இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவைகள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மாத்தறை பொது வைத்தியசாலை ஊழியர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தாத அரச உத்தியோகத்தர்களை துன்புறுத்துவது தொடர்பான சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் தலையிடாமைக்கு எதிராக அரசாங்கம் போராட்டம் நடத்தி வருகின்றது. வடமேல் மாகாண ஆளுநரின் செயலாளரின் கடமைகளுக்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்த மாத்தறை பிரதேச செயலாளரையும் குருநாகல் மேயரையும் அசௌகரியப்படுத்தியதாக சங்கம் குறிப்பிடுகிறது.",
        "இந்த வழக்குகளில் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தாவிடின், கடுமையான தொழில் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் எனவும் இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவைகள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அறிவிக்கவும்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவைகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மேற்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவைகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}