{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/iran-assures-continued-assistance/",
  "time_ut": 1660640820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Iran assures continued assistance",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Iran assures continued assistance",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ambassador of Iran Hashem Ashjazadeh called on the Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs on 15 August 2022.",
        "The Foreign Minister referred to the longstanding cordial relations and briefed the Ambassador on the economic downturn that Sri Lanka is encountering at present and tangible measures so far taken by the Government to stabilize the situation.",
        "Ambassador Hashem Ashjazadeh emphasized the importance of Sri Lanka – Iran bilateral relationship and assured the continued assistance of the Republic of Iran to Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Iran",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashjazadeh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hashem Ashjazadeh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉරානය අඛණ්ඩ සහාය සහතික කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉරාන තානාපති හෂෙම් අෂ්ජාසාදේ 2022 අගෝස්තු 15 වැනි දින විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි හමුවිය.",
        "දීර්ඝ කාලීන සුහද සබඳතා ගැන සඳහන් කළ විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වර්තමානයේ මුහුණ දෙන ආර්ථික පසුබෑම සහ තත්ත්වය ස්ථාවර කිරීම සඳහා රජය මෙතෙක් ගෙන ඇති ප්‍රත්‍යක්ෂ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව තානාපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා - ඉරාන ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතාවයේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කළ තානාපති හෂෙම් අෂ්ජාසාදේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉරාන ජනරජයේ අඛණ්ඩ සහාය ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉරානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අශ්ජාසාදේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 අගෝස්තු 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෂෙම් අෂ්ජාසාදේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தொடர்ந்து உதவி செய்வதாக ஈரான் உறுதியளிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஈரானின் தூதர் ஹஷேம் அஷ்ஜசாதே 15 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று வெளியுறவுத்துறை அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தில் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "நீண்டகாலமாக நிலவி வரும் நல்லுறவுகள் பற்றிக் குறிப்பிட்ட வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், இலங்கை தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கி வரும் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சி மற்றும் நிலைமையை ஸ்திரப்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் இதுவரை எடுத்துள்ள உறுதியான நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து தூதுவருக்கு விளக்கினார்.",
        "இலங்கை - ஈரான் இருதரப்பு உறவின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை வலியுறுத்திய தூதுவர் ஹஷேம் அஷ்ஜசாதே, இலங்கைக்கு ஈரான் குடியரசின் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவிகளை உறுதியளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஈரான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஷ்ஜசாதே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹாஷேம் அஷ்ஜஜாதே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}