{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නිදහස්-සැමරුමේදී-ජාතික-ගීය-දමිළ-බසින්-ගැයීමේ-වරදක්-නෑ/1-618222",
  "time_ut": 1660648636,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිදහස් සැමරුමේදී ජාතික ගීය දමිළ බසින් ගැයීමේ වරදක් නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There is nothing wrong in singing the national anthem in Tamil during the Independence Day celebrations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Cabinet Spokesman, Minister of Transport, Highways and Mass Media Dr. Bandula Gunawardena said that there is no problem in singing the National Anthem in Tamil during the 75th Independence Day celebrations in the country next February.",
        "The minister said that the National Anthem has been sung in the previous Independence Day celebrations in the official languages ​​of the country, Sinhala and Tamil.",
        "Mr. Gunawardena said that the cabinet also approved the establishment of a cabinet sub-committee of eight ministers with the president and the prime minister to organize the activities of the 75th Independence Day celebrations.",
        "The minister said this in response to a question raised by a journalist at the cabinet decision notification press conference held today (16) at the Government Information Department."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Independence Day",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Spokesman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Anthem",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "next February",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Anthem",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​of",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිදහස් සැමරුමේදී ජාතික ගීය දමිළ බසින් ගැයීමේ වරදක් නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලබන පෙබරවාරියේ පැවැත්වෙන මෙරට 75 වන නිදහස් දින සැමරුම් උළෙලේ දී ජාතික ගීය දමිළ භාෂාවෙන් ද ගායනා කිරීමේ ගැටලුවක් නැතැයි කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක, ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග සහ ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජාතික ගීය මීට පෙර පැවති නිදහස් දින සැමරුම් උත්සවවලදී ද මෙරට රාජ්‍ය භාෂා වන සිංහල හා දමිල භාෂාවලින් ගායනා කර තිබෙන බව ඇමතිවරයා කීය.",
        "75 වන නිදහස් දින සැමරුම් උළෙලේ කටයුතු සංවිධානය කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැතිනරයා සමඟ ඇමතිවරුන් අට දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුකමිටුවක් පිහිටුවීමට ද අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය හිමිවූ බව ගුණවර්ධන මහතා කීවේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දී අද (16) පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු නැගූ පැනයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "හි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுதந்திர தின விழாவில் தமிழில் தேசிய கீதம் பாடுவதில் தவறில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் பெப்ரவரி மாதம் நாட்டில் நடைபெறவுள்ள 75ஆவது சுதந்திர தின விழாவில் தமிழில் தேசிய கீதத்தை பாடுவதில் எவ்வித பிரச்சினையும் இல்லை என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளரும், போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சருமான கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ மொழிகளான சிங்களம் மற்றும் தமிழ் ஆகிய மொழிகளில் தேசிய கீதம் முந்தைய சுதந்திர தின கொண்டாட்டங்களில் பாடப்பட்டதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "75ஆவது சுதந்திர தின நிகழ்வுகளை ஒழுங்குபடுத்துவதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமருடன் எட்டு அமைச்சர்களைக் கொண்ட அமைச்சரவை உபகுழுவை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கும் அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக திரு.குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் இன்று (16) நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானங்களை அறிவிக்கும் செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவர் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கீதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கீதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}