{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ණය-බර-ලිහිල්-කිරීම-සඳහා-ශ්‍රී-ලංකාවට-සහාය-දැක්වීමට-සූදානම්/11-395463",
  "time_ut": 1657935959,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ණය බර ලිහිල් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට සූදානම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ready to support Sri Lanka for debt relief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China declares that it is ready to work with relevant countries and international financial institutions to play an active role in alleviating Sri Lanka's current difficulties and debt burden and for Sri Lanka's efforts to achieve sustainable development.",
        "Mr. Wang Wenbin, spokesperson of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, said this while attending the daily press conference held by China.",
        "Further commenting on China-Sri Lanka financial cooperation, he said that shortly after Sri Lanka announced that it would suspend loan payments, Chinese financial institutions are ready to contact the Sri Lankan side to find a proper way to manage the matured loans received from China."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය බර ලිහිල් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට සූදානම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් දුෂ්කරතා හා ණය බර ලිහිල් කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් හා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තිරසාර සංවර්ධනයක් ඇති කර ගැනිමට දරණ ප්‍රයන්ත සඳහා සාධනිය කාර්ය භාරයක් ඉටු කිරීමට අදාළ රටවල් හා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය ආයතන සමග කටයුතු කිරීමට චීනය සූදානම් බව චීනය ප්‍රකාශ කරයි.",
        "චින විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ  ප්‍රකාශක වැන් වෙන්බින් මහතා චීනය දිනපතා පවත්වන මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මෙහිදී චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා මූල්‍ය සහයෝගීතාවට සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවදුරටත් අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය ගෙවීම් අත්හිටුවන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් ටික කලකට පසුව චීනයේ මූල්‍ය ආයතන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ශවය සමග සම්බන්ධ වී චීනයෙන් ලබාගෙන පරිණත වූ ණය කළමනාකරණය කිරීමට නිසි ක්‍රමයක් සෙවීමට සූදානමින් සිටින බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடன் நிவாரணத்திற்காக இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க தயார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சிரமங்கள் மற்றும் கடன் சுமைகளை குறைப்பதற்கும், நிலையான அபிவிருத்தியை அடைவதற்கான இலங்கையின் முயற்சிகளுக்கும் செயலூக்கமான பங்களிப்பை வழங்குவதற்கு சம்பந்தப்பட்ட நாடுகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நிதி நிறுவனங்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்ற தயாராக இருப்பதாக சீனா அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் திரு.வாங் வென்பின், சீனாவினால் நடத்தப்படும் தினசரி செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்ட போதே இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சீன-இலங்கை நிதி ஒத்துழைப்பு குறித்து மேலும் கருத்து தெரிவித்த அவர், கடன் கொடுப்பனவுகளை இடைநிறுத்துவதாக இலங்கை அறிவித்த சிறிது நேரத்திலேயே, சீனாவிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட முதிர்ச்சியடைந்த கடன்களை நிர்வகிப்பதற்கான சரியான வழியைக் கண்டறிய சீன நிதி நிறுவனங்கள் இலங்கை தரப்பைத் தொடர்பு கொள்ளத் தயாராக உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}