{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84402/cid-records-nearly-5-hour-statement-from-maithripala",
  "time_ut": 1660906680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CID records nearly 5-hour statement from Maithripala",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CID records nearly 5-hour statement from Maithripala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has recorded a statement from former President Maithripala Sirisena for nearly five hours today (Aug 19).",
        "The former president provided a statement with regard to the presidential pardon to Royal Park murder convict Jude Shramantha Jayamaha.",
        "In early November 2019, former President Sirisena released the convict, who was sentenced to death over the Royal Park murder case in 2005, on presidential pardon.",
        "Shramantha Jayamaha was convicted of murdering 19-year-old Swedish national, Yvonne Jonsson on July 01, 2005, and was sentenced to 12 years in prison by the Colombo High Court.",
        "In 2012, the Appeals Court overturned the sentence on Shramantha Jayamaha from 12 years to a death sentence.",
        "Later, in October 2013, the Supreme Court confirmed the death sentence given by the Appeals Court to Shramantha Jayamaha.",
        "Yvonne Jonsson was residing at her apartment on the 23rd floor of the Royal Park complex in Rajagiriya while her body was found on the 19th floor.",
        "Following backlash on the move, Sirisena clarified that granting of the presidential pardon was carried out on the recommendations of a special committee of officials, civil organizations, and several distinguished members of the society, citing that Jayamaha has served his sentence in prison with good behaviour and conduct while undertaking studies to complete his external degree and to work for a PhD."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "nearly 5-hour",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maithripala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly five hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "early November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swedish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yvonne Jonsson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 01, 2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appeals Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "October 2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appeals Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yvonne Jonsson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CID මෛත්‍රීපාලගෙන් පැය 5කට ආසන්න ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගෙන් අද (අගෝස්තු 19) පැය පහකට ආසන්න කාලයක් ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කරගෙන තිබේ.",
        "රෝයල් පාක් ඝාතන චූදිත ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා දුන්නා.",
        "2019 නොවැම්බර් මස මුලදී, හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන, 2005 වසරේ රෝයල් පාර්ක් ඝාතන නඩුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් මරණ දණ්ඩනයට නියම වූ වරදකරු ජනාධිපති සමාව මත නිදහස් කළේය.",
        "2005 ජූලි 01 වැනිදා 19 හැවිරිදි ස්වීඩන් ජාතික ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන් ඝාතනය කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට වරදකරු වූ ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට කොළඹ මහාධිකරණය විසින් වසර 12ක සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කළේය.",
        "2012 වසරේදී අභියාචනාධිකරණය ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට වසර 12 ක සිරදඬුවමක් මරණ දඬුවමක් දක්වා අවලංගු කළේය.",
        "පසුව 2013 ඔක්තෝම්බර් මාසයේදී ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහට අභියාචනාධිකරණය ලබාදුන් මරණ දඬුවම ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් තහවුරු කරන ලදී.",
        "ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන් රාජගිරිය රෝයල් පාක් සංකීර්ණයේ 23 වැනි මහලේ ඇයගේ මහල් නිවාසයේ පදිංචිව සිට ඇති අතර ඇගේ සිරුර 19 වැනි මහලේ තිබී හමුවී ඇත.",
        "මෙම පියවරට පසුබෑමෙන් පසු, ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දීම විශේෂ නිලධාරීන්, සිවිල් සංවිධාන සහ සමාජයේ සම්භාවනීය සාමාජිකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුගේ නිර්දේශ මත සිදු කරන ලද බව පැහැදිලි කළ සිරිසේන, ජයමහ සිරගෙදරදී යහපත් හැසිරීමකින් දඬුවම් විඳ ඇති බව සඳහන් කළේය. සහ ඔහුගේ බාහිර උපාධිය සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට සහ ආචාර්ය උපාධියක් සඳහා වැඩ කිරීමට අධ්‍යයන කටයුතු කරගෙන යාම."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැය 5 කට ආසන්න",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය පහකට ආසන්න",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර් මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 01, 2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 12 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 12 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2013 ඔක්තෝබර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மைத்திரிபாலவிடம் இருந்து குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் சுமார் 5 மணிநேர வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவிடம் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் (CID) இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 19) 5 மணித்தியாலங்கள் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "ரோயல் பார்க் கொலைக் குற்றவாளி ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி அறிக்கையொன்றை வழங்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு ராயல் பார்க் கொலை வழக்கில் மரண தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்ட குற்றவாளியை 2019 நவம்பர் தொடக்கத்தில் முன்னாள் அதிபர் சிறிசேனா ஜனாதிபதியின் மன்னிப்பில் விடுவித்தார்.",
        "2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 01 ஆம் திகதி 19 வயதான சுவீடன் பிரஜை யுவோன் ஜோன்சனை கொலை செய்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவுக்கு கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்றத்தினால் 12 வருட சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2012 இல், மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவின் 12 வருட தண்டனையை மரண தண்டனையாக ரத்து செய்தது.",
        "பின்னர் 2013 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஒக்டோபர் மாதம் ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவுக்கு மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம் வழங்கிய மரண தண்டனையை உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் உறுதி செய்தது.",
        "இவோன் ஜோன்சன் ராஜகிரியவில் உள்ள ரோயல் பார்க் வளாகத்தின் 23வது மாடியில் உள்ள தனது குடியிருப்பில் வசித்து வந்த நிலையில், அவரது உடல் 19வது மாடியில் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கைக்குப் பின்னடைவைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜனாதிபதி பொது மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவது சிறப்பு அதிகாரிகள், சிவில் அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் சமூகத்தின் பல புகழ்பெற்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பரிந்துரைகளின் பேரில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது என்று தெளிவுபடுத்தினார், ஜெயமஹா சிறையில் தண்டனையை நன்னடத்தையுடன் அனுபவித்தார். மற்றும் அவரது வெளிப்புற பட்டப்படிப்பை முடிக்க மற்றும் பிஎச்டிக்கு வேலை செய்ய படிக்கும் போது நடத்தவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 5 மணி நேரம்",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "மைத்திரிபால",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஐந்து மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019 ஆரம்பத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இவோன் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 01, 2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஶ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இவோன் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}