{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මිලියන-33කට-අධික-කේරළ-ගංජා-අල්ලයි/11-395318",
  "time_ut": 1657525709,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මිලියන 33කට අධික කේරළ ගංජා අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Over 33 million Keralas smoke cannabis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Navy says that 113 kilos and 280 grams of Kerala cannabis, worth over 33 million rupees, were found yesterday (10th) while they were piled up in the Urumalai seashore area of ​​Welipara area of ​​Mannar.",
        "When a group of officers of the North Central Naval Command conducted a search patrol in Mannar Welipara Urumalai beach area, first 105 kg of Kerala ganja belonging to 24 bags and then another 8 kg of 280 grams were found piled up on the beach.",
        "The navy also suspects that the Kerala ganja stock may have been brought to Mannar by sea from India and the smugglers saw the navy and fled to the sea.",
        "The navy also said that steps have been taken to hand over the seized stock of Kerala ganja to the police for further investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Keralas",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 33 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first 105 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "280 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිලියන 33කට අධික කේරළ ගංජා අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් මිලියන 33 කට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුත් කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ 113 ග්‍රෑම් 280 ක් මන්නාරම වැලිපර ප්‍රදේශයේ ඌරුමලෙයි මුහුදු වෙරල ප්‍රදේශයේ ගොඩගසා තිබියදී ඊයේ  (10දා)  සොයාගත් බවට නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "උතුරුමැද නාවික විධානයේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් මන්නාරම වැලිපර ඌරුමලෙයි මුහුදු වෙරල ප්‍රදේශයේ සෝදිසි මුර සංචාරයක නිරත වූ අවස්ථාවේදී පළමුව උර 24 කට අයත් කේරල ගංජා කිලෝ 105 ක්ද  පසුව තවත් කිලෝ 8 ග්‍රෑම් 280 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් මුහුදු වෙරලේ ගොඩගසා තිබියදී සොයාගනු ලැබීය.",
        "මෙම කේරලගංජා තොගය මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ සිට මන්නාරමට රැගෙනවිත් නාවික හමුදාව දැක ජාවාරම් කරුවන් විසින් කේරල ගංජා මෙලෙස මුහුදට පලා යන්නට ඇතැයිද නාවික හමුදාව සැකපල කොට සිටියි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරල ගංජා තොගය වැඩිදුර පරික්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා පොලීසියට භාරදීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇතැයිද නාවික හමුදාව වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරළයන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 280 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 33 කට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු 105 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 8 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 280 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "33 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான கேரள மக்கள் கஞ்சா புகைக்கிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மன்னார், வெலிப்பாறை, உருமலை கடற்பரப்பில் குவிக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 33 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான 113 கிலோ 280 கிராம் கேரள கஞ்சா நேற்று (10ஆம் திகதி) கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கடற்படையினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினர் மன்னார் வெலிப்பாறை உருமலை கடற்கரை பகுதியில் ரோந்து நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்ட போது முதலில் 24 மூடைகள் கொண்ட 105 கிலோ கேரளா கஞ்சாவும் பின்னர் 8 கிலோ 280 கிராம் எடையுள்ள 280 கிராமும் கடற்பரப்பில் குவிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "கேரளா கஞ்சா கையிருப்பு இந்தியாவில் இருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக மன்னாருக்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் எனவும் கடத்தல்காரர்கள் கடற்படையினரைக் கண்டு கடலுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதாகவும் கடற்படையினர் சந்தேகம் வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவை மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கடற்படையினர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரளாக்காரர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "33 மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் 105 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "280 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}