{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Soorya-Bala-Sangramaya-should-be-re-launched-as-Kadinam-Soorya-Bala-Sangramaya-Solar-Industries-Assn/342-243743",
  "time_ut": 1661438229,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "’Soorya Bala Sangramaya’ should be re-launched as ’Kadinam Soorya Bala Sangramaya’: Solar Industries Assn.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "’Soorya Bala Sangramaya’ should be re-launched as ’Kadinam Soorya Bala Sangramaya’: Solar Industries Assn.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Solar Industries Association (SIA) today claimed that the government should re-launch the Soorya Bala Sangramaya (Battle for Solar Energy) as Kadinam Soorya Bala Sangramaya (Expedited Battle for Solar Energy) to improve the energy security level of the country.",
        "The President of the Association, Kushan Jayasuriya, said the government should take measures to promote renewable energy as it benefits the environment by reducing carbon emissions.",
        "With the 'electric shock' received recently with the new consumer tariff announced by the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL), the electricity tariff was increased by 75%.",
        "\"From a 100% renewable energy-dependent country, running almost entirely on hydroelectricity, Sri Lanka's generation mix had deteriorated to 35% renewable energy, 65% fossil fuel by 2022. The Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) did not make any reasonable effort to absorb sufficient amounts of renewable energy into the national grid in spite of clear directives from industry regulators over the past decades, particularly since 2016.",
        "These warnings and advice to increase the renewable energy component in the country's energy mix were ignored and are not reflected in the long-term generation plans of the CEB. The CEB's approach has been short-sighted and it has not established a long-term strategy for the renewable energy sector even today,\" the chairman said.",
        "The project on establishing rooftop solar systems was introduced by the association to safeguard the country's energy security.",
        "Establishing an average 3kW solar rooftop system in one million households would add 3GW to the national grid. The country will save the US $3 billion if this project continues over the next three years, and it would help to save 6% of the current national debt, the Chairman added. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bala Sangramaya’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bala Sangramaya’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Solar Industries Assn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Solar Industries Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bala Sangramaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadinam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kushan Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3GW",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘සූර්‍ය බල සංග්‍රාමය’ ‘කඩිනම් සූර්ය බල සංග්‍රාමය’ ලෙස නැවත දියත් කළ යුතුය: සෝලා ඉන්ඩස්ට්‍රීස් සහකාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ බලශක්ති සුරක්ෂිතතා මට්ටම ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා සූර්ය බල සංග්‍රාමය (සූර්‍ය බල සංග්‍රාමය) කඩිනම් සූර්ය බල සංග්‍රාමය (සූර්‍ය බලශක්ති සඳහා කඩිනම් සටන) ලෙස රජය විසින් යළි දියත් කළ යුතු බව සූර්ය බලශක්ති කර්මාන්ත සංගමය (SIA) අද කියා සිටියේය.",
        "එම සංගමයේ සභාපති කුෂාන් ජයසූරිය මහතා පැවසුවේ කාබන් විමෝචනය අවම කර පරිසරයට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලැබෙන බැවින් පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට රජය පියවර ගත යුතු බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද නව පාරිභෝගික ගාස්තුව සමඟ පසුගියදා ලැබුණු ‘විදුලි කම්පනය’ත් සමඟ විදුලි ගාස්තුව 75%කින් ඉහළ දමන ලදී.",
        "\"100% පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය මත යැපෙන, සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පාහේ ජල විදුලියෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනන මිශ්‍රණය 2022 වන විට 35% පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය, 65% ෆොසිල ඉන්ධන දක්වා පිරිහී ඇත. ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය (CEB) ඒ සඳහා සාධාරණ උත්සාහයක් ගත්තේ නැත. පසුගිය දශක කිහිපය තුළ, විශේෂයෙන් 2016 සිට කර්මාන්ත නියාමකයින්ගේ පැහැදිලි නියෝග නොතකා, ජාතික විදුලිබල පද්ධතියට ප්‍රමාණවත් පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ප්‍රමාණයක් අවශෝෂණය කර ගැනීම.",
        "රටේ බලශක්ති මිශ්‍රණයේ පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සංරචකය වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා වූ මෙම අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් සහ උපදෙස් නොසලකා හැර ඇති අතර ලංවිමේ දිගුකාලීන ජනන සැලසුම් තුළ ඒවා පිළිබිඹු නොවේ. ලංවිම ප්‍රවේශය අදූරදර්ශී වන අතර අදටත් පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ක්ෂේත්‍රය සඳහා දිගුකාලීන උපාය මාර්ගයක් ස්ථාපිත කර නැත,\" සභාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "රටේ බලශක්ති සුරක්‍ෂිතතාව ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීම සඳහා වහල මත සූර්ය පද්ධති පිහිටුවීමේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය සංගමය විසින් හඳුන්වා දෙන ලදී.",
        "නිවාස මිලියනයක සාමාන්‍ය 3kW සූර්ය වහල පද්ධතියක් ස්ථාපිත කිරීම ජාතික විදුලිබල පද්ධතියට 3GW එකතු කරනු ඇත. ඉදිරි වසර තුන තුළ මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක වුවහොත් රටට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3ක් ඉතිරි වන අතර එය වත්මන් ජාතික ණය ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 6%ක් ඉතිරි කර ගැනීමට ඉවහල් වන බවද සභාපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බාල සංග්‍රාමය'",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බාල සංග්‍රාමය'",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Solar Industries සහකාර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සූර්ය බලශක්ති කර්මාන්ත සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බාල සංග්‍රාමය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩිනම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුෂාන් ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශක කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3GW",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "'சூர்ய பால சங்கமாயா' 'கடினம் சூர்ய பால சங்கமாயா' என மீண்டும் தொடங்கப்பட வேண்டும்: சோலார் இண்டஸ்ட்ரீஸ் அஸ்ஸன்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் எரிசக்தி பாதுகாப்பு அளவை மேம்படுத்த சூரிய பல சங்க்ராமயாவை (சூரிய சக்திக்கான போர்) கடினம் சூரிய பால சங்கமாயா (சூரிய சக்திக்கான விரைவான போர்) என அரசாங்கம் மீண்டும் தொடங்க வேண்டும் என்று சோலார் இண்டஸ்ட்ரீஸ் அசோசியேஷன் (எஸ்ஐஏ) இன்று கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "கரியமில வாயு வெளியேற்றத்தை குறைப்பதன் மூலம் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு நன்மை பயக்கும் வகையில் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தியை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டுமென சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் குஷான் ஜயசூரிய தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) அறிவித்த புதிய நுகர்வோர் கட்டணத்துடன் அண்மையில் கிடைத்த 'மின்சார அதிர்ச்சி'யுடன், மின்சாரக் கட்டணம் 75% அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "\"100% புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி சார்ந்த நாட்டிலிருந்து, கிட்டத்தட்ட முழுவதுமாக நீர்மின்சாரத்தில் இயங்கும் இலங்கையின் உற்பத்தி கலவையானது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் 35% புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல், 65% புதைபடிவ எரிபொருளாக மோசமடைந்துள்ளது. கடந்த தசாப்தங்களில், குறிப்பாக 2016 முதல், தொழில்துறை கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர்களின் தெளிவான உத்தரவுகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், போதுமான அளவு புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றலை தேசிய கட்டத்திற்குள் உள்வாங்குதல்.",
        "நாட்டின் எரிசக்தி கலவையில் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்திக் கூறுகளை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான இந்த எச்சரிக்கைகள் மற்றும் ஆலோசனைகள் புறக்கணிக்கப்பட்டன மற்றும் CEBயின் நீண்டகால உற்பத்தித் திட்டங்களில் அவை பிரதிபலிக்கவில்லை. CEBயின் அணுகுமுறை குறுகிய நோக்குடையது மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி துறைக்கான நீண்ட கால மூலோபாயத்தை அது இன்றும் நிறுவவில்லை\" என்று தலைவர் கூறினார்.",
        "நாட்டின் எரிசக்தி பாதுகாப்பைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக மேற்கூரை சூரிய அமைப்புகளை நிறுவும் திட்டம் சங்கத்தால் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "ஒரு மில்லியன் குடும்பங்களில் சராசரியாக 3 கிலோவாட் சூரிய கூரை அமைப்பை நிறுவுவது, தேசிய கட்டத்திற்கு 3GW சேர்க்கும். அடுத்த மூன்று ஆண்டுகளில் இந்தத் திட்டம் தொடர்ந்தால், நாடு 3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைச் சேமிக்கும், மேலும் இது தற்போதைய தேசியக் கடனில் 6% சேமிக்க உதவும் என்று தலைவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பால சங்கமாயா’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பால சங்கமாயா’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சோலார் இண்டஸ்ட்ரீஸ் Assn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சோலார் இண்டஸ்ட்ரீஸ் அசோசியேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்ஐஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலா சங்கராமயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடினம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஷான் ஜெயசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3GW",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மூன்று ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}