{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ඇමෙරිකාවට-චීනය-යළිත්-අනතුරු-ඇඟවීමක්-කරයි/3-395287",
  "time_ut": 1657436305,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඇමෙරිකාවට චීනය යළිත් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China warns America again",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Foreign Minister Wang Yi told US Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on Saturday that it is China's hope that the United States respects China's foreign and domestic policies, removes economic sanctions and abandons the Cold War mentality.",
        "Blinken, meanwhile, had told reporters that he had pressed Wang over China's refusal to impose sanctions on Russia, apparently to no avail.",
        "Blinken and Wang met a day after a meeting of top diplomats from G20 countries in Indonesia on Saturday.",
        "The meeting came at a critical juncture for Washington-Beijing relations. The meeting came as the FBI warned of \"extensive\" industrial espionage and cybercrime emanating from China, and as US President Joe Biden recently announced that he would fight any attempt by the Chinese military to retake Taiwan.",
        "However, in this meeting, Chinese Foreign Minister Wang said, \"Since the United States has promised that it has no intention of creating a conflict with China, they should respect China's sovereignty and territorial integrity and stop interfering in China's internal affairs.\"",
        "Also, Wang accused the United States of trying to prevent and distort the One China policy, referring to Washington's official view that it recognizes China's sovereignty over Taiwan but does not endorse it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "America",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anthony Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇමෙරිකාවට චීනය යළිත් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය චීනයේ විදේශ හා දේශීය ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට ගරු කිරීම, ආර්ථික සම්බාධක ඉවත් කිරීම සහ සීතල යුද මානසිකත්වය අත්හැරීම චීනයේ බලාපොරොත්තුවක් බව විදේශ ඇමති වැන්ග් යී සෙනසුරාදා එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන්ට පවසා තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, රුසියාවට සම්බාධක පැනවීම චීනය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමා වැන්ග්ට බලපෑම් කළ බවත්, පෙනෙන විදිහට ඉන් කිසිදු ප්‍රයෝජනයක් නොවූ බවත් බ්ලින්කන් වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පවසා තිබුණි.",
        "බ්ලින්කන් සහ වැන්ග් මුණගැසුණේ සෙනසුරාදා ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ G20 රටවල ඉහළම රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින්ගේ රැස්වීමකින් දිනකට පසුවය.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීම වොෂින්ටන්-බීජිං සබඳතා සඳහා තීරණාත්මක ස්ථානයකට පැමිණියේය. චීනයෙන් පැන නගින \"පුළුල්\" කාර්මික ඔත්තු බැලීම් සහ සයිබර් අපරාධ ගැන FBI අනතුරු ඇඟවීමත් සමග සහ තායිවානය නැවත අත්පත් කර ගැනීමට චීන හමුදාව ගන්නා ඕනෑම උත්සාහයකට එරෙහිව සටන් කරන බව එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් මෑතකදී ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබූ පසුබිමක මෙම හමුව සිදුවිය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මෙම හමුවේදී චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍ය වැන්ග් පවසා තිබුණේ, \"එක්සත් ජනපදය චීනය සමග ගැටුමක් ඇති කිරීමට කිසිදු අදහසක් නොමැති බවට පොරොන්දු වී ඇති හෙයින්, ඔවුන් චීනයේ ස්වෛරීභාවයට සහ භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාවයට ගරු කළ යුතු අතර, චීනයේ අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් වීම නැවැත්විය යුතුයි\" යනුවෙනි.",
        "එසේම, තායිවානය කෙරෙහි චීනයේ ස්වෛරීභාවය පිළිගන්නා නමුත් එය අනුමත නොකරන වොෂිංටනයේ නිල මතය ගැන සඳහන් කරමින්, එක් චීනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය වැළැක්වීමට හා විකෘති කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය උත්සාහ කරන බවට වැන්ග් චෝදනා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவை சீனா மீண்டும் எச்சரித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் வாங் யீ சனிக்கிழமை அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அந்தோனி பிளின்கனிடம், சீனாவின் வெளிநாட்டு மற்றும் உள்நாட்டுக் கொள்கைகளை அமெரிக்கா மதித்து, பொருளாதாரத் தடைகளை நீக்கி, பனிப்போர் மனநிலையைக் கைவிட வேண்டும் என்பதே சீனாவின் நம்பிக்கை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், பிளின்கென் செய்தியாளர்களிடம், ரஷ்யா மீது தடைகளை விதிக்க சீனா மறுத்ததால் வாங்குக்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுத்ததாகவும், வெளிப்படையாக பலனளிக்கவில்லை என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை இந்தோனேசியாவில் G20 நாடுகளின் உயர்மட்ட இராஜதந்திரிகளின் கூட்டத்திற்கு ஒரு நாள் கழித்து Blinken மற்றும் Wang சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்பு வாஷிங்டன்-பெய்ஜிங் உறவுகளுக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான கட்டத்தில் வந்தது. சீனாவில் இருந்து வெளிவரும் \"விரிவான\" தொழில்துறை உளவு மற்றும் சைபர் கிரைம் குறித்து FBI எச்சரித்த நிலையில், தைவானை மீட்பதற்கான சீன இராணுவத்தின் எந்தவொரு முயற்சியையும் எதிர்த்துப் போராடப் போவதாக அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடன் சமீபத்தில் அறிவித்ததால் இந்த சந்திப்பு நிகழ்ந்தது.",
        "இருப்பினும், இந்த சந்திப்பில், சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் வாங், \"சீனாவுடன் மோதலை உருவாக்கும் நோக்கம் இல்லை என்று அமெரிக்கா உறுதியளித்துள்ளதால், அவர்கள் சீனாவின் இறையாண்மை மற்றும் பிராந்திய ஒருமைப்பாட்டிற்கு மதிப்பளித்து, சீனாவின் உள் விவகாரங்களில் தலையிடுவதை நிறுத்த வேண்டும்.\"",
        "மேலும், தைவான் மீதான சீனாவின் இறையாண்மையை அங்கீகரிக்கும் வாஷிங்டனின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ பார்வையை குறிப்பிடுகையில், ஒரே சீனா கொள்கையை தடுக்கவும் சிதைக்கவும் அமெரிக்கா முயற்சிப்பதாக வாங் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தோனி பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}