{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Sri-Lankan-refugee-found-unconscious-on-Tamil-Nadu-shores-dies/108-240304",
  "time_ut": 1656915705,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan refugee, found unconscious on Tamil Nadu shores, dies",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan refugee, found unconscious on Tamil Nadu shores, dies",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A 71-year-old woman refugee, who had fled crisis-ridden Sri Lanka along with her 81-year-old husband on a boat and was found unconscious on the shore at Dhanushkodi on June 27, died at Government Rajaji Hospital in Madurai on Saturday night.",
        "Of the 96 who have so far reached Indian shores on illegal ferries after the island nation plunged into an economic crisis, this is the first death, the Indian media reported.",
        "The couple, Parameswari and her husband Periyannan Sivan, from Mannar, were admitted to Ramanathapuram Government Hospital as they suffered from dehydration and shock. They were subsequently referred to Government Rajaji Hospital the same night.",
        "Doctors at GRH told Times of India that Parameswari had a blood clot in her brain and a craniotomy surgery was done to remove it. However, she continued to be in ICU and died without responding to treatment. They said the woman was diabetic and hypertensive.",
        "The elderly couple had travelled to Tamil Nadu to reunite with their two sons Sahayaseelan and Raja and daughter Udhayarani who are residing at the Valavandankottai refugee camp in Thuvakudi, Trichy. It was around 7am on June 27 that local fishermen spotted the duo unconscious near Kothandaramar temple. Periyannan Sivan is being treated at GRH and is stable."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "71-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "81-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government Rajaji Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madurai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parameswari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Periyannan Sivan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanathapuram Government Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government Rajaji Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GRH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Times of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parameswari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valavandankottai",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thuvakudi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trichy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kothandaramar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Periyannan Sivan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GRH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තමිල්නාඩු වෙරළේ සිහිසුන්ව සිටි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගතයා මිය යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පලා ගිය 81 හැවිරිදි සැමියා සමඟ බෝට්ටුවකින් පලා ගිය 71 හැවිරිදි සරණාගත කාන්තාවක්, ජුනි 27 වන දින ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙරළේ සිහිසුන්ව සිටියදී මදුරෙයිහි රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහලේදී මිය ගියේය. සෙනසුරාදා රෑ.",
        "දූපත් ජාතිය ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට ඇද වැටීමෙන් පසු නීතිවිරෝධී යාත්‍රාවලින් මේ වන විට ඉන්දීය වෙරළට පැමිණ ඇති 96 දෙනාගෙන් පළමු මරණය මෙය බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "මන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි පරමේශ්වරී සහ ඇගේ සැමියා වන පෙරියන්නන් සිවන් යුවළ විජලනය හා කම්පනයට ලක්ව රාමනාතපුරම් රජයේ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත. පසුව ඔවුන් එදිනම රාත්‍රියේ රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහල වෙත යොමු කරන ලදී.",
        "GRH හි වෛද්‍යවරු ටයිම්ස් ඔෆ් ඉන්ඩියා වෙත පැවසුවේ පරමේශ්වරීගේ මොළයේ රුධිර කැටියක් ඇති බවත් එය ඉවත් කිරීම සඳහා හිස් කබලේ සැත්කමක් කළ බවත්ය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටි ඇය ප්‍රතිකාර නොලබා මිය ගියාය. ඔවුන් පැවසුවේ මෙම කාන්තාව දියවැඩියා සහ අධි රුධිර පීඩනයෙන් පෙළෙන බවයි.",
        "ට්‍රිචි, තුවකුඩි හි වලවන්දන්කෝට්ටෙයි සරණාගත කඳවුරේ පදිංචිව සිටින ඔවුන්ගේ පුතුන් දෙදෙනා වන සහයසීලන් සහ රාජා සහ දියණිය උදයරාණි සමඟ නැවත එක්වීමට මෙම වයෝවෘද්ධ යුවළ තමිල්නාඩුවට ගොස් ඇත. ජූනි 27 වැනිදා උදේ 7 ට පමණ කොතන්දරාමර් කෝවිල අසලදී සිහිසුන්ව සිටි දෙදෙනකු ප්‍රාදේශීය ධීවරයන් දැක තිබේ. පෙරියන්නන් සිවන් GRH හි ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන අතර ඔහු ස්ථාවරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "71 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "81 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මදුරෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරමේශ්වරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරියන්නන් සිවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනාතපුරම් රජයේ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම රාත්රියේම",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GRH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටයිම්ස් ඔෆ් ඉන්දියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරමේශ්වරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලවන්දන්කෝට්ටෙයි",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුවකුඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිචි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 7",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොතන්දරාමර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරියන්නන් සිවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GRH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தமிழக கடற்கரையில் மயங்கிய நிலையில் காணப்பட்ட இலங்கை அகதி மரணம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெருக்கடியான இலங்கையிலிருந்து 81 வயது கணவருடன் படகில் சென்ற 71 வயது பெண் அகதி, ஜூன் 27 அன்று தனுஷ்கோடி கடற்கரையில் மயங்கிய நிலையில் மதுரை அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனையில் உயிரிழந்தார். சனிக்கிழமை இரவு.",
        "தீவு நாடு பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் மூழ்கிய பின்னர் இதுவரை சட்டவிரோத படகுகளில் இந்தியக் கரையை அடைந்த 96 பேரில், இது முதல் மரணம் என்று இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "மன்னாரை சேர்ந்த தம்பதி பரமேஸ்வரி மற்றும் அவரது கணவர் பெரியண்ணன் சிவன் நீர்ச்சத்து குறைபாடு மற்றும் அதிர்ச்சியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு ராமநாதபுரம் அரசு மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டனர். இதையடுத்து அவர்கள் அன்றிரவு அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனைக்கு அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "பரமேஸ்வரிக்கு மூளையில் ரத்தம் உறைந்திருப்பதாகவும், அதை அகற்ற கிரானியோட்டமி அறுவை சிகிச்சை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாகவும் ஜிஆர்ஹெச் மருத்துவர்கள் டைம்ஸ் ஆஃப் இந்தியாவிடம் தெரிவித்தனர். ஆனால், தொடர்ந்து ஐசியூவில் இருந்த அவர் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்தார். அந்தப் பெண்ணுக்கு நீரிழிவு மற்றும் உயர் இரத்த அழுத்தம் இருப்பதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "திருச்சி, துவாக்குடியில் உள்ள வளவந்தான்கோட்டை அகதிகள் முகாமில் வசிக்கும் இரண்டு மகன்கள் சகாயசீலன், ராஜா, மகள் உதயராணி ஆகியோருடன் மீண்டும் இணைய முதிய தம்பதியினர் தமிழகம் சென்றுள்ளனர். ஜூன் 27ஆம் தேதி காலை 7 மணியளவில் கோதண்டராமர் கோயில் அருகே மயங்கிய நிலையில் இருவரையும் உள்ளூர் மீனவர்கள் பார்த்தனர். பெரியண்ணன் சிவன் ஜிஆர்எச் மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று உடல்நிலை தேறி வருகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "71 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "81 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரமேஸ்வரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரியண்ணன் சிவன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாதபுரம் அரசு மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GRH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டைம்ஸ் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரமேஸ்வரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளவந்தான்கோட்டை",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "துவாக்குடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 7 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோதண்டராமர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரியண்ணன் சிவன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GRH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}