{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/despite-problems/",
  "time_ut": 1661189160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Despite problems…",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Despite problems…",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "It’s, indeed, heartening to see some of the stalwarts, in the local music scene, continue to make their presence felt by keeping music lovers, entertained, at some of the popular venues, in the city…despite the problems we are all experiencing.",
        "Going by what I see, on social media, Chandral Fonseka, a veteran in the local music scene, and his band Kings, are giving guests a cool atmosphere, with their kind of music, on a Thursday evening, at The Hilton Colombo.",
        "Marlon Amarasekera is back in the scene with his outfit, Omega, and they do their thing every Saturday night, at the Hilton Colombo.",
        "According to Marlon, they are also working, on Tuesdays, and Saturdays, during the month of August, at the same venue – the Colombo Hilton Lobby.",
        "Marlon has, in the past, performed with some of the top bands. He did it with the group Friends, Rebirth and Mirage, on lead guitar and vocals.",
        "Omega was formed in March 2021, and they operate as a four-piece band.",
        "“We do bring into our setup a female vocalist, but not on a regular basis. It all depends on the occasion, or upon a client’s request,” said Marlon.",
        "Band leader – on lead guitar and vocals. His repertoire covers the classic songs of Bryan Adams, Joe Cocker, Don Henley, Bruce Springsteen, Bon Jovi…yes, from the Golden oldies to the popular Baila.",
        "Deezone, Rebirth, Mintaka, and Rock This Country – piano/keyboards and vocals. Covers Elton John, Billy Joel, Van Morrison, Don McLean, Paul Simon, Freddy Fender, John Mayer.",
        "Damage, Gravity and Black – bass guitar/vocals. His scene includes song of Shaggy, Doobie Brothers, Gypsy Kings, Bob Marley and the current chart hits.",
        "On drums (fairly new to the scene but was drummer for KRC WORSHIP, for 10 years.)",
        "Marlon went on to say that Omega is well equipped to tackle any occasion.",
        "“We have the talent to tackle pop, soul, country, rock, blues, and, of course, Sinhala hits, and bailas.”",
        "In addition to their regular Lobby, Club and Pub performances, they also do dances, weddings, corporate events, shows, as well as tours.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandral Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Hilton Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marlon Amarasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hilton Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marlon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesdays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturdays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hilton Lobby",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friends, Rebirth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirage",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marlon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bryan Adams",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Cocker",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Henley",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bruce Springsteen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bon Jovi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baila",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rebirth",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elton John",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Billy Joel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Van Morrison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don McLean",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paul Simon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freddy Fender",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Mayer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shaggy, Doobie Brothers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gypsy Kings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bob Marley",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "KRC WORSHIP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගැටලු තිබුණත්…",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "අප සැවොම අත්විඳින ගැටලු මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, ප්‍රාදේශීය සංගීත ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ සමහර ප්‍රබලයින්, සංගීත ලෝලීන්ට, විනෝදාස්වාදයට, සමහර ජනප්‍රිය ස්ථානවලදී, නගරයේ තබා ගනිමින් ඔවුන්ගේ පැවැත්ම දිගටම දැනීම ඇත්තෙන්ම සතුටට කරුණකි.",
        "මා දකින ආකාරයට, සමාජ මාධ්‍ය තුළ, දේශීය සංගීත ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රවීණයෙකු වන චන්ද්‍රාල් ෆොන්සේකා සහ ඔහුගේ කිංග්ස් සංගීත කණ්ඩායම, බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සවස, කොළඹ හිල්ටන් හි අමුත්තන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ආකාරයේ සංගීතයෙන් සිසිල් වාතාවරණයක් ලබා දෙයි.",
        "මාලන් අමරසේකර ඔහුගේ ඇඳුම වන ඔමේගා සමඟ නැවතත් කරළියට පැමිණ ඇති අතර ඔවුන් සෑම සෙනසුරාදා රාත්‍රියකම කොළඹ හිල්ටන් හිදී ඔවුන්ගේ දේ කරති.",
        "මාලන්ට අනුව, ඔවුන් අගෝස්තු මාසයේ අඟහරුවාදා සහ සෙනසුරාදා දිනවල එම ස්ථානයේම වැඩ කරයි - කොළඹ හිල්ටන් ලොබිය.",
        "මාලන්, අතීතයේ දී, සමහර ප්‍රධාන සංගීත කණ්ඩායම් සමඟ රඟපා ඇත. ඔහු එය කළේ මිතුරන්, පුනරුත්පත්තිය සහ මිරාජ් කණ්ඩායම සමඟ ලීඩ් ගිටාරය සහ ගායනයෙනි.",
        "ඔමේගා 2021 මාර්තු මාසයේදී පිහිටුවන ලද අතර, ඒවා කොටස් හතරක සංගීත කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරයි.",
        "“අපි කාන්තා ගායන ශිල්පිනියක් අපගේ සැකසුම තුළට ගෙන එනවා, නමුත් නිතිපතා නොවේ. ඒ සියල්ල රඳා පවතින්නේ අවස්ථාව මත හෝ සේවාදායකයාගේ ඉල්ලීම මත ය, ”මාලන් පැවසීය.",
        "සංගීත කණ්ඩායමේ නායකයා - ලීඩ් ගිටාරය සහ ගායනය මත. ඔහුගේ ප්‍රසංගය Bryan Adams, Joe Cocker, Don Henley, Bruce Springsteen, Bon Jovi ගේ සම්භාව්‍ය ගීත ආවරණය කරයි... ඔව්, Golden oldies සිට ජනප්‍රිය Baila දක්වා.",
        "Deezone, Rebirth, Mintaka, සහ Rock This Country - පියානෝ/යතුරු පුවරු සහ ගායනය. Elton John, Billy Joel, Van Morrison, Don McLean, Paul Simon, Freddy Fender, John Mayer ආවරණය කරයි.",
        "හානිය, ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණය සහ කළු - බේස් ගිටාර්/ගායනය. ඔහුගේ දර්ශනයට Shaggy, Doobie Brothers, Gypsy Kings, Bob Marley සහ වර්තමාන ප්‍රස්ථාර ජනප්‍රිය ගීත ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "බෙර මත (දර්ශනයට තරමක් අලුත් නමුත් වසර 10 ක් KRC නමස්කාරය සඳහා බෙර වාදකයා විය.)",
        "මාලන් තවදුරටත් පැවසුවේ ඔමේගා ඕනෑම අවස්ථාවකට මුහුණ දීමට හොඳින් සන්නද්ධ බවයි.",
        "\"අපට පොප්, ආත්මය, රට, රොක්, බ්ලූස් සහ, ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, සිංහල හිට්ස් සහ බයිලා වලට මුහුණ දීමට හැකියාව ඇත.\"",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ නිත්‍ය ලොබි, ක්ලබ් සහ පබ් ප්‍රසංගවලට අමතරව, ඔවුන් නැටුම්, මංගල උත්සව, ආයතනික සිදුවීම්, සංදර්ශන මෙන්ම චාරිකා ද කරති.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රාල් ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ හිල්ටන්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලන් අමරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔමේගා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ හිල්ටන්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිල්ටන් ලොබිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිත්රවරුනි, නැවත ඉපදීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරාජ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔමේගා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රයන් ඇඩම්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝ කොකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොන් හෙන්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෲස් ස්ප්‍රින්ග්ස්ටීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොන් ජෝවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බයිලා",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නැවත ඉපදීම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටන් ජෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලී ජොයෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන් මොරිසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොන් මැක්ලීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝල් සයිමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්‍රෙඩී ෆෙන්ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් මේයර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂැගී, ඩූබී සහෝදරයෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිප්සී කිංග්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොබ් මාර්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "KRC නමස්කාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔමේගා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரச்சனைகள் இருந்தாலும்…",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "உண்மையில், உள்ளூர் இசைக் காட்சிகளில், சில பிரசித்தி பெற்றவர்கள், இசை ஆர்வலர்களை, மகிழ்விப்பதன் மூலம், சில பிரபலமான இடங்களில், நகரத்தில்... பிரச்சனைகளை அனுபவித்து வருகிறோம்.",
        "நான் பார்ப்பதைப் பார்த்தால், சமூக ஊடகங்களில், உள்ளூர் இசைக் காட்சியில் மூத்தவரான சந்திரல் பொன்சேகா மற்றும் அவரது இசைக்குழு கிங்ஸ், ஒரு வியாழன் மாலை, தி ஹில்டன் கொழும்பில் விருந்தினர்களுக்கு அவர்களின் வகையான இசையுடன் குளிர்ச்சியான சூழலை வழங்குகிறார்கள்.",
        "மர்லன் அமரசேகர தனது உடையான ஒமேகாவுடன் மீண்டும் காட்சிக்கு வந்துள்ளார், மேலும் அவர்கள் ஒவ்வொரு சனிக்கிழமை இரவும் ஹில்டன் கொழும்பில் தங்கள் காரியங்களைச் செய்கிறார்கள்.",
        "மார்லனின் கூற்றுப்படி, அவர்கள் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் செவ்வாய் மற்றும் சனிக்கிழமைகளில் அதே இடத்தில் - கொழும்பு ஹில்டன் லாபியில் வேலை செய்கிறார்கள்.",
        "மார்லன், கடந்த காலத்தில், சில சிறந்த இசைக்குழுக்களுடன் இணைந்து நடித்துள்ளார். அவர் அதை நண்பர்கள் குழு, மறுபிறப்பு மற்றும் மிராஜ், முன்னணி கிட்டார் மற்றும் குரல்களில் செய்தார்.",
        "ஒமேகா மார்ச் 2021 இல் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் அவை நான்கு துண்டு இசைக்குழுவாக செயல்படுகின்றன.",
        "\"நாங்கள் ஒரு பெண் பாடகரை எங்கள் அமைப்பில் கொண்டு வருகிறோம், ஆனால் வழக்கமான அடிப்படையில் அல்ல. இது அனைத்தும் சந்தர்ப்பத்தைப் பொறுத்தது அல்லது வாடிக்கையாளரின் கோரிக்கையைப் பொறுத்தது, ”என்று மார்லன் கூறினார்.",
        "இசைக்குழு தலைவர் - முன்னணி கிட்டார் மற்றும் குரல்களில். பிரையன் ஆடம்ஸ், ஜோ காக்கர், டான் ஹென்லி, புரூஸ் ஸ்பிரிங்ஸ்டீன், பான் ஜோவி ஆகியோரின் உன்னதமான பாடல்களை அவரது இசையமைப்பில் உள்ளடக்கியது... ஆம், கோல்டன் ஓல்டீஸ் முதல் பிரபலமான பைலா வரை.",
        "Deezone, Rebirth, Mintaka, and Rock This Country – பியானோ/கீபோர்டுகள் மற்றும் குரல். எல்டன் ஜான், பில்லி ஜோயல், வான் மோரிசன், டான் மெக்லீன், பால் சைமன், ஃப்ரெடி ஃபெண்டர், ஜான் மேயர் ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கியது.",
        "டேமேஜ், கிராவிட்டி மற்றும் பிளாக் - பேஸ் கிட்டார்/குரல். அவரது காட்சியில் ஷாகி, டூபி பிரதர்ஸ், ஜிப்சி கிங்ஸ், பாப் மார்லி மற்றும் தற்போதைய தரவரிசை ஹிட் பாடல்கள் அடங்கும்.",
        "டிரம்ஸில் (காட்சிக்கு மிகவும் புதியவர் ஆனால் 10 ஆண்டுகளாக KRC வழிபாட்டிற்கு டிரம்மராக இருந்தார்.)",
        "மார்லன், ஒமேகா எந்தச் சந்தர்ப்பத்தையும் சமாளிக்கத் தயாராக உள்ளது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "\"பாப், ஆன்மா, கன்ட்ரி, ராக், ப்ளூஸ், மற்றும், நிச்சயமாக, சிங்கள ஹிட்ஸ் மற்றும் பைலாக்களை சமாளிக்கும் திறமை எங்களிடம் உள்ளது.\"",
        "அவர்களின் வழக்கமான லாபி, கிளப் மற்றும் பப் நிகழ்ச்சிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக, அவர்கள் நடனங்கள், திருமணங்கள், கார்ப்பரேட் நிகழ்வுகள், நிகழ்ச்சிகள் மற்றும் சுற்றுப்பயணங்களையும் செய்கிறார்கள்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரல் பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு ஹில்டன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்லன் அமரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒமேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹில்டன் கொழும்பு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்லன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹில்டன் லாபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நண்பர்களே, மறுபிறப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிராஜ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒமேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்லன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரையன் ஆடம்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோ காக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் ஹென்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ரூஸ் ஸ்பிரிங்ஸ்டீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பான் ஜோவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைலா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மறுபிறப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்டன் ஜான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லி ஜோயல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வான் மாரிசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் மெக்லீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பால் சைமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரெடி ஃபெண்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் மேயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷாகி, டூபி பிரதர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிப்சி கிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாப் மார்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "KRC வழிபாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒமேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}