{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83293/energy-minister-off-to-qatar-for-talks-on-fuel-imports",
  "time_ut": 1656382320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Energy Minister off to Qatar for talks on fuel imports",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Energy Minister off to Qatar for talks on fuel imports",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekera, accompanied by Minister of Environment Naseer Ahamed, departed for Qatar this morning (June 28), Ada Derana correspondent says.",
        "The two lawmakers are expected to engage in discussions with Qatari officials on supplying fuel to Sri Lanka.",
        "Meanwhile, Minister of Education Susil Premajayantha, who departed for France early this morning to attend the UNESCO Ministerial Conference on Education in Paris, will be flying to Russia to discuss matters including fuel imports."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Qatar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatari",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNESCO Ministerial Conference on Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කටාර් බලා පිටත්ව යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් මහතා සමඟ අද (ජුනි 28) උදෑසන කටාර් බලා පිටත්ව ගිය බව අද දෙරණ වාර්තාකරු පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කටාර් රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නීති සම්පාදකයින් දෙදෙනා බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "මේ අතර පැරීසියේ පැවැත්වෙන යුනෙස්කෝ අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සමුළුවට සහභාගිවීම සඳහා අද අලුයම ප්‍රංශය බලා පිටත්ව ගිය අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත ඉන්ධන ආනයනය ඇතුළු කරුණු සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා රුසියාව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්ති කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්‍යාපනය පිළිබඳ යුනෙස්කෝ අමාත්‍ය සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்காக எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் கத்தார் செல்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட் ஆகியோருடன் இன்று (ஜூன் 28) காலை கட்டார் புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றதாக அத தெரண செய்தியாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை வழங்குவது தொடர்பாக கட்டார் அதிகாரிகளுடன் இரு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் ஈடுபடுவார்கள் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, பாரிஸில் நடைபெறவுள்ள யுனெஸ்கோ கல்வி அமைச்சர்கள் மாநாட்டில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக இன்று அதிகாலை பிரான்ஸ் சென்ற கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி உள்ளிட்ட விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக ரஷ்யாவிற்கு செல்லவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பவர் & எனர்ஜி காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனெஸ்கோ கல்வி அமைச்சர் மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}