{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පාන්-මිල-පා-වෙයි/1-619248",
  "time_ut": 1662212114,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාන් මිල පා වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The price of bread will rise",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "With the emergence of a black market mafia for wheat flour, due to having to buy bread flour at a higher price, a 450 gram loaf of bread has to be sold at 300 rupees, says Mr. NK Jayawardena, president of the All Lanka Bakery Owners' Association.",
        "Mr. Jayawardena also says that a 50 kg bundle of wheat flour which was bought for 3500 rupees has to be bought for 25,000 rupees today.",
        "Mr. Jayawardena says that his association has no objection to buying flour at high prices from the black market and selling a loaf of bread at 300 rupees.",
        "But Mr. Jayawardena also says that his union has not taken a decision to sell bread at 300 rupees."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "450 gram",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "NK Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bakery Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාන් මිල පා වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තිරිඟු පිටි සඳහා කළු කඩ මාෆියාවක් බිහිවීමත් සමග වැඩි මිලට පාන්පිටි මිලදී ගැනීමට සිදුවීම නිසා ග්‍රෑම් 450ක පාන් ගෙඩියක් රුපියල් 300ට  අලෙවි කිරීමට සිදුවන බව සමස්ථ ලංකා  බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති එන්.කේ  ජයවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "රුපියල් 3500ට මිලදි ගත් කිලෝ 50ක තිරිඟු පිටි මිටියක්  අද වන විට රුපියල් 25,000කට මිලදී ගැනීමට සිදුව ඇතැයි ද ජයවර්ධන මහතා කියයි.",
        "කළු කඩෙන්  අධික මිලට පිටි මිලදී ගෙන නිෂ්පාදන කර පාන් ගෙඩියක් රුපියල් 300ට අලෙවිකරනවාට තම සංගමය විරෝධයක් නැතැයි  ජයවර්ධන මහතා කියයි.",
        "නමුත් රුපියල් 300 පාන් අලෙවි කිරීමට තම සංගමය තීරණයක් ගෙන නැතැයි ද ජයවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 450 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.කේ ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரொட்டி விலை உயரும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோதுமை மாவுக்கான கறுப்புச் சந்தை மாபியாவொன்று உருவாகியுள்ள நிலையில், அதிக விலைக்கு ரொட்டி மாவை கொள்வனவு செய்ய வேண்டியுள்ளமையினால், 450 கிராம் ரொட்டி 300 ரூபாவிற்கு விற்பனை செய்ய வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரியின் தலைவர் திரு.என்.கே.ஜயவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்.",
        "3500 ரூபாவிற்கு கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்ட 50 கிலோகிராம் கோதுமை மா மூட்டை இன்று 25,000 ரூபாவிற்கு கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் திரு.ஜெயவர்தன கூறுகிறார்.",
        "கறுப்புச் சந்தையில் அதிக விலைக்கு மாவை கொள்வனவு செய்து ஒரு ரொட்டியை 300 ரூபாவிற்கு விற்பனை செய்வதில் தமது சங்கத்திற்கு எவ்வித ஆட்சேபனையும் இல்லை என ஜயவர்தன கூறுகிறார்.",
        "ஆனால் ரொட்டியை 300 ரூபாவிற்கு விற்பனை செய்வதற்கு தமது தொழிற்சங்கம் தீர்மானம் எடுக்கவில்லை என்றும் ஜயவர்தன கூறுகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "450 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.கே.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}