{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/NDB-remittance-rewards-to-over-70-customers/34-739163",
  "time_ut": 1661539303,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NDB remittance rewards to over 70 customers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NDB remittance rewards to over 70 customers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Senior Manager – Remittance Marketing and Operations Manjeeve Abeysundera, Wellawattta Branch Manager B. Balamuhunthan, Monthly Winner M. Selvarajah, and Wellawatta Assistant Branch Manager Mihiri Silva",
        "NDB Bank presented over 70 customers with cash prizes under the remittance campaign “i,a,s ráka oskqu wfmka”. As the campaign concluded on 31 July, the bank has presented cash prizes worth over one million to customers who collected their Western Union remittances from NDB Bank or any of the bank’s registered Sub Agents.",
        "“i,a,s ráka oskqu wfmka”, commenced to encourage Western Union customers to collect their remittances from NDB Bank or its Sub Agents namely Singer Sri Lanka PLC, Regional Development Bank (RDB), Sarvodaya Development Finance Ltd. (SDF) and Citizen Development Business Finance PLC (CDB). The Western Union customers were eligible for the lottery draw to win Rs. 100,000 monthly, Rs. 50,000 weekly and Rs. 10,000 daily. Accordingly, a total of 72 lucky winners were selected from 979 locations throughout the course of two months.",
        "Western Union beneficiaries were entitled to win a chance to be one of the 61 daily winners, nine weekly winners, and two monthly winners. Accordingly, the campaign concluded successfully, with the two monthly winners and the remaining set of winners were selected via the final draw, represented by the bank’s management and revenue department representatives.",
        "Based on the customer eligibility Western Union customers who collect their remittances from NDB Bank branches and its agents are entitled for the Government incentives to encourage inward worker remittances to Sri Lanka.",
        "As a part of NDB’s efforts to encourage inward remittances through formal banking channels as a responsibility towards the country, the bank is constantly striving to make the lives of its clients and stakeholders easier and more convenient and thus, has also introduced the most convenient way in which the bank’s clients can receive money via Western Union with just one phone call to NDB bank Call Centre on 0117448888 or by sending a message through the NDB NEOS app. The funds received will be credited to the respective individual’s accounts at NDB in just five minutes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NDB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Remittance Marketing and",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawattta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "B. Balamuhunthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Winner M. Selvarajah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawatta Assistant",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mihiri Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NDB Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sub Agents",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sub Agents",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singer Sri Lanka PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Regional Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarvodaya Development Finance Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SDF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Citizen Development Business Finance PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "979",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "just five minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාරිභෝගිකයින් 70 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට NDB ප්‍රේෂණ ත්‍යාග",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකරු - ප්‍රේෂණ අලෙවි සහ මෙහෙයුම් මංජීව අබේසුන්දර, වැල්ලවත්ත ශාඛා කළමනාකරු බී. බාලමුහුන්තන්, මාසික ජයග්‍රාහකයා එම්. සෙල්වරාජා, සහ වැල්ලවත්ත සහකාර ශාඛා කළමනාකාර මිහිරි සිල්වා",
        "NDB බැංකුව \"i,a,s ráka oskqu wfmka\" ප්‍රේෂණ ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ ගනුදෙනුකරුවන් 70 කට අධික පිරිසකට මුදල් ත්‍යාග පිරිනැමීය. ජුලි 31 දින ප්‍රචාරණය අවසන් වූ බැවින්, NDB බැංකුවෙන් හෝ බැංකුවේ ලියාපදිංචි උප නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන් ප්‍රේෂණ එකතු කළ ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට බැංකුව විසින් මිලියනයකට වඩා වටිනා මුදල් ත්‍යාග පිරිනමා ඇත.",
        "“i,a,s ráka oskqu wfmka”, NDB බැංකුවෙන් හෝ එහි උප නියෝජිතයන් වන Singer Sri Lanka PLC, Regional Development Bank (RDB), Sarvodaya Development Finance Ltd. (SDF) සහ වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන් ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රේෂණ ලබා ගැනීමට දිරිගැන්වීම සඳහා ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. සිටිසන් ඩිවලොප්මන්ට් බිස්නස් ෆිනෑන්ස් පීඑල්සී (සීඩීබී). වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන් පාරිභෝගිකයන් ලොතරැයි දිනුම් ඇදීමට සුදුසුකම් ලබා රු. 100,000 මාසිකව, රු. 50,000 සතිපතා සහ රු. දිනකට 10,000. ඒ අනුව මාස දෙකක කාලය තුළ ස්ථාන 979කින් වාසනාවන්ත ජයග්‍රාහකයින් 72ක් තෝරා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "වෙස්ටර්න් යූනියන් ප්‍රතිලාභීන්ට දිනපතා ජයග්‍රාහකයින් 61 දෙනාගෙන්, සතිපතා ජයග්‍රාහකයින් නව දෙනෙකුගෙන් සහ මාසික ජයග්‍රාහකයින් දෙදෙනෙකුගෙන් එක් අයෙකු වීමට අවස්ථාවක් දිනා ගැනීමට හිමිකම් ඇත. ඒ අනුව, බැංකුවේ කළමනාකාරීත්වය සහ ආදායම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නියෝජිතයින් නියෝජනය කරමින් මාසික දිනුම් ඇදීම මගින් මාසික ජයග්‍රාහකයින් දෙදෙනා සහ ඉතිරි ජයග්‍රාහකයින් තෝරා ගැනීමත් සමඟ ප්‍රචාරණය සාර්ථකව අවසන් විය.",
        "පාරිභෝගික සුදුසුකම් මත පදනම්ව NDB බැංකු ශාඛාවලින් සහ එහි නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් තම ප්‍රේෂණ එකතු කරන Western Union පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අභ්‍යන්තර සේවක ප්‍රේෂණ දිරිගැන්වීම සඳහා රජයේ දිරිගැන්වීම් සඳහා හිමිකම් ලැබේ.",
        "රට කෙරෙහි වගකීමක් ලෙස විධිමත් බැංකුකරණ මාර්ග හරහා එන්.ඩී.බී.ගේ අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රේෂණ දිරිගැන්වීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයේ කොටසක් ලෙස, බැංකුව සිය ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ගේ සහ පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ගේ ජීවිත වඩාත් පහසු සහ පහසු කිරීමට නිරන්තරයෙන් උත්සාහ කරන අතර එමඟින් වඩාත් පහසුම ක්‍රමය ද හඳුන්වා දී ඇත. 0117448888 අංකයට NDB බැංකු ඇමතුම් මධ්‍යස්ථානයට එක් දුරකථන ඇමතුමකින් හෝ NDB NEOS යෙදුම හරහා පණිවිඩයක් යැවීමෙන් බැංකුවේ ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට Western Union හරහා මුදල් ලබා ගත හැක. ලැබුණු අරමුදල් මිනිත්තු පහකින් NDB හි අදාළ පුද්ගලයාගේ ගිණුම් වෙත බැර කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NDB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේෂණ අලෙවිකරණය සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී බාලමුහුන්තන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයග්‍රාහකයා එම්.සෙල්වරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත සහකාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහිරි සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NDB බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උප නියෝජිතයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උප නියෝජිතයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගර් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත සර්වෝදය සංවර්ධන මූල්‍ය සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SDF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිටිසන් ඩිවලොප්මන්ට් බිස්නස් ෆිනෑන්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "979",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙස්ටර්න් යුනියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු පහක් පමණි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "70க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு NDB பணம் அனுப்பும் வெகுமதிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிரேஷ்ட முகாமையாளர் – பணம் அனுப்புதல் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் செயற்பாடுகள் மஞ்சீவ் அபேசுந்தர, வெள்ளவத்தை கிளை முகாமையாளர் பி.பாலமுஹுந்தன், மாதாந்த வெற்றியாளர் எம்.செல்வராஜா, மற்றும் வெள்ளவத்தை உதவிக் கிளை முகாமையாளர் மிஹிரி சில்வா.",
        "\"i,a,s ráka oskqu wfmka\" என்ற பணப்பரிமாற்ற பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ் NDB வங்கி 70க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு பணப் பரிசுகளை வழங்கியது. ஜூலை 31 அன்று பிரச்சாரம் முடிவடைந்த நிலையில், NDB வங்கி அல்லது வங்கியின் பதிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட துணை முகவர்களிடமிருந்து வெஸ்டர்ன் யூனியன் பணம் செலுத்திய வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு ஒரு மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மதிப்புள்ள ரொக்கப் பரிசுகளை வங்கி வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "“i,a,s ráka oskqu wfmka”, வெஸ்டர்ன் யூனியன் வாடிக்கையாளர்களை NDB வங்கி அல்லது அதன் துணை முகவர்களான சிங்கர் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பிஎல்சி, பிராந்திய அபிவிருத்தி வங்கி (RDB), சர்வோதயா டெவலப்மெண்ட் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட் (SDF) மற்றும் சிட்டிசன் டெவலப்மென்ட் பிசினஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் பிஎல்சி (சிடிபி). வெஸ்டர்ன் யூனியன் வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் லாட்டரி குலுக்கல் முறையில் ரூ. மாதம் 100,000, ரூ. வாரந்தோறும் 50,000 மற்றும் ரூ. தினசரி 10,000. அதன்படி, இரண்டு மாத காலப்பகுதியில் 979 இடங்களில் இருந்து மொத்தம் 72 அதிர்ஷ்டசாலிகள் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "வெஸ்டர்ன் யூனியன் பயனாளிகள் 61 தினசரி வெற்றியாளர்கள், ஒன்பது வாராந்திர வெற்றியாளர்கள் மற்றும் இரண்டு மாதாந்திர வெற்றியாளர்களில் ஒருவராக இருப்பதற்கான வாய்ப்பை வெல்லும் உரிமையைப் பெற்றனர். அதன்படி, பிரச்சாரம் வெற்றிகரமாக முடிந்தது, இரண்டு மாதாந்திர வெற்றியாளர்கள் மற்றும் மீதமுள்ள வெற்றியாளர்கள் வங்கியின் நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் வருவாய் துறை பிரதிநிதிகளால் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தப்பட்ட இறுதி குலுக்கல் மூலம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "வாடிக்கையாளர் தகுதியின் அடிப்படையில், NDB வங்கியின் கிளைகள் மற்றும் அதன் முகவர்களிடமிருந்து தங்கள் பணத்தைச் சேகரிக்கும் வெஸ்டர்ன் யூனியன் வாடிக்கையாளர்கள், இலங்கைக்கு உள்நோக்கிப் பணியாளர்கள் பணம் அனுப்புவதை ஊக்குவிப்பதற்காக அரசாங்க ஊக்குவிப்புகளுக்கு உரிமையுடையவர்கள்.",
        "நாட்டிற்கு ஒரு பொறுப்பாக முறையான வங்கி வழிகள் மூலம் உள்நோக்கி பணம் அனுப்புவதை ஊக்குவிக்கும் NDB இன் முயற்சிகளின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, வங்கி தனது வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் மற்றும் பங்குதாரர்களின் வாழ்க்கையை எளிதாகவும் வசதியாகவும் மாற்றுவதற்கு தொடர்ந்து முயற்சித்து வருகிறது. வங்கியின் வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் வெஸ்டர்ன் யூனியன் வழியாக NDB வங்கி அழைப்பு மையத்திற்கு 0117448888 என்ற எண்ணில் ஒரு தொலைபேசி அழைப்பின் மூலம் அல்லது NDB NEOS செயலி மூலம் ஒரு செய்தியை அனுப்புவதன் மூலம் பணத்தைப் பெறலாம். பெறப்பட்ட நிதியானது NDB இல் உள்ள அந்தந்த நபரின் கணக்குகளில் வெறும் ஐந்து நிமிடங்களில் வரவு வைக்கப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "என்.டி.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பணம் அனுப்பும் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பாலமுஹுந்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெற்றியாளர் எம்.செல்வராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை உதவியாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிஹிரி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NDB வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துணை முகவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துணை முகவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கர் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராந்திய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வோதயா டெவலப்மெண்ட் ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SDF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிட்டிசன் டெவலப்மெண்ட் பிசினஸ் ஃபைனான்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "979",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}