{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/up-country-trains-suspended-until-further-notice/",
  "time_ut": 1659420540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Up-country trains suspended until further notice",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Up-country trains suspended until further notice",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Due to rockfalls and landslides on the railway line at several places between Higuruoya and Rosella trains on the up-country line have been suspended until further notice.",
        "The Railway Control Room said the 'Podi-menike' and 'Udarata-menike' trains that were scheduled to operate from Colombo Fort this morning were suspended.",
        "A train operated to Colombo from Badulla was stopped in Hatton yesterday (1) due to inclement weather.",
        "Sri Lanka Railways said that the night mail train that was scheduled to operate from Colombo Fort to Badulla and the night mail train that was scheduled to operate from Badulla to Colombo Fort were also canceled."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Higuruoya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rosella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Railway Control Room",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "උඩරට දුම්රිය නැවත දැනුම් දෙනතුරු අත්හිටුවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); උඩරට මාර්ගයේ හිගුරුඔය සහ රොසැල්ල අතර ස්ථාන කිහිපයකදී දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ගල් පෙරළීම් සහ පස් කඳු කඩා වැටීම හේතුවෙන් උඩරට මාර්ගයේ දුම්රිය නැවත දැනුම් දෙනතුරු අත්හිටුවා තිබෙනවා.",
        "අද පෙරවරුවේ කොළඹ කොටුවේ සිට ධාවනය වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ ‘පොඩි මැණිකේ’ සහ ‘උඩරට මැණිකේ’ දුම්රියන් අත්හිටුවා ඇති බව දුම්රිය පාලක මැදිරිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අයහපත් කාලගුණය හේතුවෙන් බදුල්ලේ සිට කොළඹ බලා ධාවනය වූ දුම්රියක් ඊයේ (1) හැටන් ප්‍රදේශයේදී නතර කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුවේ සිට බදුල්ල දක්වා ධාවනය වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ රාත්‍රී තැපැල් දුම්රිය සහ බදුල්ලේ සිට කොළඹ කොටුව දක්වා ධාවනය වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ රාත්‍රී තැපැල් දුම්රිය ද අවලංගු කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Higuruoya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොසෙලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය පාලක මැදිරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேல்நாட்டு ரயில்கள் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மலையகப் பாதையில் ஹிகுருஓயாவிற்கும் ரொசெல்லவிற்கும் இடையில் பல இடங்களில் புகையிரதப் பாதையில் பாறைகள் சரிந்து மண்சரிவு ஏற்பட்டதன் காரணமாக மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை ரயில்கள் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இன்று காலை கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் இருந்து இயக்கப்படவிருந்த பொடி-மெனிகே மற்றும் உடரட-மெனிகே ஆகிய ரயில்கள் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ரயில்வே கட்டுப்பாட்டு அறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சீரற்ற காலநிலை காரணமாக நேற்று (1) பதுளையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு நோக்கி இயக்கப்படும் புகையிரதம் ஹட்டனில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் இருந்து பதுளைக்கு இயக்கப்படவிருந்த இரவு அஞ்சல் புகையிரதமும், பதுளையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு கோட்டைக்கு இயக்கப்படவிருந்த இரவு அஞ்சல் புகையிரதமும் இரத்து செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Higuruoya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோசெல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே கட்டுப்பாட்டு அறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}