{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/20/over-500000-gas-cylinders-distributed-litro/",
  "time_ut": 1658291880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Over 500,000 Gas Cylinders distributed – Litro",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Over 500,000 Gas Cylinders distributed – Litro",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Litro says that around 500,000 gas cylinders have been distributed so far throughout the country.",
        "The Chairman of Litro Muditha Peiris noted that it planned to distribute 60,000 gas cylinders to many areas outside of Colombo.",
        "However, long queues were seen leading to Gas Distribution Centers across the island.",
        "LIVE: Election for President – Speaker says its a historic day for Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "a historic day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "500,000 කට අධික ගෑස් සිලින්ඩර බෙදාහැරීම - ලිට්රෝ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ වන විට දිවයින පුරා ගෑස් සිලින්ඩර ලක්ෂ පහක් පමණ බෙදා හැර ඇති බව ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම පවසයි.",
        "කොළඹින් පිට ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට ගෑස් සිලින්ඩර 60,000ක් බෙදා හැරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, දිවයින පුරා ගෑස් බෙදාහැරීමේ මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත දිගු පෝලිම් දක්නට ලැබුණි.",
        "සජීවීව: ජනාධිපතිවරණ මැතිවරණය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එය ඓතිහාසික දිනයක් බව කථානායක පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඓතිහාසික දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "500,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்கள் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டன - லிட்ரோ",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாடு முழுவதும் இதுவரை 500,000 எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்கள் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக லிட்ரோ தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பிற்கு வெளியே பல பகுதிகளுக்கு 60,000 எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களை விநியோகிக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தீவு முழுவதும் எரிவாயு விநியோக மையங்களுக்கு நீண்ட வரிசைகள் காணப்பட்டன.",
        "நேரலை: ஜனாதிபதிக்கான தேர்தல் - இலங்கைக்கு இது ஒரு வரலாற்று நாள் என்று சபாநாயகர் கூறுகிறார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வரலாற்று நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}