{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/cse-recovers-following-cbsl-chiefs-observations-on-local-economy/",
  "time_ut": 1660835040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CSE recovers following CBSL chief’s observations on local economy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CSE recovers following CBSL chief’s observations on local economy",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s shares moved up within the first hour of trading yesterday though the market proved to be highly volatile. However, it later showed some marginal recovery following Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe’s positive comments on the local economy. He hinted that the economy would become stable and register steady growth by next year.",
        "Weerasinghe said inflation will reach a maximum level of 65 per cent by September and will likely indicate a downward trend afterwards. “The reason being that the Central Bank managed the sagging economy quite well and now we could provide the basic needs of the people with our current export revenue and inward remittances, he said at the CBSL’s monthly policy review meeting yesterday.",
        "Amid these developments both indices moved upwards. The All- Share Price Index rose by 3.22 points (0.04 per cent) to end at 8910.57 and S and P SL20 gained 22.36 points (0.76 per cent) to end the day at 2969.36. Turnover stood at Rs 2.7 billion with a single crossing. The crossing was reported in JKH, which crossed 500,000 shares to the tune of Rs 63.75 million; its shares traded at Rs 120.50.",
        "In the retail market, seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were, Lanka IOC Rs 578 million (three million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 313 million (1.5 million shares traded), Lankem Development Rs 208 million (ten million shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 84.6 million (ten million shares traded), LOLC Finance Rs 83 million (114,000 shares traded), Agstar Rs 82.7 million (6.8 million shares traded) and Renuka Agri Foods Rs 72.6 million (9.8 million shares traded). During the day 115 million share volumes changed hands in 29000 transactions. Yesterday the Central Bank announced the US dollar buying rate as Rs 357.33 and the selling rate as Rs 368.70.",
        "ComBank revolutionises Sri Lankan banking with ‘wearable banking’ via Flash Digital Account",
        "An interview with Yiran An, senior product manager, vivo Imaging Centre",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.04 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8910.57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22.36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.76 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2969.36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.7 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63.75 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "120.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "578 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "313 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankem Development Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "83 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "114,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agstar Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Renuka Agri Foods Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ComBank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yiran An",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imaging Centre",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CBSL ප්‍රධානියාගේ දේශීය ආර්ථිකය පිළිබඳ නිරීක්ෂණවලින් පසු CSE යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් වේ",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "වෙලඳපොල ඉතා අස්ථාවර බවක් පෙන්නුම් කළද, ඊයේ වෙළඳාමේ පළමු පැය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොටස් ඉහළ ගියේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, පසුව එය මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා දේශීය ආර්ථිකය පිළිබඳ සාධනීය අදහස් දැක්වීමෙන් පසු යම් ආන්තික ප්‍රකෘතියක් පෙන්නුම් කළේය. ලබන වසර වන විට ආර්ථිකය ස්ථාවර වී ස්ථාවර වර්ධනයක් වාර්තා කරනු ඇතැයි ඔහු ඉඟි කළේය.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් මාසය වන විට උද්ධමනය සියයට 65ක උපරිම මට්ටමට ළඟා වනු ඇති බවත් ඉන් පසුව පහළ යාමේ ප්‍රවණතාවක් පෙන්නුම් කළ හැකි බවත් වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය. “හේතුව, මහ බැංකුව පසුබෑමකට ලක් වූ ආර්ථිකය හොඳින් කළමනාකරණය කර ගැනීම සහ දැන් අපට අපගේ වර්තමාන අපනයන ආදායම සහ අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රේෂණ මගින් ජනතාවගේ මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සැපයීමට හැකි බව ඊයේ මහ බැංකුවේ මාසික ප්‍රතිපත්ති සමාලෝචන රැස්වීමේදී ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම වර්ධනයන් මධ්‍යයේ දර්ශක දෙකම ඉහළට ගමන් කළේය. සියලු කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 3.22 කින් (සියයට 0.04) ඉහළ ගොස් ඒකක 8910.57 ක් වූ අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 22.36 කින් (සියයට 0.76) ඉහළ ගොස් 2969.36 ක් විය. එක් හරස් මාර්ගයකින් පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 2.7 ක් විය. මෙම හරස් කිරීම JKH හි වාර්තා වූ අතර එය කොටස් 500,000 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 63.75 ක් විය. එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 120.50 ට ගනුදෙනු විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ, පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ සමාගම් හතක් වූයේ, ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 578 (කොටස් මිලියන තුනක්), එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 313 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.5 ක්), ලංකෙම් ඩිවලොප්මන්ට් රුපියල් මිලියන 208 (කොටස් මිලියන දහයක් වෙළඳාම් කර ඇත) , Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 84.6 (කොටස් මිලියන දහයක් ගනුදෙනු), LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 83 (කොටස් 114,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), Agstar රුපියල් මිලියන 82.7 (කොටස් මිලියන 6.8 ක් ගනුදෙනු) සහ Renuka Agri Foods රුපියල් මිලියන 72.6 (කොටස් මිලියන 9.8 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 29000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 115 ක් වෙනස් විය. ඊයේ මහ බැංකුව එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයේ ගැනුම් අනුපාතිකය රුපියල් 357.33ක් ලෙසත් විකුණුම් මිල රුපියල් 368.70ක් ලෙසත් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය.",
        "ComBank Flash Digital ගිණුම හරහා ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය බැංකුකරණයේ විප්ලවීය වෙනසක් ඇති කරයි",
        "Vivo Imaging Center හි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිෂ්පාදන කළමනාකරු Yiran An සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවක්",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 65 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියලුම-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.04 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8910.57 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22.36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.76 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2969.36 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 2.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.කේ.එච්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 63.75 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "120.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 578 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන තුනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 313 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකෙම් සංවර්ධන රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 84.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 83 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "114,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agstar රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 82.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේණුකා ඇග්‍රි ෆුඩ්ස් රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 115 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.70 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ComBank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yiran An",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරූපණ මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உள்ளூர் பொருளாதாரம் குறித்த CBSL தலைவரின் அவதானிப்புகளைத் தொடர்ந்து CSE மீண்டு வருகிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் பங்குகள் நேற்றைய வர்த்தகத்தின் முதல் ஒரு மணி நேரத்தில் ஏற்றம் கண்டது, இருப்பினும் சந்தை மிகவும் ஏற்ற இறக்கமாக இருந்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவின் உள்ளூர் பொருளாதாரம் பற்றிய நேர்மறையான கருத்துக்களைத் தொடர்ந்து அது பின்னர் ஓரளவு மீட்சியைக் காட்டியது. அடுத்த ஆண்டுக்குள் பொருளாதாரம் நிலையானதாகவும், நிலையான வளர்ச்சியை பதிவு செய்யும் என்றும் அவர் சூசகமாக கூறினார்.",
        "செப்டெம்பர் மாதத்திற்குள் பணவீக்கம் அதிகபட்சமாக 65 சதவீதத்தை எட்டும் என்றும் அதன் பின்னர் வீழ்ச்சிப் போக்கைக் குறிக்கலாம் என்றும் வீரசிங்க கூறினார். “நடுங்கும் பொருளாதாரத்தை மத்திய வங்கி மிகச் சிறப்பாக நிர்வகித்திருப்பதே இதற்குக் காரணம், தற்போது எங்களின் தற்போதைய ஏற்றுமதி வருமானம் மற்றும் உள்நோக்கிய பணப்பரிமாற்றங்கள் மூலம் மக்களின் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளை நாங்கள் வழங்க முடியும் என அவர் நேற்று CBSL இன் மாதாந்திர கொள்கை மீளாய்வு கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த முன்னேற்றங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் இரு குறியீடுகளும் மேல் நோக்கி நகர்ந்தன. அனைத்து பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 3.22 புள்ளிகள் (0.04 சதவீதம்) அதிகரித்து 8910.57 ஆகவும், S மற்றும் P SL20 22.36 புள்ளிகள் (0.76 சதவீதம்) அதிகரித்து 2969.36 ஆகவும் முடிவடைந்தது. விற்றுமுதல் ஒருமுறை கடக்க ரூ.2.7 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. 63.75 மில்லியனுக்கு 500,000 பங்குகளைத் தாண்டியது JKH இல் பதிவாகியுள்ளது; அதன் பங்குகள் 120.50 ரூபாய்க்கு வர்த்தகம் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனை சந்தையில், வருவாயில் முக்கியமாக பங்களித்த ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள், லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ 578 மில்லியன் (மூன்று மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 313 மில்லியன் (1.5 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), லங்கெம் டெவலப்மென்ட் ரூ 208 மில்லியன் (பத்து மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) , Browns Investments Rs 84.6 மில்லியன் (பத்து மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), LOLC Finance Rs 83 மில்லியன் (114,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), Agstar Rs 82.7 மில்லியன் (6.8 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் Renuka Agri Foods Rs 72.6 மில்லியன் (9.8 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்). நாளின் போது 29000 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 115 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் கைமாறின. நேற்று மத்திய வங்கி அமெரிக்க டொலரின் கொள்வனவு விலை 357.33 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை விலை 368.70 ரூபாவாகவும் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ComBank, Flash Digital கணக்கின் ஊடாக ‘அணியக்கூடிய வங்கியியல்’ மூலம் இலங்கை வங்கித்துறையில் புரட்சியை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது",
        "vivo இமேஜிங் மையத்தின் மூத்த தயாரிப்பு மேலாளர் யிரான் ஆனுடன் ஒரு நேர்காணல்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனைத்தும்-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.04 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8910.57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22.36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.76 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2969.36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.7 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.கே.எச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63.75 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "120.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "578 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "313 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கெம் அபிவிருத்தி ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கோடி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கோடி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "83 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "114,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்ஸ்டார் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரேணுகா அக்ரி ஃபுட்ஸ் ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காம்பேங்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yiran An",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இமேஜிங் மையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}