{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/බෝට්ටුවෙන්-ගිය-08ක්-ඉන්දියාවේදී-මාට්ටූ/11-396514",
  "time_ut": 1661161713,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් ගිය 08ක් ඉන්දියාවේදී මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "08 who went by boat died in India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "08 people belonging to 03 families residing in Jaffna and Trincomalee were taken into custody by the Tamil Nadu Police yesterday (21st) when they arrived in the Dhanushkodi sea area of ​​India in a small boat.",
        "It is reported that 03 men, 02 women and 3 children belonging to 03 families have sailed to Dhanushkodi coast of India along the Mannar sea border.",
        "The Tamil Nadu Police have quarantined the people who came to Dhanushkodi and taken steps for further investigation.",
        "The Indian security forces further point out that more than 140 people have gone to India through the coasts of the northern province since the 22nd of March and 130 people have taken refuge in that country.",
        "The Navy also says that nearly 600 people attempted to go abroad without permission and were taken into the custody of the Navy between January and July alone."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Nadu Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Tamil Nadu Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd of March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between January and July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් ගිය 08ක් ඉන්දියාවේදී මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනයේ සහ ත්‍රීකුණාමලයේ පදිංචි පවුල් 03කට අයත් පුද්ගලයින් 08 දෙනෙකු ඊයේ (21දා)  ඉන්දියාවේ ධනුෂ්කොඩි මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයට කුඩා මුහුදු යාත්‍රාවකින් පැමිණ සිටියදී තමිල්නාඩු පොලිස් භාරයට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පවුල් 03 කට අයත් පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 03 , කාන්තාවන් 02 ක් සහ  ළමුන් තිදෙනෙකු මෙලෙස මන්නාරම් මුහුදු සීමාව ඔස්සේ ඉන්දියාවේ ධනුෂ්කොඩි මුහුදු තීරයට යාත්‍රා කොට ඇතැයි වාර්ථා වේ.",
        "ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙතට පැමිණි පිරිස් තමිල්නාඩු පොලීසිය විසින් නිරෝධායනය කොට වැඩිදුර පරික්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ගෙවුනු මාර්තු මස 22 වනදා සිට මේ දක්වා උතුරු පලාතේ පිහිටි මුහුදු තීරයන් ඔස්සේ ඉන්දියාවට ගිය ප්‍රමාණය 140 කට අධික බවටද එරට සරණාගත භාවය ලබාගත් පිරිස 130 කට ආසන්න බවටද ඉන්දීය ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් වැඩි දුරටත් පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ජනවාරී මස සිට ජූලි මස දක්වා කාලය තුලදී පමණක් 600 කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් අනවසරයෙන් විදෙස්රටකට යෑමට උත්සහ කොට නාවිකහමුදා භාරයට පත්ව ඇතැයිද නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 22 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "600කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි සහ ජූලි අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "படகில் சென்ற 08 பேர் இந்தியாவில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் மற்றும் திருகோணமலையில் வசிக்கும் 03 குடும்பங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 08 பேர் நேற்று (21ஆம் திகதி) இந்தியாவின் தனுஷ்கோடி கடற்பகுதிக்கு சிறிய படகில் வந்த போது தமிழக காவல்துறையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "03 குடும்பங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 03 ஆண்கள், 02 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 3 சிறுவர்கள் மன்னார் கடல் எல்லை வழியாக இந்தியாவின் தனுஷ்கோடி கடற்கரைக்கு கப்பலேறியுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "தமிழக காவல்துறை தனுஷ்கோடிக்கு வந்தவர்களை தனிமைப்படுத்தியதுடன் மேலதிக விசாரணைக்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த மார்ச் மாதம் 22ஆம் திகதி முதல் வடமாகாணத்தின் கரையோரங்கள் ஊடாக 140 இற்கும் அதிகமானோர் இந்தியாவிற்கு சென்றுள்ளதாகவும், 130 பேர் அந்நாட்டில் தஞ்சமடைந்துள்ளதாகவும் இந்திய பாதுகாப்பு தரப்பினர் மேலும் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனவரி மற்றும் ஜூலை மாதங்களுக்கு இடையில் மட்டும் அனுமதியின்றி வெளிநாடு செல்ல முற்பட்ட 600 பேர் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும் கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "140க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 22 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி மற்றும் ஜூலை இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}