{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/cinema/ஜாக்குலின்-குற்றவாளி/54-302495",
  "time_ut": 1660726624,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜாக்குலின் குற்றவாளி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jacqueline is guilty",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan Bollywood actress Jacqueline Fernandez has been found guilty of extorting money from an Indian.",
        "Bollywood actress Jacqueline has been named as the culprit by the Enforcement Directorate in the Rs 215 crore extortion case.",
        "The Enforcement Directorate filed a chargesheet against Bollywood actress Jacqueline Fernandez today (17).",
        "The Enforcement Directorate says that Jacqueline knew that Sukesh Chandrasekhar was an extortionist and Jacqueline was his accomplice.",
        "Earlier, ED found that Sukesh Chandrasekhar had sent gifts worth Rs 10 crore to actress Jacqueline. So far, the Enforcement Directorate has seized more than Rs 7 crore of the actress' assets under the Anti-Money Laundering Act.",
        "Jacqueline Fernandez was repeatedly investigated by the Enforcement Directorate for alleged links with Sukesh Chandrasekhar.",
        "Sukesh Chandrasekhar has 32 criminal cases against him and is being investigated by several state police and three central agencies – CBI, Enforcement Directorate and Income Tax.",
        "Sukesh Chandrasekhar was accused of extorting Rs 215 crore from the wife of a New Delhi businessman through a fake call. Due to this he was arrested by the Delhi Police.",
        "After investigating him, it was revealed that Sukesh had extorted money from the victim by pretending to be an official of the Prime Minister's Office, Ministry of Law and Ministry of Home Affairs.",
        "Apart from that, Sukesh said over the phone that he would grant bail to the victim's husband and run their drug business. Sukesh is involved in the fraud case against AAMUK leader DTV Dhinakaran. He was arrested by the Enforcement Directorate on April 4 in connection with this case."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jacqueline",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bollywood",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Anti-Money Laundering Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Enforcement Directorate and Income Tax",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Delhi Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Prime Minister's Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Law and Ministry of Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AAMUK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DTV Dhinakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජැකලින් වැරදිකාරිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ඉන්දීය ජාතිකයෙකුගෙන් කප්පම් ගැනීමේ චෝදනාවට වරදකාරිය වී තිබේ.",
        "කෝටි 215 ක කප්පම් නඩුවේ වරදකාරිය ලෙස බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලින් නම් කර තිබේ.",
        "බොලිවුඩ් නිළි ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්ට එරෙහිව බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය අද (17) චෝදනා පත්‍රයක් ගොනු කළේය.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් කප්පම්කරුවෙකු බවත් ජැකලින් ඔහුගේ සහකාරිය බවත් ජැකලින් දැන සිටි බව බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් නිළි ජැකලින්ට රුපියල් කෝටි 10ක තෑගි යවා ඇති බව ED මීට පෙර සොයා ගත්තා. මේ වන විට බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය විසින් මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ නිළියගේ වත්කම්වලින් රුපියල් කෝටි 7 කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වූ ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්ව බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය විසින් නැවත නැවතත් විමර්ශනය කරන ලදී.",
        "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ට එරෙහිව අපරාධ නඩු 32ක් ඇති අතර, ප්‍රාන්ත පොලිස් කිහිපයක් සහ මධ්‍යම ආයතන තුනක් - CBI, බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සහ ආදායම් බදු විසින් විමර්ශනය කරයි.",
        "නවදිල්ලි ව්‍යාපාරිකයෙකුගේ බිරිඳගෙන් ව්‍යාජ ඇමතුමක් මගින් රුපියල් කෝටි 215 ක මුදලක් ලබා ගත් බවට සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ට චෝදනා එල්ල විය. මේ හේතුවෙන් ඔහු දිල්ලි පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ඔහු පිළිබඳව විමර්ශනය කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව අනාවරණය වූයේ සුකේෂ් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ, නීති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සහ ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරියෙකු ලෙස පෙනී සිටිමින් වින්දිත පුද්ගලයාගෙන් කප්පම් ලබාගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඊට අමතරව වින්දිතයාගේ සැමියාට ඇප ලබාදී ඔවුන්ගේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ව්‍යාපාරය කරගෙන යන බව සුකේෂ් දුරකථනයෙන් පැවසීය. AAMUK නායක DTV දිනකරන්ට එරෙහි වංචා නඩුවට සුකේෂ් සම්බන්ධයි. මෙම නඩුවට අදාළව පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් 4 වැනිදා ඔහුව බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැකලින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොලිවුඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණ විරෝධී පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සහ ආදායම් බදු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීති අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AAMUK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීටීවී දිනකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜாக்குலின் குற்றவாளி",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியரை மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்த வழக்கில் இலங்கையைச் ​சேர்ந்த பாலிவுட் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் குற்றவாளியாக இனங்காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "215 கோடி ரூபாய் மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்த வழக்கில், பாலிவுட் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் குற்றவாளியாக அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாலிவுட் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டசுக்கு எதிரான குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் இன்று (17) தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் மிரட்டி பணம் பறிப்பவர் என்பது ஜாக்குலினுக்கு தெரியும் என்றும் அவருக்கு உடந்தையாக ஜாக்குலின் இருந்தார் என்பதும் அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் கூறுகிறது.",
        "முன்னதாக, சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர், நடிகை ஜாக்குலினுக்கு 10 கோடி ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான பரிசுகளை அனுப்பியதை ED கண்டறிந்துள்ளது. அதனால் பணமோசடி தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் இதுவரை நடிகையின்  7 கோடி ரூபாய்க்கும் அதிகமான சொத்துக்களை பறிமுதல் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகருடன் தொடர்பு இருப்பதாக கூறி அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் பலமுறை விசாரணை நடத்தியது.",
        "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் மீது 32 கிரிமினல் வழக்குகள் உள்ளதால், பல மாநில காவல்துறை மற்றும் மூன்று மத்திய ஏஜென்சிகள் – சிபிஐ, அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம் மற்றும் வருமான வரி ஆகியவற்றால் விசாரிக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "புதுடெல்லி தொழிலதிபரின் மனைவியிடம் போலியான அழைப்பு மூலம் ரூ.215 கோடி பணம் பறித்ததாக சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் மீது குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டது. இதனால் அவர் டெல்லி பொலிஸாரினால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "பிறகு அவரிடம் விசாரணை மேற்கொண்டதில் சுகேஷ் ​பிரதமர் அலுவலகம், சட்ட அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் உள்துறை அமைச்சக அதிகாரி போல் நடித்து பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பெண்ணிடம் பணம் பறித்துள்ளது தெரியவந்தது.",
        "அதுமட்டுமல்லாமல் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பெண்ணின் கணவருக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்குவதாகவும், அவர்களின் மருந்து வணிகத்தை நடத்துவதாகவும் சுகேஷ் தொலைபேசி வாயிலாக கூறியுள்ளார்.  அமமுக தலைவர் டிடிவி தினகரன் மீதான மோசடி வழக்கில் சுகேஷ் சிக்கியுள்ளார். இந்த வழக்கு தொடர்பாக அவர் ஏப்ரல் 4ஆம் திகதி அமலாக்கத்துறையால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலிவுட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணமோசடி தடுப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.பி.ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம் மற்றும் வருமான வரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்ட அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் உள்துறை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AAMUK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிடிவி தினகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}