{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පළාත්-රැසකට--තද-වැසි-සමඟ-සුළං/1-617344",
  "time_ut": 1659321856,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පළාත් රැසකට  තද වැසි සමඟ සුළං",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Winds with heavy rains in many regions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Department of Meteorology, an increase in rain and wind conditions in the south-western part of the island, in the western and southern sea areas is expected from today (1) due to the activation of the south-west monsoon.",
        "A spokesperson of the Department of Meteorology said that there will be occasional rains in Western, Sabaragamuwa, North and North-West provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara Eliya, Galle and Matara districts, and heavy rains of more than 100 millimeters may occur in some places.",
        "The spokesperson mentioned that in Uva Province and Ampara District, there will be rains in the evening or at night, and in the western slopes of the Central Highlands and in the Southern Province, winds of up to 50 km/h may occur from time to time.",
        "He said that this situation will continue for a few more days and the sea areas off the coast from Galle through Hambantota to Pothuvil may be very rough.",
        "He said that fast winds of 60, 70 km per hour can occur in those sea areas and sea waves can also rise.",
        "The spokesman said that people engaged in fishing and marine activities in that sea area should be careful.",
        "The department is notifying the people to take measures to avoid accidents as lightning accidents and temporary strong winds may occur along with thunderstorms."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-West",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southern Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 km/h",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few more days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 km per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළාත් රැසකට  තද වැසි සමඟ සුළං",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්වයේ සක්‍රීයවීමක් හේතුවෙන් දිවයිනේ නිරිත දිග කොටසේත්, බස්නාහිර සහ දකුණු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවලත් පවතින වැසි සහ සුළං තත්වයේ වැඩිවීමක් අද (1) සිට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, උතුරු සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇතිවන අතර, ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර 100ට වැඩි තද වැසි ඇතිවිය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "ඌව පළාතේත්, අම්පාර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේත් තැනින් තැන සවස් කාලයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී වැසි ඇතිවන අතර, මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවලත්, දකුණු පළාතේත් විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර 50 පමණ වේගවත් සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම තත්වය තවත් දින කිහිපයක් පවතින අතර, ගාල්ල සිට හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ ඉතා රළු විය හැකි බව හෙතෙම පැවසීය.",
        "එම  මුහුදු ප්‍රදේවල පැයට කිලෝමීටර 60, 70 පමණ වේගවත් සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි අතර, මුහුදු රළ ඉහළයාමක්ද සිදුවිය හැකි බව හෙතෙම කීය.",
        "එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවර හා නාවුක කටයුතුවල යෙදෙන ජනතාව විමසිලිමත් විය යුතු බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බැවින් අනතුරු වළක්වා ගැනීමට පියවර ගන්නැයි එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ජනතාවට දැනුම්දීමක් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 km/h",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තවත් දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර 70 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல பகுதிகளில் பலத்த மழையுடன் காற்று வீசுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தென்மேற்குப் பருவப்பெயர்ச்சியின் செயற்பாடுகள் காரணமாக தீவின் தென்மேற்குப் பகுதி, மேற்கு மற்றும் தெற்கு கடற்பரப்புகளில் இன்று (1) முதல் மழை மற்றும் காற்றின் தாக்கம் அதிகரிக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, வடக்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யும் எனவும், சில இடங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் எனவும் வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "ஊவா மாகாணம் மற்றும் அம்பாறை மாவட்டங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழை பெய்யும் எனவும், மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும் தென் மாகாணத்திலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் காற்று வீசக்கூடும் எனவும் பேச்சாளர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். நேரம்.",
        "இந்நிலை இன்னும் சில நாட்களுக்கு தொடரும் எனவும் காலி தொடக்கம் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகள் மிகவும் கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அந்த கடற்பகுதிகளில் மணிக்கு 60, 70 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் வேகமான காற்று வீசுவதுடன் கடல் அலைகளும் எழும்பக் கூடும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அந்த கடற்பரப்பில் கடற்றொழில் மற்றும் கடற்தொழில்களில் ஈடுபடும் மக்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறும் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் மின்னல் விபத்துக்கள் மற்றும் தற்காலிக பலத்த காற்றும் ஏற்படக்கூடும் என்பதால், விபத்துக்களை தவிர்ப்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு திணைக்களம் மக்களுக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அது வரை",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 70 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}