{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Crisis-hit-Sri-Lanka-strikes-staff-level-pact-with-IMF-on-loan/108-244064",
  "time_ut": 1661924706,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka strikes staff-level pact with IMF on loan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka strikes staff-level pact with IMF on loan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) have reached a preliminary agreement on an emergency loan to the crisis-hit country and a formal announcement will be made on Thursday, four sources with direct knowledge of the matter said.",
        "The island nation, struggling with its worst economic crisis in more than seven decades, had sought up to $3 billion from the IMF.",
        "Spokespersons for the IMF and the Sri Lankan government did not immediately respond to requests for comment.",
        "Staff-level agreements are typically subject to the approval of the IMF management and its executive board, after which the recipient nations get access to funds.",
        "A visiting IMF team held talks with Sri Lankan government officials, including the treasury secretary, late into the night on Tuesday to address concerns on the political front, the sources said. Most of the technical details had been agreed to beforehand.",
        "The country of 22 million was plunged into political crisis last month when then president Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled after a popular uprising against an acute shortage of basic goods and sky-high prices.",
        "Rajapaksa was replaced by six-time prime minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, who also heads the finance department and held several rounds of talks with the IMF team. (Reuters)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than seven decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to $3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය සඳහා IMF සමඟ සේවක මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) අර්බුදකාරී රටට හදිසි ණයක් ලබා දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මූලික එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණ ඇති අතර ඒ පිළිබඳ විධිමත් නිවේදනයක් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට නියමිත බව මේ පිළිබඳව සෘජු දැනුමක් ඇති මූලාශ්‍ර හතරක් පවසයි.",
        "දශක හතකට වැඩි කාලයක් තුළ එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටින දූපත් ජාතිය, IMF වෙතින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 3ක් දක්වා ඉල්ලා තිබුණි.",
        "IMF සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ප්‍රකාශකයින් අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා වූ ඉල්ලීම්වලට ක්ෂණිකව ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ නැත.",
        "කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කළමනාකාරිත්වයේ සහ එහි විධායක මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතියට යටත් වන අතර ඉන් පසුව ලබන්නන් හට අරමුදල් සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය ලැබේ.",
        "IMF කණ්ඩායමක් දේශපාලන පෙරමුණේ ගැටළු විසඳීම සඳහා භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ අඟහරුවාදා රාත්‍රිය දක්වා සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූ බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි. බොහෝ තාක්ෂණික තොරතුරු කලින් එකඟ වී තිබුණි.",
        "පසුගිය මාසයේ උග්‍ර මූලික භාණ්ඩ හිඟයකට සහ අහස උසට නැඟුණු මිලට එරෙහිව ඇති වූ ජනතා නැගිටීමකින් පසු එවක ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පලා යාමත් සමඟ මිලියන 22 ක රට දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට ඇද වැටුණි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙනුවට හය වතාවක් අගමැති වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මුදල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධානියා ද වන අතර IMF කණ්ඩායම සමඟ සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් පැවැත්වීය. (රොයිටර්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දශක හතකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கையானது கடனுக்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் ஊழியர்கள் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்தை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நாட்டிற்கு அவசரகால கடன் வழங்குவதற்கான ஆரம்ப உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டியுள்ளது மற்றும் முறையான அறிவிப்பு வியாழன் அன்று வெளியிடப்படும் என்று இந்த விஷயம் பற்றி நேரடியாக அறிந்த நான்கு வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ஏழு தசாப்தங்களுக்கும் மேலாக அதன் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியுடன் போராடும் தீவு நாடு, IMF யிடம் இருந்து $3 பில்லியன் வரை கோரியது.",
        "IMF மற்றும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்கள் கருத்துக்கான கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு உடனடியாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை.",
        "பணியாளர்-நிலை ஒப்பந்தங்கள் பொதுவாக IMF நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் அதன் நிர்வாகக் குழுவின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு உட்பட்டது, அதன் பிறகு பெறுநர் நாடுகள் நிதிக்கான அணுகலைப் பெறுகின்றன.",
        "வருகை தந்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழு, கருவூலச் செயலாளர் உட்பட இலங்கை அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகளுடன் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை நள்ளிரவு வரை அரசியல் முன்னணியில் உள்ள கவலைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்காக பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தியதாக அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. பெரும்பாலான தொழில்நுட்ப விவரங்கள் முன்பே ஒப்புக் கொள்ளப்பட்டன.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்கள் வாழும் நாடு கடந்த மாதம் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியில் மூழ்கியது, அப்போது ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, அடிப்படைப் பொருட்களின் கடுமையான தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் வானத்தில் உயர்ந்த விலைக்கு எதிரான மக்கள் எழுச்சியின் பின்னர் தப்பி ஓடிவிட்டார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சேவுக்குப் பதிலாக ஆறு முறை பிரதமராக இருந்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கே நிதித் துறைக்கு தலைமை தாங்கினார் மற்றும் IMF குழுவுடன் பல சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை நடத்தினார். (ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு தசாப்தங்களுக்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 பில்லியன் வரை",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}