{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජනපති-දිවුරුම-වෙලාවේ-විදුලිය-බිඳ-වැටෙයි/1-616791",
  "time_ut": 1658382828,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති දිවුරුම වෙලාවේ විදුලිය බිඳ වැටෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "During the swearing in of the President, the power goes out",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Secret Police has been handed over to investigate the power outage in the Parliament complex at the time of the swearing in of the President.",
        "The swearing-in ceremony of Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe as the 8th Executive President was scheduled to be broadcast live by Independent Television and broadcast by other television channels simultaneously.",
        "The live broadcast stopped after the President entered the Parliament complex on the red carpet.",
        "It was later reported that the live broadcast was stopped due to a power outage in the Parliament complex.",
        "In the event of a power outage in the Parliament complex, the generators are usually switched on automatically within two minutes and it is reported that the power was down for about ten minutes at the time of the swearing in of the President.",
        "Due to this reason, TV channels have not been able to cover live broadcasts."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Secret Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independent Television",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "about ten minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති දිවුරුම වෙලාවේ විදුලිය බිඳ වැටෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා දිවුරුම් දෙන අවස්ථාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේ විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීම සම්බන්ධව පරීක්ෂණ කිරීමට රහස් පොලිසියට බාර දී තිබේ.",
        "8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපති ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දෙන අවස්ථාව ස්වාධීන රූපවාහිනිය මඟින් සජීවීව විකාශය කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබූ අතර සෙසු රූපවාහිනි නාලිකා මගින් සමගාමී විකාශයක් ලෙස ප්‍රචාරය කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබිණි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා රතු පලස මතින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයට ඇතුලු වීමෙන් පසු එම සජීවී විකාශය නැවතී ගියේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේ විදුලිය බිඳ වැටීමක් නිසා සජීවී විකාශය නතර වූ බවට පසුව වාර්තා විය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේ විදුලිය බිඳ වැටීමක දී සාමාන්‍යයෙන් විනාඩි දෙකක් වැනි කෙටි කලකදී විදුලි ජනක යන්ත්‍ර නැවත ස්වයංක්‍රීයව ක්‍රියාත්මක වන අතර ජනපති දිවුරුම් දෙන අවස්ථාවේ විනාඩි දහයක පමණ කාලයක් මෙසේ විදුලිය බිඳ වැටී තිබූ බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මේ හේතුව නිසා රූපවාහිනි නාලිකා වලට සජීවී විකාශ ආවරණය කර ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රහස් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි දෙකක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි දහයක් පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிப் பிரமாணத்தின் போது மின்சாரம் துண்டிக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி சத்தியப் பிரமாணம் செய்யும் போது பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட மின் தடை தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்த இரகசிய பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக திரு. ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்பு விழாவை சுயாதீன தொலைக்காட்சி நேரடியாக ஒளிபரப்பவும், ஏனைய தொலைக்காட்சிகள் ஒரே நேரத்தில் ஒளிபரப்பவும் திட்டமிடப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் சிவப்புக் கம்பளத்தில் நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்ததும் நேரடி ஒளிபரப்பு நிறுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட மின்தடை காரணமாக நேரடி ஒளிபரப்பு நிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக பின்னர் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் மின் தடை ஏற்பட்டால் இரண்டு நிமிடங்களுக்குள் ஜெனரேட்டர்கள் தானாக இயங்குவது வழக்கம் எனவும், ஜனாதிபதி பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்யும் போது சுமார் பத்து நிமிடங்களுக்கு மின்சாரம் தடைப்பட்டதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதன் காரணமாக, தொலைக்காட்சி சேனல்கள் நேரடி ஒளிபரப்பு செய்ய முடியவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரகசிய போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயாதீன தொலைக்காட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் பத்து நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}