{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මාලදිවයින්-කතානායකගෙන්-නිවේදනයක්/101-616427",
  "time_ut": 1657809565,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මාලදිවයින් කතානායකගෙන් නිවේදනයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An announcement from the Maldives Speaker",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has resigned from his post, the speaker and former president of Maldives, Mohammad Nasheed, said in a tweet.",
        "He says that Sri Lanka can now move forward and that if the President was in Sri Lanka, he would not have resigned due to fear for his life.",
        "Mohammad Nasheed also says that he appreciates the thoughtful actions of the people of Maldives.",
        "My warm greetings to the people of Sri Lanka, according to his tweet."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammad Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mohammad Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාලදිවයින් කතානායකගෙන් නිවේදනයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වී ඇතැයි මාලදිවයිනේ කතානායක සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ් ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැන් ඉදිරියට යා හැකි බවත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටියා නම් ජීවිත බිය නිසා ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස් නොවනු ඇති බවත් හෙතෙම පවසයි.",
        "මාලදිවයිනේ ජනතාවගේ කල්පනාකාරී ක්‍රියා තමා අගය කරන බවත් මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ් කියයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට මගේ උණුසුම් සුබ පැතුම් පිරිනමන බව ඔහුගේ ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයේ දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாலைதீவு சபாநாயகரின் அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தனது பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளதாக சபாநாயகரும் மாலைதீவு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மொஹமட் நஷீட் டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை தற்போது முன்னோக்கி செல்ல முடியும் எனவும் ஜனாதிபதி இலங்கையில் இருந்திருந்தால் உயிருக்கு பயந்து பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்திருக்க மாட்டார் எனவும் அவர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "மாலத்தீவு மக்களின் சிந்தனைமிக்க செயல்களைப் பாராட்டுவதாகவும் முகமது நஷீத் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எனது அன்பான வணக்கங்கள் என அவர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முகமது நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}