{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-opposition-leader-vows-to-have-ex-mp-ranjan-ramanayake-back-in-parliament-99052/",
  "time_ut": 1661498760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka opposition leader vows to have ex-MP Ranjan Ramanayake back in parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka opposition leader vows to have ex-MP Ranjan Ramanayake back in parliament",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s main opposition the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) will reappoint former MP Ranjan Ramanayake, who is to be released from prison on a presidential pardon,  in the first instance a national list vacancy is available, SJB leader Sajith Premadasa said.",
        "Shortly after it was announced that President Ranil Wickremesinghe had signed a conditional pardon for Ramanayake, Premadasa tweeted Friday August 26 afternoon that he pledged to bring Ramanayake back into parliament’s fold.",
        "We the @sjbsrilanka wholeheartedly pledge to appoint @ramanayaker to the parliament in the first instance of an occurrence of a vacancy in the national list. pic.twitter.com/xz68cEidAp",
        "Ramanayake was serving a four-year rigorous imprisonment sentence over charges of contempt court when President Wickremesinghe, after lobbying from politicians, actors, and others, granted him a pardon on the condition that he would not make any remarks that will be deemed to be in contempt of the courts.",
        "Sri Lanka president signs conditional pardon for ex MP Ranjan Ramanayake",
        "Ramanayake has yet to comment on whether he is interested in getting back into parliament as an SJB MP.",
        "Two former SJB MPs — Harin Fernando and Manusha Nanayakkara – who pushed for the actor-turned politician’s pardon crossed over to to the government and have been alluding to more SJB parliamentarians joining the government or Wickremesinhe’s United National Party (UNP) to help the president steer the country through economic reforms.",
        "Sri Lanka is in the midst of its worst economic crisis since Independence, and Wickremesinghe has been calling for the formation of an all-party government since he was appointed President. (Colombo/Aug26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday August 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinhe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක යළි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට කැඳවන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ප්‍රතිඥා දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) ජනාධිපති සමාව මත බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වීමට නියමිත හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක යලි පත් කරනු ඇති බවත්, පළමු අවස්ථාවේදී ජාතික ලැයිස්තු පුරප්පාඩුවක් පවතින බව SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රාමනායක මහතාට කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් අත්සන් කර ඇති බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් ටික වේලාවකට පසු ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා පස්වරුවේ ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ රාමනායක නැවත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගෙන ඒමට තමා ප්‍රතිඥා දුන් බවයි.",
        "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇති වූ පළමු අවස්ථාවේදීම @රාමනායක මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කිරීමට @sjbsrilanka අපි මුළු හදවතින්ම ප්‍රතිඥා දෙමු. pic.twitter.com/xz68cEidAp",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත රාමනායක වසර හතරක බරපතල සිරදඬුවමක් විඳිමින් සිටියදී, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ, දේශපාලනඥයින්, නළු නිළියන් සහ වෙනත් අයගෙන් බලපෑම් කිරීමෙන් පසු ඔහුට සමාව ලබා දුන්නේ ඔහු තුළ යැයි සැලකෙන කිසිදු ප්‍රකාශයක් නොකිරීමේ කොන්දේසිය මත ය. අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම.",
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් අත්සන් කරයි",
        "SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස නැවත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීමට තමන් කැමතිද යන්න පිළිබඳව රාමනායක තවමත් අදහස් දක්වා නොමැත.",
        "නළුවෙකු බවට පත් වූ දේශපාලනඥයාගේ සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටි SJB හිටපු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ මනූෂ නානායක්කාර ආණ්ඩුවට ගොස් තවත් SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රජයට හෝ වික්‍රමසිංහගේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට (එජාප) එක්වන බවට ඉඟි කරමින් සිටී. ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හරහා රට.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මැදිව සිටින අතර වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් වූ දා සිට සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை மீண்டும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வரவுள்ளதாக இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) ஜனாதிபதியின் மன்னிப்பின் பேரில் சிறையில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்படும் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை மீண்டும் நியமிக்கும், முதற்கட்டமாக ஒரு தேசிய பட்டியல் வெற்றிடம் உள்ளது, SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பில் கையொப்பமிட்டுள்ளார் என்று அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட சிறிது நேரத்திலேயே, ஆகஸ்ட் 26 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் பிரேமதாச, ராமநாயக்கவை மீண்டும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு கொண்டுவருவதாக உறுதியளித்ததாக ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "@sjbsrilanka தேசியப் பட்டியலில் வெற்றிடமொன்று ஏற்பட்டால் முதல் தடவையாக @ராமநாயக்கரை நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்க உறுதிமொழி எடுப்போம். pic.twitter.com/xz68cEidAp",
        "நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் ராமநாயக்க நான்கு வருட கடூழிய சிறைத்தண்டனையை அனுபவித்துக்கொண்டிருந்தபோது, ​​ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, அரசியல்வாதிகள், நடிகர்கள் மற்றும் பிறரிடமிருந்து வற்புறுத்தலுக்குப் பிறகு, அவர் எந்தவொரு கருத்தையும் வெளியிடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனையுடன் மன்னிப்பு வழங்கினார். நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு.",
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளார்",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக மீண்டும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வருவதற்கு ஆர்வமாக உள்ளாரா என்பது குறித்து ராமநாயக்க இன்னும் கருத்து தெரிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "இரண்டு முன்னாள் SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார - நடிகராக மாறிய அரசியல்வாதியின் மன்னிப்பை அரசாங்கத்திடம் கடந்து, மேலும் SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அரசாங்கத்தில் அல்லது விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியில் (UNP) இணைந்து ஜனாதிபதியை வழிநடத்த உதவுவதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர். பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மூலம் நாடு.",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் உள்ளது, விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க அழைப்பு விடுத்து வருகிறார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}