{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/China-says-its-loans-projects-boosted-SLs-economy/108-242024",
  "time_ut": 1659081555,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China says its loans, projects boosted SL’s economy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China says its loans, projects boosted SL’s economy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China on Thursday defended its massive infrastructure ventures and investments in crisis-hit Sri Lanka and said that they have \"boosted\" its economic development, amid criticism from the US of Beijing's unproductive projects and opaque loan deals among the reasons for the country's bankruptcy.",
        "\"The China-Sri Lanka practical cooperation has always been led by Sri Lanka with scientific planning and thorough verification with no strings attached,\" Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Zhao Lijian told a media briefing here.",
        "\"Chinese projects have boosted Sri Lanka's economic development, and brought tangible benefits to the Sri Lankan people,\" he said while responding to a question on the criticism of China's projects and policies towards Sri Lanka by the USAID administrator Samantha Power.",
        "Speaking in New Delhi on Wednesday, Power said India reacted \"really swiftly\" with an absolutely critical set of measures to help Sri Lanka tide over its economic crisis, but calls to China to provide significant relief have gone unanswered.",
        "Power said China became one of Sri Lanka's \"biggest creditors\" offering often \"opaque loan\" deals at higher interest rates than other lenders and wondered whether Beijing would restructure the debt to help the island nation.",
        "Refuting her allegations, Zhao said \"there are multiple components to Sri Lanka's foreign debt, where China-related debts take far less share than the international capital market and multilateral development banks.\"",
        "\"Besides what China provides for Sri Lanka almost preferential loans with low-interest rates and long terms, which have played a positive part in improving Sri Lanka's infrastructure and livelihood,\" he said.",
        "China's unproductive projects in Sri Lanka, including the Hambantota port, which Beijing took over on a 99-year lease as a debt swap, has come under sharp criticism.",
        "The unprecedented economic crisis faced by Sri Lanka has led to severe shortages of fuel, cooking gas and medicine and long lines for essential supplies, which led to massive anti-government protests and the ouster of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa this month.",
        "China, which accounts for 10 per cent of Sri Lanka's debt, is reported to have resisted offering a debt cut.",
        "He also sought to blame the US policies including the interest rate hikes, unilateral sanctions and massive stimulus policies which had seriously impacted many developing countries like Sri Lanka.",
        "\"I want to stress that the global economic and financial markets have taken a heavy toll as the US's recent sudden interest rate hikes and balance sheet reduction has siphoned off dollars more rapidly, reverse from the long-running quantitative easing policy and irresponsible massive stimulus,\" he said.",
        "Without referring to the Russia-Ukraine war, Zhao also blamed the US sanctions.",
        "\"The US's unilateral sanctions and tariff barriers have undermined the security of industrial chains and have worsened the price surge of energy, food and other commodities. This has further aggravated the financial and economic situation of many developing countries,including Sri Lanka,\" he said.(The Economic Times)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The China-Sri Lanka",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Zhao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "he said.(The Economic Times",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනය පවසන්නේ තම ණය, ව්‍යාපෘති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය ඉහළ නැංවූ බවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සිය දැවැන්ත යටිතල පහසුකම් ව්‍යාපාර සහ ආයෝජන ආරක්ෂා කළ අතර, රට බංකොලොත් වීමට හේතු වන බීජිං හි ඵලදායි නොවන ව්‍යාපෘති සහ පාරාන්ධ ණය ගනුදෙනු පිළිබඳ එක්සත් ජනපදයේ විවේචන මධ්‍යයේ, ඔවුන් එහි ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය “උසස් කර” ඇති බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "\"චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රායෝගික සහයෝගීතාවය සෑම විටම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලැබුවේ විද්‍යාත්මක සැලසුම් සහ සම්පූර්ණ සත්‍යාපනයක් සමඟ කිසිදු සම්බන්ධයක් නොමැතිව,\" චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක ෂාඕ ලිජියන් මෙහි පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "\"චීන ව්‍යාපෘති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය ඉහළ නංවා ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට ප්‍රත්‍යක්ෂ ප්‍රතිලාභ ගෙන දී ඇත\" යනුවෙන් USAID පරිපාලක සමන්තා පවර් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනයේ ව්‍යාපෘති සහ ප්‍රතිපත්ති විවේචනය කිරීම පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "බදාදා නවදිල්ලියේ දී අදහස් දක්වමින් පවර් පැවසුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව අතිශය තීරණාත්මක ක්‍රියාමාර්ග මාලාවක් සමඟ “ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම වේගයෙන්” ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූ නමුත් සැලකිය යුතු සහනයක් ලබා දෙන ලෙස චීනයට කළ ඉල්ලීම්වලට පිළිතුරු නොලැබී ගොස් ඇති බවයි.",
        "අනෙකුත් ණය දෙන්නන්ට වඩා වැඩි පොලී අනුපාත යටතේ බොහෝ විට \"පාරා විනිවිද නොයන ණය\" ගනුදෙනු පිරිනමන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ \"විශාලතම ණය දෙන්නන්ගෙන්\" එකක් බවට චීනය පත් වූ බවත්, දිවයිනේ ජාතියට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා බීජිනය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරන්නේ දැයි කල්පනා කරන බවත් පවර් පැවසීය.",
        "ඇයගේ චෝදනා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමින් ෂාඕ පැවසුවේ \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ නය සඳහා බහුවිධ සංරචක ඇති අතර, චීනය ආශ්‍රිත ණය ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළඳපොළට සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවර්ධන බැංකුවලට වඩා බෙහෙවින් අඩු පංගුවක් ගනී.\"",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යටිතල පහසුකම් සහ ජීවනෝපාය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ධනාත්මක කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කර ඇති අඩු පොලී අනුපාත සහ දිගු කාලීන වරණීය ණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට චීනය සපයන දෙයට අමතරව,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නය හුවමාරුවක් ලෙස බීජිනය වසර 99ක බදු පදනම මත පවරා ගත් හම්බන්තොට වරාය ඇතුළු චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඵලදායී නොවන ව්‍යාපෘති දැඩි විවේචනයට ලක්ව ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී ඇති පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ඉන්ධන, ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සහ ඖෂධවල උග්‍ර හිඟයක් සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා දිගු පෝලිම් ඇති වූ අතර, එය දැවැන්ත රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී විරෝධතාවලට සහ මේ මාසයේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බලයෙන් පහ කිරීමට හේතු විය.",
        "ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණයවලින් සියයට 10කට හිමිකම් කියන චීනය, ණය කප්පාදුවක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට විරුද්ධ වී ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි බොහෝ සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවලට බරපතල ලෙස බලපා ඇති පොලී අනුපාත ඉහළ දැමීම්, ඒකපාර්ශ්වික සම්බාධක සහ දැවැන්ත උත්තේජක ප්‍රතිපත්ති ඇතුළු එක්සත් ජනපද ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට දොස් පැවරීමට ඔහු උත්සාහ කළේය.",
        "\"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මෑත කාලීන හදිසි පොලී අනුපාත ඉහල දැමීම් සහ ශේෂ පත්‍රය අඩු කිරීම නිසා, දිගු කාලීන ප්‍රමාණාත්මක ලිහිල් කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියෙන් සහ වගකීම් විරහිත දැවැන්ත උත්තේජකයෙන් ආපසු හැරවීම නිසා, ගෝලීය ආර්ථික හා මූල්‍ය වෙලඳපොලවල් විශාල හානියක් ගෙන ඇති බව මට අවධාරණය කිරීමට අවශ්‍යයි. \" ඔහු කිව්වා.",
        "රුසියානු-යුක්රේන යුද්ධය ගැන සඳහන් නොකර, ෂාඕ එක්සත් ජනපද සම්බාධකවලට ද දොස් පැවරීය.",
        "\"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඒකපාර්ශ්වික සම්බාධක සහ තීරුබදු බාධක කාර්මික දාමවල ආරක්ෂාව අඩාල කර ඇති අතර බලශක්ති, ආහාර සහ අනෙකුත් භාණ්ඩවල මිල ඉහළ යාම නරක අතට හැරී ඇත. මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු බොහෝ සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල මූල්‍ය හා ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් උග්‍ර කර ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. .(ද ඉකොනොමික් ටයිම්ස්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂාඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 99",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂාඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔහු පැවසීය.(ද ඉකොනොමික් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனது கடன்கள், திட்டங்கள் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை உயர்த்தியதாக சீனா கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வியாழனன்று சீனா தனது பாரிய உள்கட்டமைப்பு முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கையில் முதலீடுகளை பாதுகாத்ததுடன், பெய்ஜிங்கின் உற்பத்தியற்ற திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் ஒளிபுகா கடன் ஒப்பந்தங்கள் ஆகியவை நாட்டின் திவால்நிலைக்கான காரணங்களில் அமெரிக்காவின் விமர்சனங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், அதன் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை \"உயர்த்தியுள்ளன\" என்று கூறியது.",
        "சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் Zhao Lijian இங்கு நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில், “சீனா-இலங்கை நடைமுறை ஒத்துழைப்பு எப்போதும் விஞ்ஞான திட்டமிடல் மற்றும் முழுமையான சரிபார்ப்புடன் இலங்கையால் வழிநடத்தப்படுகிறது.",
        "\"சீன திட்டங்கள் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை உயர்த்தியதுடன், இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உறுதியான நன்மைகளையும் கொண்டு வந்துள்ளது,\" என USAID நிர்வாகி சமந்தா பவரின் இலங்கை தொடர்பான சீனாவின் திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் கொள்கைகள் மீதான விமர்சனம் குறித்த கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த போது அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதனன்று புது தில்லியில் பேசிய பவர், இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க உதவும் மிக முக்கியமான நடவடிக்கைகளுடன் இந்தியா \"உண்மையில் விரைவாக\" செயல்பட்டதாகவும், ஆனால் கணிசமான நிவாரணம் வழங்குமாறு சீனாவுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "மற்ற கடன் வழங்குபவர்களை விட அதிக வட்டி விகிதத்தில் அடிக்கடி \"ஒளிபுகா கடன்\" ஒப்பந்தங்களை வழங்கும் இலங்கையின் \"பெரிய கடன் வழங்குநர்களில்\" ஒன்றாக சீனா மாறியுள்ளது என்றும், தீவு தேசத்திற்கு உதவ பெய்ஜிங் கடனை மறுசீரமைக்குமா என்று ஆச்சரியப்படுவதாகவும் பவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவரது குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை மறுத்த ஜாவோ, \"இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனில் பல கூறுகள் உள்ளன, அங்கு சீனா தொடர்பான கடன்கள் சர்வதேச மூலதனச் சந்தை மற்றும் பலதரப்பு அபிவிருத்தி வங்கிகளை விட மிகக் குறைவான பங்கையே எடுத்துக் கொள்கின்றன\" என்றார்.",
        "\"சீனா இலங்கைக்கு குறைந்த வட்டி விகிதங்கள் மற்றும் நீண்ட கால கடன்களை வழங்குவதைத் தவிர, இலங்கையின் உள்கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதில் சாதகமான பங்கைக் கொண்டுள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பெய்ஜிங் 99 வருட குத்தகைக்கு கடனாகப் பெற்றுக் கொண்ட அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம் உட்பட இலங்கையில் சீனாவின் உற்பத்தியற்ற திட்டங்கள் கடுமையான விமர்சனத்திற்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியானது எரிபொருள், சமையல் எரிவாயு மற்றும் மருந்துகளின் கடுமையான தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்கான நீண்ட வரிசையில் வழிவகுத்தது, இது பாரிய அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களுக்கும் இந்த மாதம் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி நீக்கத்திற்கும் வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "இலங்கையின் கடனில் 10 வீதத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ள சீனா, கடனைக் குறைக்க முன்வருவதை எதிர்த்துள்ளதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை போன்ற பல வளரும் நாடுகளை கடுமையாக பாதித்த வட்டி விகித உயர்வு, ஒருதலைப்பட்ச தடைகள் மற்றும் பாரிய ஊக்கக் கொள்கைகள் உள்ளிட்ட அமெரிக்காவின் கொள்கைகளை அவர் குற்றம் சாட்ட முயன்றார்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்காவின் சமீபத்திய திடீர் வட்டி விகித உயர்வுகள் மற்றும் இருப்புநிலைக் குறைப்பு ஆகியவை, நீண்டகால அளவு தளர்த்தும் கொள்கை மற்றும் பொறுப்பற்ற பாரிய ஊக்கத்திலிருந்து தலைகீழாக டாலர்களை விரைவாகப் பறித்துள்ளதால், உலகப் பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் நிதிச் சந்தைகள் பெரும் பாதிப்பைச் சந்தித்துள்ளன என்பதை நான் வலியுறுத்த விரும்புகிறேன். \" அவன் சொன்னான்.",
        "ரஷ்யா-உக்ரைன் போரைக் குறிப்பிடாமல், ஜாவோ அமெரிக்கத் தடைகளையும் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்காவின் ஒருதலைப்பட்ச தடைகள் மற்றும் கட்டணத் தடைகள் தொழில்துறை சங்கிலிகளின் பாதுகாப்பைக் குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தியுள்ளன மற்றும் ஆற்றல், உணவு மற்றும் பிற பொருட்களின் விலை ஏற்றத்தை மோசமாக்கியுள்ளன. இது இலங்கை உட்பட பல வளரும் நாடுகளின் நிதி மற்றும் பொருளாதார நிலைமையை மேலும் மோசமாக்கியுள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். .(தி எகனாமிக் டைம்ஸ்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா-இலங்கை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USAID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாவோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாவோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவர் கூறினார்.(எகனாமிக் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}