{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131964",
  "time_ut": 1658403286,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Ranil Wickremesinghe resigned as Member of Parliament",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has today (21) submitted his letter of resignation as a Member of Parliament to the Secretary General of Parliament following his swearing in office today (21).",
        "The Parliamentary Secretary General has informed the National Elections Commission about the resignation letter.",
        "Accordingly, the Parliamentary Secretary General hereby informs the Parliamentary Secretary General under Section 64(5) of the Parliamentary Elections Act No. 01 of 1981, as amended by the Parliamentary Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 35 of 1988, that a vacancy has occurred in the membership of the Ninth Parliament in accordance with Article 66(e) of the Constitution. Officially announced to the Chairman of the National Elections Commission."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Section 64(5",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Elections Act No. 01 of 1981",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Elections (Special Provisions) Act No.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 of 1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 66(e",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Elections Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (21) දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා වෙත අද (21) භාරදී තිබේ.",
        "ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසමට දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව 1988 අංක 35 දරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත මගින් සංශෝධිත 1981 අංක 01 දරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනතේ 64(5) වගන්තිය යටතේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇති බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයාට මෙයින් දැනුම් දෙයි. ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 66 (ඊ) ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සාමාජිකත්වය ලබා ගැනීම ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයාට නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වගන්තිය 64(5",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 අංක 01 දරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත අංක.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988 35",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "66 වැනි වගන්තිය(ඉ",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (21) பதவி பிரமாணம் செய்ததை தொடர்ந்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யும் கடிதத்தை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகத்திடம் இன்று (21) கையளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பதவி விலகல் கடிதம் தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதற்கமைய பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் அரசியலமைப்பின் 66(இ) உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தில், உறுப்பாண்மையில் வெற்றிடமொன்று ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதால் 1988ஆம் ஆண்டின் 35 ஆம் இலக்க பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தினால் திருத்தப்பட்டவாறான 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 01ஆம் இலக்க பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்கள் சட்டத்தின் 64(5)ஆம் பிரிவின் கீழ் அறியத்தருகிறேன் என பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவருக்கு உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 64(5",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 01 ஆம் இலக்க பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம் எண்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988 இன் 35",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 66(எ",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}