{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Samsung-introduces-Big-Offer-Days-for-Galaxy-accessories/34-736665",
  "time_ut": 1656097289,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Samsung introduces ‘Big Offer Days’ for Galaxy accessories",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Samsung introduces ‘Big Offer Days’ for Galaxy accessories",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samsung, Sri Lanka’s No. 1 smartphone brand, recently unveiled their promotional prices for Galaxy accessories to alleviate the financial burdens of consumers in the midst of turbulent times.",
        "Samsung, as a caring brand for its people, has introduced up to 48% discounts in their promotional prices and hence relieves consumers of paying large sums for accessories to adorn their Galaxy devices. This promotional campaign introduces reduced prices for adapters, wearables, hearables, chargers, smart tags and headphones, all part of the Galaxy ecosystem, to allow consumers to experience the true brilliance of Samsung.",
        "“Samsung has always been a people brand and has always paid attention to the well-being of the consumer. In these trying times, it is important to help consumers in our own ways to help them alleviate the stress of inflation. We have introduced our promotional prices for Galaxy accessories to allow our consumers to integrate themselves into the Galaxy ecosystem without having to worry about the prices caused by inflation,” said Samsung Sri Lanka Managing Director Kevin SungSu YOU.",
        "Under this all-market promotional campaign, Samsung has reduced its Galaxy accessories of up to 48% of its market price. Items including Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters and Wireless Chargers are included under this campaign.",
        "The Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) has been discounted to Rs. 71,999 in a 42% discount rate. The Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) has been discounted to Rs. 104,999 in a 41% discount rate.",
        "Galaxy hearables have also seen large price reductions under this campaign. The Glaxy Buds 2 has been reduced to Rs. 47,999 at a discount rate of 23%, while the Galaxy Buds Live has been discounted to Rs. 35,999 at a rate of 48%. Meanwhile, the Galaxy Buds Pro has been discounted to Rs. 46,499 in a 48% discount rate. The Level U2 headphone is now available for a reduced price of Rs. 10,499 in a 42% discount rate.",
        "The Galaxy SmartTag (one pack) is now available for a reduced price of Rs. 5,999 in a 40% discount rate.",
        "Meanwhile, the Wireless Charger Due 2021 (without PA) is now available for a discounted price of Rs. 9,199, while the Wireless Charger Pad 2021 (Without PA) has been discounted to Rs. 5,599. The Wireless Charger Trio is available at a discounted price of Rs. 17,999. Meanwhile, the Wireless Charger Convertible has been discounted to Rs. 8,999.",
        "The car charger for Galaxy devices of 15 W and two ports has been discounted to Rs. 3,199. The Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) has been discounted to Rs. 3,389, while the adapter and cable have been reduced to Rs. 5,599.",
        "The UV Steriliser has been discounted to Rs. 9,999 while the Galaxy Z Fold3 Silicone Cover is now available for a discounted price of Rs. 10,499.",
        "Consumers in Sri Lanka can order their Galaxy accessories for a reduced price at island-wide authorised dealers of John Keells Office Automation and Softlogic Mobile Distribution which can be easily identified by the Samsung logo placed outside the shop.",
        "It is also available at authorised partners; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri and Damro, Network Partners Dialog and Mobitel, and via the online portals; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Samsung",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "smart tags",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kevin SungSu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Watch",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Travel Adapters and",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "71,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "104,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Glaxy Buds 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galaxy Buds Live",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galaxy Buds Pro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Galaxy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wireless Charger Trio",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wireless Charger Convertible",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Galaxy Travel Adapter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25W",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,389",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Steriliser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Office Automation and Softlogic Mobile Distribution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singer",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damro, Network Partners Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung EStore",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "samsungsrilanka.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Samsung Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා 'Big Offer Days' හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අංක 1 ස්මාර්ට්ෆෝන් සන්නාමය වන Samsung, නොසන්සුන්කාරී කාලවලදී පාරිභෝගිකයින්ගේ මූල්‍ය බර අඩු කර ගැනීම සඳහා Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රවර්ධන මිල ගණන් පසුගියදා එළිදක්වන ලදී.",
        "Samsung, එහි ජනතාව සඳහා සැලකිලිමත් සන්නාමයක් ලෙස, ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රවර්ධන මිල ගණන් වල 48% දක්වා වට්ටම් හඳුන්වා දී ඇති අතර එම නිසා පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ Galaxy උපාංග අලංකාර කිරීම සඳහා අමතර උපාංග සඳහා විශාල මුදලක් ගෙවීමෙන් නිදහස් වේ. මෙම ප්‍රවර්ධන ව්‍යාපාරය මගින් පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට Samsung හි සැබෑ දීප්තිය අත්විඳීමට ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා Galaxy පරිසර පද්ධතියේ සියලුම කොටස්, ඇඩැප්ටර, පැළඳිය හැකි, ශ්‍රවණය කළ හැකි, චාජර්, ස්මාර්ට් ටැග් සහ හෙඩ්ෆෝන් සඳහා අඩු මිලක් හඳුන්වා දෙයි.",
        "“Samsung සැමවිටම ජනතා සන්නාමයක් වන අතර පාරිභෝගිකයාගේ යහපැවැත්ම කෙරෙහි සැමවිටම අවධානය යොමු කර ඇත. මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී, උද්ධමනයේ ආතතිය සමනය කිරීමට පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට අපගේම ආකාරයෙන් උපකාර කිරීම වැදගත් වේ. උද්ධමනය නිසා ඇති වන මිල ගණන් ගැන කනස්සල්ලෙන් තොරව අපගේ පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට Galaxy පරිසර පද්ධතියට ඒකාබද්ධ වීමට ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා අපි Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා අපගේ ප්‍රවර්ධන මිල ගණන් හඳුන්වා දී ඇත,\" Samsung ශ්‍රී ලංකා කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ Kevin SungSu YOU පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම සියලු වෙළඳපල ප්‍රවර්ධන ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ, Samsung විසින් සිය Galaxy උපාංග වෙළඳපල මිලෙන් 48% දක්වා අඩු කර ඇත. Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters සහ Wireless Chargers ඇතුළු අයිතම මෙම ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) රු. 42% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 71,999. Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) රු. 41% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 104,999.",
        "Galaxy Hearables මෙම ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ විශාල මිල අඩු කිරීම් ද දැක ඇත. Glaxy Buds 2 රු. 47,999 23% ක වට්ටම් අනුපාතයක් යටතේ, Galaxy Buds Live රු. 48% ක අනුපාතයකින් 35,999. මේ අතර, Galaxy Buds Pro සඳහා රු. 46,499 48% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින්. Level U2 headphone දැන් රු. 42% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 10,499.",
        "Galaxy SmartTag (එක් පැක් එකක්) දැන් රු. 40% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 5,999.",
        "මේ අතර, Wireless Charger Due 2021 (PA නොමැතිව) දැන් රු. 9,199, Wireless Charger Pad 2021 (PA නොමැතිව) රු. 5,599 කි. Wireless Charger Trio එක වට්ටම් සහිත මිලකට රු. 17,999 කි. මේ අතර Wireless Charger Convertible රථය රු. 8,999 කි.",
        "15 W සහ වරායන් දෙකක Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා කාර් චාජරය රු. 3,199 කි. Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) රු. 3,389 ක් වන අතර, ඇඩප්ටරය සහ කේබල් රු. 5,599 කි.",
        "UV Steriliser එක රු. 9,999 ක් වන අතර Galaxy Z Fold3 සිලිකන් කවරය දැන් රු. 10,499 කි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට සාප්පුවෙන් පිටත තබා ඇති Samsung ලාංඡනය මගින් පහසුවෙන් හඳුනාගත හැකි John Keells Office Automation සහ Softlogic Mobile Distribution හි දීපව්‍යාප්ත බලයලත් අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් වෙත අඩු මිලට ඔවුන්ගේ Galaxy උපාංග ඇණවුම් කළ හැකිය.",
        "එය බලයලත් හවුල්කරුවන්ගෙන් ද ලබා ගත හැකිය; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri සහ Damro, Network Partners Dialog සහ Mobitel, සහ අන්තර්ජාල ද්වාර හරහා; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සැම්සුන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්මාර්ට් ටැග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙවින් සුංසු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Watch",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක ඇඩැප්ටර සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "71,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "104,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Glaxy Buds 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Buds Live",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Buds Pro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,499 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,199 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රැහැන් රහිත චාජර් ත්‍රිත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රැහැන් රහිත චාජරය පරිවර්තනය කළ හැකිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy සංචාරක ඇඩැප්ටරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25W",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,389",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විෂබීජ නාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් ඔෆිස් ඔටෝමේෂන් සහ සොෆ්ට්ලොජික් ජංගම දුරකථන බෙදා හැරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic සිල්ලර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගායකයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damro, Network Partners Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොබිටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung EStore",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "samsungsrilanka.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சாம்சங் கேலக்ஸி ஆக்சஸரிகளுக்கு ‘பிக் ஆஃபர் டேஸ்’ அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் நம்பர் 1 ஸ்மார்ட்போன் பிராண்டான Samsung, கொந்தளிப்பான காலங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் நுகர்வோரின் நிதிச் சுமைகளைத் தணிக்க Galaxy துணைக்கருவிகளுக்கான அவர்களின் விளம்பர விலைகளை அண்மையில் வெளியிட்டது.",
        "சாம்சங், அதன் மக்களுக்கான அக்கறையுள்ள பிராண்டாக, அவர்களின் விளம்பர விலைகளில் 48% வரை தள்ளுபடியை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது, எனவே வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் தங்கள் Galaxy சாதனங்களை அலங்கரிப்பதற்காக அதிக தொகையை ஆக்சஸரீஸ்களுக்குச் செலுத்துவதில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கிறது. இந்த விளம்பரப் பிரச்சாரமானது அடாப்டர்கள், அணியக்கூடியவை, கேட்கக்கூடியவை, சார்ஜர்கள், ஸ்மார்ட் டேக்குகள் மற்றும் ஹெட்ஃபோன்கள், கேலக்ஸி சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பின் அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளுக்கும் குறைக்கப்பட்ட விலைகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "\"சாம்சங் எப்போதும் ஒரு மக்கள் பிராண்டாக இருந்து வருகிறது மற்றும் நுகர்வோரின் நல்வாழ்வில் எப்போதும் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது. இந்த கடினமான காலங்களில், பணவீக்கத்தின் அழுத்தத்தைத் தணிக்க நுகர்வோருக்கு எங்கள் சொந்த வழிகளில் உதவுவது முக்கியம். பணவீக்கத்தால் ஏற்படும் விலைகளைப் பற்றி கவலைப்படாமல், எங்கள் நுகர்வோர் Galaxy சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பில் தங்களை ஒருங்கிணைக்க அனுமதிக்கும் வகையில் Galaxy துணைப் பொருட்களுக்கான எங்கள் விளம்பர விலைகளை நாங்கள் அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளோம்,” என்று Samsung Sri Lanka நிர்வாக இயக்குநர் Kevin SungSu YOU தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த அனைத்து சந்தை விளம்பர பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ், Samsung தனது Galaxy பாகங்கள் அதன் சந்தை விலையில் 48% வரை குறைத்துள்ளது. Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters மற்றும் Wireless Chargers உள்ளிட்ட பொருட்கள் இந்த பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) விலையில் ரூ. 42% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 71,999. Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) விலையில் ரூ. 41% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 104,999.",
        "இந்த பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ் Galaxy ஹியர்பபிள்களும் பெரிய விலைக் குறைப்புகளைக் கண்டுள்ளன. Glaxy Buds 2 ரூ. ஆக குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 47,999 23% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில், Galaxy Buds Live ரூ. 48% வீதத்தில் 35,999. இதற்கிடையில், Galaxy Buds Pro விலையில் ரூ. 48% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 46,499. Level U2 ஹெட்ஃபோன் இப்போது குறைந்த விலையில் ரூ. 42% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 10,499.",
        "Galaxy SmartTag (ஒரு பேக்) இப்போது குறைந்த விலையில் ரூ. 40% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 5,999.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் டூ 2021 (PA இல்லாமல்) இப்போது தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 9,199, வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் பேட் 2021 (பிஏ இல்லாமல்) ரூ. 5,599. வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் ட்ரையோ தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 17,999. இதற்கிடையில், வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் மாற்றத்தக்கது ரூ. 8,999.",
        "15 W மற்றும் இரண்டு போர்ட்கள் கொண்ட Galaxy சாதனங்களுக்கான கார் சார்ஜர் ரூ. 3,199. Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) ரூ. தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. 3,389, அடாப்டர் மற்றும் கேபிள் ரூ. 5,599.",
        "UV ஸ்டெரிலைசர் ரூ. 9,999 மற்றும் Galaxy Z Fold3 சிலிகான் கவர் இப்போது தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 10,499.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள நுகர்வோர்கள், ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் ஆபீஸ் ஆட்டோமேஷன் மற்றும் சாஃப்ட்லொஜிக் மொபைல் விநியோகத்தின் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட விநியோகஸ்தர்களிடம் குறைந்த விலையில் தங்கள் Galaxy துணைப் பொருட்களை ஆர்டர் செய்யலாம்.",
        "இது அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட கூட்டாளர்களிடமும் கிடைக்கிறது; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri மற்றும் Damro, Network Partners Dialog மற்றும் Mobitel மற்றும் ஆன்லைன் போர்ட்டல்கள் மூலம்; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சாம்சங்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்மார்ட் குறிச்சொற்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெவின் சுங்சு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி வாட்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயண அடாப்டர்கள் மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "71,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "104,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிளாக்ஸி பட்ஸ் 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி பட்ஸ் லைவ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Buds Pro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்மார்ட் டேக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் ட்ரையோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் மாற்றத்தக்கது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி டிராவல் அடாப்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25W",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,389",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டெர்லைசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Office Automation மற்றும் Softlogic Mobile Distribution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாஃப்ட்லாஜிக் சில்லறை விற்பனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாடகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damro, நெட்வொர்க் பார்ட்னர்கள் உரையாடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் எஸ்டோர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "samsungsrilanka.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Samsung introduces ‘Big Offer Days’ for Galaxy accessories",
  "body_lines": [
    "Samsung, Sri Lanka’s No. 1 smartphone brand, recently unveiled their promotional prices for Galaxy accessories to alleviate the financial burdens of consumers in the midst of turbulent times.",
    "Samsung, as a caring brand for its people, has introduced up to 48% discounts in their promotional prices and hence relieves consumers of paying large sums for accessories to adorn their Galaxy devices. This promotional campaign introduces reduced prices for adapters, wearables, hearables, chargers, smart tags and headphones, all part of the Galaxy ecosystem, to allow consumers to experience the true brilliance of Samsung.",
    "“Samsung has always been a people brand and has always paid attention to the well-being of the consumer. In these trying times, it is important to help consumers in our own ways to help them alleviate the stress of inflation. We have introduced our promotional prices for Galaxy accessories to allow our consumers to integrate themselves into the Galaxy ecosystem without having to worry about the prices caused by inflation,” said Samsung Sri Lanka Managing Director Kevin SungSu YOU.",
    "Under this all-market promotional campaign, Samsung has reduced its Galaxy accessories of up to 48% of its market price. Items including Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters and Wireless Chargers are included under this campaign.",
    "The Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) has been discounted to Rs. 71,999 in a 42% discount rate. The Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) has been discounted to Rs. 104,999 in a 41% discount rate.",
    "Galaxy hearables have also seen large price reductions under this campaign. The Glaxy Buds 2 has been reduced to Rs. 47,999 at a discount rate of 23%, while the Galaxy Buds Live has been discounted to Rs. 35,999 at a rate of 48%. Meanwhile, the Galaxy Buds Pro has been discounted to Rs. 46,499 in a 48% discount rate. The Level U2 headphone is now available for a reduced price of Rs. 10,499 in a 42% discount rate.",
    "The Galaxy SmartTag (one pack) is now available for a reduced price of Rs. 5,999 in a 40% discount rate.",
    "Meanwhile, the Wireless Charger Due 2021 (without PA) is now available for a discounted price of Rs. 9,199, while the Wireless Charger Pad 2021 (Without PA) has been discounted to Rs. 5,599. The Wireless Charger Trio is available at a discounted price of Rs. 17,999. Meanwhile, the Wireless Charger Convertible has been discounted to Rs. 8,999.",
    "The car charger for Galaxy devices of 15 W and two ports has been discounted to Rs. 3,199. The Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) has been discounted to Rs. 3,389, while the adapter and cable have been reduced to Rs. 5,599.",
    "The UV Steriliser has been discounted to Rs. 9,999 while the Galaxy Z Fold3 Silicone Cover is now available for a discounted price of Rs. 10,499.",
    "Consumers in Sri Lanka can order their Galaxy accessories for a reduced price at island-wide authorised dealers of John Keells Office Automation and Softlogic Mobile Distribution which can be easily identified by the Samsung logo placed outside the shop.",
    "It is also available at authorised partners; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri and Damro, Network Partners Dialog and Mobitel, and via the online portals; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Samsung introduces ‘Big Offer Days’ for Galaxy accessories",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samsung, Sri Lanka’s No. 1 smartphone brand, recently unveiled their promotional prices for Galaxy accessories to alleviate the financial burdens of consumers in the midst of turbulent times.",
        "Samsung, as a caring brand for its people, has introduced up to 48% discounts in their promotional prices and hence relieves consumers of paying large sums for accessories to adorn their Galaxy devices. This promotional campaign introduces reduced prices for adapters, wearables, hearables, chargers, smart tags and headphones, all part of the Galaxy ecosystem, to allow consumers to experience the true brilliance of Samsung.",
        "“Samsung has always been a people brand and has always paid attention to the well-being of the consumer. In these trying times, it is important to help consumers in our own ways to help them alleviate the stress of inflation. We have introduced our promotional prices for Galaxy accessories to allow our consumers to integrate themselves into the Galaxy ecosystem without having to worry about the prices caused by inflation,” said Samsung Sri Lanka Managing Director Kevin SungSu YOU.",
        "Under this all-market promotional campaign, Samsung has reduced its Galaxy accessories of up to 48% of its market price. Items including Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters and Wireless Chargers are included under this campaign.",
        "The Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) has been discounted to Rs. 71,999 in a 42% discount rate. The Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) has been discounted to Rs. 104,999 in a 41% discount rate.",
        "Galaxy hearables have also seen large price reductions under this campaign. The Glaxy Buds 2 has been reduced to Rs. 47,999 at a discount rate of 23%, while the Galaxy Buds Live has been discounted to Rs. 35,999 at a rate of 48%. Meanwhile, the Galaxy Buds Pro has been discounted to Rs. 46,499 in a 48% discount rate. The Level U2 headphone is now available for a reduced price of Rs. 10,499 in a 42% discount rate.",
        "The Galaxy SmartTag (one pack) is now available for a reduced price of Rs. 5,999 in a 40% discount rate.",
        "Meanwhile, the Wireless Charger Due 2021 (without PA) is now available for a discounted price of Rs. 9,199, while the Wireless Charger Pad 2021 (Without PA) has been discounted to Rs. 5,599. The Wireless Charger Trio is available at a discounted price of Rs. 17,999. Meanwhile, the Wireless Charger Convertible has been discounted to Rs. 8,999.",
        "The car charger for Galaxy devices of 15 W and two ports has been discounted to Rs. 3,199. The Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) has been discounted to Rs. 3,389, while the adapter and cable have been reduced to Rs. 5,599.",
        "The UV Steriliser has been discounted to Rs. 9,999 while the Galaxy Z Fold3 Silicone Cover is now available for a discounted price of Rs. 10,499.",
        "Consumers in Sri Lanka can order their Galaxy accessories for a reduced price at island-wide authorised dealers of John Keells Office Automation and Softlogic Mobile Distribution which can be easily identified by the Samsung logo placed outside the shop.",
        "It is also available at authorised partners; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri and Damro, Network Partners Dialog and Mobitel, and via the online portals; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Samsung",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "smart tags",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kevin SungSu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Watch",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Travel Adapters and",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "71,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "104,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Glaxy Buds 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galaxy Buds Live",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galaxy Buds Pro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Galaxy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wireless Charger Trio",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wireless Charger Convertible",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Galaxy Travel Adapter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25W",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,389",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Steriliser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,999",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Office Automation and Softlogic Mobile Distribution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic Retail",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singer",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damro, Network Partners Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung EStore",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "samsungsrilanka.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Samsung Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා 'Big Offer Days' හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අංක 1 ස්මාර්ට්ෆෝන් සන්නාමය වන Samsung, නොසන්සුන්කාරී කාලවලදී පාරිභෝගිකයින්ගේ මූල්‍ය බර අඩු කර ගැනීම සඳහා Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රවර්ධන මිල ගණන් පසුගියදා එළිදක්වන ලදී.",
        "Samsung, එහි ජනතාව සඳහා සැලකිලිමත් සන්නාමයක් ලෙස, ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රවර්ධන මිල ගණන් වල 48% දක්වා වට්ටම් හඳුන්වා දී ඇති අතර එම නිසා පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ Galaxy උපාංග අලංකාර කිරීම සඳහා අමතර උපාංග සඳහා විශාල මුදලක් ගෙවීමෙන් නිදහස් වේ. මෙම ප්‍රවර්ධන ව්‍යාපාරය මගින් පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට Samsung හි සැබෑ දීප්තිය අත්විඳීමට ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා Galaxy පරිසර පද්ධතියේ සියලුම කොටස්, ඇඩැප්ටර, පැළඳිය හැකි, ශ්‍රවණය කළ හැකි, චාජර්, ස්මාර්ට් ටැග් සහ හෙඩ්ෆෝන් සඳහා අඩු මිලක් හඳුන්වා දෙයි.",
        "“Samsung සැමවිටම ජනතා සන්නාමයක් වන අතර පාරිභෝගිකයාගේ යහපැවැත්ම කෙරෙහි සැමවිටම අවධානය යොමු කර ඇත. මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී, උද්ධමනයේ ආතතිය සමනය කිරීමට පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට අපගේම ආකාරයෙන් උපකාර කිරීම වැදගත් වේ. උද්ධමනය නිසා ඇති වන මිල ගණන් ගැන කනස්සල්ලෙන් තොරව අපගේ පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට Galaxy පරිසර පද්ධතියට ඒකාබද්ධ වීමට ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා අපි Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා අපගේ ප්‍රවර්ධන මිල ගණන් හඳුන්වා දී ඇත,\" Samsung ශ්‍රී ලංකා කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ Kevin SungSu YOU පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම සියලු වෙළඳපල ප්‍රවර්ධන ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ, Samsung විසින් සිය Galaxy උපාංග වෙළඳපල මිලෙන් 48% දක්වා අඩු කර ඇත. Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters සහ Wireless Chargers ඇතුළු අයිතම මෙම ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) රු. 42% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 71,999. Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) රු. 41% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 104,999.",
        "Galaxy Hearables මෙම ව්‍යාපාරය යටතේ විශාල මිල අඩු කිරීම් ද දැක ඇත. Glaxy Buds 2 රු. 47,999 23% ක වට්ටම් අනුපාතයක් යටතේ, Galaxy Buds Live රු. 48% ක අනුපාතයකින් 35,999. මේ අතර, Galaxy Buds Pro සඳහා රු. 46,499 48% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින්. Level U2 headphone දැන් රු. 42% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 10,499.",
        "Galaxy SmartTag (එක් පැක් එකක්) දැන් රු. 40% වට්ටම් අනුපාතයකින් 5,999.",
        "මේ අතර, Wireless Charger Due 2021 (PA නොමැතිව) දැන් රු. 9,199, Wireless Charger Pad 2021 (PA නොමැතිව) රු. 5,599 කි. Wireless Charger Trio එක වට්ටම් සහිත මිලකට රු. 17,999 කි. මේ අතර Wireless Charger Convertible රථය රු. 8,999 කි.",
        "15 W සහ වරායන් දෙකක Galaxy උපාංග සඳහා කාර් චාජරය රු. 3,199 කි. Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) රු. 3,389 ක් වන අතර, ඇඩප්ටරය සහ කේබල් රු. 5,599 කි.",
        "UV Steriliser එක රු. 9,999 ක් වන අතර Galaxy Z Fold3 සිලිකන් කවරය දැන් රු. 10,499 කි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට සාප්පුවෙන් පිටත තබා ඇති Samsung ලාංඡනය මගින් පහසුවෙන් හඳුනාගත හැකි John Keells Office Automation සහ Softlogic Mobile Distribution හි දීපව්‍යාප්ත බලයලත් අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් වෙත අඩු මිලට ඔවුන්ගේ Galaxy උපාංග ඇණවුම් කළ හැකිය.",
        "එය බලයලත් හවුල්කරුවන්ගෙන් ද ලබා ගත හැකිය; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri සහ Damro, Network Partners Dialog සහ Mobitel, සහ අන්තර්ජාල ද්වාර හරහා; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සැම්සුන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්මාර්ට් ටැග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙවින් සුංසු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Watch",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක ඇඩැප්ටර සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "71,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "104,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Glaxy Buds 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Buds Live",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy Buds Pro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,499 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galaxy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,199 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රැහැන් රහිත චාජර් ත්‍රිත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රැහැන් රහිත චාජරය පරිවර්තනය කළ හැකිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy සංචාරක ඇඩැප්ටරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25W",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,389",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,599 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විෂබීජ නාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,999 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,499 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් ඔෆිස් ඔටෝමේෂන් සහ සොෆ්ට්ලොජික් ජංගම දුරකථන බෙදා හැරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Softlogic සිල්ලර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගායකයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damro, Network Partners Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොබිටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung EStore",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "samsungsrilanka.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daraz.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சாம்சங் கேலக்ஸி ஆக்சஸரிகளுக்கு ‘பிக் ஆஃபர் டேஸ்’ அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் நம்பர் 1 ஸ்மார்ட்போன் பிராண்டான Samsung, கொந்தளிப்பான காலங்களுக்கு மத்தியில் நுகர்வோரின் நிதிச் சுமைகளைத் தணிக்க Galaxy துணைக்கருவிகளுக்கான அவர்களின் விளம்பர விலைகளை அண்மையில் வெளியிட்டது.",
        "சாம்சங், அதன் மக்களுக்கான அக்கறையுள்ள பிராண்டாக, அவர்களின் விளம்பர விலைகளில் 48% வரை தள்ளுபடியை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது, எனவே வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் தங்கள் Galaxy சாதனங்களை அலங்கரிப்பதற்காக அதிக தொகையை ஆக்சஸரீஸ்களுக்குச் செலுத்துவதில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கிறது. இந்த விளம்பரப் பிரச்சாரமானது அடாப்டர்கள், அணியக்கூடியவை, கேட்கக்கூடியவை, சார்ஜர்கள், ஸ்மார்ட் டேக்குகள் மற்றும் ஹெட்ஃபோன்கள், கேலக்ஸி சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பின் அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளுக்கும் குறைக்கப்பட்ட விலைகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "\"சாம்சங் எப்போதும் ஒரு மக்கள் பிராண்டாக இருந்து வருகிறது மற்றும் நுகர்வோரின் நல்வாழ்வில் எப்போதும் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது. இந்த கடினமான காலங்களில், பணவீக்கத்தின் அழுத்தத்தைத் தணிக்க நுகர்வோருக்கு எங்கள் சொந்த வழிகளில் உதவுவது முக்கியம். பணவீக்கத்தால் ஏற்படும் விலைகளைப் பற்றி கவலைப்படாமல், எங்கள் நுகர்வோர் Galaxy சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பில் தங்களை ஒருங்கிணைக்க அனுமதிக்கும் வகையில் Galaxy துணைப் பொருட்களுக்கான எங்கள் விளம்பர விலைகளை நாங்கள் அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளோம்,” என்று Samsung Sri Lanka நிர்வாக இயக்குநர் Kevin SungSu YOU தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த அனைத்து சந்தை விளம்பர பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ், Samsung தனது Galaxy பாகங்கள் அதன் சந்தை விலையில் 48% வரை குறைத்துள்ளது. Galaxy Watch, Galaxy Buds, Galaxy SmartTag, Travel Adapters மற்றும் Wireless Chargers உள்ளிட்ட பொருட்கள் இந்த பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "Galaxy Watch 4 (BT, 40 mm) விலையில் ரூ. 42% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 71,999. Galaxy Watch 4 Classic (BT, 46 mm) விலையில் ரூ. 41% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 104,999.",
        "இந்த பிரச்சாரத்தின் கீழ் Galaxy ஹியர்பபிள்களும் பெரிய விலைக் குறைப்புகளைக் கண்டுள்ளன. Glaxy Buds 2 ரூ. ஆக குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 47,999 23% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில், Galaxy Buds Live ரூ. 48% வீதத்தில் 35,999. இதற்கிடையில், Galaxy Buds Pro விலையில் ரூ. 48% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 46,499. Level U2 ஹெட்ஃபோன் இப்போது குறைந்த விலையில் ரூ. 42% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 10,499.",
        "Galaxy SmartTag (ஒரு பேக்) இப்போது குறைந்த விலையில் ரூ. 40% தள்ளுபடி விகிதத்தில் 5,999.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் டூ 2021 (PA இல்லாமல்) இப்போது தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 9,199, வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் பேட் 2021 (பிஏ இல்லாமல்) ரூ. 5,599. வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் ட்ரையோ தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 17,999. இதற்கிடையில், வயர்லெஸ் சார்ஜர் மாற்றத்தக்கது ரூ. 8,999.",
        "15 W மற்றும் இரண்டு போர்ட்கள் கொண்ட Galaxy சாதனங்களுக்கான கார் சார்ஜர் ரூ. 3,199. Galaxy Travel Adapter (25W) ரூ. தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. 3,389, அடாப்டர் மற்றும் கேபிள் ரூ. 5,599.",
        "UV ஸ்டெரிலைசர் ரூ. 9,999 மற்றும் Galaxy Z Fold3 சிலிகான் கவர் இப்போது தள்ளுபடி விலையில் ரூ. 10,499.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள நுகர்வோர்கள், ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் ஆபீஸ் ஆட்டோமேஷன் மற்றும் சாஃப்ட்லொஜிக் மொபைல் விநியோகத்தின் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட விநியோகஸ்தர்களிடம் குறைந்த விலையில் தங்கள் Galaxy துணைப் பொருட்களை ஆர்டர் செய்யலாம்.",
        "இது அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட கூட்டாளர்களிடமும் கிடைக்கிறது; Softlogic Retail, Singer, Singhagiri மற்றும் Damro, Network Partners Dialog மற்றும் Mobitel மற்றும் ஆன்லைன் போர்ட்டல்கள் மூலம்; Samsung EStore (samsungsrilanka.lk), MySoftlogic.lk, Daraz.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சாம்சங்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்மார்ட் குறிச்சொற்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங் இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெவின் சுங்சு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "48% வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேலக்ஸி வாட்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galaxy SmartTag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயண அடாப்டர்கள் மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
