{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/First-aerial-mapping-of-SL-petroleum-resources-to-be-presented-at-SEAPEX-confab/108-239788",
  "time_ut": 1656115108,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "First aerial mapping of SL petroleum resources to be presented at SEAPEX confab",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "First aerial mapping of SL petroleum resources to be presented at SEAPEX confab",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Hydrocarbon potential could create a multibillion dollar revenue stream for govt.",
        "Publicity created at upcoming SEAPEX in London could help SL attract new round of foreign investors",
        "Bell Geospace, the world leaders in gravity gradiometry, is gearing up to present the insights gathered from the first aerial mapping of petroleum resources in Sri Lanka at the prestigious South East Asia Petroleum Exploration Society (SEAPEX) Asia Pacific Conference in London.",
        "The mapping that as carried out in the fourth quarter of 2021 will be presented together with Wintermoon Geophysics on June 30.",
        "The mapping project was conducted in 2021 as part of a collaboration between Bell Geospace and the Government of Sri Lanka, with the aim to explore offshore oil and gas potential in the seas off the North and Northwest of the island.",
        "This entailed the acquisition, processing and interpretation of data from Airborne 3D Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG), Gravity Gradiometry, and Magnetic Surveys that were employed to gather data on hydrocarbon potential below the surfaces around the Cauvery Basin off the Northern peninsula and the Mannar Basin off the West coast.",
        "Data and interpretation from this survey has revealed new insights into the structure, tectonic history, and hydrocarbon potential of Sri Lanka’s Mannar Basin M1, M2, and the Cauvery Basin C1 blocks.",
        "With Sri Lanka outlaying US$ 6-7 billion annually to purchase fuel, and the domestic hydrocarbon potential estimated at several billion barrels of oil and 9 trillion cubic feet of gas, this is a potential multibillion-dollar revenue stream for the Government of Sri Lanka.",
        "Especially taking into consideration that Cairn India, which explored the Mannar M2 block, invested US$ 200 million in the region 10 years ago.",
        "Additionally, with Bell Geospace’s modern geophysical data and interpretation, the publicity created at a major Oil and Gas conference such as SEAPEX in London holds the potential for Sri Lanka to attract a new round of foreign investors bringing in US$ to the country.",
        "US-based Bell Geospace is the leading provider of high quality airborne Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG) data for the mining industry. This data is used to map geology and thus define the shape and scale of existing mineral deposits as well as highlight potential new areas of exploration.",
        "Wintermoon Geophysics is a premier consulting firm for integrated exploration applications of Gravity, Magnetics, GIS, and Remote Sensing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "First",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SEAPEX",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "multibillion dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South East Asia Petroleum Exploration Society",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific Conference",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the fourth quarter of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wintermoon Geophysics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Airborne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gravity Gradiometry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cauvery Basin",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mannar Basin",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "West coast",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar Basin M1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cauvery Basin C1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 6-7 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "several billion barrels",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 trillion cubic feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "multibillion-dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cairn India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar M2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the region",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oil and Gas",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ to",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wintermoon Geophysics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gravity",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magnetics",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SEAPEX confab හිදී ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සම්පත් පිළිබඳ පළමු ගුවන් සිතියම්ගත කිරීම",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය රජයට ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක ආදායම් මාර්ගයක් නිර්මාණය කළ හැකිය.",
        "එළඹෙන ලන්ඩනයේ SEAPEX හි ඇති කරන ලද ප්‍රචාරණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නව වටයේ විදේශීය ආයෝජකයින් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට උපකාරී වේ",
        "ලන්ඩනයේ පැවැත්වෙන කීර්තිමත් අග්නිදිග ආසියා පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ගවේෂණ සංගමයේ (SEAPEX) ආසියා ශාන්තිකර සමුළුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඛනිජ තෙල් සම්පත් පිළිබඳ ප්‍රථම ගුවන් සිතියම්කරණයෙන් රැස් කරගත් තීක්ෂ්ණ බුද්ධිය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ ග්‍රැඩියෝමිතිය පිළිබඳ ලෝක ප්‍රමුඛයා වන බෙල් භූ අභ්‍යවකාශය සූදානම් වේ.",
        "2021 සිව්වන කාර්තුවේ සිදු කරන ලද සිතියම්කරණය ජූනි 30 වෙනිදා Wintermoon Geophysics සමඟ ඉදිරිපත් කෙරේ.",
        "දිවයිනේ උතුරට සහ වයඹ දෙසින් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල අක්වෙරළ තෙල් හා ගෑස් විභවයන් ගවේෂණය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් බෙල් භූ අවකාශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අතර සහයෝගීතාවයේ කොටසක් ලෙස සිතියම්කරණ ව්‍යාපෘතිය 2021 දී පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "උතුරු අර්ධද්වීපයෙන් සහ මන්නාරමෙන් ඔබ්බෙන් වූ කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණිය ආශ්‍රිත පෘෂ්ඨවලට පහළින් හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය පිළිබඳ දත්ත රැස් කිරීම සඳහා යොදා ගන්නා ලද Airborne 3D Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG), Gravity Gradiometry සහ චුම්භක සමීක්ෂණ මගින් දත්ත ලබා ගැනීම, සැකසීම සහ අර්ථ නිරූපණය කිරීම මෙයට ඇතුළත් විය. බටහිර වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ද්‍රෝණිය.",
        "මෙම සමීක්ෂණයේ දත්ත සහ අර්ථ නිරූපණය මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණියේ M1, M2 සහ කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණියේ C1 කුට්ටිවල ව්‍යුහය, භූගෝලීය ඉතිහාසය සහ හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය පිළිබඳ නව අවබෝධයක් අනාවරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වාර්ෂිකව ඩොලර් බිලියන 6-7ක් වැය කරන අතර, දේශීය හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය තෙල් බැරල් බිලියන කිහිපයක් සහ ගෑස් ඝන අඩි ට්‍රිලියන 9ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති හෙයින්, මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක ආදායම් මාර්ගයකි. .",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම මන්නාරම M2 කොටස ගවේෂණය කළ Cairn India සමාගම මීට වසර 10කට පෙර එම කලාපය තුළ ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 200ක් ආයෝජනය කිරීම සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින්.",
        "මීට අමතරව, Bell Geospace හි නවීන භූ භෞතික දත්ත සහ අර්ථ නිරූපණය සමඟින්, ලන්ඩනයේ SEAPEX වැනි ප්‍රධාන තෙල් හා ගෑස් සම්මන්ත්‍රණයකදී ඇති කරන ලද ප්‍රචාරණය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇ.ඩො.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය පදනම් කරගත් Bell Geospace යනු පතල් කර්මාන්තය සඳහා උසස් තත්ත්වයේ වාතයේ පූර්ණ ආතති ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ ග්‍රැඩියෝමෙට්‍රි (FTG) දත්ත සපයන ප්‍රමුඛයා වේ. මෙම දත්ත භූ විද්‍යාව සිතියම්ගත කිරීමට භාවිතා කරන අතර එමගින් දැනට පවතින ඛනිජ නිධි වල හැඩය සහ පරිමාණය නිර්වචනය කිරීම මෙන්ම ගවේෂණ සිදු කළ හැකි නව ක්ෂේත්‍ර ඉස්මතු කරයි.",
        "Wintermoon Geophysics යනු ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ, චුම්බක, GIS සහ දුරස්ථ සංවේදයේ ඒකාබද්ධ ගවේෂණ යෙදුම් සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛ උපදේශන සමාගමකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පළමුවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සීපෙක්ස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනකි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු ඛනිජ තෙල් ගවේෂණ සංගමය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 සිව්වන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වින්ටර්මූන් භූ භෞතික විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන්ගත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ ග්‍රැඩියෝමිතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර වෙරළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණිය M1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණිය C1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 6-7",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැරල් බිලියන කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඝන අඩි ට්‍රිලියන 9 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනකි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙයාර්න් ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම M2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලාපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙල් සහ ගෑස්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇ.ඩො",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වින්ටර්මූන් භූ භෞතික විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චුම්බක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL பெட்ரோலிய வளங்களின் முதல் வான்வழி மேப்பிங் SEAPEX confab இல் வழங்கப்பட உள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹைட்ரோகார்பன் சாத்தியம் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பல பில்லியன் டாலர் வருவாயை உருவாக்கலாம்.",
        "லண்டனில் நடைபெறவிருக்கும் SEAPEX இல் உருவாக்கப்படும் விளம்பரம், புதிய சுற்று வெளிநாட்டு முதலீட்டாளர்களை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவும்",
        "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ், புவியீர்ப்பு கிரேடியோமெட்ரியில் உலகத் தலைவர்கள், இலங்கையின் பெட்ரோலிய வளங்களின் முதல் வான்வழி வரைபடத்திலிருந்து சேகரிக்கப்பட்ட நுண்ணறிவுகளை லண்டனில் உள்ள புகழ்பெற்ற தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய பெட்ரோலியம் ஆய்வுச் சங்கத்தின் (SEAPEX) ஆசிய பசிபிக் மாநாட்டில் முன்வைக்கத் தயாராகி வருகிறது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நான்காவது காலாண்டில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மேப்பிங் ஜூன் 30 அன்று Wintermoon Geophysics உடன் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ் மற்றும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, தீவின் வடக்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கில் உள்ள கடல்களில் கடல் எண்ணெய் மற்றும் எரிவாயு சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராயும் நோக்கத்துடன், மேப்பிங் திட்டம் 2021 இல் நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இது வான்வழி 3D ஃபுல் டென்சர் கிராவிட்டி கிரேடியோமெட்ரி (எஃப்டிஜி), கிராவிட்டி கிரேடியோமெட்ரி மற்றும் காந்த ஆய்வுகள் ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து தரவைப் பெறுதல், செயலாக்குதல் மற்றும் விளக்கமளித்தல் ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கியது. மேற்கு கடற்கரையில் உள்ள படுகை.",
        "இந்த ஆய்வின் தரவு மற்றும் விளக்கம் இலங்கையின் மன்னார் படுகை M1, M2 மற்றும் காவிரிப் படுகை C1 தொகுதிகளின் கட்டமைப்பு, டெக்டோனிக் வரலாறு மற்றும் ஹைட்ரோகார்பன் சாத்தியம் பற்றிய புதிய நுண்ணறிவுகளை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு இலங்கை வருடாந்தம் 6-7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை செலவிடுவதுடன், உள்நாட்டு ஹைட்ரோகார்பன் ஆற்றல் பல பில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள் எண்ணெய் மற்றும் 9 டிரில்லியன் கன அடி எரிவாயு என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், இது இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பல பில்லியன் டொலர் வருமானத்தை வழங்கக்கூடிய சாத்தியக்கூறுகளாகும். .",
        "குறிப்பாக மன்னார் எம்2 தொகுதியை ஆய்வு செய்த கெய்ர்ன் இந்தியா நிறுவனம் 10 வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இப்பகுதியில் 200 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை முதலீடு செய்தது.",
        "கூடுதலாக, பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸின் நவீன புவி இயற்பியல் தரவு மற்றும் விளக்கத்துடன், லண்டனில் நடந்த SEAPEX போன்ற ஒரு பெரிய எண்ணெய் மற்றும் எரிவாயு மாநாட்டில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட விளம்பரம், நாட்டிற்கு US$ ஐக் கொண்டுவரும் புதிய சுற்று வெளிநாட்டு முதலீட்டாளர்களை ஈர்க்கும் திறனைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்காவைத் தளமாகக் கொண்ட பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ், சுரங்கத் தொழிலுக்கான உயர்தர வான்வழி ஃபுல் டென்சர் கிராடியோமெட்ரி (எஃப்டிஜி) தரவை வழங்கும் முன்னணி நிறுவனமாகும். புவியியலை வரைபடமாக்க இந்தத் தரவு பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, இதனால் தற்போதுள்ள கனிம வைப்புகளின் வடிவம் மற்றும் அளவை வரையறுக்கவும் அத்துடன் புதிய ஆய்வுப் பகுதிகளை முன்னிலைப்படுத்தவும் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது.",
        "விண்டர்மூன் ஜியோபிசிக்ஸ் என்பது புவியீர்ப்பு, காந்தவியல், ஜிஐஎஸ் மற்றும் ரிமோட் சென்சிங் ஆகியவற்றின் ஒருங்கிணைந்த ஆய்வு பயன்பாடுகளுக்கான முதன்மையான ஆலோசனை நிறுவனமாகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "முதலில்",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீபெக்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பல பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய பெட்ரோலியம் ஆய்வு சங்கம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக் மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 இன் நான்காவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விண்டர்மூன் ஜியோபிசிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வான்வழி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிராவிட்டி கிரேடியோமெட்ரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிரிப் படுகை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் படுகை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்கரை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் படுகை M1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிரிப் படுகை C1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல பில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 டிரில்லியன் கன அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெய்ர்ன் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் எம்2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராந்தியம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எண்ணெய் மற்றும் எரிவாயு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர் வரை",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விண்டர்மூன் ஜியோபிசிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவியீர்ப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காந்தவியல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "First aerial mapping of SL petroleum resources to be presented at SEAPEX confab",
  "body_lines": [
    "Hydrocarbon potential could create a multibillion dollar revenue stream for govt.",
    "Publicity created at upcoming SEAPEX in London could help SL attract new round of foreign investors",
    "Bell Geospace, the world leaders in gravity gradiometry, is gearing up to present the insights gathered from the first aerial mapping of petroleum resources in Sri Lanka at the prestigious South East Asia Petroleum Exploration Society (SEAPEX) Asia Pacific Conference in London.",
    "The mapping that as carried out in the fourth quarter of 2021 will be presented together with Wintermoon Geophysics on June 30.",
    "The mapping project was conducted in 2021 as part of a collaboration between Bell Geospace and the Government of Sri Lanka, with the aim to explore offshore oil and gas potential in the seas off the North and Northwest of the island.",
    "This entailed the acquisition, processing and interpretation of data from Airborne 3D Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG), Gravity Gradiometry, and Magnetic Surveys that were employed to gather data on hydrocarbon potential below the surfaces around the Cauvery Basin off the Northern peninsula and the Mannar Basin off the West coast.",
    "Data and interpretation from this survey has revealed new insights into the structure, tectonic history, and hydrocarbon potential of Sri Lanka’s Mannar Basin M1, M2, and the Cauvery Basin C1 blocks.",
    "With Sri Lanka outlaying US$ 6-7 billion annually to purchase fuel, and the domestic hydrocarbon potential estimated at several billion barrels of oil and 9 trillion cubic feet of gas, this is a potential multibillion-dollar revenue stream for the Government of Sri Lanka.",
    "Especially taking into consideration that Cairn India, which explored the Mannar M2 block, invested US$ 200 million in the region 10 years ago.",
    "Additionally, with Bell Geospace’s modern geophysical data and interpretation, the publicity created at a major Oil and Gas conference such as SEAPEX in London holds the potential for Sri Lanka to attract a new round of foreign investors bringing in US$ to the country.",
    "US-based Bell Geospace is the leading provider of high quality airborne Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG) data for the mining industry. This data is used to map geology and thus define the shape and scale of existing mineral deposits as well as highlight potential new areas of exploration.",
    "Wintermoon Geophysics is a premier consulting firm for integrated exploration applications of Gravity, Magnetics, GIS, and Remote Sensing."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "First aerial mapping of SL petroleum resources to be presented at SEAPEX confab",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Hydrocarbon potential could create a multibillion dollar revenue stream for govt.",
        "Publicity created at upcoming SEAPEX in London could help SL attract new round of foreign investors",
        "Bell Geospace, the world leaders in gravity gradiometry, is gearing up to present the insights gathered from the first aerial mapping of petroleum resources in Sri Lanka at the prestigious South East Asia Petroleum Exploration Society (SEAPEX) Asia Pacific Conference in London.",
        "The mapping that as carried out in the fourth quarter of 2021 will be presented together with Wintermoon Geophysics on June 30.",
        "The mapping project was conducted in 2021 as part of a collaboration between Bell Geospace and the Government of Sri Lanka, with the aim to explore offshore oil and gas potential in the seas off the North and Northwest of the island.",
        "This entailed the acquisition, processing and interpretation of data from Airborne 3D Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG), Gravity Gradiometry, and Magnetic Surveys that were employed to gather data on hydrocarbon potential below the surfaces around the Cauvery Basin off the Northern peninsula and the Mannar Basin off the West coast.",
        "Data and interpretation from this survey has revealed new insights into the structure, tectonic history, and hydrocarbon potential of Sri Lanka’s Mannar Basin M1, M2, and the Cauvery Basin C1 blocks.",
        "With Sri Lanka outlaying US$ 6-7 billion annually to purchase fuel, and the domestic hydrocarbon potential estimated at several billion barrels of oil and 9 trillion cubic feet of gas, this is a potential multibillion-dollar revenue stream for the Government of Sri Lanka.",
        "Especially taking into consideration that Cairn India, which explored the Mannar M2 block, invested US$ 200 million in the region 10 years ago.",
        "Additionally, with Bell Geospace’s modern geophysical data and interpretation, the publicity created at a major Oil and Gas conference such as SEAPEX in London holds the potential for Sri Lanka to attract a new round of foreign investors bringing in US$ to the country.",
        "US-based Bell Geospace is the leading provider of high quality airborne Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG) data for the mining industry. This data is used to map geology and thus define the shape and scale of existing mineral deposits as well as highlight potential new areas of exploration.",
        "Wintermoon Geophysics is a premier consulting firm for integrated exploration applications of Gravity, Magnetics, GIS, and Remote Sensing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "First",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SEAPEX",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "multibillion dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South East Asia Petroleum Exploration Society",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific Conference",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the fourth quarter of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wintermoon Geophysics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Airborne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gravity Gradiometry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cauvery Basin",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mannar Basin",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "West coast",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar Basin M1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cauvery Basin C1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 6-7 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "several billion barrels",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 trillion cubic feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "multibillion-dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cairn India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar M2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the region",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oil and Gas",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ to",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bell Geospace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wintermoon Geophysics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gravity",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magnetics",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SEAPEX confab හිදී ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සම්පත් පිළිබඳ පළමු ගුවන් සිතියම්ගත කිරීම",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය රජයට ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක ආදායම් මාර්ගයක් නිර්මාණය කළ හැකිය.",
        "එළඹෙන ලන්ඩනයේ SEAPEX හි ඇති කරන ලද ප්‍රචාරණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නව වටයේ විදේශීය ආයෝජකයින් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට උපකාරී වේ",
        "ලන්ඩනයේ පැවැත්වෙන කීර්තිමත් අග්නිදිග ආසියා පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ගවේෂණ සංගමයේ (SEAPEX) ආසියා ශාන්තිකර සමුළුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඛනිජ තෙල් සම්පත් පිළිබඳ ප්‍රථම ගුවන් සිතියම්කරණයෙන් රැස් කරගත් තීක්ෂ්ණ බුද්ධිය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ ග්‍රැඩියෝමිතිය පිළිබඳ ලෝක ප්‍රමුඛයා වන බෙල් භූ අභ්‍යවකාශය සූදානම් වේ.",
        "2021 සිව්වන කාර්තුවේ සිදු කරන ලද සිතියම්කරණය ජූනි 30 වෙනිදා Wintermoon Geophysics සමඟ ඉදිරිපත් කෙරේ.",
        "දිවයිනේ උතුරට සහ වයඹ දෙසින් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල අක්වෙරළ තෙල් හා ගෑස් විභවයන් ගවේෂණය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් බෙල් භූ අවකාශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අතර සහයෝගීතාවයේ කොටසක් ලෙස සිතියම්කරණ ව්‍යාපෘතිය 2021 දී පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "උතුරු අර්ධද්වීපයෙන් සහ මන්නාරමෙන් ඔබ්බෙන් වූ කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණිය ආශ්‍රිත පෘෂ්ඨවලට පහළින් හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය පිළිබඳ දත්ත රැස් කිරීම සඳහා යොදා ගන්නා ලද Airborne 3D Full Tensor Gravity Gradiometry (FTG), Gravity Gradiometry සහ චුම්භක සමීක්ෂණ මගින් දත්ත ලබා ගැනීම, සැකසීම සහ අර්ථ නිරූපණය කිරීම මෙයට ඇතුළත් විය. බටහිර වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ද්‍රෝණිය.",
        "මෙම සමීක්ෂණයේ දත්ත සහ අර්ථ නිරූපණය මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණියේ M1, M2 සහ කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණියේ C1 කුට්ටිවල ව්‍යුහය, භූගෝලීය ඉතිහාසය සහ හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය පිළිබඳ නව අවබෝධයක් අනාවරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වාර්ෂිකව ඩොලර් බිලියන 6-7ක් වැය කරන අතර, දේශීය හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන් විභවය තෙල් බැරල් බිලියන කිහිපයක් සහ ගෑස් ඝන අඩි ට්‍රිලියන 9ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති හෙයින්, මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක ආදායම් මාර්ගයකි. .",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම මන්නාරම M2 කොටස ගවේෂණය කළ Cairn India සමාගම මීට වසර 10කට පෙර එම කලාපය තුළ ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 200ක් ආයෝජනය කිරීම සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින්.",
        "මීට අමතරව, Bell Geospace හි නවීන භූ භෞතික දත්ත සහ අර්ථ නිරූපණය සමඟින්, ලන්ඩනයේ SEAPEX වැනි ප්‍රධාන තෙල් හා ගෑස් සම්මන්ත්‍රණයකදී ඇති කරන ලද ප්‍රචාරණය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇ.ඩො.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය පදනම් කරගත් Bell Geospace යනු පතල් කර්මාන්තය සඳහා උසස් තත්ත්වයේ වාතයේ පූර්ණ ආතති ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ ග්‍රැඩියෝමෙට්‍රි (FTG) දත්ත සපයන ප්‍රමුඛයා වේ. මෙම දත්ත භූ විද්‍යාව සිතියම්ගත කිරීමට භාවිතා කරන අතර එමගින් දැනට පවතින ඛනිජ නිධි වල හැඩය සහ පරිමාණය නිර්වචනය කිරීම මෙන්ම ගවේෂණ සිදු කළ හැකි නව ක්ෂේත්‍ර ඉස්මතු කරයි.",
        "Wintermoon Geophysics යනු ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ, චුම්බක, GIS සහ දුරස්ථ සංවේදයේ ඒකාබද්ධ ගවේෂණ යෙදුම් සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛ උපදේශන සමාගමකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පළමුවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සීපෙක්ස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනකි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු ඛනිජ තෙල් ගවේෂණ සංගමය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 සිව්වන කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වින්ටර්මූන් භූ භෞතික විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන්ගත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණ ග්‍රැඩියෝමිතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර වෙරළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම් ද්‍රෝණිය M1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවේරි ද්‍රෝණිය C1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 6-7",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැරල් බිලියන කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඝන අඩි ට්‍රිලියන 9 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනකි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙයාර්න් ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම M2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලාපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙල් සහ ගෑස්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇ.ඩො",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල් භූ අවකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වින්ටර්මූන් භූ භෞතික විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චුම්බක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL பெட்ரோலிய வளங்களின் முதல் வான்வழி மேப்பிங் SEAPEX confab இல் வழங்கப்பட உள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹைட்ரோகார்பன் சாத்தியம் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பல பில்லியன் டாலர் வருவாயை உருவாக்கலாம்.",
        "லண்டனில் நடைபெறவிருக்கும் SEAPEX இல் உருவாக்கப்படும் விளம்பரம், புதிய சுற்று வெளிநாட்டு முதலீட்டாளர்களை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவும்",
        "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ், புவியீர்ப்பு கிரேடியோமெட்ரியில் உலகத் தலைவர்கள், இலங்கையின் பெட்ரோலிய வளங்களின் முதல் வான்வழி வரைபடத்திலிருந்து சேகரிக்கப்பட்ட நுண்ணறிவுகளை லண்டனில் உள்ள புகழ்பெற்ற தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய பெட்ரோலியம் ஆய்வுச் சங்கத்தின் (SEAPEX) ஆசிய பசிபிக் மாநாட்டில் முன்வைக்கத் தயாராகி வருகிறது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நான்காவது காலாண்டில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மேப்பிங் ஜூன் 30 அன்று Wintermoon Geophysics உடன் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ் மற்றும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, தீவின் வடக்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கில் உள்ள கடல்களில் கடல் எண்ணெய் மற்றும் எரிவாயு சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராயும் நோக்கத்துடன், மேப்பிங் திட்டம் 2021 இல் நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இது வான்வழி 3D ஃபுல் டென்சர் கிராவிட்டி கிரேடியோமெட்ரி (எஃப்டிஜி), கிராவிட்டி கிரேடியோமெட்ரி மற்றும் காந்த ஆய்வுகள் ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து தரவைப் பெறுதல், செயலாக்குதல் மற்றும் விளக்கமளித்தல் ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கியது. மேற்கு கடற்கரையில் உள்ள படுகை.",
        "இந்த ஆய்வின் தரவு மற்றும் விளக்கம் இலங்கையின் மன்னார் படுகை M1, M2 மற்றும் காவிரிப் படுகை C1 தொகுதிகளின் கட்டமைப்பு, டெக்டோனிக் வரலாறு மற்றும் ஹைட்ரோகார்பன் சாத்தியம் பற்றிய புதிய நுண்ணறிவுகளை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு இலங்கை வருடாந்தம் 6-7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை செலவிடுவதுடன், உள்நாட்டு ஹைட்ரோகார்பன் ஆற்றல் பல பில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள் எண்ணெய் மற்றும் 9 டிரில்லியன் கன அடி எரிவாயு என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், இது இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பல பில்லியன் டொலர் வருமானத்தை வழங்கக்கூடிய சாத்தியக்கூறுகளாகும். .",
        "குறிப்பாக மன்னார் எம்2 தொகுதியை ஆய்வு செய்த கெய்ர்ன் இந்தியா நிறுவனம் 10 வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இப்பகுதியில் 200 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை முதலீடு செய்தது.",
        "கூடுதலாக, பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸின் நவீன புவி இயற்பியல் தரவு மற்றும் விளக்கத்துடன், லண்டனில் நடந்த SEAPEX போன்ற ஒரு பெரிய எண்ணெய் மற்றும் எரிவாயு மாநாட்டில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட விளம்பரம், நாட்டிற்கு US$ ஐக் கொண்டுவரும் புதிய சுற்று வெளிநாட்டு முதலீட்டாளர்களை ஈர்க்கும் திறனைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்காவைத் தளமாகக் கொண்ட பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ், சுரங்கத் தொழிலுக்கான உயர்தர வான்வழி ஃபுல் டென்சர் கிராடியோமெட்ரி (எஃப்டிஜி) தரவை வழங்கும் முன்னணி நிறுவனமாகும். புவியியலை வரைபடமாக்க இந்தத் தரவு பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, இதனால் தற்போதுள்ள கனிம வைப்புகளின் வடிவம் மற்றும் அளவை வரையறுக்கவும் அத்துடன் புதிய ஆய்வுப் பகுதிகளை முன்னிலைப்படுத்தவும் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது.",
        "விண்டர்மூன் ஜியோபிசிக்ஸ் என்பது புவியீர்ப்பு, காந்தவியல், ஜிஐஎஸ் மற்றும் ரிமோட் சென்சிங் ஆகியவற்றின் ஒருங்கிணைந்த ஆய்வு பயன்பாடுகளுக்கான முதன்மையான ஆலோசனை நிறுவனமாகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "முதலில்",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீபெக்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பல பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய பெட்ரோலியம் ஆய்வு சங்கம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக் மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 இன் நான்காவது காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விண்டர்மூன் ஜியோபிசிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல் ஜியோஸ்பேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வான்வழி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FTG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிராவிட்டி கிரேடியோமெட்ரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிரிப் படுகை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் படுகை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்கரை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் படுகை M1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M2",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிரிப் படுகை C1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
