{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83758/live-parliamentary-vote-to-elect-new-president",
  "time_ut": 1658290920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "LIVE: Parliamentary vote to elect new President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "LIVE: Parliamentary vote to elect new President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The parliament is meeting at 10.00 a.m. today (July 20) to elect a new Head of State in a three-way contest.",
        "Accordingly, Acting President and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, SLPP MP Dullas Alahapperuma and NPP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake, whose names were proposed yesterday when the nominations were called in the parliament, will face off in the vote.",
        "Meanwhile, Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena has sought the support of all parties to make the parliamentary vote to appoint a successor president, a success.",
        "He made these remarks at the Committee on Parliamentary Business yesterday (19).",
        "The Speaker added that he expects the support of all parties to successfully complete the election to be held today (20) in accordance with the relevant rules. He urged them to respect democracy and to help successfully conduct the process of selecting the successor president within the relevant legal framework.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena has also advised not to bring mobile phones into the House when the election is in progress.",
        "Secretary-General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake, who is the Returning Officer of the secret ballot today, said that before the commencement of the poll, all necessary guidelines will be informed to the Members of Parliament as per the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981.",
        "It was also decided that the Parliament will meet on the 27th Wednesday, and to submit the emergency proclamation announced by the Acting President under the Public Security Act for approval on that day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Security Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජීවීව: නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද (ජූලි 20) පෙරවරු 10.00 ට රැස්වේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී නාමයෝජනා කැදවූ අවස්ථාවේදී නම් යෝජනා වූ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ එන්පීපී නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මේ අතර, අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීම සඳහා වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීම සාර්ථක කර ගැනීම සඳහා කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා සියලු පක්ෂවල සහය ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "ඔහු මේ අදහස් පළ කළේ ඊයේ (19) පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේදීය.",
        "අදාළ නීතිරීතිවලට අනුව අද (20) පැවැත්වෙන මැතිවරණය සාර්ථකව නිම කිරීමට සියලු පක්ෂවල සහයෝගය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කථානායකවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට ගරු කරන ලෙසත්, අදාළ නීති රාමුව තුළ අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සාර්ථකව සිදු කිරීමට උදව් කරන ලෙසත් ඔහු ඔවුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මැතිවරණය පැවැත්වෙන විට ජංගම දුරකථන සභාව තුළට ගෙන ඒමෙන් වළකින ලෙස කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ද උපදෙස් දී තිබේ.",
        "අද රහස් ඡන්දයේ තේරීම් භාර නිලධාරී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක කියා සිටියේ ඡන්ද විමසීම ආරම්භ කිරීමට පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතට අනුව අවශ්‍ය සියලු මාර්ගෝපදේශ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වෙත දැනුම් දෙන බවයි. 1981 2.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ලබන 27 වැනි බදාදා රැස් වීමටත්, මහජන ආරක්‍ෂක පනත යටතේ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ හදිසි ප්‍රකාශය එදින අනුමැතිය සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමටත් මෙහිදී තීරණය විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන ආරක්ෂක පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நேரலை: புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மும்முனைப் போட்டியில் புதிய அரச தலைவரைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்காக இன்று (ஜூலை 20) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு நாடாளுமன்றம் கூடுகிறது.",
        "இதன்படி, நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வேட்புமனு கோரப்பட்ட போது, ​​அவர்களின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் NPP தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் வாக்கெடுப்பில் எதிர்கொள்கின்றனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, வாரிசான ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பை வெற்றியடையச் செய்வதற்கு அனைத்து கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவையும் கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று (19) பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழு கூட்டத்தில் அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உரிய விதிமுறைகளுக்கு அமைய இன்று (20) நடைபெறவுள்ள தேர்தலை வெற்றிகரமாக நிறைவு செய்வதற்கு அனைத்து கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவையும் எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு மதிப்பளித்து, உரிய சட்ட கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் வாரிசு ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் செயல்முறையை வெற்றிகரமாக நடத்த உதவுமாறு அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "தேர்தல் நடைபெறும் போது கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகளை சபைக்குள் கொண்டு வர வேண்டாம் எனவும் சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம், வாக்கெடுப்பு ஆரம்பிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர், தேவையான அனைத்து வழிகாட்டுதல்களும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு அறிவிக்கப்படும் என இன்று இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பின் தேர்தல் அதிகாரியான பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார். 2. 1981.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை கூடவுள்ளதாகவும், அன்றைய தினம் பொது பாதுகாப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியினால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட அவசரகால பிரகடனத்தை ஒப்புதலுக்காக சமர்ப்பிக்கவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பாதுகாப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}