{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/210-km-Integrated-Roads-Project-sees-steady-progress-under-Access-Engineering/34-737155",
  "time_ut": 1657149788,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "210 km Integrated Roads Project sees steady progress under Access Engineering",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "210 km Integrated Roads Project sees steady progress under Access Engineering",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Access Engineering PLC (AEL), Sri Lanka’s premier construction enterprise is eyeing the completion of the 210 km Integrated Roads (i-roads) Project in the Gampaha District of the Western Province by early 2023.",
        "The project initiated by the Road Development Authority (RDA), aims to provide the much needed accessibility required by communities in the rural areas of the district.",
        "Enriching Sri Lankan lives, AEL, who has engaged in the development of roads in many rural areas in the past, serve as the main contractor for the rehabilitation, improvements and maintenance of these roads.",
        "Having begun work on the project back in April 2020, AEL has faced a number of challenges hindering the smooth progression of the project, mainly due to the COVID-19 pandemic back in 2020 and 2021 and the current economic crisis being experienced have caused disruptions sporadically.",
        "However, AEL, the foremost civil engineering enterprise in the island is continuing to pull through to make good on its promise of ‘Engineering tomorrow’s heritage, today’.",
        "The project, funded by the Asian Development Bank (ADB) also stands to bring in much needed foreign currency to Sri Lanka and the project will eliminate issues pertaining to poor transport infrastructure and will provide rural citizens with improved connectivity to socio-economic centres, uplifting their lives.",
        "The project which falls under the Second Integrated Road Investment Program of the RDA is earmarked for completion by February 2023."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "210",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Integrated Roads Project",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Access Engineering PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "210",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "early 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Road Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Asian Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Second Integrated Road Investment Program of the RDA",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "210 km ඒකාබද්ධ මාර්ග ව්‍යාපෘතිය ප්‍රවේශ ඉංජිනේරු යටතේ ස්ථාවර ප්‍රගතියක් දකියි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම ඉදිකිරීම් ව්‍යවසාය වන Access Engineering PLC (AEL) බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ කිලෝමීටර් 210 ක ඒකාබද්ධ මාර්ග (i-මාර්ග) ව්‍යාපෘතිය 2023 මුල් භාගය වන විට නිම කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "මාර්ග සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය (RDA) විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලද මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රදේශවල ප්‍රජාවන්ට අවශ්‍ය වන ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාවය ලබා දීම අරමුණු කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජන ජීවිතය සරු කරමින්, අතීතයේ ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රදේශ රැසක මාර්ග සංවර්ධන කටයුතුවල නිරත වූ AEL සමාගම මෙම මාර්ග ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය, වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම් සහ නඩත්තු කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන කොන්ත්‍රාත්කරු ලෙස කටයුතු කරයි.",
        "2020 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ව්‍යාපෘතියේ වැඩ ආරම්භ කර ඇති AEL විසින් ව්‍යාපෘතියේ සුමට ප්‍රගතියට බාධා කරන අභියෝග රැසකට මුහුණ දී ඇත, ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් 2020 සහ 2021 දී COVID-19 වසංගතය සහ වර්තමාන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය අත්විඳින විට කඩාකප්පල් වීමට හේතු විය. .",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, දිවයිනේ ප්‍රමුඛතම සිවිල් ඉංජිනේරු ව්‍යවසාය වන AEL, 'ඉංජිනේරු හෙට උරුමය, අද' යන පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කර ගැනීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව ඉදිරියට යමින් සිටී.",
        "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව (ADB) විසින් අරමුදල් සපයනු ලබන මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය විදේශ මුදල් ප්‍රමාණයක් ගෙන ඒමට ද හැකි වන අතර මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය මගින් දුර්වල ප්‍රවාහන යටිතල පහසුකම් සම්බන්ධ ගැටළු ඉවත් කර ග්‍රාමීය පුරවැසියන්ට සමාජ-ආර්ථික මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත වැඩිදියුණු කළ සම්බන්ධතාවක් ලබා දෙනු ඇත. ඔවුන්ගේ ජිවිත.",
        "RDA හි දෙවන ඒකාබද්ධ මාර්ග ආයෝජන වැඩසටහන යටතේ වන ව්‍යාපෘතිය 2023 පෙබරවාරි වන විට නිම කිරීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "210",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඒකාබද්ධ මාර්ග ව්‍යාපෘතිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Access Engineering PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "210",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්ග සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RDA හි දෙවන ඒකාබද්ධ මාර්ග ආයෝජන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "210 கிமீ ஒருங்கிணைந்த சாலைகள் திட்டம் அணுகல் பொறியியலின் கீழ் நிலையான முன்னேற்றத்தைக் காண்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முதன்மையான கட்டுமான நிறுவனமான Access Engineering PLC (AEL), மேற்கு மாகாணத்தின் கம்பஹா மாவட்டத்தில் 210 கிமீ ஒருங்கிணைந்த சாலைகள் (i-roads) திட்டத்தை 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் நிறைவு செய்வதைக் கண்காணித்து வருகிறது.",
        "வீதி அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபையால் (RDA) ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட திட்டம், மாவட்டத்தின் கிராமப்புறங்களில் உள்ள சமூகங்களுக்குத் தேவையான மிகவும் தேவையான அணுகலை வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் வாழ்வை வளப்படுத்துவதுடன், கடந்த காலங்களில் பல கிராமப்புறங்களில் வீதிகளை அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள AEL, இந்த வீதிகளின் புனரமைப்பு, மேம்பாடு மற்றும் பராமரிப்புக்கான பிரதான ஒப்பந்ததாரராக செயற்படுகிறது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 2020 இல் திட்டப்பணியைத் தொடங்கிய AEL, திட்டத்தின் சுமூகமான முன்னேற்றத்தைத் தடுக்கும் பல சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டது, முக்கியமாக 2020 மற்றும் 2021 இல் மீண்டும் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் மற்றும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக அவ்வப்போது இடையூறுகளை ஏற்படுத்தியது. .",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தீவின் முதன்மையான சிவில் இன்ஜினியரிங் நிறுவனமான AEL, ‘நாளைய பாரம்பரியம், இன்றே இன்ஜினியரிங்’ என்ற வாக்குறுதியை நிறைவேற்ற தொடர்ந்து முயற்சித்து வருகிறது.",
        "ஆசிய அபிவிருத்தி வங்கியின் (ADB) நிதியுதவியுடன் கூடிய இத்திட்டமானது, இலங்கைக்கு மிகவும் தேவையான வெளிநாட்டு நாணயங்களை கொண்டு வருவதுடன், இத்திட்டமானது மோசமான போக்குவரத்து உட்கட்டமைப்பு தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகளை நீக்குவதுடன், கிராமப்புற குடிமக்களுக்கு சமூக-பொருளாதார மையங்களுடன் மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட இணைப்பை வழங்கும். அவர்களுடைய வாழ்க்கை.",
        "RDA இன் இரண்டாவது ஒருங்கிணைந்த சாலை முதலீட்டுத் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் வரும் இந்தத் திட்டம் பிப்ரவரி 2023க்குள் முடிவடையும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "210",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒருங்கிணைந்த சாலைகள் திட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Access Engineering PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஇஎல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "210",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 இன் ஆரம்பத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீதி அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஇஎல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஇஎல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஇஎல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RDA இன் இரண்டாவது ஒருங்கிணைந்த சாலை முதலீட்டுத் திட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}