{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රට-බංකොලොත්-කළේ-පාර්ලිමේන්තුව-නොදැනුවත්වයි/1-619111",
  "time_ut": 1662016125,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රට බංකොලොත් කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොදැනුවත්වයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament bankrupted the country without knowing it",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "United National Party Member Vajira Abiveardhana said in the Parliament that it is the duty of all the 225 members of the Parliament to demand a proper investigation into the bankruptcy of the country and that the country has been bankrupted without the knowledge of the Parliament.",
        "Mr. Vajira Abewardana said that the country was bankrupted not by the representatives of the parliament but by a group without the knowledge of the parliament, but the blame has been placed on the parliament.",
        "Mr. Abeywardhana said that the Ministry of Finance or the Central Bank does not have the power to bankrupt the country. When they do something they do not have the power to do, everyone remains silent and the representatives of the Parliament are punished.",
        "Mr. Abeywardena said that according to the constitution, there is no power to take arbitrary decisions not to pay the foreign debt and he said that all the 225 people should be ashamed when the power of the parliament was misused.",
        "Mr. Vajira Abeivardhana said that if the situation of the country had been reported to the parliament, the parliament would have met and made a process to deal with it without bankrupting the country.",
        "Mr. Vajira Abewardana said that Parliament has given up financial control and handed it over to others, but by law, financial control belongs to Parliament.",
        "Mr. Vajira Abiveardhana said that there has been a powerless process in Sri Lanka and the President was questioned about it in Parliament when he was a Member of Parliament.",
        "Mr. Vajira Abiveardhana said that the 225 responsibility of the Parliament is not necessary to bankrupt the country and those who have declared the country bankrupt have done illegal work if the Parliament has not approved this process.",
        "Mr. Vajira Abeywardena said this while participating in the budget debate in Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abiveardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abewardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeivardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abewardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abiveardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abiveardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රට බංකොලොත් කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොදැනුවත්වයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට බංකොලොත් කිරීම ගැන  නිසි පරීක්ෂණයක් ඉල්ලීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 225 දෙනාගේම යුතුකම බවත්  රට බංකොලොත් කර ඇත්තේ   පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොදැනුවත්ව බව  පරීක්ෂණයක් කර රටට කිව යුතු බවත් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රී වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "රට බංකොලොත් කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජිතයන් නොව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව  නොදැනුවත්ව වෙන කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් වන නමුත් වරද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පිට පටවා තිබෙන බවද වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා කීය.",
        "රට බංකොලොත් කිරීමේ බලය මුදල් අමාත්‍යංශයට හෝ මහ බැංකුවට නැතැයි ද  බලයක් නොමැති දෙයක් කළ විට සියලුම දෙනා නිහඬව සිටින අතර දඬුවම් විඳින්නේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ  නියෝජිතයන් බවද අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය .",
        "විදේශ ණය ගෙවන්නේ නැතැයි හිතුමතේ තීරණ ගන්නට ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව බලයක් නැතැයි කී අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තිබෙන බලය අයුතු ලෙස පාවිච්චි කළ විට 225 දෙනාම ලැජ්ජාවට පත්විය යුතු බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රටේ තත්ත්වය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට වාර්තා කළා නම් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වී රට බංකොලොත් නොකර කටයුතු කරන්නට ක්‍රියාවලියක් හදනු ඇති බවද එසේනම් අද කරන වැඩේ එදා කරන්න තිබූ බවද වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මූල්‍ය පාලනය අතහැර වෙන අයට බාරදී තිබෙන නමුත් නීතියෙන් මූල්‍ය පාලනය අයත් වී ඇත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට බවද වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බලයක් නැති ක්‍රියාවලියක් ලංකාවේ සිදුවී තිබෙන අතර ඒ ගැන ජනාධිපතිවරයා මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ලෙස සිටියදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රශ්න කර තිබෙන්නේ යැයිද සාර්ථක ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් අසාර්ථක ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොවේ යැයි වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "රට බංකොලොත් කිරීමට  පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 225 වගකීම අවශ්‍ය නැති අතර මෙි ක්‍රියාවලියට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතිය ලබාදී නැත්නම් රට බංකොලොත් බවට ප්‍රකාශ කළ අය කර තිබෙන්නේ නීති විරෝධී වැඩක් බවද වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා කීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අයවැය විවාදයට සහභාගී වෙමින් වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා මේ බව කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අභිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අභිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අභිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பார்லிமென்ட் நாட்டைத் தெரியாமல் திவாலாக்கியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் வங்குரோத்து நிலை குறித்து உரிய விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு கோருவது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள 225 உறுப்பினர்களினதும் கடமை எனவும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு தெரியாமல் நாடு வங்குரோத்து செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர் வஜிர அபிவர்தன பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளால் அல்ல, நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்குத் தெரியாமல் ஒரு குழுவினால்தான் நாடு வங்குரோத்தப்பட்டது என்றும், ஆனால் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மீது பழி சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டை திவாலாக்கும் அதிகாரம் நிதி அமைச்சுக்கோ அல்லது மத்திய வங்கிக்கோ கிடையாது எனவும் தமக்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லாத ஒன்றைச் செய்யும் போது அனைவரும் மௌனம் காப்பதாகவும் பாராளுமன்ற பிரதிநிதிகள் தண்டிக்கப்படுவதாகவும் அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை செலுத்துவதில்லை என தன்னிச்சையான தீர்மானங்களை எடுக்க அதிகாரம் இல்லை என தெரிவித்த திரு.அபேவர்தன, நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் அதிகாரத்தை தவறாக பயன்படுத்திய போது 225 பேரும் வெட்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "நாட்டின் நிலைமையை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்திருந்தால், பாராளுமன்றம் கூடி நாட்டை வங்குரோத்து செய்யாமல் சமாளிப்பதற்கான செயலணியை மேற்கொண்டிருக்கும் என வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் நிதிக் கட்டுப்பாட்டை கைவிட்டு மற்றவர்களிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளது, ஆனால் சட்டப்படி நிதிக் கட்டுப்பாடு பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கே சொந்தம் என திரு வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் அதிகாரமற்ற செயற்பாடு இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாகவும், ஜனாதிபதி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இருந்த போது அது தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கேள்வி எழுப்பப்பட்டதாகவும் வஜிர அபிவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டை திவாலாக்குவதற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தின் 225 பொறுப்பு அவசியமில்லை எனவும், நாடு திவாலாகிவிட்டதாக அறிவித்தவர்கள் இந்த செயலணிக்கு பாராளுமன்றம் அங்கீகாரம் வழங்காத பட்சத்தில் சட்டவிரோதமான வேலைகளை செய்துள்ளதாகவும் வஜிர அபிவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட விவாதத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே வஜிர அபேவர்தன மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}