{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නිදහස-ලැබූ-රන්ජන්-ගංගාරාමයට/1-618804",
  "time_ut": 1661512752,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිදහස ලැබූ රන්ජන් ගංගාරාමයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "To Ranjan Gangarama who was freed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Minister of State Ranjan Ramanayake, who was pardoned by the President, went to Gangarama Temple, Hunupitiya, Colombo after coming out of Welikada Prison.",
        "Seth Patha blessed Ranjan Ramanayake, the Maha Sangha led by Dr. Kirinde Assaji Thero, Gangarama Viharaya Director, who had returned from freedom.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa and a group of parliamentarians also attended the event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gangarama Temple",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada Prison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seth Patha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirinde Assaji Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gangarama Viharaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිදහස ලැබූ රන්ජන් ගංගාරාමයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති සමාව ලැබ නිදහස ලැබූ හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටතට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු කොළඹ, හුණුපිටිය ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානයට ගොස් ආශීර්වාද ලබාගත්තේය.",
        "ගංගාරාම විහාරාධිකාරී ආචාර්ය කිරින්දේ අස්සජි හිමි ප්‍රමුඛ මහා සංඝරත්නය නිදහස් වී පැමිණි රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට මෙහිදී සෙත් පතා ආශීර්වාද කළහ.",
        "විපක්ෂනායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇතුළු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙත් පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirinde Assaji Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංගාරාම විහාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட ரஞ்சன் கங்காராமவுக்கு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியினால் மன்னிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையிலிருந்து வெளியே வந்த பின்னர் கொழும்பு ஹுனுப்பிட்டிய கங்காராம விகாரைக்குச் சென்று ஆசி பெற்றார்.",
        "விடுதலை பெற்று நாடு திரும்பிய கங்காராம விகாரையின் பணிப்பாளர் கலாநிதி கிரிந்தே அஸ்ஸாஜி தேரர் தலைமையிலான மகாசங்கத்தினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை சேத் பாத்தா ஆசிர்வதித்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்காராம கோவில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சேத் பாத்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirinde Assaji Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்காராம விகாரை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}