{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-mass-protest-against-president-rajapaksa-amid-tear-gas-97141/",
  "time_ut": 1657343760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka mass protest against President Rajapaksa amid tear gas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka mass protest against President Rajapaksa amid tear gas",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Thousands protestors gathered at Sri Lanka’s capital Colombo shouting slogan against President Gotabaya Rajapaksa while police tear gassed crowds in the city centre, witnesses said.",
        "Police tear gassed protestors at Chatham Street, near President Rajapaksa’s official residence.",
        "“Even though you are in uniform you must stand with the people,” former military chief Sarath Fonseka told security forces.",
        "Sri Lanka imposed curfew ahead of the protest in a bid to curb the crowds but it was lifted at 0800 am.",
        "Protestors came to Colombo walking and in whatever transport they could find."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chatham Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0800 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන විරෝධතා කඳුළු ගෑස් මධ්‍යයේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අගනුවර වන කොළඹට රැස් වූ දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට එරෙහිව සටන් පාඨ කියමින් නගර මධ්‍යයේ සිටි පිරිසට පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ බව දුටුවෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂගේ නිල නිවස අසල චැතම් වීදියේ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළේය.",
        "“ඔබ නිල ඇඳුමෙන් සිටියත් ඔබ ජනතාව සමඟ සිටිය යුතුයි,” හිටපු හමුදාපති සරත් ෆොන්සේකා ආරක්ෂක අංශවලට පැවසීය.",
        "ජනකාය මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විරෝධතාවයට පෙර ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවූ නමුත් එය පෙරවරු 0800 ට ඉවත් කරන ලදී.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹට පැමිණියේ පා ගමනින් සහ තමන්ට හමුවන ඕනෑම ප්‍රවාහනයකින්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චැතම් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0800 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு எதிராக கண்ணீர் புகைக்குண்டுக்கு எதிராக பொதுமக்கள் போராட்டம் நடத்தினர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் தலைநகர் கொழும்பில் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு எதிராக முழக்கங்களை எழுப்பினர், அதே நேரத்தில் நகர மையத்தில் போலீசார் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசினர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்திற்கு அருகிலுள்ள சத்தம் தெருவில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை பொலிஸார் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசினர்.",
        "\"நீங்கள் சீருடையில் இருந்தாலும் மக்களுடன் நிற்க வேண்டும்\" என முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தளபதி சரத் பொன்சேகா பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கூட்டத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும் முயற்சியில் போராட்டத்திற்கு முன்னதாக இலங்கை ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை விதித்தது, ஆனால் அது காலை 0800 மணிக்கு தளர்த்தப்பட்டது.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் நடந்தும் எந்தப் போக்குவரத்திலும் கொழும்புக்கு வந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாத்தம் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 0800 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}