{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Committee-to-grant-approval-for-new-appointments-or-changes-to-heads-of-govt-institutions/108-243164",
  "time_ut": 1660636980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Committee to grant approval for new appointments or changes to heads of govt institutions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Committee to grant approval for new appointments or changes to heads of govt institutions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has appointed a committee to oversee and grant prior approval for new appointments or changes to the existing positions of chairmen and directors of state corporations, statutory boards and state-owned enterprises.",
        "President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake will chair the committee including Prime Minister's Secretary Anura Dissanayake and Cabinet Secretary W.M.D.J. Fernando, the President's Media Division said.",
        "President’s Additional Secretary Chaminda Kularatne will serve as the Secretary of this committee.",
        "In the event it is required to change the positions of chairmen or board of directors of state corporations, statutory boards and state-owned enterprises, it is mandatory to submit nominations to the above committee with justifiable reasons and obtain prior approval.",
        "This committee has been appointed, paying heed to the written requests made to the President periodically, to change the positions of chairmen and board of directors of state corporations, statutory boards and state-owned enterprises without prior agreement and certain informal appointments.",
        "Accordingly, a letter has been sent directly to all the secretaries of ministries under the signature of the President's Secretary, and copies have been sent to the Prime Minister's Secretary and the Ministry of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policy for the implementation of necessary arrangements."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.M.D.J. Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Kularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන ප්‍රධානීන්ගේ නව පත්වීම් හෝ වෙනස් කිරීම් සඳහා අනුමැතිය ලබාදීමට කමිටුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල සහ රජය සතු ව්‍යවසායන්හි සභාපතිවරුන් සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන් යන තනතුරුවල නව පත්වීම් හෝ වෙනස් කිරීම් සඳහා අධීක්‍ෂණය සහ පූර්ව අනුමැතිය ලබාදීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ කමිටුවක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් අනුර දිසානායක සහ කැබිනට් ලේකම් ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු, ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම කමිටුවේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් චමින්ද කුලරත්න මහතා කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල සහ රජය සතු ව්‍යාපාරවල සභාපති හෝ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ තනතුරු වෙනස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් සාධාරණ හේතු සහිතව ඉහත කමිටුවට නාමයෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කර පූර්ව අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම අනිවාර්ය වේ.",
        "රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල සහ රජය සතු ව්‍යාපාරවල සභාපති සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල තනතුරු පූර්ව එකඟතාවයකින් තොරව සහ ඇතැම් අවිධිමත් පත්වීම්වලින් තොරව වෙනස් කරන ලෙස වරින් වර ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත කරන ලද ලිඛිත ඉල්ලීම්වලට අවධානය යොමු කරමින් මෙම කමිටුව පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයාගේ අත්සනින් සියලුම අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන් වෙත ඍජුවම ලිපියක් යවා ඇති අතර, අවශ්‍ය වැඩපිළිවෙල ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා එහි පිටපත් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම්වරයාට සහ මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත යවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய நியமனங்கள் அல்லது அரசு நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்களை மாற்றுவதற்கு ஒப்புதல் வழங்குவதற்கான குழு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரச கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள், சட்ட சபைகள் மற்றும் அரச நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பணிப்பாளர் பதவிகளில் புதிய நியமனங்கள் அல்லது மாற்றங்களை மேற்பார்வையிடவும் முன் அனுமதி வழங்கவும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க குழுவொன்றை நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் அநுர திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் அமைச்சரவை செயலாளர் டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே உள்ளிட்ட குழுவிற்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க தலைமை தாங்குவார். பெர்னாண்டோ, ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் சமிந்த குலரத்ன இந்த குழுவின் செயலாளராக கடமையாற்றவுள்ளார்.",
        "அரச கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள், சட்ட சபைகள் மற்றும் அரசுக்குச் சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்கள் அல்லது பணிப்பாளர் சபையின் பதவிகளை மாற்ற வேண்டியிருக்கும் பட்சத்தில், நியாயமான காரணங்களுடன் மேற்கண்ட குழுவிடம் பரிந்துரைகளைச் சமர்ப்பித்து முன் அனுமதி பெறுவது கட்டாயமாகும்.",
        "அரச கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள், சட்ட சபைகள் மற்றும் அரச நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பணிப்பாளர் பதவிகளை முன் உடன்பாடு மற்றும் சில முறைசாரா நியமனங்கள் இன்றி மாற்றுமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அவ்வப்போது விடுக்கப்பட்ட எழுத்து மூலமான கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு செவிசாய்த்து இந்தக் குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளரின் கையொப்பத்துடன் அனைத்து அமைச்சுக்களின் செயலாளர்களுக்கும் நேரடியாக கடிதம் அனுப்பப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், தேவையான ஏற்பாடுகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கான பிரதிகள் பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் மற்றும் நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கை அமைச்சுக்கு அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே. பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த குலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}