{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83355/us-ambassador-assures-support-to-find-solutions-to-sri-lankas-economic-issues",
  "time_ut": 1656608700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US Ambassador assures support to find solutions to Sri Lanka’s economic issues",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US Ambassador assures support to find solutions to Sri Lanka’s economic issues",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The U.S. Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that the United States will assist Sri Lanka in finding a solution to the economic crisis.",
        "This was stated when Mrs. Julie Chung called on the President at the President’s House in Colombo, today (30).",
        "A high-level US delegation assured the support of the United States of America to maintain the relationship with the International Monetary Fund at a strong footing. US President Joe Biden has also taken steps to provide humanitarian assistance to Sri Lanka on several occasions.",
        "President Rajapaksa expressed gratitude to the US President Joe Biden for his support to Sri Lanka to enter into an agreement with the International Monetary Fund and for its humanitarian assistance.",
        "Mrs. Julie Chung stated with the President that she understands the current situation in Sri Lanka and is confident that a quick recovery will take place.",
        "Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake was present at this occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් සෙවීමට සහාය දෙන බවට එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිවරයා සහතික වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය ලබා දෙන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් මහත්මිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "ජුලී චුන්ග් මහත්මිය අද (30) කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග සබඳතාව ශක්තිමත් පදනමකින් පවත්වාගෙන යාමට ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සහය ලබාදෙන බවට ඉහළ පෙළේ එක්සත් ජනපද නියෝජිත පිරිසක් සහතික විය. අමෙරිකානු ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් ද අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබාදීමට පියවර ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් සහය සහ එහි මානුෂීය සහය පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපතිතුමා අමෙරිකානු ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩෙන් වෙත සිය කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව තමාට අවබෝධයක් ඇති බවත්, ඉක්මන් සුවයක් ලැබෙනු ඇති බවට විශ්වාසය පළ කරන බවත් ජූලි චුන්ග් මහත්මිය ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමඟ ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී අනුර දිසානායක මහතා සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண ஆதரவளிப்பதாக அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா உதவும் என இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "திருமதி ஜூலி சுங் இன்று (30) கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்த போதே இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான உறவை வலுவாகப் பேணுவதற்கு அமெரிக்காவின் ஆதரவை உயர்மட்ட அமெரிக்கக் குழு உறுதியளித்தது. அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனும் இலங்கைக்கு மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்கு பல தடவைகள் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் உடன்படிக்கை செய்து கொள்ள இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்கும் அதன் மனிதாபிமான உதவிக்கும் அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையை தாம் புரிந்து கொண்டுள்ளதாகவும், விரைவில் குணமடைவார்கள் என நம்புவதாகவும் திருமதி ஜூலி சுங் ஜனாதிபதியுடன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிப்பாளர் பிரதானி அனுர திஸாநாயக்க கலந்துகொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}