{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/defence-secretary-at-pcoi-on-may-9th-violence/",
  "time_ut": 1656387720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Defence Secretary at PCOI on May 9th Violence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Defence Secretary at PCOI on May 9th Violence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Defense Secretary Kamal Gunaratne appeared at the Presidential Commission of Inquiry to ascertain lapses, if any, by the armed forces and State Intelligence Services during the recent incidents of violence in Mirihana on March 31st and island-wide violence since May 9th.",
        "A senior official attached to the Presidential Commission said that statements were obtained from the Defense Secretary.",
        "In addition, the Commission obtained statements from former Ministers Channa Jayasumana and Dr. Ramesh Pathirana on Monday (27).",
        "Former Army Commander General Shavendra Silva also appeared to the Commission.",
        "Nearly 30 military officers have been summoned to the Commission.",
        "Former Navy Commander, Admiral of the Fleet Wasantha Karannagoda, Former Air Force Commander Marshal of the Air Force Roshan Goonetileke and Former Army Commander Daya Ratnayake are the members of the Presidential Commission of Inquiry that was appointed by the President recently.",
        "BREAKING: Only essential services to operate from midnight (27); CPC will only issue fuel for essential services"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PCOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "May 9th",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Commission of Inquiry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Intelligence Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 31st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force Roshan Goonetileke",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daya Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Commission of Inquiry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැයි 9 ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය පිළිබඳ PCOI හි ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පසුගිය මාර්තු 31 වැනිදා මිරිහාන ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුවූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා සහ මැයි 9 වැනිදා සිට දිවයින පුරා සිදුවූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවලදී ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවේ සහ රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශවල අතපසුවීම් ඇත්නම් ඒවා පිළිබඳව සොයා බැලීම සඳහා ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා ජනාධිපති විමර්ශන කොමිසමට පැමිණ සිටියේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති කොමිසමට අනුයුක්ත ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකු පැවසුවේ ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයාගෙන් ප්‍රකාශ ලබා ගත් බවයි.",
        "මීට අමතරව හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන චන්න ජයසුමන සහ වෛද්‍ය රමේෂ් පතිරණ යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් ද කොමිසම සඳුදා (27) ප්‍රකාශ ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "හිටපු යුද හමුදාපති ජනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා ද කොමිසම වෙත පැමිණ සිටියේය.",
        "හමුදා නිලධාරීන් 30කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් කොමිසමට කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "හිටපු නාවික හමුදාපති, අද්මිරාල් ඔෆ් ද ෆ්ලීට් වසන්ත කරන්නාගොඩ, හිටපු ගුවන් හමුදාපති මාර්ෂල් ඔෆ් ද එයාර් ෆෝස් රොෂාන් ගුණතිලක සහ හිටපු යුද හමුදාපති දයා රත්නායක යන මහත්වරුන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් පසුගියදා පත් කරන ලද ජනාධිපති විමර්ශන කොමිසමේ සාමාජිකයින් වේ.",
        "BREAKING: මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ (27) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා පමණක්; තෙල් සංස්ථාව ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන්නේ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පමණි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PCOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති විමර්ශන කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය බුද්ධි සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30ට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව රොෂාන් ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයා රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති විමර්ශන කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மே 9 வன்முறையில் PCOI இல் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடந்த மார்ச் 31ஆம் திகதி மிரிஹானவில் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்கள் மற்றும் மே 9ஆம் திகதி முதல் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களின் போது ஆயுதப் படைகள் மற்றும் அரச புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரால் ஏதேனும் குறைபாடுகள் ஏற்பட்டிருந்தால், அவற்றைக் கண்டறிவதற்காக பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் கமல் குணரத்ன ஜனாதிபதி விசாரணை ஆணைக்குழுவில் ஆஜரானார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளரிடம் வாக்குமூலம் பெறப்பட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஆணைக்குழுவின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், திங்கட்கிழமை (27) முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்களான சன்ன ஜயசுமண மற்றும் கலாநிதி ரமேஷ் பத்திரன ஆகியோரிடம் ஆணைக்குழு வாக்குமூலங்களைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டது.",
        "முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தளபதி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வாவும் ஆணைக்குழுவில் ஆஜராகியிருந்தார்.",
        "கிட்டத்தட்ட 30 இராணுவ அதிகாரிகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியினால் அண்மையில் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி விசாரணை ஆணைக்குழுவில் முன்னாள் கடற்படைத் தளபதி அட்மிரல் வசந்த கரன்னாகொட, முன்னாள் விமானப்படைத் தளபதி மார்ஷல் ஆஃப் தி எயார்ஃபோர்ஸ் ரொஷான் குணதிலக மற்றும் முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தளபதி தயா ரத்நாயக்க ஆகியோர் அங்கம் வகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "BREAKING: நள்ளிரவு (27) முதல் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் மட்டும் செயல்படும்; அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு மட்டுமே CPC எரிபொருளை வழங்கும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிசிஓஐ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி விசாரணை ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில புலனாய்வு சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தரகு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை ரொஷான் குணதிலக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயா ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி விசாரணை ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}