{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මහින්දානන්ද-බදු-ෆයිල්-එළියට-අදී/101-619075",
  "time_ut": 1661941931,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මහින්දානන්ද බදු ෆයිල් එළියට අදී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Mahindananda pulled out the tax file",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna MP Mahindananda Aluthgamage said in Parliament today (31) that a major paddy mill owner in Sri Lanka who earns a net profit of 100 billion rupees in two seasons pays only 900,000 rupees in tax per year.",
        "The MP also said that the owner of that V mill has made a net profit of 50 billion in one season.",
        "Mr. Mahindananda Aluthgamage mentioned that he has bought 5 lakh metric tons of rice in a season and has sold it at 220 rupees and has made a profit of 70 rupees per kilo.",
        "Mr. Aluthgamage questioned where the Income Tax Department is when things like this are happening.",
        "The Income Tax Department has sent a letter to him asking him to pay 10 billion and he has sent a letter to the Income Tax Department saying that he cannot pay it. Mr. Mahindananda Aluthgamage said.",
        "Mr. Aluthgamage said that a liquor licensee earns a net profit of 15,200,000 per month, but pays only 2 or 3,000,000 in taxes per year. A gas station owner pays only 50,000 or 68,000 in taxes per year.",
        "Joining the debate on the interim budget, Mr. Mahindananda Aluthgamage said that if the country's revenues are properly managed, there will be no need for the IMF."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahindananda",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahindananda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 billion rupees",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two seasons",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahindananda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 lakh metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "a season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Income Tax Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Income Tax Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Income Tax Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahindananda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 50,000 or 68,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahindananda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහින්දානන්ද බදු ෆයිල් එළියට අදී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කන්න දෙකකට රුපියල් බිලියන 100 ක ශුද්ධ ලාභයක් ලබන මෙරට ප්‍රධාන  පෙළේ වී මෝල් හිමියකු වසරකට බදු ගෙවන්නේ රුපියල් ලක්ෂ නවයක් පමණක් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රී මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී අද (31)පැවසීය.",
        "එම වී මෝල් හිමියා එක කන්නයකට බිලියන  50 ක ශුද්ධ ලාභයක් ලබා තිබෙන බවද මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කීය.",
        "ඔහු කන්නයකට වී මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් ලක්ෂ 5 ක් මිලදී ගෙන තිබෙන අතර රුපියල්  අනුවට මිලදී ගත් වී රුපියල්   220 ට විකුණා තිබෙන බවත් එක කිලෝවකින් රුපියල් 70 ක ලාභයක් ලබා තිබෙන බවත් මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙවැනි දේ සිදු වෙද්දී ආදායම් බදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඉන්නේ කොහිදැයි අලුත්ගමගේ  මහතා ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "රේස් බුකි තිබෙන අයකුගේ ලිපිගොනුවක් ද තමා ගෙන්වා ගත් බවද බිලියන 10 ක් ගෙවන්නැයි ඔහුට ආදායම් බදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ලිපියක් යවා තිබෙන අතර ඔහු එය ගෙවන්නට නොහැකි බවට ලිපියක් ආදායම් බදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට  යවා තිබෙන බවත් වසරකට පසු පරීක්ෂණයක් තබා ලක්ෂ 10 ක් අය කරගෙන බදු ෆයිල් එක වසා දමා තිබෙන බවත් මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා කීය.",
        "මත්පැන්  බලපත්‍ර ලාභියෙකු මසකට ලක්ෂ පහළොවක විස්සක  ශුද්ධ ලාභයක් ලබන නමුත් වසරකට බදු ලෙස ගෙවන්නේ ලක්ෂ දෙකක් හෝ තුනක් පමණක් බවද අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා කීය.ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියෙක් වසරකට බදු ගෙවන්නේ පනස් දහසක් හෝ හැට අටදහසක් පමණක් බවද මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කීය.",
        "රටේ තිබෙන ආදායම් ටික හරියට කළමනාකරණය කර ගත්තොත් අයි.එම්.එෆ් යන්න අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ නැතැයි ද අතුරු අයවැය පිළිබඳ විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහින්දානන්ද",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 100යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක් කන්නයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් ලක්ෂ 5යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආදායම් බදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආදායම් බදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 10 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආදායම් බදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 ක් හෝ 68,000 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மகிந்தானந்த வரிக் கோப்பினை இழுத்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரண்டு பருவகாலங்களில் 100 பில்லியன் ரூபாவை நிகர இலாபம் ஈட்டும் இலங்கையின் பிரதான நெல் ஆலை உரிமையாளர் வருடமொன்றுக்கு 900,000 ரூபா வரியை மட்டுமே செலுத்துவதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே இன்று (31) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்த வி மில் உரிமையாளர் ஒரு பருவத்தில் 50 பில்லியன் நிகர லாபம் ஈட்டியுள்ளதாகவும் எம்.பி.",
        "ஒரு சீசனில் 5 இலட்சம் மெற்றிக் தொன் அரிசியை கொள்வனவு செய்து 220 ரூபாவிற்கு விற்பனை செய்து ஒரு கிலோவிற்கு 70 ரூபா இலாபம் ஈட்டியுள்ளதாக திரு மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இவ்வாறான விடயங்கள் இடம்பெறும் போது வருமான வரி திணைக்களம் எங்கே இருக்கின்றது என திரு அளுத்கமகே கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "10 பில்லியனை செலுத்துமாறு வருமான வரித் திணைக்களம் அவருக்கு கடிதம் அனுப்பியுள்ளதாகவும், அதனை செலுத்த முடியாது என வருமான வரி திணைக்களத்திற்கு கடிதம் அனுப்பியுள்ளதாகவும் மஹிந்தானந்த அலுத்கமகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மதுபான அனுமதிப்பத்திரம் பெற்றவர் மாதாந்தம் 15,200,000 நிகர லாபம் ஈட்டினாலும் வருடத்திற்கு 2 அல்லது 3,000,000 வரிகளை மட்டுமே செலுத்துவதாகவும், ஒரு எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலைய உரிமையாளர் வருடத்திற்கு 50,000 அல்லது 68,000 வரிகளை மட்டுமே செலுத்துவதாக திரு.அலுத்கமகே தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் மீதான விவாதத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய திரு.மகிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே, நாட்டின் வருமானம் சரியாக நிர்வகிக்கப்பட்டால், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் தேவையே இருக்காது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மகிந்தானந்தா",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 பில்லியன் ரூபாய்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு பருவங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 லட்சம் மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருமான வரித்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வருமான வரித்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருமான வரித்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 அல்லது 68,000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}