{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83881/dan-priyasads-brother-hacked-to-death",
  "time_ut": 1658828280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dan Priyasad’s brother hacked to death",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dan Priyasad’s brother hacked to death",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A 34-year-old was hacked to death in the area of Orugodawatta in Wellampitiya last night.",
        "The victim was pronounced dead while being rushed to the Colombo National Hospital with critical injuries.",
        "The deceased was identified as the brother of social activist Dan Priyasad. He was reportedly residing in the area of Kuruniyawatta, Wellampitiya.",
        "Preliminary police investigations uncovered that two men who arrived on a motorcycle had attacked the victim. They have since fled the scene.",
        "The police suspect that the murder was committed over a dispute linked to a drug syndicate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dan Priyasad",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "34-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellampitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dan Priyasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuruniyawatta, Wellampitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්ගේ සහෝදරයා කපා කොටා ඝාතනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැල්ලම්පිටිය - ඔරුගොඩවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේදී 34 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ කපා කොටා ඝාතනය කර තිබුණා.",
        "පහරකෑමට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයා බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට රැගෙන යමින් සිටියදී මියගොස් ඇත.",
        "මිය ගොස් ඇත්තේ සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්ගේ සොහොයුරෙක්. ඔහු වැල්ලම්පිටිය කුරුනියාවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිව සිටි බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු මෙම පහරදීම සිදුකර ඇති බවයි මූලික පොලිස් පරීක්ෂණවලදී අනාවරණ වී ඇත්තේ. එතැන් සිට ඔවුන් එම ස්ථානයෙන් පලා ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්කරුවෙකු සම්බන්ධ ආරවුලක් මත මෙම ඝාතනය සිදුව ඇති බවට පොලිසිය සැකකරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "34 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලම්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණියවත්ත, වැල්ලම්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டான் பிரியசாத்தின் சகோதரர் வெட்டிக் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய, ஒருகொடவத்த பகுதியில் 34 வயதுடைய நபர் ஒருவர் நேற்றிரவு வெட்டி படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த நபர் கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட போது உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் சமூக ஆர்வலர் டான் பிரியசாத்தின் சகோதரர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டார். இவர் குருனியாவத்தை, வெல்லம்பிட்டிய பிரதேசத்தில் வசிப்பதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இருவர் உயிரிழந்த நபரை தாக்கியுள்ளதாக பொலிஸாரின் ஆரம்பகட்ட விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து தெரியவந்துள்ளது. இதையடுத்து அவர்கள் அங்கிருந்து தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தலுடன் தொடர்புடைய தகராறில் இந்த கொலை நடந்திருக்கலாம் என போலீசார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டான் பிரியசாத்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "34 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டான் பிரியசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருனியாவத்தை, வெல்லம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}