{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/diesel-distribution-underway/",
  "time_ut": 1661753880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Diesel Distribution underway",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Diesel Distribution underway",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Petroleum Private Tanker Owners' Association says the distribution of Diesel resumed across the country last night (28).",
        "The Secretary of the Sri Lanka Petroleum Private Tanker Owners' Association Shantha Silva says the shortage of Diesel will be addressed in the next two days.",
        "However, he said that the Petrol is distributed according to a priority list, adding that a short supply of Petrol is likely until another shipment arrives in the country.",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) says an additional 500 to 1000 MT of Diesel and Petrol are being distributed across the country.",
        "This is in addition to 4,000 MT of Diesel and 3,000 MT of Petrol that is distributed daily.",
        "The CPC emphasized that there are sufficient reserves of Petrol, Diesel, and Kerosene to meet the local demand.",
        "Over 1,000 people killed by Pakistan monsoon rains and floods"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Petroleum Private Tanker Owners'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shantha Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an additional 500 to 1000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol, Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerosene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩීසල් බෙදා හැරීම සිදු කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඊයේ (28) රාත්‍රියේ රට පුරා ඩීසල් බෙදා හැරීම යළි ආරම්භ කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "ඩීසල් හිඟයට ඉදිරි දින දෙක තුළ විසඳුම් ලබා දෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ ලේකම් ශාන්ත සිල්වා මහතා පවසයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පෙට්‍රල් බෙදා හරිනු ලබන්නේ ප්‍රමුඛතා ලැයිස්තුවකට අනුව බව පැවසූ ඔහු, තවත් තොගයක් මෙරටට පැමිණෙන තෙක් පෙට්‍රල් හිඟයක් ඇතිවීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500ත් 1000ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් රට පුරා බෙදා හරින බව ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව පවසයි.",
        "මෙය දිනකට බෙදා හරින ඩීසල් මෙ.ටොන් 4,000ක් සහ පෙට්‍රල් මෙ.ටොන් 3,000ට අමතරවය.",
        "දේශීය ඉල්ලුමට සරිලන පරිදි පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල් සහ භූමිතෙල් සංචිත ප්‍රමාණවත් බව ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "පකිස්ථානයේ මෝසම් වැසි සහ ගංවතුර හේතුවෙන් 1000කට අධික පිරිසක් මිය ගියහ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමතර 500 සිට 1000 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භූමිතෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டீசல் விநியோகம் நடைபெற்று வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாடு முழுவதும் டீசல் விநியோகம் நேற்று (28) இரவு மீண்டும் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய தனியார் டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "டீசல் தட்டுப்பாடு இன்னும் இரண்டு நாட்களில் நிவர்த்தி செய்யப்படும் என இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய தனியார் டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் செயலாளர் சாந்த சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், முன்னுரிமை பட்டியலின் படி பெட்ரோல் விநியோகிக்கப்படுகிறது என்று அவர் கூறினார், மேலும் நாட்டிற்கு மற்றொரு ஏற்றுமதி வரும் வரை பெட்ரோல் பற்றாக்குறை இருக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) நாடு முழுவதும் 500 முதல் 1000 மெட்ரிக்தொன் டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோல் கூடுதலாக விநியோகிக்கப்படுவதாக தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "இது தினசரி வினியோகிக்கப்படும் 4,000 மெ.டன் டீசல் மற்றும் 3,000 மெ.டன் பெட்ரோல் கூடுதலாகும்.",
        "உள்ளூர் தேவையை பூர்த்தி செய்ய போதுமான அளவு பெட்ரோல், டீசல் மற்றும் மண்ணெண்ணெய் இருப்பு உள்ளது என்று CPC வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "பாகிஸ்தானில் பெய்த மழை மற்றும் வெள்ளத்தால் 1,000க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய தனியார் டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதலாக 500 முதல் 1000 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல், டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்ணெண்ணெய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}