{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-imposes-curfew-in-colombo-district-from-july-14-15-97416/",
  "time_ut": 1657782060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka imposes curfew in Colombo district from July 14-15",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka imposes curfew in Colombo district from July 14-15",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has imposed a curfew in the commercial capital of Colombo from 12 pm (July 14) to 5 am July 15, an extraordinary gazette notice said.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, the Premier and the Acting President of the country said in the gazette that “no person shall be on any public road, railway, public park, recreation park or other public ground or seashore in such areas…except under the authority of a written permit granted by the Secretary, Ministry of Defence or Secretary, Ministry of Public Security or Inspector General of Police or any other officer authorized by them.",
        "The curfew will apply to the Administrative District of Colombo and the territorial water adjacent to such district."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 14-15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Public Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Administrative District of Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජූලි 14-15 දක්වා කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවා ඇත",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කොළඹ වාණිජ අගනුවරට දහවල් 12 (ජූලි 14) සිට ජූලි 15 උදෑසන 5 දක්වා ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවා ඇති බව අතිවිශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එම ගැසට් පත්‍රයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත්තේ “කිසිම පුද්ගලයෙක් එවැනි ප්‍රදේශවල කිසිදු පොදු මාර්ගයක, දුම්රිය, පොදු උද්‍යානයක, විනෝද උද්‍යානයක හෝ වෙනත් පොදු භූමියක හෝ මුහුදු වෙරළක නොසිටිය යුතු බවයි.… ලේකම්, ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය හෝ ලේකම්, මහජන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය හෝ පොලිස්පතිවරයා හෝ ඔවුන් විසින් බලය පවරන ලද වෙනත් නිලධාරියෙකු විසින් ලබා දෙන ලිඛිත බලපත්‍රයක්.",
        "ඇඳිරි නීතිය කොළඹ පරිපාලන දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට සහ එම දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට යාබද ප්‍රාදේශිය ජලයට අදාළ වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 14-15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව. 12",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ පරිපාලන දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ஜூலை 14 முதல் 15 வரை ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் வர்த்தக தலைநகரான கொழும்பில் மதியம் 12 (ஜூலை 14) முதல் ஜூலை 15 காலை 5 மணி வரை ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஒரு அசாதாரண வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பு தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் பிரதமரும், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, அந்த வர்த்தமானியில், “எந்தவொரு பொது வீதி, புகையிரத, பொது பூங்கா, பொழுதுபோக்கு பூங்கா அல்லது ஏனைய பொது மைதானம் அல்லது கடற்பரப்பு போன்ற பகுதிகளில்... செயலாளர், பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் அல்லது செயலாளர், பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் அல்லது போலீஸ் இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் அல்லது அவர்களால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட வேறு எந்த அதிகாரியும் எழுத்துப்பூர்வ அனுமதி.",
        "ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு கொழும்பின் நிர்வாக மாவட்டத்திற்கும் அத்தகைய மாவட்டத்தை அண்டிய பிராந்திய நீரிற்கும் பொருந்தும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 14-15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பின் நிர்வாக மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}