{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නිවාස-අමාත්‍යාංශයේ-මහජන-දිනයට-වාසුත්-ඇවිත්/1-618552",
  "time_ut": 1661165354,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශයේ මහජන දිනයට වාසුත් ඇවිත්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vasut has come to the Public Day of the Ministry of Housing",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is special that former minister Vasudeva Nanayakkara, who was an independent member of the opposition, also participated in the Public Day of the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing, which was held today (22) under the chairmanship of Minister Prasanna Ranatunga.",
        "Mr. Nanayakkara presented a problem faced by the people of Nugegoda area to Minister Prasanna Ranatunga.",
        "Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga took steps to solve the problem presented by the MP Vasudeva Nanayakkara within a few minutes.",
        "The presidents, directors general and general managers of 21 institutions under the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing participated in this public day.",
        "Minister Prasanna Ranatunga, who made a statement at the beginning of the People's Day, informed the heads of the institutions to provide solutions to the problems presented by the people on a weekly basis and submit a report to him that same week.",
        "The minister said that the people should never be harassed and emphasized that the officials should ensure that those issues are not presented to the next public day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vasut",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Ministry of Housing",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this public day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that same week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next public day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශයේ මහජන දිනයට වාසුත් ඇවිත්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ  ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද (22) පැවැත්වුණු හැබැයි නාගරික සංවර්ධන සහ නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශයේ   මහජන දිනයට විපක්ෂයේ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු වූ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතාද  සහභාගී වීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "නුගේගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ගැටලුවක් නානායක්කාර මහතා ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග අමාත්‍යවරයාට එහිදී ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ඉදිරිපත් කළ ගැටළුව විනාඩි කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත විසඳා දීමට ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා එහිදී  පියවර ගත්තේය.",
        "මෙම මහජන දිනයට නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ ඇති ආයතන 21ක සභාපතිවරු අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරු සහ සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරු සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "මහජන දිනය ආරම්භ කරමින් ප්‍රකාශයක් කළ අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා ආයතන ප්‍රධානීන්ට දැනුම් දුන්නේ ජනතාව සතිපතා ඉදිරිපත්කරන ගැටලුවලට ඒ සතියෙම විසඳුම් ලබාදී තමාට වාර්තාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "කිසි විටෙකත් ජනතාව රස්තියාදු නොකළ යුතු බව කියා සිටි  අමාත්‍යවරයා එම ගැටළු ඊළඟ මහජන දිනයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකිරීමට  නිලධාරීන් වග බලා ගත යුතු බවද අවධාරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වාසුත්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවාස අමාත්යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මහජන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම සතියේම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ මහජන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வீட்டு வசதி அமைச்சகத்தின் பொது தினத்திற்கு வசுத் வந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தலைமையில் இன்று (22) இடம்பெற்ற நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சின் பொது தின நிகழ்வில் எதிர்க்கட்சியின் சுயேச்சை உறுப்பினராக இருந்த முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்காரவும் கலந்துகொண்டமை விசேட அம்சமாகும்.",
        "நுகேகொட பிரதேச மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினையொன்றை அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்கவிடம் திரு நாணயக்கார முன்வைத்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார முன்வைத்த பிரச்சினையை சில நிமிடங்களில் தீர்க்க திரு.பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்தார்.",
        "இந்த பொது தினத்தில் நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள 21 நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்கள், பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் மற்றும் பொது முகாமையாளர்கள் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "மக்கள் தினத்தை ஆரம்பித்து வைத்து கருத்து வெளியிட்ட அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க, மக்கள் முன்வைக்கும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு வாராந்தம் தீர்வை வழங்குமாறும், அதே வாரத்தில் தமக்கு அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறும் நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்களுக்கு அறிவித்தார்.",
        "மக்கள் ஒருபோதும் துன்புறுத்தப்படக்கூடாது என்று கூறிய அமைச்சர், அந்த பிரச்சினைகள் அடுத்த பொது நாளுக்கு முன்வைக்கப்படாமல் இருப்பதை அதிகாரிகள் உறுதிப்படுத்த வேண்டும் என்றும் வலியுறுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வசுத்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த பொது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த பொது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}