{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පාර්ලිමේන්තු-කමිටු--රැස්වීම්-නවතී/101-616248",
  "time_ut": 1657535619,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටු  රැස්වීම් නවතී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliamentary committee meetings stopped",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Considering the current situation in the country, the committee meetings of the Parliament have also been temporarily stopped.",
        "Ceylon Petroleum Statutory Corporation, Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Company and the chairpersons of the Public Utilities Commission were scheduled to be called before the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE Committee) of the Parliament tomorrow (12) at 10.00 am, but due to the current political situation in the country, it was decided not to hold the meeting. That was done by the Chairman of the Committee, Member of Parliament Professor Charita Herath.",
        "Due to the private statement made by the Chairman of Sri Lanka Public Utilities Commission in the last COP committee meeting, a great controversy arose in the country regarding the price of petroleum. Accordingly, the COPE Committee had decided to invite the Chairman of the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka and the heads of the Petroleum Statutory Corporation to investigate the matter.",
        "Mr. Charathi Herath further said that it was decided to hold the COP committee meeting after the situation in the country calmed down."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Statutory Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminal Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the COPE Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Statutory Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Charathi Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටු  රැස්වීම් නවතී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ පවතින තත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කමිටු  රැස්වීම්ද තාවකාලිකව නතර කර ඇත.",
        "ලංකා ඛණිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව, ලංකා ඛණිජ තෙල් තොග ගබඩා පර්යන්ත සමාගම සහ මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරුන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (කෝප් කමිටුව)  හමුවට  හෙට  (12) පෙරවරු 10.00 ට කැඳවීමට නියමිතව තිබූ නමුත්  රටේ පවතින ‍දේශපාලන තත්වය හේතුකොටගෙන එම රැස්වීම නොපැවැත්වීමට තීරණය කළ බව  කමිටුවේ   සභාපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය   චරිත හේරත් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගීතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා පසුගිය කෝප් කමිටු රැස්වීමේදී කළ   පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රකාශය හේතු කොටගෙන ඛණිජ තෙල් මිල සම්බන්ධයෙන්  රට තුළ විශාල ආන්දෝලනාත්මක තත්වයක් උද්ගත විය. මේ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගීතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා සහ  ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ ප්‍රධානීන් කැඳවා ඒ ගැන විමර්ශන පැවැත්වීමට කෝප් කමිටුව තීරණය කර තිබිණ.",
        "රටේ තත්වය සමනය වූ පසු  කෝප් කමිටු රැස්වීම පැවැත්වීමට තීරණය කළ බවද චරිත හේරත් මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් ගබඩා පර්යන්ත සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චරති හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக் கூட்டங்கள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலவரத்தை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் குழு கூட்டங்களும் தற்காலிகமாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியம் சட்டப்பூர்வ கூட்டுத்தாபனம், இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய சேமிப்பு முனைய நிறுவனம் மற்றும் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர்கள் நாளை (12) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பொது அலுவல் குழுவிற்கு (COP குழு) அழைக்கப்படவிருந்தனர், ஆனால் தற்போதைய அரசியல் சூழ்நிலை காரணமாக நாடு, கூட்டத்தை நடத்த வேண்டாம் என்று முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.அதை குழுவின் தலைவர், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத் செய்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் கடந்த COP குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவித்த தனிப்பட்ட கருத்து காரணமாக, பெற்றோலியத்தின் விலை தொடர்பில் நாட்டில் பெரும் சர்ச்சை எழுந்தது. இதன்படி, இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பெற்றோலிய சட்டக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தலைவர்களை விசாரணைக்கு அழைக்க கோப் குழு தீர்மானித்திருந்தது.",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் சூழல் சுமுகமான பின்னர் COP குழு கூட்டத்தை நடத்த தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டதாக திரு.சாரதி ஹேரத் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியம் சட்டப்பூர்வ கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய சேமிப்பு முனைய நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் சட்டப்பூர்வ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரதி ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}