{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජනපති-තෝරන-ඡන්දයට-සියල්ල-සුදානම්/1-616713",
  "time_ut": 1658285946,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති තෝරන ඡන්දයට සියල්ල සුදානම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Everything is ready for the election of the President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The decisive vote to choose the new president will be held in Parliament this morning.",
        "Parliamentary Secretary General Dhammika Dasanayake said that all arrangements have been made for the polling. Three candidates are competing for the presidency.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, Dallas Alahapperuma and National People's Power Party leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake are the three candidates. Due to this poll, measures have been taken to double the security of the Parliament and its surrounding areas.",
        "The police said that special security will be provided to the MPs coming for the polling."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People's Power Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති තෝරන ඡන්දයට සියල්ල සුදානම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අභිනව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනෙන තීරණාත්මක ඡන්ද විමසීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අද පෙරවරුවේ පැවැත්වේ.",
        "ඡන්ද විමසීම සඳහා සියලු කටයුතු සූදානම් කර ඇතැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා පැවසීය. ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා අපේක්ෂකයෝ තිදෙනෙක් තරග වදිති.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ ජාතික ජන බලවේගය පක්ෂයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක එම අපේක්ෂකයන් තිදෙනාය. මෙම ඡන්ද විමසීම හේතුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශවල ආරක්ෂාව දෙගුණයකින් වැඩි කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඡන්ද විමසීම සඳහා පැමිණෙන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ටද විශේෂ ආරක්ෂාව ලබාදෙන බව පොලිසිය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலுக்கு எல்லாம் தயாராகிவிட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான தீர்மான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "வாக்குப்பதிவுக்கான அனைத்து ஏற்பாடுகளும் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக நாடாளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு 3 பேர் போட்டியிடுகின்றனர்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகிய மூவரும் போட்டியிடுகின்றனர். இந்த வாக்கெடுப்பின் காரணமாக நாடாளுமன்றம் மற்றும் அதனை சுற்றியுள்ள பகுதிகளின் பாதுகாப்பை இரட்டிப்பாக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வாக்குப்பதிவுக்கு வரும் எம்.பி.க்களுக்கு சிறப்பு பாதுகாப்பு அளிக்கப்படும் என போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}