{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Around-250-Kandakadu-detainees-arrested/108-240048",
  "time_ut": 1656518112,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Around 250 Kandakadu detainees arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Around 250 Kandakadu detainees arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Reports reached that 248 detainees at the Kandakadu Rehabilitation Centre  have been arrested, however search operations are underway to apprehend more than 200 more inmates who fled the Centre this morning, Police said.",
        "Police Spokesman SSP Nihal Thalduwa said there was an unpleasant situation arose between the security forces and a group of inmates who subsequently escaped.",
        "However, the police and the security forces were able to control the situation in which the detainees surrendered to the Pulasthipura Police Station.",
        "Tension flared up at the Kandakadu Rehabilitation Centre since last night following  the death of an inmate.",
        "As a result, about 600 detainees broke through the two main gates of the Centre this morning and fled.",
        "The spokesman said that the deceased has been identified as 35-year old, a resident of Haliela.",
        "Meanwhile, SSP Thalduwa said around 300 inmates at the Centre had taken the body of deceased when police tried to take the corpse following the magisterial inquiry this evening.",
        "Meanwhile, Commissioner General of Rehabilitation Dharshana Hettiarachchi said that an impartial inquiry is being conducted into the death of the detainee. (Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "248",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandakadu Rehabilitation Centre  ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Pulasthipura Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kandakadu Rehabilitation Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35-year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haliela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Thalduwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharshana Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්දකාඩු රැඳවියන් 250ක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ රඳවා සිටි රැඳවියන් 248 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බවට වාර්තා වූ නමුත් අද උදෑසන එම මධ්‍යස්ථානයෙන් පලා ගිය තවත් රැඳවියන් 200 කට වැඩි පිරිසක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුම් ක්‍රියාත්මක බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල් තල්දූව පැවසුවේ, ආරක්ෂක අංශ සහ රැඳවියන් පිරිසක් අතර නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් ඇති වූ අතර පසුව පලා ගිය බව ය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එම රැඳවියන් පුලස්තිපුර පොලිස් ස්ථානයට භාර වූ තත්ත්වය පාලනය කිරීමට පොලීසිය සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ සමත් වුණා.",
        "රැඳවියෙකු මියයාමත් සමඟ කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ සිට නොසන්සුන්තාවක් හටගත්තා.",
        "මේ හේතුවෙන් අද පෙරවරුවේ එම මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ ප්‍රධාන ගේට්ටු දෙක කඩා රැඳවියන් 600ක් පමණ පළා ගියහ.",
        "මිය ගොස් ඇත්තේ 35 හැවිරිදි හාලිඇල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී තල්දූව පැවසුවේ, අද සවස මහේස්ත්‍රාත් පරීක්ෂණයෙන් අනතුරුව පොලිසිය විසින් මෘත ශරීරය රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී එම මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ රැඳවියන් 300ක් පමණ මියගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ සිරුර රැගෙන ගොස් ඇති බව ය.",
        "මේ අතර, පුනරුත්ථාපන කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් දර්ශන හෙට්ටිආරච්චි කියා සිටියේ රැඳවියාගේ මරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බවයි. (දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "248",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුලස්තිපුර පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "600 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාලිඇල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී තල්දූව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දර්ශන හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுமார் 250 கண்டக்காடு கைதிகள் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கந்தகாடு புனர்வாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் 248 கைதிகள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தகவல்கள் கிடைத்துள்ளன, எனினும் இன்று காலை மையத்திலிருந்து தப்பிச் சென்ற மேலும் 200க்கும் மேற்பட்ட கைதிகளை கைது செய்வதற்கான தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படையினருக்கும், பின்னர் தப்பியோடிய கைதிகள் குழுவிற்கும் இடையில் விரும்பத்தகாத சூழ்நிலை ஏற்பட்டதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிஹால் தல்துவா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் புலஸ்திபுர பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் சரணடைந்த நிலைமையை பொலிஸாரும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரும் கட்டுப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "கந்தகாடு புனர்வாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் கைதி ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து நேற்று இரவு முதல் பதற்றம் நிலவியது.",
        "இதனையடுத்து இன்று காலை சுமார் 600 கைதிகள் மையத்தின் இரண்டு பிரதான வாயில்களை உடைத்துக்கொண்டு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் ஹாலிஎல பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 35 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இன்று மாலை மாஜிஸ்திரேட் விசாரணையைத் தொடர்ந்து போலீசார் சடலத்தை எடுக்க முயன்றபோது, ​​​​மையத்தில் இருந்த சுமார் 300 கைதிகள் இறந்தவரின் உடலை எடுத்துச் சென்றதாக எஸ்எஸ்பி தல்துவா கூறினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, கைதானவரின் மரணம் தொடர்பில் பக்கச்சார்பற்ற விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட்டு வருவதாக புனர்வாழ்வு ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் தர்ஷன ஹெட்டியாராச்சி தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "248",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தகாடு மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "புலஸ்திபுரா காவல் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கந்தகாடு மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாலியேலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி தல்துவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷன ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}