{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පොහොර-නැවේ-හබයේ-දී-’’යාලුකම’’-රකින-වගකීම-විදේශ-අමාත්‍යාංශයට/101-619311",
  "time_ut": 1662355692,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොර නැවේ හබයේ දී ’’යාලුකම’’ රකින වගකීම විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs is responsible for maintaining \"friendship\" at the oar of the fertilizer ship",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Conservation, Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera said that it has been decided to entrust the preparation of a process to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in order to deal with the problem of the Chinese fertilizer ship in a way that does not damage the friendship between the two countries.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture said that President Ranil Wickremesinghe's position in the matter regarding this fertilizer ship is to resolve the issue in such a way that the friendly relations between the two countries are not damaged.",
        "Speaking to the media regarding the special report issued by the Auditor General, the minister said this regarding the fertilizer ship bought by China's Qingdao Sea Win Biotech Institute.",
        "The Minister said that whoever was involved in the transaction related to this fertilizer ship, the burden of the 6.9 million dollars paid for the ship was ultimately borne by the people of the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Forest Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Sea Win Biotech Institute",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 6.9 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොර නැවේ හබයේ දී ’’යාලුකම’’ රකින වගකීම විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීන පොහොර නැව සම්බන්ධව ගැටළුවේ දී දෙරට මිත්‍රත්වය පළුදු නොවන ආකාරයට කටයුතු කිරීම සඳහා  ක්‍රියාවලියක් සැකසීම විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශයට බාර දීමට  තීරණය කර ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම වනජීවී සහ වන සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම පොහොර නැව සම්බන්ධයෙන් කාරණයේ දී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ  ස්ථාවරය වන්නේ දෙරට අතර ඇති මිත්‍ර සබඳතා පළුදු නොවන ආකාරයට ගැටළුව විසඳා ගැනීම බවද කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "චීනයේ Qingdao Sea win Biotech ආයතනය මගින් මිල දී ගන්නා ලද පොහොර නැව සම්බන්ධයෙන් එම සමාගමට නඩු පවරන්නැයි විගණකාධිපතිවරයා විසින් නිකුත් කර ඇති විශේෂ වාර්තාව සම්බන්ධව මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ අදහස් දක්වමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා මෙි බව කීය.",
        "මෙම පොහොර නැව සම්බන්ධ ගනුදෙනුවට කවුරු සම්බන්ධ වුනත් අවසානයේ  නැවට ගෙවන ලද ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9ක බර පැටවුනේ රටේ ජනතාවට බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වන සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Sea Win Biotech Institute",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உரக் கப்பலின் துடுப்பில் \"நட்பை\" பேணுவதற்கு வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் பொறுப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீன உரக் கப்பலில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையிலான செயற்பாடுகளை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சிடம் ஒப்படைப்பதற்கு தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக விவசாய, வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வனப் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார். இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான நட்புறவை சேதப்படுத்தாது.",
        "இந்த உரக்கப்பல் தொடர்பான விடயத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் நிலைப்பாடாக இரு நாடுகளுக்குமிடையிலான நட்புறவு பாதிக்கப்படாத வகையில் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வுகாண வேண்டும் என விவசாய அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள விசேட அறிக்கை தொடர்பில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த அமைச்சர், சீனாவின் Qingdao Sea Win Biotech Institute கொள்வனவு செய்த உரக்கப்பல் தொடர்பில் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த உரக்கப்பல் தொடர்பான கொடுக்கல் வாங்கலில் யார் ஈடுபட்டிருந்தாலும், கப்பலுக்காக செலுத்தப்பட்ட 6.9 மில்லியன் டொலர்களின் சுமையை இறுதியில் நாட்டு மக்களே சுமந்ததாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வன பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Sea Win Biotech Institute",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}