{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/President-Ramaphosa-keen-to-further-enhance-ties-with-Sri-Lanka/56-739106",
  "time_ut": 1661469047,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Ramaphosa keen to further enhance ties with Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Ramaphosa keen to further enhance ties with Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "South African President Matamela Cyril Ramaphosa expressed desire to further enhance the existing close ties between South Africa and Sri Lanka.",
        "Extending his congratulations and best wishes to President Ranil Wickremesinghe on his appointment as the President of Sri Lanka, he noted that South Africa attached great importance to its relationship with Sri Lanka, which was underscored by strong bonds of solidarity, friendship and mutual understanding.",
        "President Ramaphosa also said he looked forward to further enhancing longstanding cooperation between the two countries.",
        "The South African President wished President Wickremesinghe good health and reaffirmed his desire to further enhance and consolidate the excellent bond of friendship that currently exists between the two"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ramaphosa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matamela Cyril Ramaphosa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "solidarity",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramaphosa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සබඳතා තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කර ගැනීමට ජනාධිපති රමපෝසා උනන්දු වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දකුණු අප්‍රිකාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර පවතින සමීප සබඳතා තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කර ගැනීමට දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු ජනාධිපති මතමෙලා සිරිල් රමපෝසා කැමැත්ත පළ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත්වීම පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සිය සුබ පැතුම් සහ සුබ පැතුම් එක් කළ ඔහු, සහයෝගීතාවය, මිත්‍රත්වය සහ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය අවබෝධය යන ශක්තිමත් බැඳීම්වලින් අවධාරනය කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ ඇති සම්බන්ධතාවයට දකුණු අප්‍රිකාව විශාල වැදගත්කමක් ලබා දුන් බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "දෙරට අතර දීර්ඝ කාලීන සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කර ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ද ජනාධිපති රමෆෝසා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට නිදුක් නිරෝගී බව ප්‍රාර්ථනා කළ දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඔවුන් දෙදෙනා අතර දැනට පවතින විශිෂ්ට මිත්‍රත්වය තවදුරටත් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට සහ තහවුරු කිරීමට තමාගේ අභිලාෂය යළිත් තහවුරු කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රමෆෝසා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මතමෙල සිරිල් රමපෝසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහයෝගීතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රමෆෝසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையுடனான உறவுகளை மேலும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதி ரமபோசா ஆர்வமாக உள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தென்னாபிரிக்காவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் தற்போதுள்ள நெருங்கிய உறவுகளை மேலும் மேம்படுத்த விரும்புவதாக தென்னாபிரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி மாடமெல சிறில் ரமபோசா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு தனது வாழ்த்துக்களையும் வாழ்த்துக்களையும் தெரிவித்த அவர், இலங்கையுடனான தனது உறவுக்கு தென்னாபிரிக்கா அதிக முக்கியத்துவம் அளித்துள்ளதாகவும், இது வலுவான ஒற்றுமை, நட்பு மற்றும் பரஸ்பர புரிந்துணர்வு ஆகியவற்றால் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டப்பட்டது என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான நீண்டகால ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி ரமபோசா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தென்னாபிரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி, ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு நல்ல ஆரோக்கியம் இருப்பதாக வாழ்த்தியதுடன், தற்போது இருவருக்குமிடையில் நிலவும் சிறந்த நட்புறவை மேலும் மேம்படுத்தி பலப்படுத்துவதற்கான தனது விருப்பத்தை மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரமபோசா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதமேலா சிரில் ரமபோசா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒற்றுமை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரமபோசா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}