{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83877/india-hands-over-humanitarian-aid-valued-at-over-rs-34-billion-to-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1658817420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India hands over humanitarian aid valued at over Rs 3.4 billion to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India hands over humanitarian aid valued at over Rs 3.4 billion to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay today handed over humanitarian supplies valued at over Rs. 3.4 billion, donated by the government of Tamil Nadu, to the Sri Lankan government.",
        "The donations were handed over to the Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry and Health Minsiter Keheliya Rambukwella in Colombo today in the presence of MPs and other dignitaries, the High Commission said.",
        "In a twitter message, it said donations of 40,000 metric tonnes of rice, 500 metric tonnes of milk powder and more than 100 metric tonnes of medicines whose combined worth is around USD 22 million has come in from Tamil Nadu.",
        "“Coming together of the people and Government of India for the people of Sri Lanka.”",
        "“High Commissioner handed over humanitarian supplies valued at over SLR 3.4 billion donated by Government of Tamil Nadu to Hon’ble Ministers Ali Sabry and Keheliya Rambukwella in Colombo today in the presence of MPs and other dignitaries.”",
        "“Donation of 40,000 MT rice, 500 MT milk powder and more than 100 MT of medicines whose combined worth is around USD 22 million has come in from Tamil Nadu,” it said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health Minsiter Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව රුපියල් බිලියන 3.4කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් මානුෂීය ආධාර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට භාර දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ මහතා විසින් රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් මානුෂීය ද්‍රව්‍ය තොගයක් අද භාරදුන්නා. තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද රුපියල් බිලියන 3.4 කි.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල යන මහත්වරුන් වෙත මෙම පරිත්‍යාග අද කොළඹදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඇතුළු ප්‍රභූන් ඉදිරියේ භාරදුන් බව මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින්, සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100 කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් තමිල්නාඩුවෙන් පරිත්‍යාග කර ඇති අතර ඒවායේ ඒකාබද්ධ වටිනාකම ඩොලර් මිලියන 22 ක් පමණ වේ.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් ජනතාව සහ ඉන්දීය රජය එක්ව සිටීම.\"",
        "\"තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් බිලියන 3.4 කට වැඩි වටිනාකමකින් යුත් මානුෂීය ද්‍රව්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා විසින් ගරු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන අලි සබ්රි සහ කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල වෙත අද කොළඹ දී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රභූන් ඉදිරියේ භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "“සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100 කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම තමිල්නාඩුවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 22 ක් පමණ වන බව එහි සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "3.4 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே இன்று 1000 கோடி ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான மனிதாபிமான பொருட்களை கையளித்தார். 3.4 பில்லியன், தமிழக அரசால், இலங்கை அரசுக்கு நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த நன்கொடைகள் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல ஆகியோரிடம் இன்று கொழும்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் முக்கியஸ்தர்கள் முன்னிலையில் கையளிக்கப்பட்டதாக உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ட்விட்டர் செய்தியில், தமிழகத்தில் இருந்து 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 100 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகளின் மொத்த மதிப்பு சுமார் 22 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் நன்கொடையாக வந்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இலங்கை மக்களுக்காக இந்திய அரசும் மக்களும் ஒன்றுபடுவோம்.\"",
        "“தமிழ்நாடு அரசாங்கத்தினால் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட SLR 3.4 பில்லியன் பெறுமதியான மனிதாபிமான பொருட்களை உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் இன்று கொழும்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் முக்கியஸ்தர்கள் முன்னிலையில் கௌரவ அமைச்சர்களான அலி சப்ரி மற்றும் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல அவர்களிடம் கையளித்தார்.",
        "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 100 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகளின் மொத்த மதிப்பு சுமார் 22 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் தமிழ்நாட்டிலிருந்து வந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 மெட்ரிக் டன்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}