{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/චීන-තානාපති-මහා-නාහිමිවරුන්-බැහැ-දකියි/101-618873",
  "time_ut": 1661679650,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීන තානාපති මහා නාහිමිවරුන් බැහැ දකියි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Chinese ambassador visits the great bishops",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese Ambassador Chi Shenhong said in Kandy that the Chinese government will continue to support Sri Lanka to rescue it from the temporary economic crisis it is currently facing.",
        "Malwatu Asgiri emphasized this after visiting the patriarchs.",
        "Although the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka will not end overnight, the Chinese government believes that Sri Lanka will be able to get out of it within a short reasonable time.",
        "In addition to the Chinese government's cooperation aid grant, the Chinese Buddhist Association has planned a program to provide aid for the revival of temples and Buddhism in this country.",
        "Although various changes took place in Sri Lanka, there was no change in Sri Lanka China friendship. The aim of the Chinese government is to maintain bilateral relations between the two countries. We believe that Sri Lanka has the ability to get out of the difficult situation. The ambassador added that the Chinese government will also support it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malwatu Asgiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Buddhist Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන තානාපති මහා නාහිමිවරුන් බැහැ දකියි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වන විට මුහුණ දී තිබෙන තාවකාලික ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මුදවා ගැනීම සඳහා චීන රජයේ  සහයෝගය අඛණ්ඩ හිමිවන බව චීන තානාපති චී ෂෙන්හොං මහතා මහනුවර දී පැවසීය.",
        "මල්වතු අස්ගිරි මහනාහිමිවරුන් බැහැදැකීමෙන් අනතුරුව මේ බව අවධාරණය කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මේ වන පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය එක් රැයකින් නිමා නොවුණත් කෙටි සාධාරණ කාලයක් තුළදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන් මිදීමට හැකියාව පවතින බව චීන රජයේ විශ්වාසයයි .",
        "චීන රජයේ සහයෝගිතා ආධාර ප්‍රදානයට අමතරව චීන බෞද්ධ සංගමය මගින් මෙරට විහාරස්ථාන හා බුදු දහමේ පුනර්ජීවනය උදෙසා ආධාර ලබාදීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සැලසුම් කොට තිබෙනවා .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ විවිධ වෙනස්කම් සිදු වුවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා චීන මිත්‍රත්වය තුළ කිසිදු වෙනස්වීමක් සිදු වූයේ නැහැ. දෙරට අතර දී ද්විපාක්ෂික සම්බන්ධතා අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වා ගැනීම චීන රජයේ අරමුණයි . පවතින අසීරු තත්ත්වයෙන් මිදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකියාව තිබෙන බව අපගේ විශ්වාසයයි . එය සඳහා චීන රජයේ නොමද සහය පළ කරන බවද තානාපති වරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්වතු අස්ගිරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන බෞද්ධ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன தூதர் பெரிய ஆயர்களை சந்திக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கும் தற்காலிக பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீட்பதற்கு சீன அரசாங்கம் தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என சீன தூதுவர் சி ஷென்ஹோங் கண்டியில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மல்வத்து அஸ்கிரி பீடாதிபதிகளை பார்வையிட்டதன் பின்னர் இதனை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி ஒரே இரவில் முடிவுக்கு வராது என்றாலும், குறுகிய காலத்துக்குள் அதிலிருந்து இலங்கை மீள முடியும் என சீன அரசாங்கம் நம்புகிறது.",
        "சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் ஒத்துழைப்பு உதவி மானியத்திற்கு மேலதிகமாக, சீன பௌத்த சங்கம் இந்த நாட்டில் கோவில்கள் மற்றும் பௌத்தத்தின் மறுமலர்ச்சிக்கான உதவிகளை வழங்கும் திட்டத்தை திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் பல்வேறு மாற்றங்கள் ஏற்பட்டாலும், இலங்கை சீன நட்புறவில் எந்த மாற்றமும் ஏற்படவில்லை. இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை பேணுவதே சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் நோக்கமாகும். இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்து வெளியேறும் திறன் இலங்கைக்கு இருப்பதாக நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். சீன அரசாங்கமும் அதற்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்றும் தூதுவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மல்வத்து அஸ்கிரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன புத்த சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}