{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/වී-මිල-අඩුවෙලා-පොලොන්නරුව-ගොවීන්-ගැටලුවක/11-396555",
  "time_ut": 1661247448,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වී මිල අඩුවෙලා පොලොන්නරුව ගොවීන් ගැටලුවක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Polonnaruwa farmers are in trouble as paddy prices have dropped",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena said today (23) in Polonnaruwa that the farmer is in a serious crisis due to the decrease in the price of paddy.",
        "Also, he said that the development projects started in Polonnaruwa when he was the president were in ruins and he spoke strongly to the parliament, the government and the media and it was not his fault.",
        "According to this, the administrative building complex built in Polonnaruwa is currently growing wild and the former president made these comments when he met journalists in Polonnaruwa to urgently inform about it.",
        "\"The people of Polonnaruwa know that I have done a huge amount of work. I am not going to tell each other. It is now August, but the lakes in Polonnaruwa are full and all the canals are flowing. This has happened because the Moragaha Kanda Kalu Gaga reservoirs were built. I am now everywhere in the villages of the district yesterday. Yesterday, a serious issue has arisen especially regarding the decrease in the price of paddy.",
        "The farmers of the Batticaloa district came and met me yesterday, representatives of the farmers' organizations. They say that as soon as one acre is cultivated, one lakh rupees will be lost. Now everywhere in Polonnaruwa, the farmers are saying that they are losing so much from paddy. Therefore, the farmer is in serious trouble.",
        "The government should focus on this, the Ministry of Agriculture should focus on this, the Ministry of Finance should focus on this and give relief to the farmers, otherwise the farmers will not do farming."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalu Gaga reservoirs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one acre",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වී මිල අඩුවෙලා පොලොන්නරුව ගොවීන් ගැටලුවක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වී මිල අඩුවීම පිළිබඳව ගොවියා දැඩි අර්බුදයකින් පසුවන බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා අද (23) පොළොන්නරුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එසේම තමන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිටි කාලේ පොලොන්නරුවේ ආරම්භ කළ සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති නටබුන් වීමත් තමන්  පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සමඟත් රජය සමඟත් මාධ්‍යයටත් දැඩිව කතා කරන බවත් එය තමන්ගේ වරදක් නොවන බවත් ඔහු පැවැසීය.",
        "මේ අනුය පොළොන්නරුවේ ඉදි කරන ලද පරිපාලන ගොඩනැගිලි සංකීර්ණය මේ වන විට වල් බිහිවෙමින් පවතින අතර ඒ පිළිබඳව හදිසියේ දැනුවත් කිරීමට මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පොළොන්නරුවේ දී හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේය.",
        "\"පොලොන්නරුවේ ජනතාව දන්නවා මම අති විශාල වැඩ කොටසක් කෙරුවා කියන එක.ඒව මං එකිනෙක කියන්න යන්නෑ දැන් අගෝස්තු මාසේ වෙලා නමුත් පොලොන්නරුවේ වැව් පිරිලා ඇලවල් ඔක්කොම ගලාගෙන යනවා. එහෙම වෙලා තියෙන්නෙ මොරගහ කන්ද කලු ගග ජලාශ හදපු නිසා.  මම දැන් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ගම්මාන වල හැම තැනම ඊයේ පෙරේදා ගියා විශේෂයෙන්ම වී මිල අඩුවීම පිළිබඳව බරපතළ ප්‍රශ්නයක් මතුවෙලා තිබෙනවා.",
        "මඩකලපුවේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ගොවීන් ඇවිල්ල පෙරේදා මාව හම්බුනා  ඒ ගොවි සංවිධානවල නියෝජිතයින්. අක්කරයක් කරපු වහාම රුපියල් ලක්ෂයක් පාඩුයි කියලා ඒ අය කියනවා.දැන් පොළොන්නරුවේත් හැමතැනම ගොවීන් කියන්නේ වී වලින් මෙච්චර මෙච්චර පාඩු වෙනවා කියලා.ඉතින් ඒ නිසා ගොවියා බරපතළ අමාරුවක වැටිලා තිබෙනවා.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳව රජයේ අවධානය යොමු කරලා කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අවධානය යොමු කරලා මුදල් අමාත්‍යංශයේ අවධානය යොමුකර එය ගොවිජනතාවට සහනයක් දෙන්න නැත්නම් ලබන කන්නේ ගොවීන් ගොවිතැන් කටයුතු කරන්නේ නැහැ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ගග ජලාශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කරයක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெல் விலை வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளதால் பொலன்னறுவை விவசாயிகள் சிரமத்தில் உள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெல் விலை குறைந்துள்ளதால் விவசாயி கடும் நெருக்கடிக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன இன்று (23) பொலன்னறுவையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அத்துடன், தான் ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்தபோது பொலன்னறுவையில் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டங்கள் பாழடைந்து காணப்படுவதாகவும், நாடாளுமன்றம், அரசாங்கம், ஊடகங்கள் போன்றவற்றில் கடுமையாகப் பேசியதாகவும், அது தனது தவறில்லை எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதன்படி பொலன்னறுவையில் நிர்மாணிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிர்வாக கட்டிடத் தொகுதி தற்போது காடுகளாக வளர்ந்து வருவதாகவும், அது தொடர்பில் அவசரமாக அறிவிப்பதற்காக பொலன்னறுவையில் ஊடகவியலாளர்களை சந்தித்த போதே முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நான் பெரிய அளவில் வேலை செய்துள்ளேன் என்பது பொலன்னறுவை மக்களுக்கு தெரியும், நான் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் சொல்லப் போவதில்லை, இப்போது ஆகஸ்ட், ஆனால் பொலன்னறுவையில் உள்ள ஏரிகள் நிரம்பியுள்ளன, அனைத்து கால்வாய்களும் பாய்கின்றன. மொரகஹாவால் இது நடந்தது. கந்தகளுக் காக நீர்த்தேக்கங்கள் நிர்மாணிக்கப்பட்டன.இப்போது மாவட்டத்தின் அனைத்து கிராமங்களிலும் நேற்று நான்.நேற்று குறிப்பாக நெல் விலை வீழ்ச்சி தொடர்பில் பாரிய பிரச்சினை எழுந்துள்ளது.",
        "நேற்று மட்டக்களப்பு மாவட்ட விவசாயிகள் விவசாய அமைப்புகளின் பிரதிநிதிகள் என்னை வந்து சந்தித்தனர். ஒரு ஏக்கர் பயிரிட்டால் ஒரு இலட்சம் ரூபா நஷ்டம் ஏற்படும் என கூறுகின்றனர்.இப்போது பொலன்னறுவை எங்கும் நெற்பயிர்களால் இவ்வளவு நஷ்டம் ஏற்படுவதாக விவசாயிகள் கூறுகின்றனர்.இதனால் விவசாயி கடும் சிரமத்திற்குள்ளாகியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதில் அரசு கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டும், விவசாய அமைச்சகம் இதில் கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டும், நிதி அமைச்சகம் இதில் கவனம் செலுத்தி விவசாயிகளுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்க வேண்டும், இல்லையெனில் விவசாயிகள் விவசாயம் செய்ய மாட்டார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலு காகா நீர்த்தேக்கங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}