{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Leave-aside-party-politics-and-lets-join-hands-to-resolve-burning-issues-RW-writes-to-Sajith/342-237033",
  "time_ut": 1652512579,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Leave aside party politics and lets join hands to resolve burning issues - RW writes to Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Leave aside party politics and lets join hands to resolve burning issues - RW writes to Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has invited the Samagi Jana Balawegaya(SJB) to join hands with the new government to resolve burning issues, leaving aside party politics.",
        "In a letter to the Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, the Prime Minister invited the SJB to support the joint effort made by them to immediately resolve the burning issues faced by the people and also to stabilize the country economically, politically and socially by obtaining foreign assistance.",
        "The Prime Minister has also sought the Opposition Leader's positive and swift response as the future of the country was facing a serious situation day by day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balawegaya(SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ දේශපාලනය පසෙකලා දැවෙන ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට අත්වැල් බැඳ ගනිමු - RW සජිත්ට ලියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පක්ෂ දේශපාලනය පසෙකලා දැවෙන ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට නව රජය සමඟ අත්වැල් බැඳ ගන්නා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමගි ජන බලවේගයට ආරාධනා කර තිබේ.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා වෙත ලිපියක් යවමින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා එස්.ජේ.බී.ට ආරාධනා කළේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන දැවෙන ප්‍රශ්න වහා විසඳා විදේශ ආධාර ලබාගෙන රට ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජීය වශයෙන් ස්ථාවර කිරීමට ගන්නා ඒකාබද්ධ උත්සාහයට සහාය දෙන ලෙසයි.",
        "රටේ අනාගතය දිනෙන් දින බරපතළ තත්ත්වයකට මුහුණ පා සිටින බැවින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගේ ධනාත්මක සහ ඉක්මන් ප්‍රතිචාරය ද අපේක්ෂා කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சி அரசியலை விட்டுவிட்டு எரியும் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க கைகோர்ப்போம் - RW சஜித்துக்கு கடிதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்சி அரசியலை தவிர்த்து எரியும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண புதிய அரசாங்கத்துடன் கைகோர்க்குமாறு பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) க்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவுக்கு எழுதியுள்ள கடிதத்தில், மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் எரியும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு உடனடியாகத் தீர்வு காண்பதற்கும் வெளிநாட்டு உதவிகளைப் பெற்று நாட்டை பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக ரீதியில் ஸ்திரப்படுத்துவதற்கும் மேற்கொள்ளும் கூட்டு முயற்சிக்கு ஆதரவு வழங்குமாறும் SJBக்கு பிரதமர் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டின் எதிர்காலம் நாளுக்கு நாள் பாரதூரமான சூழ்நிலையை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் நேர்மறையான மற்றும் விரைவான பதிலையும் பிரதமர் கோரியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா (SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}