{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/IMF-සමග-සාකච්ඡා-සාර්ථකයි/11-396750",
  "time_ut": 1661870097,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "IMF සමග සාකච්ඡා සාර්ථකයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Negotiations with the IMF are successful",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe says that Sri Lanka has made \"good progress\" in negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to obtain an extended credit facility.",
        "“I can state that we have made good progress in the discussions with the International Monetary Fund. Hopefully, we will be able to reach the first milestone, which is a staff-level agreement with the IMF,” the central bank governor said. He said this at a press conference held in Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF සමග සාකච්ඡා සාර්ථකයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විස්තීරණ ණය පහසුකමක් ලබා ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “හොඳ ප්‍රගතියක්” ලබා ඇති බව මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "“ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලදී අපි හොඳ ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇති බව මට ප්‍රකාශ කළ හැකියි. IMF සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් වන පළමු සන්ධිස්ථානයට ලඟා වීමට අපට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,” යැයි මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කරයි. කොළඹදී පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ඔහු මේ බව පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF உடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தை வெற்றியடைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட கடன் வசதியைப் பெறுவதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் இலங்கை \"நல்ல முன்னேற்றம்\" அடைந்துள்ளதாக மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான கலந்துரையாடல்களில் நாம் நல்ல முன்னேற்றம் கண்டுள்ளோம் என்பதை என்னால் கூற முடியும். IMF உடனான ஊழியர்கள் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தமான முதல் மைல்கல்லை எங்களால் அடைய முடியும் என்று நம்புகிறோம்,” என்று மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் கூறினார். கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}