{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Basil-paid-Rs-5-3mn-in-cash-to-leave-for-Washington/342-240928",
  "time_ut": 1657639880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Basil paid Rs. 5.3mn in cash to leave for Washington",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Basil paid Rs. 5.3mn in cash to leave for Washington",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "After the attempt by former Minister Basil Rajapaksa to leave the country through the Silk Route Passenger Clearance Terminal was foiled, several details of his immediate airline ticket purchase were also brought to light.",
        "According to information from the Emirates Airlines, a first class GOLD Membership tier ticket was issued for him to travel to Washington from the Bandaranaike International Airport (BIA).",
        "The ticket was issued on July 11, 2022 under the booking reference PCR652 for the flight EK-649. The ticket number was 176 2349819160.",
        "As per details given in the ticket, his first destination was the Dubai International Airport (DXB) from Colombo (CMB). The check-in time was given at 00.15 last night (12) and the departure was at 3.15 am last morning. The first destination to DXB was scheduled to touch down at 6.00 am on the same day.",
        "The second flight would take off from Dubai at 02.25 yesterday and scheduled to land at Dulles International Airport in Washington at 8.45 am today.",
        "However, another ticket was found booked on the same airline to reach Colombo on March 2, 2023, from Washington.",
        "The First Class ticket for the flight EK232 by Emirates Airlines scheduled to leave from Dulles International Airport in Washington on March 2, 2023 at 10.30 am and scheduled to reach Dubai at 8.15 am on March 2, 2023 and again scheduled to reach Colombo at 16.25 on March 2, 2023 after taking off from Dubai on March 02, 2023 at 10.25 am.",
        "A sum of 5.3 million (LKR 5,302,700) was paid in cash for up and down airfare, which is a Flex Plus fare. Flex Plus fare is a totally flexible and unrestricted fare.",
        "According to the ticket fares on Emirates official website, it could see that some fares are same at over 5 million LKR. However, the ticket fare varies day to day based on currency valuations. So Emirates first class ticket fare for yesterday was over Rs.5.3 million. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Basil paid Rs",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Washington",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Silk Route Passenger Clearance Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Emirates Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GOLD Membership",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 11, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dubai International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "00.15 last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.15 am last morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.45 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EK232",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.15 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 02, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,302,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බැසිල් රු. වොෂින්ටනයට යාමට මුදල් මිලියන 5.3 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සේද මාර්ග මගී නිෂ්කාශන පර්යන්තය හරහා හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පිටවීමට දැරූ උත්සාහය ව්‍යර්ථ වීමත් සමඟ ඔහුගේ ක්ෂණික ගුවන් ටිකට්පත් මිලදී ගැනීම පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු කිහිපයක් ද හෙළිදරව් විය.",
        "එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවයේ තොරතුරුවලට අනුව, බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් (BIA) වොෂින්ටනයට යාමට ඔහුට පළමු පන්තියේ GOLD සාමාජිකත්ව පෙළ ටිකට් පතක් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "EK-649 ගුවන් යානය සඳහා PCR652 වෙන්කරවා ගැනීමේ යොමුව යටතේ ටිකට් පත නිකුත් කරන ලද්දේ 2022 ජූලි 11 වැනිදාය. ටිකට් අංකය 176 2349819160 විය.",
        "ටිකට් පතේ දක්වා ඇති විස්තර අනුව, ඔහුගේ පළමු ගමනාන්තය වූයේ කොළඹ (CMB) සිට ඩුබායි ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ (DXB) ය. පෙරේදා (12) රාත්‍රී 00.15 ට ඇතුළු වීමේ වේලාව ලබා දී ඇති අතර පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇත්තේ ඊයේ අලුයම 3.15 ට ය. DXB වෙත පළමු ගමනාන්තය එදිනම උදෑසන 6.00 ට ළඟා වීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි.",
        "දෙවන ගුවන් යානය ඊයේ අලුයම 02.25 ට ඩුබායි සිට පිටත්ව ගොස් අද පෙරවරු 8.45 ට වොෂින්ටනයේ ඩලස් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළට ගොඩ බැස්සවීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, 2023 මාර්තු 2 වන දින වොෂින්ටනයේ සිට කොළඹට පැමිණීමට එම ගුවන් සේවයේම තවත් ටිකට් පතක් වෙන් කරවා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවයේ EK232 ගුවන් යානයේ පළමු පන්තියේ ටිකට් පත 2023 මාර්තු 2 වන දින වොෂින්ටනයේ ඩලස් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පෙරවරු 10.30 ට පිටත් වීමට නියමිත අතර 2023 මාර්තු 2 වන දින පෙ.ව. 8.15 ට ඩුබායි වෙත ළඟා වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ අතර නැවත 16.25 ට කොළඹට ළඟා වීමට නියමිතය. මාර්තු 2, 2023 ඩුබායි සිට 2023 මාර්තු 02 දින පෙ.ව.",
        "Flex Plus ගාස්තුවක් වන ඉහළ සහ පහළ ගුවන් ගාස්තු සඳහා මිලියන 5.3 ක මුදලක් (රුපියල් 5,302,700) මුදල් වශයෙන් ගෙවන ලදී. Flex Plus ගාස්තුව සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම නම්‍යශීලී සහ සීමා රහිත ගාස්තුවකි.",
        "එමිරේට්ස් නිල වෙබ් අඩවියේ ප්‍රවේශපත්‍ර ගාස්තු අනුව, සමහර ගාස්තු රුපියල් මිලියන 5කට වඩා සමාන බව දැකගත හැකිය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ප්‍රවේශපත්‍ර ගාස්තුව මුදල් වටිනාකම් මත පදනම්ව දිනෙන් දින වෙනස් වේ. ඉතින් ඊයේ දිනයේ එමිරේට්ස් පළමු පන්තියේ ටිකට් ගාස්තුව රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 53කට අධිකයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැසිල් රු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේද මාර්ගයේ මගී නිෂ්කාශන පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GOLD සාමාජිකත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ රාත්‍රී 00.15",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය අලුයම 3.15 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව.8.45",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EK232",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව.8.15",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මාර්තු 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,302,700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பசில் ரூ. வாஷிங்டனுக்குச் செல்ல 5.3 மில்லியன் பணம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச பட்டுப்பாதை பயணிகள் அனுமதி முனையத்தின் ஊடாக நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற முயற்சித்ததை அடுத்து, அவர் உடனடியாக விமானப் பயணச்சீட்டு கொள்வனவு செய்தமை தொடர்பிலும் பல தகவல்கள் வெளியாகியுள்ளன.",
        "எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் தகவலின்படி, பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து (BIA) வாஷிங்டனுக்கு செல்வதற்காக முதல் வகுப்பு கோல்ட் உறுப்பினர் அடுக்கு டிக்கெட் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "EK-649 விமானத்திற்கான முன்பதிவு குறிப்பு PCR652 இன் கீழ் ஜூலை 11, 2022 அன்று டிக்கெட் வழங்கப்பட்டது. டிக்கெட் எண் 176 2349819160.",
        "டிக்கெட்டில் கொடுக்கப்பட்ட விவரங்களின்படி, கொழும்பில் இருந்து (CMB) துபாய் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம் (DXB) அவரது முதல் இலக்கு. நேற்றிரவு (12) 00.15 மணிக்கு செக்-இன் நேரம் வழங்கப்பட்டு, நேற்று அதிகாலை 3.15 மணிக்கு புறப்பட்டது. DXBக்கான முதல் இலக்கு அதே நாளில் காலை 6.00 மணிக்குத் தொடும் எனத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இரண்டாவது விமானம் துபாயில் இருந்து நேற்று மதியம் 02.25 மணிக்கு புறப்பட்டு இன்று காலை 8.45 மணிக்கு வாஷிங்டனில் உள்ள டல்லஸ் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் தரையிறங்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இருப்பினும், அதே விமான நிறுவனத்தில் மார்ச் 2, 2023 அன்று வாஷிங்டனில் இருந்து கொழும்பை அடைய மற்றொரு டிக்கெட் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் EK232 விமானத்திற்கான முதல் வகுப்பு டிக்கெட், மார்ச் 2, 2023 அன்று வாஷிங்டனில் உள்ள Dulles சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து காலை 10.30 மணிக்கு புறப்பட்டு, மார்ச் 2, 2023 அன்று காலை 8.15 மணிக்கு துபாய் சென்றடையும், மீண்டும் 16.25க்கு கொழும்பு சென்றடையும். மார்ச் 2, 2023, மார்ச் 02, 2023 அன்று காலை 10.25 மணிக்கு துபாயிலிருந்து புறப்பட்ட பிறகு.",
        "5.3 மில்லியன் (LKR 5,302,700) ரொக்கமாகச் செலுத்தப்பட்டது, இது Flex Plus கட்டணமாகும். Flex Plus கட்டணம் என்பது முற்றிலும் நெகிழ்வான மற்றும் கட்டுப்பாடற்ற கட்டணமாகும்.",
        "எமிரேட்ஸ் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இணையதளத்தில் உள்ள டிக்கெட் கட்டணங்களின்படி, சில கட்டணங்கள் 5 மில்லியன் LKRக்கும் அதிகமாக இருப்பதைக் காணலாம். இருப்பினும், நாணய மதிப்பீட்டின் அடிப்படையில் டிக்கெட் கட்டணம் நாளுக்கு நாள் மாறுபடும். எனவே நேற்றைய எமிரேட்ஸ் முதல் வகுப்பு டிக்கெட் கட்டணம் ரூ.5.3 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக இருந்தது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பசில் ரூ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டு பாதை பயணிகள் அனுமதி முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்க உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎம்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு 00.15",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று அதிகாலை 3.15 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.45 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "EK232",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.15 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 02, 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,302,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}