{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62149877",
  "time_ut": 1657697152,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අරගලකරුවන් අගමැති කාර්යාලය අත්පත් කර ගත් ආකාරය ඔබ දුටුවාද?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Did you see how the protesters took over the Prime Minister's office?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The group protesting in Malpara, Colombo, demanding the resignation of the Acting President and Prime Minister, Ranil Wickremesinghe, entered the Prime Minister's office premises and are still there.",
        "Meanwhile, protests were held in front of the Speaker's official residence and the Sri Lanka Television Corporation located on Parliament Avenue in Battaramulla and the police fired tear gas and water cannons at the protesters several times to disperse the crowd.",
        "Another large group of protestors are still staying in the premises of the President's Secretariat, the presidential palace in the fort, as well as in the Aralia Gaha Mandir."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Malpara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Television Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Avenue",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලකරුවන් අගමැති කාර්යාලය අත්පත් කර ගත් ආකාරය ඔබ දුටුවාද?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැඩබලන ජනපති, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ධුරයෙන් ඉවත්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් කොළඹ මල්පාරේ විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත පිරිස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාල පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළු වූ අතර තවමත් එහි රැඳී සිටිති.",
        "මේ අතර බත්තරමුල්ල පාර්ලිමේන්තු මාවතේ පිහිටි කතානායකවරයාගේ නිල නිවස සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනි සංස්ථාව ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයන් පැවැත්වුණු අතර පිරිස් පළවා හැරීම සඳහා කිහිප විටක් පොලිසිය විරෝධතාකරුවන් වෙත කඳුළු ගෑස් හා අධිපීඩක ජල ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළේය.",
        "තවත් විශාල පිරිසක් විරෝධතාකරුවන් මීට පෙර අත්පත් කරගත්  ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාල පරිශ්‍රයේත්, කොටුවේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ මෙන්ම අරලිය ගහ මන්දිරයේද තවදුරටත් රැදී සටිති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්පාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் எப்படி கைப்பற்றினார்கள் பார்த்தீர்களா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி கொழும்பு மல்பாறையில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட குழுவினர், பிரதமர் அலுவலக வளாகத்துக்குள் பிரவேசித்து அங்கேயே உள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, சபாநாயகரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் மற்றும் பத்தரமுல்லை பாராளுமன்ற அவென்யூவில் அமைந்துள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா தொலைக்காட்சி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு முன்பாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் இடம்பெற்றதுடன், கூட்டத்தை கலைக்க பொலிஸார் பல தடவைகள் கண்ணீர் புகை மற்றும் நீர்த்தாரைகளை பிரயோகித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலக வளாகத்திலும், கோட்டையிலுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையிலும், அராலியா கஹா மந்திரிலும் இன்னும் ஒரு பெரும் போராட்டக்குழுவினர் தங்கியுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மல்பாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொலைக்காட்சி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற அவென்யூ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}