{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84671/supreme-court-informed-of-govts-policy-decision-on-death-penalty",
  "time_ut": 1661949240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Supreme Court informed of govt’s policy decision on death penalty",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Supreme Court informed of govt’s policy decision on death penalty",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Additional Solicitor General Nerin Pulle today (Aug 31), appearing on behalf of the Attorney General, informed the Supreme Court that there is no change in the government’s policy decision to not carry out the death penalty in Sri Lanka.",
        "This was conveyed when fundamental rights (FR) petitions filed by four death row inmates, who were convicted of drug charges, challenging the decision taken by former President Maithripala Sirisena in 2019 to execute their death sentences.",
        "The petitions seeking the revocation of the said decision were called before Supreme Court bench consisting of Justices Vijith Malalgoda, L.T.B. Dehideniya and Murdu Fernando earlier today.",
        "Further consideration of relevant FR petitions has been fixed for February 23, 2022.",
        "During the court proceedings, Justice Malalgoda, who presides over the bench, told the attorneys representing the petitioners to inform the court whether they wish to proceed with the hearing of the petitions.",
        "On June 26, 2019, then-President Sirisena announced his decision to sign the execution order for four death row inmates convicted of drug charges.",
        "In protest of the decision, the accused in question filed FR petitions, stressing that it is a violation of the government’s policy and international human rights principles.",
        "The petitions were put forward by the Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL), Centre for Policy Alternatives, the four accused and several other parties."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Supreme Court",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nerin Pulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malalgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.T.B. Dehideniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murdu Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 23, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malalgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 26, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Centre for Policy Alternatives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මරණීය දණ්ඩනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය තීරණය ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය දැනුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ මරණ දඬුවම ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකිරීමේ රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය තීරණයේ කිසිදු වෙනසක් නොමැති බව නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් නෙරින් පුල්ලේ අද (අගෝස්තු 31) ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "2019 වසරේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන තමන්ට මරණ දඩුවම ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය අභියෝගයට ලක් කරමින් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් වරදකරුවන් වූ මරණ දණ්ඩනය නියම වූ රැඳවියන් සිව් දෙනෙකු විසින් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් සලකා බැලීමේදී මේ බව දන්වා ඇත.",
        "එම තීන්දුව අවලංගු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම් විජිත් මලල්ගොඩ, එල්.ටී.බී. යන ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල හමුවේ කැඳවනු ලැබීය. දෙහිදෙණිය සහ මුර්දු ප්‍රනාන්දු අද පෙරේදා.",
        "අදාළ FR පෙත්සම් තවදුරටත් සලකා බැලීම 2022 පෙබරවාරි 23 දිනට නියම කර ඇත.",
        "අධිකරණ ක්‍රියාදාමයන් අතරතුර විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලේ සභාපති විනිසුරු මලල්ගොඩ මහතා පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතීඥවරුන්ට කියා සිටියේ පෙත්සම් විභාගය කරගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය දැයි අධිකරණයට දන්වන ලෙසයි.",
        "2019 ජුනි 26 වැනි දින එවකට ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන විසින් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය චෝදනාවලට වරදකරුවන් වූ මරණීය දණ්ඩනය නියම වූ රැඳවියන් හතර දෙනෙකුට මරණ දඬුවම ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ නියෝගයට අත්සන් කිරීමට තීරණය කළේය.",
        "මෙම තීරණයට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් අදාළ චූදිතයන් විසින් FR පෙත්සම් ගොනු කළේ එය රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මානව හිමිකම් මූලධර්ම උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමක් බව අවධාරණය කරමිනි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය (BASL), විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති කේන්ද්‍රය, විත්තිකරුවන් හතර දෙනා සහ තවත් පාර්ශව කිහිපයක් විසින් මෙම පෙත්සම් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නෙරින් පුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ටී.බී. දෙහිදෙණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්දු ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පෙබරවාරි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මලල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019 ජූනි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකල්ප ප්‍රතිපත්ති මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மரண தண்டனை குறித்த அரசின் கொள்கை முடிவை உச்சநீதிமன்றம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றக் கூடாது என்ற அரசாங்கத்தின் கொள்கை முடிவில் எந்த மாற்றமும் இல்லை என அட்டர்னி ஜெனரல் சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் நெரின் புல்லே இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 31) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தமது மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு எடுத்த தீர்மானத்தை எதிர்த்து, போதைப்பொருள் குற்றச்சாட்டில் தண்டனை பெற்ற நான்கு மரண தண்டனைக் கைதிகள் தாக்கல் செய்த அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் (FR) மனுக்களின் போது இது தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மேற்படி தீர்ப்பை ரத்து செய்யக் கோரி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுக்கள் உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகளான விஜித் மலல்கொட, எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய மற்றும் முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோர் இன்று முற்பகல்.",
        "தொடர்புடைய FR மனுக்களை மேலும் பரிசீலிப்பது பிப்ரவரி 23, 2022க்கு நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீதிமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளின் போது, ​​பெஞ்ச் தலைமையிலான நீதியரசர் மலல்கொட, மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணிகளிடம், மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணையை தொடர விரும்புகிறீர்களா என்பதை நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு தெரிவிக்குமாறு கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூன் 26, 2019 அன்று, போதைப்பொருள் குற்றச்சாட்டில் தண்டனை பெற்ற நான்கு மரண தண்டனை கைதிகளுக்கு மரணதண்டனை விதிக்கும் உத்தரவில் கையெழுத்திடும் முடிவை அப்போதைய அதிபர் சிறிசேனா அறிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த முடிவுக்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில், குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டவர்கள், அரசாங்கத்தின் கொள்கை மற்றும் சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைக் கோட்பாடுகளை மீறுவதாக வலியுறுத்தி, FR மனுக்களை தாக்கல் செய்தனர்.",
        "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL), மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம், குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட நான்கு பேர் மற்றும் பல தரப்பினரால் இந்த மனுக்கள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேரின் புள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 23, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 26, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாற்றுக் கொள்கைகளுக்கான மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}