{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/19/treasure-hunters-arrested-with-loot-worth-over-rs-100-mn/",
  "time_ut": 1660893120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Treasure hunters arrested with loot worth over Rs. 100 Mn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Treasure hunters arrested with loot worth over Rs. 100 Mn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police arrested five people who attempting to sell looted treasure and artifacts worth over Rs. 100 Million.",
        "The Anuradhapura Police Crimes Division and the Anuradhapura Regional Vice Division made the arrested.",
        "Two ancient manuscripts carved out of stone, and nine decorative caskets made out of stone were seized from the possession of the suspects.",
        "The suspects will be produced to court, and the artifacts will be handed over to the Department of Archaeology for further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Anuradhapura Police Crimes Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Anuradhapura Regional Vice Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Archaeology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් කොල්ලකෑම් සමඟ නිදන් හෑරූ පිරිසක් අත්අඩංගුවට මිලියන 100",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කොල්ලකන ලද නිධන් වස්තු සහ කෞතුක භාණ්ඩ අලෙවි කිරීමට තැත් කළ පුද්ගලයින් පස් දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ. මිලියන 100 කි.",
        "අනුරාධපුර මූලස්ථාන පොලිසියේ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශය සහ අනුරාධපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය උප කොට්ඨාසය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් සන්තකයේ තිබී ගලින් නෙළන ලද ඉපැරණි අත්පිටපත් දෙකක් සහ ගලින් නිමවූ විසිතුරු කරඬු නවයක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත අතර, ඉදිරි පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 100 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ අනුරාධපුර පොලිසියේ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය උප කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோடிக்கு மேல் கொள்ளையடித்த புதையல் கொள்ளையர்கள் கைது! 100 மில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொள்ளையடிக்கப்பட்ட புதையல் மற்றும் தொல்பொருட்களை விற்பனை செய்ய முயன்ற ஐந்து பேரை இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர். 100 மில்லியன்.",
        "அநுராதபுரம் பொலிஸ் குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு மற்றும் அநுராதபுரம் பிராந்திய உப பிரிவினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களிடம் இருந்து கல்லால் செதுக்கப்பட்ட இரண்டு பழங்கால கையெழுத்துப் பிரதிகளும், கல்லால் செய்யப்பட்ட ஒன்பது அலங்கார கலசங்களும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டன.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளதுடன், மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக தொல்பொருள் திணைக்களத்திடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் பொலிஸ் குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் பிராந்திய துணை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}