{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/mikhail-gorbachev-the-first-and-only-president-of-the-soviet-union-has-died/",
  "time_ut": 1661920680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Mikhail Gorbachev, the first and only president of the Soviet Union, has died",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Mikhail Gorbachev, the first and only president of the Soviet Union, has died",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "RT: Mikhail Gorbachev, the first and only president of the Soviet Union, has died at the age of 91, in Moscow.",
        "His death was reported on Tuesday night by the Central Clinical Hospital, which said in a statement that “Mikhail Sergeyevich Gorbachev died this evening after a serious and prolonged illness.”",
        "According to the news agency TASS, Gorbachev was hospitalized at the very beginning of the Covid-19 pandemic, at the request of his doctors, and had been under medical supervision ever since.",
        "Gorbachev will be buried in Moscow’s Novodevichy Cemetery next to his wife, Raisa, who died in 1999, TASS revealed, citing a source familiar with the family’s wishes.",
        "A divisive figure, supporters credit him with having played a key part in bringing about an end to the Cold War, while opponents accuse him of aiding in the fall of the Soviet Union and a major loss to Moscow’s prestige and global influence.",
        "Born in 1931 into a peasant family in southern Russia, in his teens Gorbachev operated combine harvesters on collective farms. His party career started early in his student years, when he studied law at Lomonosov Moscow State University. His ascent through the ranks was relatively rapid, and in 1985 he became the general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, making him the highest ranking official in the USSR.",
        "During his time in office, Gorbachev aimed to re-energize the stalled Soviet economy, which was riddled with inefficiency, overblown defense spending and creeping corruption. He called for urgent reorganization and modernization, but soon expanded his reform to the political and social structure of the whole nation.",
        "The policy of ‘perestroika’ was announced in 1986 as an attempt to reorganize the economy. More of a political movement, the “restructuring” aimed to give more independence to ministries and large state-owned enterprises. It also introduced some free market-style reforms. In 1988, Gorbachev permitted establishing private enterprises in the country for the first time since Vladimir Lenin’s “New Economic Policy” of the 1920s.",
        "Another policy proclaimed was ‘glasnost'. Gorbachev aimed to bring transparency into society, ease the Communist Party’s control over the media and release political prisoners. This was a radical change, since control over public speech had previously been an essential part of the Soviet regime.",
        "Gorbachev also proposed a constitutional change to move to a presidential system and created a new political body called the Congress of People’s Deputies. The 2,250 members were elected in the Soviet Union’s first semi-competitive parliamentary election. On March 15, 1990, following a vote in the Congress of People’s Deputies, Mikhail Gorbachev became president of the USSR.",
        "Gorbachev’s foreign policy, also known as the “new thinking,” marked a period of significant improvement of relations between the Soviet Union and Western countries, replacing the era of Cold War hostilities.",
        "In 1986, he announced plans to withdraw Soviet troops from Afghanistan, but it took three more years to complete the pullout.",
        "The Soviet-Afghan war was a major point of criticism for the West. It also cost the Soviet Union at least 15,000 casualties, put additional strains on an already creaking bureaucratic planned economy and filled the country with veterans suffering from combat stress disorders.",
        "The reengagement with the West paved the way for several key disarmament treaties to be signed. Moscow and Washington agreed to dismantle their intermediate-range conventional and nuclear missiles – the very precise weapons that could tempt the military into using nuclear weapons on a limited scale, but still trigger global mutual annihilation. Under Gorbachev, Moscow unilaterally stopped all nuclear tests.",
        "Moscow’s relations with the Eastern Bloc countries also underwent a radical change. Earlier, Soviet troops always served as the final argument, should one of the countries of the Cold War-era Warsaw Pact try to shift its allegiance. But Gorbachev’s liberalization included the right of self-determination for those nations. This was jokingly called the “Sinatra doctrine” after the singer Frank Sinatra, alluding to his song, 'My Way', as countries were allowed to determine their own internal policies. A string of revolutions in 1989 ousted European Communist regimes, and in 1990 West and East Germany reunified as one country.",
        "Mikhail Gorbachev, the first and only president of the Soviet Union, has died",
        "SLPP Chairman G. L. Peiris & several SLPP MPs become independent"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Soviet Union",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 91",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Clinical Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Sergeyevich Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TASS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Novodevichy Cemetery",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Raisa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TASS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1931",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lomonosov Moscow State University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Communist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USSR",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Lenin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Economic Policy",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1920s",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Communist Party’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Congress of People’s Deputies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 15, 1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Congress of People’s Deputies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USSR",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three more years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Bloc",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cold War-era",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Warsaw Pact",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinatra",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Frank Sinatra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "European Communist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "East Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris &",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෝවියට් සංගමයේ පළමු සහ එකම ජනාධිපතිවරයා වූ මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් මිය ගියේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "RT: සෝවියට් සංගමයේ පළමු සහ එකම ජනාධිපතිවරයා වන මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් වයස අවුරුදු 91 දී මොස්කව්හිදී මිය ගියේය.",
        "ඔහුගේ මරණය අඟහරුවාදා රාත්‍රියේ මධ්‍යම සායනික රෝහල විසින් වාර්තා කරන ලද අතර එය ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ “මිහායිල් සර්ජියෙවිච් ගොර්බචෙව් බරපතල හා දිගුකාලීන රෝගාබාධයකින් පසු අද සවස මිය ගිය” බවයි.",
        "TASS ප්‍රවෘත්ති ඒජන්සියට අනුව, ගොර්බචෙව් කොවිඩ් -19 වසංගතයේ ආරම්භයේදීම, ඔහුගේ වෛද්‍යවරුන්ගේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි රෝහල් ගත කරන ලද අතර එතැන් සිට වෛද්‍ය අධීක්ෂණය යටතේ සිටියේය.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව් 1999 දී මියගිය ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ රයිසා අසල මොස්කව්හි නොවොඩෙවිචි සුසාන භූමියේ තැන්පත් කරනු ඇති බව TASS අනාවරණය කළේ පවුලේ කැමැත්ත පිළිබඳව හුරුපුරුදු මූලාශ්‍රයක් උපුටා දක්වමින්.",
        "බෙදුම්වාදී චරිතයක්, සීතල යුද්ධය අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළ බවට ආධාරකරුවන් ඔහුට ගෞරවය පිරිනමන අතර, විරුද්ධවාදීන් ඔහුට චෝදනා කරන්නේ සෝවියට් සංගමයේ වැටීමට සහ මොස්කව්හි කීර්තියට සහ ගෝලීය බලපෑමට විශාල පාඩුවක් සිදු කළ බවටයි.",
        "1931 දී දකුණු රුසියාවේ ගොවි පවුලක උපත ලද ගොර්බචෙව් ඔහුගේ නව යොවුන් වියේදී සාමූහික ගොවිපලවල ඒකාබද්ධ අස්වනු නෙළන යන්ත්‍ර ක්‍රියාත්මක කළේය. ඔහුගේ පක්ෂ ජීවිතය ආරම්භ වූයේ ඔහුගේ ශිෂ්‍ය අවධියේදී, ඔහු ලොමොනොසොව් මොස්කව් ප්‍රාන්ත විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ නීතිය හැදෑරූ විටය. නිලයන් හරහා ඔහුගේ නැගීම සාපේක්ෂව වේගවත් වූ අතර 1985 දී ඔහු සෝවියට් සංගමයේ කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාවේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් බවට පත් වූ අතර ඔහු සෝවියට් සංගමයේ ඉහළම නිලය බවට පත් කළේය.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව් ඔහුගේ නිල කාලය තුළ, අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව, අධික ලෙස පුපුරවා හරින ලද ආරක්ෂක වියදම් සහ බඩගා යන දූෂණයෙන් පිරී ගිය සෝවියට් ආර්ථිකය නැවත පණ ගැන්වීම අරමුණු කළේය. ඔහු හදිසි ප්‍රතිසංවිධානයක් සහ නවීකරණයක් ඉල්ලා සිටි නමුත් ඉක්මනින්ම ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ මුළු ජාතියේම දේශපාලන හා සමාජ ව්‍යුහය දක්වා ව්‍යාප්ත කළේය.",
        "ආර්ථිකය ප්‍රතිසංවිධානය කිරීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස 1986 දී 'පෙරෙස්ත්‍රොයිකා' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයකට වඩා, “ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම” අරමුණු කළේ අමාත්‍යාංශවලට සහ විශාල රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන්ට වැඩි ස්වාධීනත්වයක් ලබා දීමයි. එය නිදහස් වෙළඳපල ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කිහිපයක් ද හඳුන්වා දුන්නේය. 1920 ගනන්වල ව්ලැඩිමීර් ලෙනින්ගේ \"නව ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තියෙන්\" පසු ප්‍රථම වතාවට 1988 දී ගොර්බචෙව් රට තුළ පුද්ගලික ව්‍යවසායන් පිහිටුවීමට අවසර දුන්නේය.",
        "ප්‍රකාශිත තවත් ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් වූයේ ‘ග්ලාස්නොස්ට්’ ය. ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ අරමුණ වූයේ සමාජය තුළ විනිවිදභාවය ගෙන ඒම, මාධ්‍ය කෙරෙහි කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ පාලනය ලිහිල් කිරීම සහ දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන් නිදහස් කිරීම ය. මහජන කථාව පාලනය කිරීම මීට පෙර සෝවියට් පාලනයේ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය අංගයක් වූ බැවින් මෙය රැඩිකල් වෙනසක් විය.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව් ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමයකට යාමට ව්‍යවස්ථාමය වෙනසක් ද යෝජනා කළ අතර මහජන නියෝජිතයින්ගේ සම්මේලනය නමින් නව දේශපාලන ආයතනයක් නිර්මාණය කළේය. සෝවියට් සංගමයේ පළමු අර්ධ තරඟකාරී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයෙන් සාමාජිකයින් 2,250 තේරී පත් විය. 1990 මාර්තු 15 වන දින මහජන නියෝජිතයින්ගේ සම්මේලනයේ ඡන්දයෙන් පසුව, මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් සෝවියට් සංගමයේ සභාපති බවට පත්විය.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය, \"නව චින්තනය\" ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ, සෝවියට් සංගමය සහ බටහිර රටවල් අතර සබඳතා සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ කාල පරිච්ඡේදයක් සලකුනු කලේය, සීතල යුද්ධ සතුරු යුගය වෙනුවට.",
        "1986 දී, ඔහු ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයෙන් සෝවියට් හමුදා ඉවත් කර ගැනීමේ සැලසුම් නිවේදනය කළ නමුත්, ඉවත් කිරීම සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට තවත් වසර තුනක් ගත විය.",
        "සෝවියට්-ඇෆ්ගන් යුද්ධය බටහිර රටවල විවේචනයට තුඩු දුන් ප්‍රධාන කරුණක් විය. එය සෝවියට් සංගමයට අවම වශයෙන් 15,000 තුවාල ලබා ඇති අතර, දැනටමත් බිඳවැටෙමින් පවතින නිලධාරිවාදී සැලසුම්ගත ආර්ථිකයකට අමතර ආතතියක් ඇති කළ අතර සටන් ආතති ආබාධවලින් පෙළෙන ප්‍රවීණයන්ගෙන් රට පුරවා ඇත.",
        "බටහිර සමඟ නැවත සම්බන්ධ වීම ප්‍රධාන නිරායුධකරණ ගිවිසුම් කිහිපයකට අත්සන් කිරීමට මග පෑදීය. මොස්කව් සහ වොෂින්ටනය ඔවුන්ගේ අතරමැදි පරාසයේ සාම්ප්‍රදායික සහ න්‍යෂ්ටික මිසයිල බිඳ දැමීමට එකඟ විය - සීමිත පරිමාණයෙන් න්‍යෂ්ටික අවි භාවිතා කිරීමට මිලිටරිය පොළඹවා ගත හැකි, නමුත් තවමත් ගෝලීය අන්‍යෝන්‍ය විනාශයක් අවුලුවාලන ඉතා නිවැරදි අවි. ගොර්බචෙව් යටතේ මොස්කව් ඒකපාර්ශ්විකව සියලු න්‍යෂ්ටික අත්හදා බැලීම් නතර කළේය.",
        "නැගෙනහිර බ්ලොක් රටවල් සමඟ මොස්කව්හි සබඳතා ද රැඩිකල් වෙනසක් සිදු විය. මීට පෙර, සීතල යුද්ධයේ යුගයේ වෝර්සෝ ගිවිසුමේ එක් රටක් තම පක්ෂපාතීත්වය වෙනස් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළහොත් සෝවියට් හමුදා සෑම විටම අවසාන තර්කය ලෙස සේවය කළහ. නමුත් ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ ලිබරල්කරණයට එම ජාතීන්ට ස්වයං නිර්ණ අයිතිය ඇතුළත් විය. ෆ්‍රෑන්ක් සිනාත්‍රා ගායකයාගේ 'My Way' ගීතය ගැන සඳහන් කරමින් මෙය විහිළුවට \"Sinatra doctrine\" ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලැබුවේ, රටවල් වලට තමන්ගේ අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රතිපත්ති තීරණය කිරීමට අවසර දී තිබූ බැවිනි. 1989 දී විප්ලව මාලාවක් යුරෝපීය කොමියුනිස්ට් පාලන තන්ත්‍රයන් නෙරපා හරින ලද අතර 1990 දී බටහිර හා නැගෙනහිර ජර්මනිය එක් රටක් ලෙස යලි ඒකාබද්ධ විය.",
        "සෝවියට් සංගමයේ පළමු සහ එකම ජනාධිපතිවරයා වූ මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් මිය ගියේය",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති ජී එල් පීරිස් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ස්වාධීන වෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පළමුවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 91",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම සායනික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් සර්ජිවිච් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Novodevichy සුසාන භූමිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රයිසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1931",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලොමොනොසොව් මොස්කව් රාජ්ය විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් ලෙනින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1920 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන නියෝජිතයින්ගේ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,250 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමයේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990 මාර්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන නියෝජිතයින්ගේ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තව අවුරුදු තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර බ්ලොක්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධ යුගය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෝර්සෝ ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිනාත්රා",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රෑන්ක් සිනාත්රා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය කොමියුනිස්ට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස් සහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் முதல் மற்றும் ஒரே ஜனாதிபதியான மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் காலமானார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆர்டி: சோவியத் யூனியனின் முதல் மற்றும் ஒரே ஜனாதிபதியான மைக்கேல் கோர்பச்சேவ் தனது 91வது வயதில் மாஸ்கோவில் காலமானார்.",
        "அவரது மரணம் செவ்வாய் இரவு மத்திய மருத்துவ மருத்துவமனையால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது, இது ஒரு அறிக்கையில் \"மிகைல் செர்ஜியேவிச் கோர்பச்சேவ் தீவிரமான மற்றும் நீடித்த நோய்க்குப் பிறகு இன்று மாலை இறந்தார்\" என்று கூறியது.",
        "செய்தி நிறுவனமான TASS இன் கூற்றுப்படி, கோர்பச்சேவ் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோயின் ஆரம்பத்திலேயே, அவரது மருத்துவர்களின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார், அன்றிலிருந்து மருத்துவ மேற்பார்வையில் இருந்தார்.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவ் 1999 இல் இறந்த அவரது மனைவி ரைசாவுக்கு அடுத்துள்ள மாஸ்கோவின் நோவோடெவிச்சி கல்லறையில் அடக்கம் செய்யப்படுவார், குடும்பத்தின் விருப்பங்களை நன்கு அறிந்த ஒரு ஆதாரத்தை மேற்கோள் காட்டி TASS வெளிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "பிளவுபடுத்தும் நபரான, ஆதரவாளர்கள் பனிப்போரை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டுவருவதில் முக்கியப் பங்காற்றியதாக அவரைப் பாராட்டுகிறார்கள், அதே நேரத்தில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் அவர் சோவியத் யூனியனின் வீழ்ச்சிக்கு உதவியதாகவும், மாஸ்கோவின் கௌரவம் மற்றும் உலகளாவிய செல்வாக்கிற்கு பெரும் இழப்பு என்றும் குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றனர்.",
        "1931 ஆம் ஆண்டு தெற்கு ரஷ்யாவில் ஒரு விவசாயக் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்த கோர்பச்சேவ் தனது பதின்ம வயதிலேயே கூட்டுப் பண்ணைகளில் அறுவடை இயந்திரங்களை இயக்கினார். லோமோனோசோவ் மாஸ்கோ ஸ்டேட் யுனிவர்சிட்டியில் சட்டம் பயின்றபோது அவரது கட்சி வாழ்க்கை அவரது மாணவர் ஆண்டுகளில் தொடங்கியது. அணிகள் மூலம் அவரது ஏற்றம் ஒப்பீட்டளவில் விரைவானது, மேலும் 1985 இல் அவர் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் மத்தியக் குழுவின் பொதுச் செயலாளராக ஆனார், அவரை சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் மிக உயர்ந்த பதவியில் ஆக்கினார்.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவ் பதவியில் இருந்த காலத்தில், திறமையின்மை, மிகைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பாதுகாப்புச் செலவுகள் மற்றும் ஊர்ந்து செல்லும் ஊழல் ஆகியவற்றால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட சோவியத் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீண்டும் உற்சாகப்படுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டிருந்தார். அவர் அவசர மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் நவீனமயமாக்கலுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார், ஆனால் விரைவில் தனது சீர்திருத்தத்தை முழு தேசத்தின் அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக கட்டமைப்பிற்கு விரிவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "பொருளாதாரத்தை மறுசீரமைக்கும் முயற்சியாக 1986 இல் ‘பெரெஸ்ட்ரோயிகா’ கொள்கை அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. ஒரு அரசியல் இயக்கம், \"மறுசீரமைப்பு\" என்பது அமைச்சகங்கள் மற்றும் பெரிய அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களுக்கு அதிக சுதந்திரத்தை வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டது. இது சில தடையற்ற சந்தை பாணி சீர்திருத்தங்களையும் அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. 1920களின் விளாடிமிர் லெனினின் \"புதிய பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கை\"க்குப் பிறகு 1988 ஆம் ஆண்டில், கோர்பச்சேவ் முதல் முறையாக நாட்டில் தனியார் நிறுவனங்களை நிறுவ அனுமதித்தார்.",
        "பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மற்றொரு கொள்கை ‘கிளாஸ்னோஸ்ட்’. கோர்பச்சேவ் சமூகத்தில் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையைக் கொண்டுவருவதையும், ஊடகங்கள் மீதான கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் கட்டுப்பாட்டை எளிதாக்குவதையும், அரசியல் கைதிகளை விடுதலை செய்வதையும் நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டிருந்தார். இது ஒரு தீவிரமான மாற்றமாக இருந்தது, ஏனெனில் பொது பேச்சு மீதான கட்டுப்பாடு முன்பு சோவியத் ஆட்சியின் இன்றியமையாத பகுதியாக இருந்தது.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவ் ஒரு ஜனாதிபதி முறைக்கு செல்ல அரசியலமைப்பு மாற்றத்தை முன்மொழிந்தார் மற்றும் மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளின் காங்கிரஸ் என்ற புதிய அரசியல் அமைப்பை உருவாக்கினார். சோவியத் யூனியனின் முதல் அரை-போட்டி நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் 2,250 உறுப்பினர்கள் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டனர். மார்ச் 15, 1990 இல், மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளின் காங்கிரஸில் வாக்களித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் தலைவரானார்.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவின் வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கை, \"புதிய சிந்தனை\" என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது, இது சோவியத் யூனியனுக்கும் மேற்கத்திய நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க முன்னேற்றத்தின் காலகட்டத்தைக் குறித்தது, இது பனிப்போர் விரோதங்களின் சகாப்தத்தை மாற்றியது.",
        "1986 ஆம் ஆண்டில், ஆப்கானிஸ்தானில் இருந்து சோவியத் துருப்புக்களை திரும்பப் பெறுவதற்கான திட்டங்களை அவர் அறிவித்தார், ஆனால் வெளியேறுவதை முடிக்க இன்னும் மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் ஆனது.",
        "சோவியத்-ஆப்கான் போர் மேற்குலகின் முக்கிய விமர்சனப் புள்ளியாக இருந்தது. இது சோவியத் யூனியனுக்கு குறைந்தபட்சம் 15,000 உயிரிழப்புகளை ஏற்படுத்தியது, ஏற்கனவே அதிகாரத்துவ திட்டமிட்ட பொருளாதாரத்தின் மீது கூடுதல் அழுத்தங்களை ஏற்படுத்தியது மற்றும் போர் அழுத்தக் கோளாறுகளால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட வீரர்களால் நாட்டை நிரப்பியது.",
        "மேற்கத்திய நாடுகளுடன் மீண்டும் நிச்சயதார்த்தம் பல முக்கிய ஆயுதக் குறைப்பு ஒப்பந்தங்கள் கையெழுத்திட வழி வகுத்தது. மாஸ்கோவும் வாஷிங்டனும் தங்களுடைய இடைநிலை-தரப்பு மரபுவழி மற்றும் அணுசக்தி ஏவுகணைகளை அகற்ற ஒப்புக்கொண்டன - மிகத் துல்லியமான ஆயுதங்கள், அணு ஆயுதங்களை வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட அளவில் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு இராணுவத்தைத் தூண்டக்கூடும், ஆனால் இன்னும் உலகளாவிய பரஸ்பர அழிவைத் தூண்டும். கோர்பச்சேவின் கீழ், மாஸ்கோ ஒருதலைப்பட்சமாக அனைத்து அணுசக்தி சோதனைகளையும் நிறுத்தியது.",
        "கிழக்குத் தொகுதி நாடுகளுடனான மாஸ்கோவின் உறவுகளும் தீவிரமான மாற்றத்திற்கு உட்பட்டன. முன்னதாக, சோவியத் துருப்புக்கள் எப்போதும் இறுதி வாதமாக செயல்பட்டன, பனிப்போர் கால வார்சா ஒப்பந்தத்தின் நாடுகளில் ஒன்று அதன் விசுவாசத்தை மாற்ற முயற்சிக்க வேண்டும். ஆனால் கோர்பச்சேவின் தாராளமயமாக்கல் அந்த நாடுகளுக்கான சுயநிர்ணய உரிமையை உள்ளடக்கியது. பாடகர் ஃபிராங்க் சினாட்ராவின் 'மை வே' பாடலைக் குறிப்பிட்டு, நாடுகள் தங்கள் சொந்த உள் கொள்கைகளைத் தீர்மானிக்க அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டதால், இது நகைச்சுவையாக \"சினாட்ரா கோட்பாடு\" என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டது. 1989 இல் புரட்சிகளின் ஒரு சரம் ஐரோப்பிய கம்யூனிஸ்ட் ஆட்சிகளை அகற்றியது, 1990 இல் மேற்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு ஜெர்மனி ஒரு நாடாக மீண்டும் இணைந்தது.",
        "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் முதல் மற்றும் ஒரே ஜனாதிபதியான மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் காலமானார்",
        "SLPP தலைவர் G. L. பீரிஸ் மற்றும் பல SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் சுயேச்சையாக மாறியுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதலில்",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயது 91",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய மருத்துவ மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் செர்ஜியேவிச் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோவோடெவிச்சி கல்லறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரைசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1931",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லோமோனோசோவ் மாஸ்கோ மாநில பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் லெனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதிய பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1920கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளின் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 15, 1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளின் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் மூன்று ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு தொகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர் காலம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார்சா ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சினாட்ரா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிராங்க் சினாட்ரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய கம்யூனிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ் &",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}