{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/mps-visit-former-president-at-his-residence/",
  "time_ut": 1662199860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "MPs visit former President at his residence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "MPs visit former President at his residence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Several MPs visited former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at his residence after he returned from overseas.",
        "MP Ajith Rajapakse who visited the former President, said that the former President was a great leader of the country, and wanted to know about his health.",
        "\"He is well. He remains at his home without any trouble\" Rajapakse said.",
        "Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa too visited the former President in the morning.",
        "The former President arrived in the country last night, and was welcomed into the country by SLPP MPs Prasanna Ranatunge and Tiran Alles at the Bandaranaike International Airport.",
        "Meanwhile, SJB MP Nalin Bandara said that there is no issue in the former President returning to the country, however the fact that he will continue to enjoy his benefits as a President remains a question.",
        "MP Nalin Bandara further stated that he requests for the ongoing cases which were filed against the former President to be reinstituted,as he no longer has the Presidential immunity as a former President.",
        "Positive response from International community over IMF mission statement on SL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tiran Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්ත්‍රීවරු හිටපු ජනපතිගේ නිවසට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විදේශගතව සිට ආපසු පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඔහුගේ නිවසට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු පැමිණියා.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවීමට ගිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ කියා සිටියේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා රටේ විශිෂ්ට නායකයෙකු බවත්, ඔහුගේ සෞඛ්‍ය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව දැනගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය බවත්ය.",
        "\"ඔහු හොඳින් ඉන්නවා. කිසිම කරදරයක් නැතිව එයාගේ ගෙදර ඉන්නවා\" රාජපක්ෂ පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ද උදෑසන හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා බැලීමට පැමිණියා.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ දිවයිනට පැමිණි අතර, බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග සහ ටිරාන් අලස් විසින් ඔහු පිළිගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "මේ අතර, SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නලින් බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසුවේ, හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා යළි දිවයිනට පැමිණීමේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් නොමැති බවත්, කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිලාභ තවදුරටත් භුක්ති විඳීම ප්‍රශ්නයක් බවයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස ඔහුට තවදුරටත් ජනාධිපති මුක්තිය නොමැති බැවින් ඔහුට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති දැනට පවතින නඩු යළි ස්ථාපිත කරන ලෙස තමන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නලින් බණ්ඩාර වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ IMF මෙහෙවර ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවෙන් ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිරාන් අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்திற்கு எம்.பி.க்கள் வருகை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வெளிநாட்டில் இருந்து நாடு திரும்பிய பின்னர் பல எம்.பி.க்கள் அவரது இல்லத்திற்குச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டின் தலைசிறந்த தலைவர் எனவும், அவரின் உடல்நிலை குறித்து அறிய விரும்புவதாகவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"அவர் நலமுடன் இருக்கிறார். எந்த பிரச்சனையும் இல்லாமல் அவர் வீட்டில் இருக்கிறார்\" என்று ராஜபக்ஷ கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவும் இன்று காலை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்றிரவு நாட்டை வந்தடைந்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மற்றும் திரான் அலஸ் ஆகியோர் பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி நாடு திரும்புவதில் எந்தப் பிரச்சினையும் இல்லை எனவும், எனினும் ஜனாதிபதி என்ற வகையில் அவர் தனது பலன்களை தொடர்ந்து அனுபவிப்பாரா என்பது கேள்விக்குறியாகவே உள்ளது எனவும் SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நளின் பண்டார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்குகளை மீள ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு தாம் கோரிக்கை விடுப்பதாகவும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி என்ற வகையில் அவருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி விதிவிலக்கு இல்லை எனவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நளின் பண்டார மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "SL பற்றிய IMF பணி அறிக்கைக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் நேர்மறையான பதில்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்னா ரணதுங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரன் அலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}