{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Govt-to-present-interim-budget-today/108-243976",
  "time_ut": 1661800043,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Govt. to present interim budget today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Govt. to present interim budget today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The government of President Ranil Wickremesinghe is scheduled to present an interim budget to Parliament today for the remainder of 2022, as the crisis-hit nation tries to stay afloat.",
        "The Amendment to the Appropriation Bill for 2022 was presented to Parliament ahead of the interim budget speech.",
        "According to PublicFinance.lk, the amended bill shows a 20 percent increase in expenditure to Rs.4,672 billion for the year 2022, which could widen the budget deficit, unless revenue enhancement measures are adopted.",
        "The interim budget is likely to aim for a 9.9 percent budget deficit for 2022, which is lower than the earlier 12 percent. While reversing of the deep tax cuts introduced in 2019 has not taken place fully to boost the government revenue, Sri Lanka raised some key tax rates after May.",
        "The interim budget comes amid Sri Lanka’s ongoing negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for a possible bailout package.",
        "The Sri Lankan Parliament’s communications office said President Wickremesinghe, in his capacity as the Finance Minister, will present the interim budget on August 30 and the parliamentarians will debate the budget from Tuesday to Friday that week.",
        "The government is expected to present a full budget for the year 2023 in November."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PublicFinance.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9.9 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the earlier 12 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය අද අතුරු අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අර්බුදකාරී ජාතිය නොනැසී සිටීමට උත්සාහ කරන 2022 වසරේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා වන අතුරු අයවැයක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ රජය අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "2022 සඳහා වන විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත අතුරු අයවැය කතාවට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කෙරිණි.",
        "PublicFinance.lk ට අනුව, සංශෝධිත පනත් කෙටුම්පත මගින් 2022 වසර සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 4,672 දක්වා වියදම් සියයට 20 කින් වැඩි වී ඇති අතර, ආදායම් වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග අනුගමනය නොකළහොත් අයවැය හිඟය පුළුල් කළ හැකිය.",
        "අතුරු අයවැය 2022 සඳහා සියයට 9.9 ක අයවැය හිඟයක් ඉලක්ක කර ගැනීමට ඉඩ ඇති අතර එය පෙර පැවති සියයට 12 ට වඩා අඩුය. 2019 දී හඳුන්වා දුන් ගැඹුරු බදු කප්පාදුව ආපසු හැරවීම රාජ්‍ය ආදායම ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම සිදු නොවූ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මැයි මාසයෙන් පසු ප්‍රධාන බදු අනුපාත කිහිපයක් ඉහළ නැංවීය.",
        "හැකි ඇප පැකේජයක් සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අඛණ්ඩව පවතින සාකච්ඡා මධ්‍යයේ මෙම අතුරු අයවැය පැමිණේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සන්නිවේදන කාර්යාලය පැවසුවේ, මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා අතුරු අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කරන බවත්, එම සතියේ අඟහරුවාදා සිට සිකුරාදා දක්වා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අයවැය විවාදයට ගන්නා බවත්ය.",
        "2023 වසර සඳහා සම්පූර්ණ අයවැයක් නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට රජය අපේක්ෂා කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PublicFinance.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 9.9 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර සියයට 12",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு இன்று இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் தாக்கல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கியுள்ள தேசம் நிலைத்திருக்க முயற்சிக்கும் வேளையில் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசாங்கம் இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளது.",
        "2022ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலத்தில் திருத்தம் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரைக்கு முன்னதாக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "PublicFinance.lk இன் படி, திருத்தப்பட்ட சட்டமூலமானது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான செலவினங்களில் 20 வீத அதிகரிப்பு ரூ.4,672 பில்லியனைக் காட்டுகிறது, இது வரவு செலவுத் திட்டப் பற்றாக்குறையை விரிவுபடுத்தும், வருமானத்தை மேம்படுத்தும் நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படாவிட்டால்.",
        "இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் 2022 க்கு 9.9 சதவீத பட்ஜெட் பற்றாக்குறையை இலக்காகக் கொண்டிருக்கும், இது முந்தைய 12 சதவீதத்தை விட குறைவாகும். 2019 இல் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஆழமான வரிக் குறைப்புக்கள் அரசாங்க வருவாயை அதிகரிக்க முழுமையாக நடைபெறாத நிலையில், மே மாதத்திற்குப் பிறகு இலங்கை சில முக்கிய வரி விகிதங்களை உயர்த்தியது.",
        "சாத்தியமான பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) இலங்கையின் தொடர்ச்சியான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் வந்துள்ளது.",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை ஆகஸ்ட் 30 ஆம் திகதி சமர்ப்பிப்பார் என்றும் அந்த வாரம் செவ்வாய் முதல் வெள்ளி வரை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை விவாதிப்பார்கள் என்றும் இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் தகவல் தொடர்பு அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "2023ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான முழு வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை அரசாங்கம் நவம்பரில் சமர்ப்பிக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PublicFinance.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய 12 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}