{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/22/new-long-fingered-bat-species-discovered-in-india-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1661153640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "New long-fingered bat species discovered in India, Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "New long-fingered bat species discovered in India, Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An international team of researchers has found a new species of long-fingered bats in India and Sri Lanka, close on the heels of the discovery of a thick-thumbed bat species in Meghalaya.",
        "The team led by Tharaka Kusuminda of University of Ruhuna in the island country named the new species of long-fingered bats as Miniopterus phillipsi.",
        "It was named after W W A Philips (1892-1981) in recognition of his contributions to studies on the mammals of Sri Lanka and South Asia.",
        "The specimens for this species were collected from Idulgashinna cave in Uva Province in Sri Lanka and are now deposited in the Natural History Museum of the neighbouring country.",
        "The initial research was carried out in Sri Lanka in 2019 and it took three years to be completed in both Sri Lanka and India.",
        "The discovery has been published in Acta Chiropterologica, an international scientific journal.",
        "Researchers found that the population of long-fingered bats in Robber's cave in Mahabaleshwar in the Western Ghats of India also belongs to this species which was earlier mistaken as Eastern bent-winged bats.",
        "The long-fingered bats belonging to the family Miniopteridae are part of a large group comprising at least 40 species worldwide.",
        "They have similar morphology and overlapping dimensions rendering species identification problematic.",
        "To describe this new species, researchers have DNA barcoded the specimens from India and Sri Lanka and compared them with all other Asian members of this group and found strong evidence for these specimens as belonging to a distinct species.",
        "Besides, researchers also analysed the morphological and anatomical features of the new species with the congeners occurring in India and Sri Lanka and found that the new species is indeed distinct, Kusuminda said.",
        "\"The Long-fingered bats are obligatory cave and tunnel dwellers living in large colonies and this new species is also no exception,\" the researcher stated.",
        "While in Sri Lanka it is relatively widespread, more studies are needed to determine its exact distribution range in India.",
        "At least 13 renowned scientists were involved in this particular research – six from Sri Lanka and one each from India, Russia, Switzerland, Hungary, the UK, and the USA.",
        "A team of scientists had recently discovered a new species of thick-thumbed bat from a bamboo forest in Meghalaya and named it after the state.",
        "The discovery of Glischropus meghalayanus was published in Zootaxa, a prominent taxonomic journal.",
        "SL Navy recovers prescription drugs worth Rs. 4.5 million in Mannar"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meghalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tharaka Kusuminda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Ruhuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Miniopterus phillipsi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "W W A Philips",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1892-1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Idulgashinna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Natural History Museum",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Acta Chiropterologica",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Robber",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahabaleshwar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusuminda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Long-fingered",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "colonies",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "At least 13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hungary",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Meghalaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Glischropus",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zootaxa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව දිගු ඇඟිලි සහිත වවුලන් විශේෂයක් සොයා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර පර්යේෂකයන් කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් ඉන්දියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් නව දිගු ඇඟිලි සහිත වවුලන් විශේෂයක් සොයාගෙන ඇති අතර, මේඝාලය ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ඝන මාපටැඟිලි සහිත වවුලන් විශේෂයක් සොයා ගැනීමත් සමගයි.",
        "දිවයිනේ රුහුණු විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ තාරක කුසුමින්ද ප්‍රමුඛ කණ්ඩායම විසින් මෙම නව දිගු ඇඟිලි සහිත වවුලන් විශේෂය Miniopterus phillipsi ලෙස නම් කර ඇත.",
        "එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ දකුණු ආසියාවේ ක්ෂීරපායින් පිළිබඳ අධ්‍යයනයන් සඳහා ඔහුගේ දායකත්වය අගයමින් W W A Philips (1892-1981) නමින් නම් කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම විශේෂයේ නිදර්ශක ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඌව පළාතේ ඉදුල්ගස්හින්න ගුහාවෙන් එකතු කරන ලද අතර දැනට අසල්වැසි රටේ ස්වභාවික ඉතිහාස කෞතුකාගාරයේ තැන්පත් කර ඇත.",
        "මූලික පර්යේෂණ 2019 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිදු කරන ලද අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඉන්දියාව යන දෙඅංශයෙන්ම අවසන් කිරීමට වසර තුනක් ගත විය.",
        "මෙම සොයාගැනීම ජාත්‍යන්තර විද්‍යාත්මක සඟරාවක් වන Acta Chiropterologica හි ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ බටහිර කඳුකරයේ මහාබලේෂ්වර් හි රොබර්ස් ගුහාවේ සිටින දිගු ඇඟිලි සහිත වවුලන් ගහනය ද පෙරදිග නැමුණු පියාපත් සහිත වවුලන් ලෙස වරදවා වටහාගෙන ඇති මෙම විශේෂයට අයත් බව පර්යේෂකයන් සොයා ගත්හ.",
        "Miniopteridae පවුලට අයත් දිගු ඇඟිලි සහිත වවුලන් අවම වශයෙන් ලොව පුරා විශේෂ 40 කින් සමන්විත විශාල කණ්ඩායමක කොටසකි.",
        "ඒවාට සමාන රූප විද්‍යාව සහ අතිච්ඡාදනය වන මානයන් ඇති අතර විශේෂ හඳුනාගැනීම ගැටළු සහගත වේ.",
        "මෙම නව විශේෂය විස්තර කිරීම සඳහා, පර්යේෂකයන් විසින් ඉන්දියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිදර්ශක DNA තීරු කේතයක් කර මෙම කණ්ඩායමේ අනෙකුත් සියලුම ආසියානු සාමාජිකයින් සමඟ සංසන්දනය කර මෙම නිදර්ශක වෙනස් විශේෂයකට අයත් බවට ප්‍රබල සාක්ෂි සොයාගෙන ඇත.",
        "මීට අමතරව, පර්යේෂකයන් ඉන්දියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇති සංජානන සමඟ නව විශේෂයේ රූප විද්‍යාත්මක හා ව්‍යුහ විද්‍යාත්මක ලක්ෂණ විශ්ලේෂණය කර නව විශේෂය සැබවින්ම වෙනස් බව සොයා ගත් බව කුසුමින්ද පැවසීය.",
        "\"දිගු ඇගිලි සහිත වවුලන් විශාල ජනපදවල ජීවත් වන අනිවාර්ය ගුහා සහ උමං වාසීන් වන අතර මෙම නව විශේෂය ද ව්යතිරේකයක් නොවේ,\" පර්යේෂකයා ප්රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එය සාපේක්ෂ වශයෙන් ව්‍යාප්තව පවතින අතර, ඉන්දියාවේ එහි නිශ්චිත ව්‍යාප්ති පරාසය තීරණය කිරීම සඳහා තවත් අධ්‍යයනයන් අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "අවම වශයෙන් කීර්තිමත් විද්‍යාඥයින් 13 දෙනෙකු මෙම පර්යේෂණයට සම්බන්ධ වී ඇත - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් හය දෙනෙක් සහ ඉන්දියාව, රුසියාව, ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය, හංගේරියාව, එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයෙන් එක් අයෙකු බැගින්.",
        "විද්‍යාඥයින් කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් මෑතකදී මේඝාලයේ උණ බම්බු වනාන්තරයකින් ඝන මාපටැඟිලි සහිත නව වවුලන් විශේෂයක් සොයාගෙන එය ප්‍රාන්තයේ නමින් නම් කර ඇත.",
        "Glischropus meghalayanus සොයා ගැනීම ප්‍රමුඛ වර්ගීකරණ සඟරාවක් වන Zootaxa හි පළ විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් රුපියල් කෝටි 1000ක් වටිනා බෙහෙත් වට්ටෝරු සොයා ගනී. මන්නාරමේ ලක්ෂ 45යි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේඝාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tharaka Kusuminda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුහුණු විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Miniopterus phillipsi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් ඩබ්ලිව් ඒ පිලිප්ස්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1892-1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදුල්ගස්හින්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වභාවික ඉතිහාස කෞතුකාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇක්ටා චිරොප්ටෙරොලොජිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හොරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාබලේශ්වර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusuminda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිගු ඇඟිලි ඇති",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනපද",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හංගේරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේඝාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Glischropus",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zootaxa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா, இலங்கையில் புதிய நீண்ட விரல் கொண்ட வௌவால் இனங்கள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேகாலயாவில் தடித்த கட்டைவிரல் கொண்ட வௌவால் இனம் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதை அடுத்து, சர்வதேச ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் குழு இந்தியாவிலும் இலங்கையிலும் புதிய வகை நீண்ட விரல் கொண்ட வௌவால்களைக் கண்டறிந்துள்ளது.",
        "தீவு நாட்டில் உள்ள ருஹுனா பல்கலைக்கழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த தாரக குசுமிந்த தலைமையிலான குழுவினர், புதிய வகை நீண்ட விரல் கொண்ட வௌவால்களுக்கு மினியோப்டெரஸ் பிலிப்சி என பெயரிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை மற்றும் தெற்காசியாவின் பாலூட்டிகள் பற்றிய ஆய்வுகளில் அவர் ஆற்றிய பங்களிப்பை அங்கீகரிப்பதற்காக டபிள்யூ டபிள்யூ ஏ பிலிப்ஸின் (1892-1981) பெயரிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த இனத்திற்கான மாதிரிகள் இலங்கையில் ஊவா மாகாணத்தில் உள்ள இதுல்கசின்ன குகையில் இருந்து சேகரிக்கப்பட்டு தற்போது அண்டை நாட்டின் இயற்கை வரலாற்று அருங்காட்சியகத்தில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஆரம்ப ஆராய்ச்சி 2019 இல் இலங்கையில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது மற்றும் இது இலங்கை மற்றும் இந்தியா ஆகிய இரண்டிலும் முடிக்க மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் ஆனது.",
        "இந்த கண்டுபிடிப்பு சர்வதேச அறிவியல் இதழான Acta Chiropterologica இல் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியாவின் மேற்குத் தொடர்ச்சி மலையில் உள்ள மகாபலேஷ்வரில் உள்ள ராபர்ஸ் குகையில் உள்ள நீண்ட விரல் கொண்ட வவ்வால்களின் எண்ணிக்கையும் இந்த இனத்தைச் சேர்ந்தது என்று ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் கண்டறிந்தனர், இது முன்பு கிழக்கு வளைந்த இறக்கைகள் கொண்ட வெளவால்கள் என்று தவறாகக் கருதப்பட்டது.",
        "மினியோப்டெரிடே குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த நீண்ட விரல் கொண்ட வெளவால்கள் உலகளவில் குறைந்தது 40 இனங்களைக் கொண்ட ஒரு பெரிய குழுவின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும்.",
        "அவை ஒரே மாதிரியான உருவவியல் மற்றும் ஒன்றுடன் ஒன்று பரிமாணங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளன, அவை இனங்கள் அடையாளம் காண்பதில் சிக்கலை ஏற்படுத்துகின்றன.",
        "இந்த புதிய இனத்தை விவரிக்க, ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் டிஎன்ஏ இந்தியா மற்றும் இலங்கையின் மாதிரிகளை பார்கோடு செய்து, இந்த குழுவின் மற்ற அனைத்து ஆசிய உறுப்பினர்களுடன் ஒப்பிட்டு, இந்த மாதிரிகள் ஒரு தனித்துவமான இனத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவை என்பதற்கு வலுவான ஆதாரங்களைக் கண்டறிந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தவிர, ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் இந்தியாவிலும் இலங்கையிலும் நிகழும் புதிய இனங்களின் உருவவியல் மற்றும் உடற்கூறியல் அம்சங்களையும் ஆய்வு செய்தனர் மற்றும் புதிய இனங்கள் உண்மையில் வேறுபட்டவை என்பதைக் கண்டறிந்தனர், குசுமிந்தா கூறினார்.",
        "\"நீண்ட விரல் கொண்ட வெளவால்கள் பெரிய காலனிகளில் வாழும் கட்டாய குகை மற்றும் சுரங்கப்பாதையில் வசிப்பவர்கள் மற்றும் இந்த புதிய இனமும் விதிவிலக்கல்ல\" என்று ஆராய்ச்சியாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் இது ஒப்பீட்டளவில் பரவலாக இருந்தாலும், இந்தியாவில் அதன் சரியான விநியோக வரம்பை தீர்மானிக்க கூடுதல் ஆய்வுகள் தேவைப்படுகின்றன.",
        "இந்த குறிப்பிட்ட ஆராய்ச்சியில் குறைந்தது 13 புகழ்பெற்ற விஞ்ஞானிகள் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர் - ஆறு இலங்கை மற்றும் இந்தியா, ரஷ்யா, சுவிட்சர்லாந்து, ஹங்கேரி, இங்கிலாந்து மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவிலிருந்து தலா ஒருவர்.",
        "மேகாலயாவில் உள்ள மூங்கில் காட்டில் இருந்து தடித்த கட்டைவிரல் கொண்ட வௌவால்களின் புதிய இனத்தை விஞ்ஞானிகள் குழு சமீபத்தில் கண்டுபிடித்து அதற்கு மாநிலத்தின் பெயரை சூட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "Glischropus meghalayanus இன் கண்டுபிடிப்பு Zootaxa, ஒரு முக்கிய வகைபிரித்தல் இதழில் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படை 2000 ரூபா பெறுமதியான மருந்துகளை மீட்டுள்ளது. மன்னாரில் 4.5 மில்லியன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேகாலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tharaka Kusuminda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருஹுணு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மினியோப்டெரஸ் பிலிப்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ டபிள்யூ ஏ பிலிப்ஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1892-1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இதுல்கஷின்னா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயற்கை வரலாற்று அருங்காட்சியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆக்டா சிரோப்டெரோலாஜிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளைக்காரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாபலேஷ்வர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusuminda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீண்ட விரல் உடையவர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலனிகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹங்கேரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேகாலயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிளிச்ரோபஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூடாக்சா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}