{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/05/navy-nabs-5-indian-fishermen-poaching-in-sea-of-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1657012560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy nabs 5 Indian fishermen poaching in Sea of Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy nabs 5 Indian fishermen poaching in Sea of Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lanka Navy conducted a special operation to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in northern waters of the island in the evening of 04th July 2022.",
        "Accordingly, the operation led to the seizure of an Indian trawler with 05 Indian fishermen poaching in Sri Lankan waters off the Analaitivu Island.",
        "The Navy deployed Fast Attack Craft of the 4th Fast Attack Flotilla (4 FAF), attached to the Northern Naval Command to chase away those Indian trawlers from Sri Lankan waters, after having spotted them poaching off the Analaitivu Island, via the International Maritime Boundary Line (IMBL).",
        "In this operation, the Navy seized an Indian trawler with 05 Indian fishermen and their fishing gear, for poaching in the island’s waters.",
        "In a similar operation carried out on 03rd July, the Navy seized another Indian trawler with 12 fishermen poaching in Sri Lankan waters off Point Pedro.",
        "Accordingly, both Indian poaching vessels and 17 Indian fishermen have been produced for onward legal proceedings. Meanwhile, the Navy is determined to carry out regular operations to protect the country’s fishery resources and livelihood of the local fishing community."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "04th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Analaitivu Island",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Analaitivu Island",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Maritime Boundary Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03rd July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Point Pedro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදේ ධීවර කටයුතුවල නිරත වූ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 5 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 ජුලි 04 වන දින සවස දිවයිනේ උතුරු මුහුදු තීරයේ දඩයම් කරන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීම සඳහා විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමක් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව අනලතිව් දූපතට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ ධීවර කටයුතුවල නිරත වූ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 05 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට මෙම මෙහෙයුම හේතු විය.",
        "එම ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවෙන් පළවා හැරීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත 4 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක ෆ්ලෝටිලා (4 FAF) හි වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාවක් යොදවා ඇති අතර, ඒවා ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර මායිම් රේඛාව හරහා අනලතිව් දූපතෙන් ඔබ්බට දඩයම් කරන බව දැකීමෙන් පසුවය. (IMBL).",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 05 දෙනෙකු සමග ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ධීවර ආම්පන්න නාවික හමුදාව විසින් දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ මසුන් ඇල්ලීම සඳහා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ජුලි මස 03 වැනි දින සිදු කරන ලද මෙවැනිම මෙහෙයුමකදී පේදුරුතුඩුවට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු තීරයේදී ධීවරයින් 12 දෙනෙකු සමඟ තවත් ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රා සහ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 17 දෙනෙකු ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබෙනවා. මේ අතර, මෙරට ධීවර සම්පත සහ දේශීය ධීවර ප්‍රජාවගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා නිරන්තර මෙහෙයුම් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට නාවික හමුදාව තීරණය කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනලතිව් දූපත",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්රහාරක යාත්රාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනලතිව් දූපත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර මායිම් රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේදුරුතුඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடற்பகுதியில் அத்துமீறி மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 5 இந்திய மீனவர்களை கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 04 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று மாலை தீவின் வடக்கு கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டுவதற்கு இலங்கை கடற்படை சிறப்பு நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, அனலைதீவு கடற்பரப்பில் இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் அத்துமீறி மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 05 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் இந்திய இழுவை படகு ஒன்று கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "அனலைதீவு தீவில், சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு வழியாக வேட்டையாடுவதைக் கண்டறிந்த கடற்படையினர், இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் இருந்து அந்த இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டுவதற்காக வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட 4வது ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் புளோட்டிலாவின் (4 FAF) விரைவு தாக்குதல் கப்பலை அனுப்பியுள்ளனர். (IMBL).",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில், தீவு கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடியதற்காக 05 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் ஒரு இந்திய இழுவை படகு மற்றும் அவர்களது மீன்பிடி உபகரணங்களை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றினர்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 03ஆம் திகதி மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இதேபோன்ற நடவடிக்கையில் பருத்தித்துறை கடற்பரப்பில் இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் அத்துமீறி மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 12 மீனவர்களுடன் மற்றொரு இந்திய இழுவை படகு கடற்படையினரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "அதன்படி, இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் படகுகளும், 17 இந்திய மீனவர்களும் சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். இதேவேளை, நாட்டின் கடற்றொழில் வளங்கள் மற்றும் உள்ளூர் மீனவ மக்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக வழக்கமான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள கடற்படை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனலைதீவு தீவு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனலைதீவு தீவு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பருத்தித்துறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}