{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/ඉතාලි-අගමැති-ඉල්ලා-අස්වෙයි/14-616804",
  "time_ut": 1658393270,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉතාලි අගමැති ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Italian Prime Minister resigns",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Italian Prime Minister Mario Draghi has decided to resign from his post. Draghi made this decision because his intervention led to the collapse of the coalition government formed 17 months ago.",
        "Draghi is also said to have met Italian President Serge Mattarella and handed in his resignation. At that time, President Mattarella said that Draghi should remain as Prime Minister until a new government is appointed. Accordingly, it is also said that Draghi will remain as Acting Prime Minister.",
        "A motion of no confidence was brought against Draghi in the Senate of the Italian Parliament, which also defeated Draghi.",
        "However, several major political groups in the coalition government refused to support Draghi, so he could not stay in office any longer.",
        "The Italian Senate consists of 315 seats. During the no-confidence vote in the Senate, Draghi's coalition government received 95 votes in favor and 36 votes against."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Italian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Italian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mario Draghi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Italian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Serge Mattarella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mattarella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draghi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Senate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Italian Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Italian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "315",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draghi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉතාලි අගමැති ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉතාලි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාරියෝ ඩ්‍රාගී සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තීරණය කළේය. ඩ්‍රාගී මෙසේ තීරණය කළේ ඔහුගේ මැදිහත් වීමෙන් මීට මාස 17 කට පෙර පිහිටුවූ සන්ධාන රජය බිඳ වැටුණු නිසාය.",
        "ඩ්‍රාගී ඉතාලි ජනාධිපති සර්ගේ මැටරෙල්ලා හමුවී සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම බාර දුන් බව ද පැවැසෙයි. එම අවස්ථාවේදී ජනාධිපති මැටරෙල්ලා පවසා ඇත්තේ නව රජයක් පත් කරන තුරු ඩ්‍රාගී අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයේ රැදී සිටින යුතු බවය. ඒ අනුව, ඩ්‍රාගී වැඩ බලන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලෙස රැදී සිටිනු ඇතැයි ද පැවැසෙයි.",
        "ඩ්‍රාගීට එරෙහිව ඉතාලි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සෙනෙට් මණ්ඩලයට විශ්වාසභංගක් ඉදිරිපත් කෙරුණු අතර එය ද ඩ්‍රාගී පරාජය කළේය.",
        "එසේ වුවත් සන්ධාන රජයේ ප්‍රධාන දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් කීපයක් ඩ්‍රාගීට සහාය පළ කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බැවින් තව දුරටත් ධුරයේ රැදී සිටීමට ඔහුට නොහැකි විය.",
        "ඉතාලි සෙනෙට් මණ්ඩලය ආසන 315 කින් සමන්විතය. සෙනෙට් මණ්ඩලයේ විශ්වාසභංගයට අදාල ඡන්ද විමසුම පැවැත්වෙද්දී, ඩ්‍රාගීගේ සන්ධාන රජයට පක්ෂව ඡන්ද 95 ක් සහ විපක්ෂව ඡන්ද 36 ක් හිමිවිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉතාලි",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාරියෝ ඩ්‍රාගි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 17කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ජ් මැටරෙල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැට්ටරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩ්රාගි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "315",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩ්රාගි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இத்தாலி பிரதமர் ராஜினாமா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இத்தாலி பிரதமர் மரியோ டிராகி தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய முடிவு செய்துள்ளார். அவரது தலையீடு 17 மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு அமைக்கப்பட்ட கூட்டணி ஆட்சியை கவிழ்க்க வழிவகுத்ததால் டிராகி இந்த முடிவை எடுத்தார்.",
        "Draghi இத்தாலிய ஜனாதிபதி Serge Mattarella ஐ சந்தித்து தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை கையளித்ததாக கூறப்படுகிறது. அப்போது, ​​புதிய அரசாங்கம் நியமிக்கப்படும் வரை டிராகி பிரதமராக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று அதிபர் மேட்டரெல்லா கூறினார். அதன்படி, தற்காலிக பிரதமராக திராகி நீடிப்பார் என்றும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "இத்தாலிய பாராளுமன்றத்தின் செனட்டில் டிராகிக்கு எதிராக நம்பிக்கையில்லா தீர்மானம் கொண்டு வரப்பட்டது, அது டிராகியையும் தோற்கடித்தது.",
        "இருப்பினும், கூட்டணி அரசாங்கத்தில் உள்ள பல முக்கிய அரசியல் குழுக்கள் டிராகியை ஆதரிக்க மறுத்ததால், அவர் இனி பதவியில் இருக்க முடியவில்லை.",
        "இத்தாலிய செனட் 315 இடங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. செனட்டில் நடந்த நம்பிக்கையில்லா வாக்கெடுப்பின் போது, ​​டிராகியின் கூட்டணி அரசுக்கு ஆதரவாக 95 வாக்குகளும் எதிராக 36 வாக்குகளும் கிடைத்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இத்தாலிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரியோ ட்ராகி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செர்ஜ் மேட்டரெல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேட்டரெல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ராகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செனட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலிய பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "315",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ராகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}