{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/13/ranil-declared-emergency-pms-media-division/",
  "time_ut": 1657697400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil declared emergency – PMs Media Division",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil declared emergency – PMs Media Division",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Prime Minister’s Media Division on Wednesday (13) said that Ranil Wickremesinghe has declared Emergency Law as the Acting President and the Prime Minister.",
        "The Prime Minister’s Media Division said that curfew had been declared for the entire Western Province.",
        "The Prime Minister’s Media Division also said that the Ranil Wickremesinghe had informed the Inspector General of Police and the Three-Armed Force to arrest those who behave in an unruly manner and seized their lorries and tipper trucks that they travel in.",
        "Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa flew to the Maldives with his wife and two personal security officers, early this morning.",
        "However, The Hindu Newspaper in India reported that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe will declare an island-wide Emergency when he becomes acting President, his office said on July 13 although President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is yet to officially resign.",
        "The move came as thousands of angry protesters gathered outside the PM’s office, official and private residences, and several other locations in capital Colombo on July 13 morning.",
        "Ranil to perform & discharge duties of President, as Gotabaya Rajapaksa is overseas – Speaker"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Media Division",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emergency Law",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Three-Armed Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Hindu Newspaper",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13 morning",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් හදිසි ප්‍රකාශයක් - අගමැති මාධ්‍ය අංශය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අගමැති මාධ්‍ය අංශය බදාදා (13) කියා සිටියේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය අංශය පැවසුවේ බස්නාහිර පළාතටම ඇඳිරි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "නොසන්සුන්කාරී ලෙස හැසිරෙන පුද්ගලයින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙසත් ඔවුන් ගමන් ගන්නා ලොරි සහ ටිපර් රථ අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙසත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පොලිස්පතිවරයාට සහ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවට දැනුම් දී ඇති බව ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය බිරිඳ සහ පෞද්ගලික ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනකු සමඟ අද අලුයම මාලදිවයිනට පියාසර කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඉන්දියාවේ හින්දු පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේ, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති වූ පසු දිවයින පුරා හදිසි තත්ත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන බව, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තවමත් නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී නොමැති නමුත් ජූලි 13 වන දින ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජුලි 13 උදෑසන අගමැති කාර්යාලය, නිල සහ පෞද්ගලික නිවාස සහ අගනුවර කොළඹ තවත් ස්ථාන කිහිපයකින් පිටත කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් දහස් ගණනක් රැස්ව සිටීමත් සමඟ මෙම පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ විදේශගතව සිටින නිසා රනිල් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ රාජකාරිය ඉටුකර ඉටුකරනවා - කථානායක"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු පුවත්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 උදේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் அவசரநிலை பிரகடனம் – பிரதமர் ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பதில் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமராக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை பிரகடனப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு புதன்கிழமை (13) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மாகாணம் முழுவதும் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அநாகரீகமாக நடந்துகொள்பவர்களைக் கைது செய்யுமாறு பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் மற்றும் முப்படையினருக்கு ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க அறிவித்துள்ளதாகவும், அவர்கள் பயணிக்கும் லொறிகள் மற்றும் டிப்பர் பாரவூர்திகளையும் கைப்பற்றுவதாகவும் பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தனது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு தனிப்பட்ட பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளுடன் இன்று அதிகாலை மாலைதீவுக்கு சென்றார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றதும் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அவசரநிலையை பிரகடனப்படுத்துவார் என தி ஹிந்து நாளிதழ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது, ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்னும் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பதவி விலகவில்லை என்றாலும், ஜூலை 13 அன்று அவரது அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 13 காலை தலைநகர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகம், உத்தியோகபூர்வ மற்றும் தனியார் இல்லங்கள் மற்றும் பல இடங்களுக்கு வெளியே ஆயிரக்கணக்கான கோபமான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் கூடியிருந்ததால் இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வெளிநாட்டில் இருப்பதால் ரணில் ஜனாதிபதியின் கடமைகளை நிறைவேற்றுவார் - சபாநாயகர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று ஆயுதப் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி இந்து நாளிதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 காலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}