{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130500",
  "time_ut": 1656588490,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கந்தப்பளையில் ஆலய உண்டியல் உடைக்கப்பட்டு பணம் திருட்டு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Temple bill broken and money stolen in Kandapalai",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "A two-foot-tall silver billboard of the Tea Hill Sri Baladandayuthapani temple in the garden section of the Kandapalai police division was broken into by mysterious persons on Wednesday night and a large amount of money was stolen.",
        "The thieves broke through the window of the temple, broke the lock of the bill found inside the temple, stole a large amount of money found in the bill and threw the bill outside the temple.",
        "Preliminary investigations have revealed that the money found in the temple bill had not been taken by the temple administration for more than five years.",
        "With the help of a sniffer dog, the Kandhapalaya police are carrying out further investigations regarding the incident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kandapalai",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two-foot",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tea Hill",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandapalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kandhapalaya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්දපලෙයි පන්සලේ බිල්පත කඩා මුදල් සොරකම් කරයි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "කන්දපලෙයි පොලිස් වසමේ උද්‍යාන කොටසේ තේ කන්ද ශ්‍රී බලදණ්ඩායුතපාණි විහාරස්ථානයේ අඩි දෙකක් පමණ උස රිදී දැන්වීම් පුවරුවක් අද්භූත පුද්ගලයන් විසින් බදාදා රාත්‍රියේ කඩා විශාල මුදලක් සොරාගෙන ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "විහාරස්ථානයේ ජනේලය කඩා විහාරස්ථානයේ තිබු බිල්පතේ අගුල කඩා බිල්පතේ තිබු විශාල මුදලක් සොරාගත් සොරුන් බිල්පත විහාරස්ථානයෙන් පිටතට විසිකර තිබෙනවා.",
        "විහාරස්ථානයේ බිල්පතේ තිබී සොයාගත් මුදල් වසර පහකට වැඩි කාලයක සිට විහාරස්ථානයේ පාලනාධිකාරිය විසින් ලබාගෙන නොමැති බව මූලික විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී තිබේ.",
        "කඳපලෙයි පොලිසිය නිල සුනඛයකුගේද සහාය ඇතිව වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කන්දපාලෙයි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අඩි දෙකක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේ කන්ද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්දපාලෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්දපාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கந்தப்பளையில் ஆலய உண்டியல் உடைக்கப்பட்டு பணம் திருட்டு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "கந்தப்பளை பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட பார்க்தோட்ட பிரிவான தேயிலை மலை ஸ்ரீ பாலதண்டாயுதபாணி ஆலயத்தின் இரண்டு அடி உயரம் கொண்ட வெள்ளியால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட உண்டியல் 29 ஆம் திகதி புதன் இரவு மர்ம நபர்களினால் உடைக்கப்பட்டு பெரும் தொகையான பணம் களவாடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குறித்த ஆலயத்தின் யன்னல் பகுதியூடாக உள்ளே சென்ற திருடர்கள் ஆலயத்தின் உள்ளே காணப்பட்ட உண்டியலின் பூட்டை உடைத்து உண்டியலில் காணப்பட்ட பெருந் தொகையான பணம் களவாடப்பட்டு உண்டியலை ஆலய வெளிப்பகுதியில் வீசப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இவ் ஆலய உண்டியலில் காணப்பட்ட பணம் சுமார் ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு மேலாக ஆலய நிருவாகத்தினரால்  எடுக்கப்படாடத பணம் என ஆரம்ப கட்ட விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கந்தப்பளை பொலிஸார் மோப்ப நாய்யின் உதவியுடன் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை முன்னெடுத்து வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கந்தபளை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேயிலை மலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தபளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கந்தபாலய",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}