{
  "newspaper_id": "colombo-telegraph-com",
  "url": "https://www.colombotelegraph.com/index.php/cid-waits-till-the-rti-act-is-used-to-investigate-death-threats-by-dig-deshabandu-tennakoon-against-a-journalist/",
  "time_ut": 1660266851,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CID Waits Till The RTI Act Is Used To Investigate Death Threats By DIG Deshabandu Tennakoon Against A Journalist",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CID Waits Till The RTI Act Is Used To Investigate Death Threats By DIG Deshabandu Tennakoon Against A Journalist",
      "author": "COLOMBO TELEGRAPH",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has finally commenced investigations into a complaint regarding death threats issued to a journalist by a senior police officer on Facebook in 2021, more than a year after the complaint was filed. This was after the Right to Information Commission issued summons to the Inspector General of Police (IGP) in 2022 following the journalist appealing to the Commission. His RTI request in 2021 asking for the status of the investigations had been ignored by the Police Department.",
        "Issuing an interim order on 27th June 2022, the RTI Commission had directed the Inspector General of Police (IGP) to respond on nine questions asked by journalist Tharindu Jayawardena regarding a Facebook post by senior DIG Deshabandu Tennakoon on 1st July 2021.",
        "The social media message, posted by Tennakoon at the dead of night, had stated that, the journalist was writing lies and that ‘nature’ or ‘natural justice’ would ‘take care of him.’ This rang alarm bells in the journalistic and civil activist community. The deaths and assaults of many journalists had commonly followed such ‘warnings.’ A collective of media organisations wrote to the IGP asking for a formal inquiry. However, no inquiry took place. The Facebook posts by Tennakoon were in response to articles on the witchhunting of former head of the CID Shani Abeysekera who had handled key investigations against former President Mahinda Rajapaksa, his brothers and his cronies.",
        "The journalist had then filed an RTI request to the IGP in 2021 asking, if the inquiry into the complaints on the death threats had commenced, if so, how many witnesses had been summoned, who had been put in charge, what was the status etc. After both the Information Officer and Designated Officer had failed to respond, he had filed an appeal to the Commission.",
        "On the summons of the Commission, the CID had informed that, on the recommendation of its legal committee, the social media division of the CID has now commenced investigations under the direction of a senior DIG. The investigations will proceed on the instructions of the Attorney General, the CID said.",
        "In its final Order on 3rd of August 2022, the RTI Commission recorded the responses of the CID to all the questions asked by the journalist and directed the IGP to release the correspondence that had passed between himself and the CID regarding the matter as well as the recommendation of the legal committee. The Commission also issued a warning to the IGP to respond to RTI requests without delay as required in the RTI Act.",
        "Shortly after the RTIC Order, the CID had summoned the journalist for a hearing this Tuesday (9th August 2022). Senior DIG Tennakoon has meanwhile been questioned by the CID on his intentionally permitting thugs of former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa to attack peaceful protestors on Galle Face Green on May 9th 2022. Tennakoon was himself attacked by enraged protestors a day later, two suspects have been arrested in connection with that incident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than a year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Right to Information Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27th June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tharindu Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DIG Deshabandu Tennakoon",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st July 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tennakoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tennakoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DIG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Order on 3rd of August 2022",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the RTIC Order",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9th 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day later",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන් මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකුට මරණ තර්ජන ගැන විමර්ශනය කිරීමට තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනත යොදා ගන්නා තෙක් CID බලා සිටී",
      "author": "COLOMBO Telegraph",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) අවසානයේ 2021 වසරේදී ෆෙස්බුක් වෙබ් අඩවියේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු විසින් මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකුට මරණීය තර්ජන එල්ල කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කර වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක් ගතවීමෙන් පසු විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කර ඇත. ඒ, මාධ්‍යවේදියා කොමිසමට අභියාචනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිය පිළිබඳ කොමිෂන් සභාව 2022 වසරේ පොලිස්පතිවරයාට සිතාසි නිකුත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි. 2021 දී ඔහු විසින් සිදු කරන ලද තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිය පිළිබඳ ඉල්ලීම් පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නොසලකා හරින ලදී.",
        "2022 ජූනි 27 වැනි දින අතුරු නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරමින් RTI කොමිසම 2021 ජූලි 01 වැනි දින ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන් මහතාගේ ෆේස්බුක් සටහනක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍යවේදී තරිඳු ජයවර්ධන විසින් අසන ලද ප්‍රශ්න නවයකට පිළිතුරු දෙන ලෙස පොලිස්පතිවරයාට නියෝග කර තිබුණි.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදියා බොරු ලියන බවත්, 'සොබාදහම' හෝ 'ස්වාභාවික යුක්තිය' ඔහුව බලා ගනු ඇති බවත්, තෙන්නකෝන් රාත්‍රියේ තැබූ සමාජ මාධ්‍ය පණිවිඩයේ සඳහන්ව තිබුණි. මෙය මාධ්‍යවේදයේ සහ සිවිල් සමාජයේ අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ සීනු නාද විය. ක්රියාකාරී ප්රජාව. බොහෝ මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ගේ මරණ සහ පහරදීම් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සිදුවූයේ එවැනි ‘අනතුරු ඇඟවීම්’ අනුගමනය කරමිනි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, කිසිදු පරීක්ෂණයක් සිදු නොවීය. හිටපු ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරන්ට සහ ඔහුගේ හිතවතුන්ට එරෙහිව ප්‍රධාන පරීක්ෂණ මෙහෙයවූ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ හිටපු ප්‍රධානී ශානි අබේසේකර මන්ත්‍රීවරයා දඩයම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පළ වූ ලිපිවලට පිළිතුරු ලෙස තෙන්නකෝන් ගේ ෆේස්බුක් සටහන් විය.",
        "අනතුරුව මාධ්‍යවේදියා 2021 වසරේ පොලිස්පතිවරයාට RTI ඉල්ලීමක් කරමින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ මරණ තර්ජන පිළිබඳ පැමිණිලි විමර්ශනය ආරම්භ කළේ නම්, සාක්ෂිකරුවන් කී දෙනෙකු කැඳවා තිබේද, භාරව සිටියේ කවුරුන්ද, තත්ත්වය කුමක්ද යන්නයි. තොරතුරු නිලධාරියා සහ නම් කරන ලද නිලධාරියා යන දෙදෙනාම ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට අපොහොසත් වූ පසු, ඔහු කොමිසමට අභියාචනයක් ගොනු කර ඇත.",
        "කොමිසමේ කැඳවීම මත අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දන්වා තිබුණේ සිය නීති කමිටුවේ නිර්දේශ මත අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සමාජ මාධ්‍ය අංශය ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පතිවරයෙකුගේ මෙහෙයවීමෙන් මේ වනවිට පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවයි. නීතිපතිවරයාගේ උපදෙස් මත විමර්ශන කටයුතු සිදුකරන බව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 03 වැනි දින සිය අවසන් නියෝගයෙන් RTI කොමිසම මාධ්‍යවේදියා විසින් අසන ලද සියලුම ප්‍රශ්නවලට රහස් පොලිසියේ ප්‍රතිචාර සටහන් කර ගත් අතර, ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමා සහ CID අතර ඇති වූ ලිපි හුවමාරුව මෙන්ම, නීති කමිටුවේ නිර්දේශය. තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනතේ අවශ්‍ය පරිදි තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිවාසිකම් ඉල්ලීම්වලට ප්‍රමාදයකින් තොරව ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වන ලෙසද කොමිසම පොලිස්පතිවරයාට අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් කළේය.",
        "තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනතේ නියෝගයෙන් ටික වේලාවකට පසු, අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මෙම මාධ්‍යවේදියා මෙම අඟහරුවාදා (2022 අගෝස්තු 9) නඩු විභාගයක් සඳහා කැඳවා තිබුණි. මේ අතර 2022 මැයි 9 වනදා ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ සාමකාමී විරෝධතාවයකට පහර දීමට හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ මැරයින්ට හිතාමතාම අවසර දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති තෙන්නකෝන් මහතාගෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ප්‍රශ්න කර ඇත. ඊට දිනකට පසු තෙන්නකෝන්ටම ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල වී සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ. ඒ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිය කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජුනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තරිඳු ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජූලි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙන්නකෝන් ය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙන්නකෝන් ය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.අයි.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 3 වන දින ඇණවුම් කරන්න",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RTIC නියෝගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලුමුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනකට පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவருக்கு எதிரான DIG தேசபந்து தென்னகோனின் மரண அச்சுறுத்தல்களை விசாரிக்க RTI சட்டம் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் வரை CID காத்திருக்கிறது",
      "author": "கொழும்பு டெலிகிராப்",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் (CID) இறுதியாக 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு பேஸ்புக்கில் மூத்த பொலிஸ் அதிகாரியினால் ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவருக்கு மரண அச்சுறுத்தல் விடுக்கப்பட்டமை தொடர்பான முறைப்பாடு தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது. 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு தகவல் அறியும் உரிமை ஆணைக்குழு, ஊடகவியலாளர் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் முறையிட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கு (IGP) சம்மன் அனுப்பப்பட்டது. 2021 இல் விசாரணைகளின் நிலையைக் கேட்டு அவர் செய்த RTI கோரிக்கை காவல் துறையால் புறக்கணிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜூன் 27, 2022 அன்று இடைக்கால உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்த RTI ஆணைக்குழு, 2021 ஜூலை 1 அன்று மூத்த டிஐஜி தேசபந்து தென்னகோனின் முகநூல் பதிவு தொடர்பாக ஊடகவியலாளர் தரிந்து ஜெயவர்தன கேட்ட ஒன்பது கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்குமாறு பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கு (IGP) உத்தரவிட்டிருந்தது.",
        "அந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் பொய்களை எழுதுவதாகவும், 'இயற்கையோ' 'இயற்கை நீதியோ' அவரைப் பார்த்துக்கொள்ளும்' எனவும் தென்னகோன் வெளியிட்ட சமூக ஊடகச் செய்தியில், ஊடகவியலாளர் மற்றும் சிவில் ஊடகங்களில் எச்சரிக்கை மணி அடித்தது. ஆர்வலர் சமூகம். பல ஊடகவியலாளர்களின் மரணங்கள் மற்றும் தாக்குதல்கள் பொதுவாக இத்தகைய 'எச்சரிக்கைகளை' பின்பற்றி வந்தன. ஊடக அமைப்புகளின் கூட்டு, முறையான விசாரணையைக் கோரி ஐஜிபிக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியது. ஆனால், எந்த விசாரணையும் நடக்கவில்லை. தென்னகோனின் முகநூல் பதிவுகள், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது சகோதரர்கள் மற்றும் அவரது கூட்டாளிகளுக்கு எதிரான முக்கிய விசாரணைகளை கையாண்ட குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் ஷானி அபேசேகர மீதான சூனிய வேட்டை தொடர்பான கட்டுரைகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில் அமைந்திருந்தது.",
        "கொலை மிரட்டல் தொடர்பான புகார்கள் மீதான விசாரணை தொடங்கப்பட்டிருந்தால், எத்தனை சாட்சிகளுக்கு சம்மன் அனுப்பப்பட்டது, யார் பொறுப்பேற்றனர், நிலை என்ன போன்றவற்றைக் கேட்டு 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஐஜிபியிடம் செய்தியாளர் தகவல் அறியும் உரிமைக் கோரிக்கையை தாக்கல் செய்தார். தகவல் அதிகாரி மற்றும் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட அதிகாரி இருவரும் பதிலளிக்கத் தவறியதால், அவர் ஆணையத்தில் மேல்முறையீடு செய்தார்.",
        "ஆணைக்குழுவின் அழைப்பின் பேரில், சிஐடி தனது சட்டக் குழுவின் பரிந்துரையின் பேரில், சிஐடியின் சமூக ஊடகப் பிரிவு தற்போது மூத்த டிஐஜி ஒருவரின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ் விசாரணைகளைத் தொடங்கியுள்ளது என்று தெரிவித்தது. சட்டமா அதிபரின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் விசாரணைகள் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் என சிஐடி தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 3, 2022 அன்று, ஆர்டிஐ ஆணையம் தனது இறுதி உத்தரவில், பத்திரிகையாளர் கேட்ட அனைத்து கேள்விகளுக்கும் சிஐடியின் பதில்களைப் பதிவுசெய்தது மற்றும் இந்த விவகாரம் தொடர்பாக தனக்கும் சிஐடிக்கும் இடையே நடந்த கடிதங்களை வெளியிடுமாறு ஐஜிபிக்கு உத்தரவிட்டது. சட்டக் குழுவின் பரிந்துரை. தகவல் அறியும் உரிமைச் சட்டத்தில் தேவைப்படும் தகவல் அறியும் உரிமைக் கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு தாமதமின்றி பதிலளிக்குமாறு ஐஜிபிக்கு ஆணையம் எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "RTIC உத்தரவுக்குப் பிறகு, CID இந்த செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (9 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022) பத்திரிகையாளரை விசாரணைக்கு அழைத்தது. இதற்கிடையில், 2022 மே 9 ஆம் திகதி காலி முகத்திடலில் அமைதியான முறையில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களை தாக்க முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் குண்டர்கள் வேண்டுமென்றே அனுமதித்தமை தொடர்பில் சிரேஷ்ட பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தென்னகோனிடம் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் விசாரணைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். அந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பாக."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றவியல் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தகவல் அறியும் உரிமை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரிந்து ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DIG தேசபந்து தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 1, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.ஐ.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 3, 2022 அன்று ஆர்டர் செய்யுங்கள்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RTIC ஆணை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள் கழித்து",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}