{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83407/22a-aims-to-achieve-political-stability-minister-wijeyadasa",
  "time_ut": 1656872940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "22A aims to achieve political stability – Minister Wijeyadasa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "22A aims to achieve political stability – Minister Wijeyadasa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution was presented to establish political stability in the country which is requested by most of the international agencies assisting Sri Lanka, Minister of Justice, Prison Affairs & Constitutional Reforms Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe says.",
        "His views came in the backdrop where SLFP chairman Maithripala Sirisena criticized the 22nd constitutional amendment as an attempt to strengthen the powers of incumbent President Gotabaya Rajapaksa until the end of his tenure.",
        "Speaking at a media briefing today (July 03), Minister Rajapakshe said they do not intend to protect any person or a family via the 22nd constitutional amendment.",
        "“We have taken necessary steps to protect the country through this [constitutional amendment. The 22A was approved after all political parties agreed to it.”",
        "Speaking further, he said the Supreme Court has decided that the amendment presented bythe Opposition which includes 69 clauses covering 8 subject matters cannot be approved without a referendum.",
        "“Through the Bill that we have presented, we are avoiding a referendum,” he explained, adding that it has been presented in a way that none of the public representatives can object to it. “They can object, however, their conscience knows that they are acting against the people’s desires.”",
        "The condition set by the international organizations including IMF, the UN and the World Bank as well as the friendly nations that in talk with Sri Lanka at present, is that the law and order need to be established before obtaining their assistance to solve the country’s economic crisis, Minister Rajapakshe noted.",
        "The 21st Amendment to the Constitution is the constitutional amendments presented to the parliament by the main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) in April as a private Bill.",
        "It was later published in the government gazette and it was challenged in the Supreme Court.",
        "Dr. Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe, who was appointed the Minister of Justice, Prison Affairs & Constitutional Reforms, later presented a government Bill to the Cabinet of Ministers in his ministerial capacity, which is referred to as the 22nd amendment.",
        "The Supreme Court, delivering its determination, ruled that the 21st amendment put forward by the SJB cannot proceed further without a public referendum.",
        "In such a backdrop, the Cabinet of Ministers gave the approval to gazette the 22nd amendment presented by the Justice Minister.",
        "Once the 22nd amendment is passed in parliament, it will become the 21st amendment as the SJB’s amendment cannot proceed further."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22A",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wijeyadasa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prison Affairs & Constitutional Reforms Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22A",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 21st Amendment",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prison Affairs & Constitutional Reforms",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22A දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ළඟා කර ගැනීම අරමුණු කරයි - ඇමති විජයදාස",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ඉදිරිපත් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වන බොහෝ ජාත්‍යන්තර ආයතන විසින් ඉල්ලා සිටින දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය රට තුළ ඇති කිරීම සඳහා බව අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලනිප සභාපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය වත්මන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ධූර කාලය අවසන් වනතුරු ඔහුගේ බලතල ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස විවේචනය කළ පසුබිමකයි ඔහු මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ.",
        "අද (ජූලි 03) පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් අමාත්‍ය රාජපක්ෂ කියා සිටියේ 22 වන ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය හරහා කිසිදු පුද්ගලයෙකු හෝ පවුලක් ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට ඔවුන් අදහස් නොකරන බවයි.",
        "“අපි මේ [ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය හරහා රට ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගෙන තිබෙනවා. 22A අනුමත කළේ සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ ඊට එකඟ වීමෙන් පසුවයි.”",
        "එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දැක්වූ ඔහු කියා සිටියේ විෂය කරුණු 8ක් ආවරණය වන පරිදි වගන්ති 69ක් ඇතුළත් විපක්ෂය ඉදිරිපත් කළ සංශෝධනය ජනමත විචාරණයකින් තොරව අනුමත කළ නොහැකි බවට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය තීරණය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "“අපි ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති පනත් කෙටුම්පත හරහා අපි ජනමත විචාරණයක් මඟහරිනවා,” ඔහු පැහැදිලි කළ අතර, මහජන නියෝජිතයන් කිසිවෙකුට එයට විරුද්ධ විය නොහැකි ආකාරයෙන් එය ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව පැවසීය. \"ඔවුන්ට විරුද්ධ විය හැකිය, කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔවුන් මිනිසුන්ගේ ආශාවන්ට එරෙහිව ක්‍රියා කරන බව ඔවුන්ගේ හෘද සාක්ෂිය දනී.\"",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය, ලෝක බැංකුව ඇතුළු ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන මෙන්ම දැනට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ කතා කරන මිත්‍ර රටවල් ද ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති කොන්දේසිය වන්නේ රටේ ආර්ථිකය විසඳීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමට පෙර නීතිය හා සාමය ස්ථාපිත කළ යුතු බවයි. අර්බුදය, අමාත්‍ය රාජපක්ෂ සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "21 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය යනු ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) විසින් අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී පුද්ගලික පනතක් ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද ව්‍යවස්ථාමය සංශෝධන වේ.",
        "පසුව එය රජයේ ගැසට් පත්‍රයේ පළ වූ අතර එය ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ අභියෝගයට ලක් විය.",
        "අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කෙරුණු ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුව 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලබන රජයේ පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "SJB විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය මහජන ජනමත විචාරණයකින් තොරව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බව ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය තීරණය කළේය.",
        "එවැනි පසුබිමක අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉදිරිපත් කළ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ගැසට් කිරීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අනුමැතිය ලබාදුන්නා.",
        "22 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සම්මත වූ පසු එය 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය බවට පත්වනු ඇත්තේ SJB සංශෝධන තවදුරටත් ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බැවිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22A",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "විජයදාස ය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22A",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22A அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை அடைவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது – அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தம் நாட்டில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்காக முன்வைக்கப்பட்டது, இது இலங்கைக்கு உதவும் பெரும்பாலான சர்வதேச நிறுவனங்களால் கோரப்பட்டது என்று நீதி, சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, 22ஆவது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தத்தை தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவிக்காலம் முடியும் வரை வலுப்படுத்தும் முயற்சி என விமர்சித்த பின்னணியிலேயே அவர் இவ்வாறு குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று (ஜூலை 03) நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் பேசிய அமைச்சர் ராஜபக்ஷ, 22ஆவது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தத்தின் ஊடாக எந்தவொரு நபரையும் அல்லது குடும்பத்தையும் பாதுகாக்கும் நோக்கத்தை கொண்டிருக்கவில்லை.",
        "“இந்த அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தின் மூலம் நாட்டைப் பாதுகாக்க தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளோம். அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் ஒப்புக்கொண்டதையடுத்து 22ஏ ஒப்புதல் அளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மேலும் பேசிய அவர், 8 பாடங்களை உள்ளடக்கிய 69 ஷரத்துகளை உள்ளடக்கிய எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் முன்வைத்த திருத்தத்திற்கு வாக்கெடுப்பு இல்லாமல் ஒப்புதல் அளிக்க முடியாது என உச்சநீதிமன்றம் முடிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "\"நாங்கள் முன்வைத்த மசோதா மூலம், நாங்கள் ஒரு வாக்கெடுப்பை தவிர்க்கிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் விளக்கினார், பொது பிரதிநிதிகள் யாரும் அதை எதிர்க்க முடியாத வகையில் இது முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. \"அவர்கள் எதிர்க்க முடியும், இருப்பினும், அவர்கள் மக்களின் விருப்பங்களுக்கு எதிராக செயல்படுகிறார்கள் என்பது அவர்களின் மனசாட்சிக்குத் தெரியும்.\"",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம், ஐ.நா., உலக வங்கி உள்ளிட்ட சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளும் தற்போது இலங்கையுடன் பேசும் நட்பு நாடுகளும் முன்வைத்துள்ள நிபந்தனை என்னவென்றால், நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை தீர்க்க அவர்களின் உதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கு முன் சட்டம் ஒழுங்கை நிலைநாட்ட வேண்டும். நெருக்கடி, அமைச்சர் ராஜபக்ஷ குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 21 வது திருத்தம் என்பது பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) ஏப்ரல் மாதம் ஒரு தனியார் மசோதாவாக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தமாகும்.",
        "பின்னர் அரசு அரசிதழில் வெளியிடப்பட்டு, அதை எதிர்த்து உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் வழக்கு தொடரப்பட்டது.",
        "நீதி, சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சராக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ, பின்னர் 22வது திருத்தம் என குறிப்பிடப்படும் அரசாங்க சட்டமூலமொன்றை தனது அமைச்சுப் பதவியில் அமைச்சரவைக்கு சமர்ப்பித்தார்.",
        "பொது வாக்கெடுப்பு இல்லாமல் SJB முன்வைத்த 21 வது திருத்தத்தை தொடர முடியாது என்று உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் தீர்ப்பளித்தது.",
        "இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியில் நீதி அமைச்சரினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட 22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தை வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடுவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "22வது திருத்தம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டவுடன், SJBயின் திருத்தம் மேலும் தொடர முடியாததால் அது 21வது திருத்தமாக மாறும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22A",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "விஜயதாச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்கள் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22A",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறை விவகாரங்கள் & அரசியலமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}