{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Three-pronged-battle-for-presidency/108-240939",
  "time_ut": 1657678315,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three-pronged battle for presidency",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three-pronged battle for presidency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, SLPP MP Dulles Alahapperuma and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa mull the submission of nomination papers",
        "Parliament will take a secret ballot on July 20 to elect the new president",
        "A three-pronged battle is set to take place for the selection of the next president by approval of Parliament on July 20, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) MP Dalles Alahapperuma and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa mull the submission of nomination papers to vie for presidency in the secret ballot.",
        "The presidential post fell vacant prematurely in Sri Lankan history one occasion – the assassination of President R. Premadasa on May 1, 1993 . It is now slated to be vacant after the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa as already announced by him.",
        "Parliament will take a secret ballot on July 20 to elect the new president. Daily Mirror learns that Mr. Wickremesinghe will contest for the post to serve the rest of the current presidential term. A section of the SLPP is planning to back him. Another faction of the SLPP including the ten-party alliance supports Mr. Alahapperuma. Earlier, the SJB announced that Mr. Sajith Premadasa will be its candidate.",
        "The candidates who get more than 50 percent of valid votes will become the president. Unless any of the contestants cross the 50 percent mark, the preferential votes marked by the MPs will be counted.",
        "According to informed sources, the JVP has taken up the position that a neutral MP with no future electoral ambitions should be appointed next president. The party says Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardane should be appointed. The JVP believes the appointment of a political leader with future presidential ambitions will work for the interests of his party with the next election in mind. (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 1, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපතිවරණයට තුන්කොන් සටනක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස නාමයෝජනා පත්‍ර භාරදීම සලකා බලයි.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රහස් ඡන්දයක් ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වේ",
        "ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතියෙන් මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා තුන්කොන් සටනක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස යන මහත්වරුන් රහස් ඡන්දයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කිරීම සඳහා නාමයෝජනා පත්‍ර භාරදීම සලකා බලයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ඉතිහාසයේ එක් අවස්ථාවක ජනාධිපති ධුරය අකාලයේ පුරප්පාඩු විය - 1993 මැයි 1 වැනිදා ආර්. ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඝාතනය කිරීම. ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති පරිදි ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසුව එය පුරප්පාඩු වීමට නියමිතව ඇත.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රහස් ඡන්දයක් ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වේ. ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වන්නේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වත්මන් ජනාධිපති ධූර කාලයෙහි ඉතිරි කාලය ද එම තනතුර සඳහා තරඟ කරනු ඇති බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ කොටසක් ඔහුට සහාය දැක්වීමට සැලසුම් කරයි. පක්ෂ දහයක සන්ධානය ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ තවත් කණ්ඩායමක් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය පළ කරයි. සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා තම අපේක්ෂකයා ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් වන බව එස්.ජේ.බී.",
        "වලංගු ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිශතයෙන් සියයට 50කට වැඩි ප්‍රතිශතයක් ලබා ගන්නා අපේක්ෂකයින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත් වේ. තරඟකරුවන්ගෙන් කිසිවෙකු සියයට 50 සීමාව ඉක්මවා නොගියහොත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් සලකුණු කරන ලද මනාප ගණන් කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "තතු දත් ආරංචි මාර්ගවලට අනුව ඉදිරි ජනාධිපති ධූරයට අනාගත මැතිවරණ අපේක්ෂාවක් නොමැති මධ්‍යස්ථ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පත්කළ යුතු බවට ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ ස්ථාවරය වී තිබේ. කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පත් කළ යුතු බව එම පක්ෂය පවසයි. ඉදිරි ජනාධිපතිවරණ අභිලාෂයන් සහිත දේශපාලන නායකයෙකු පත්කිරීම ඉදිරි මැතිවරණය ගැන සිතා තම පක්ෂයේ අවශ්‍යතා වෙනුවෙන් කටයුතු කරනු ඇතැයි ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ විශ්වාස කරයි. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50කට වඩා වැඩියි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 යි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான மும்முனைப் போர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஆகியோர் வேட்புமனுவை சமர்ப்பிப்பதை ஆராய்கின்றனர்.",
        "புதிய அதிபரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது",
        "ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஒப்புதலுடன் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான மும்முனைப் போர் நடைபெற உள்ளது என்று டெய்லி மிரர் அறியிறது.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஆகியோர் இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு போட்டியிடுவதற்கான வேட்புமனுக்களை சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "1993 மே 1 இல் ஜனாதிபதி ஆர். பிரேமதாச படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் இலங்கை வரலாற்றில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி காலத்துக்கு முன்னரே வெற்றிடமாகியது. ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஏற்கனவே அறிவித்தபடி அவர் பதவி விலகியதையடுத்து தற்போது அது வெற்றிடமாக உள்ளது.",
        "புதிய அதிபரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது. தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக் காலத்தின் எஞ்சிய காலப்பகுதியை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்காக திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க இப்பதவிக்கு போட்டியிடுவார் என டெய்லி மிரர் அறிகிறது. SLPP இன் ஒரு பகுதி அவருக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது. SLPP இன் மற்றுமொரு தரப்பினர், பத்து கட்சிகள் கொண்ட கூட்டணி உட்பட திரு. அழகப்பெருமவை ஆதரிக்கின்றனர். முன்னதாக, SJB தனது வேட்பாளராக திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச நிறுத்தப்படுவார் என்று அறிவித்தது.",
        "செல்லுபடியாகும் வாக்குகளில் 50 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல் பெறும் வேட்பாளர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியாக வருவார்கள். போட்டியாளர்களில் எவரும் 50 சதவீதத்தை கடக்காதபட்சத்தில், எம்.பி.க்களால் குறிக்கப்பட்ட விருப்பு வாக்குகள் எண்ணப்படும்.",
        "எதிர்கால தேர்தல் அபிலாஷைகள் இல்லாத நடுநிலையான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரை அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்க வேண்டும் என்ற நிலைப்பாட்டை ஜே.வி.பி எடுத்துள்ளதாக தகவலறிந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டுமென கட்சி கூறுகிறது. எதிர்கால ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலை மனதில் கொண்டு தனது கட்சியின் நலன்களுக்காக எதிர்கால ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான அரசியல் தலைவர் ஒருவரை நியமிப்பதாக ஜே.வி.பி நம்புகிறது. (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}