{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/dance-of-the-lions-down-under/",
  "time_ut": 1658943780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dance of the Lions down under",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dance of the Lions down under",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lankans, in Australia – Melbourne, in particular – sure love to party, and that’s exactly what they keep doing, on a regular basis.The Old Boys, from Trinity College, Kandy, made their presence felt at their big night, ‘Dance of the Lions,’ held at the Grand on Cathies Lane, in Melbourne.",
        "The event took place on July 16th, and there was plenty of action, from 7.00 pm to 1.00 am.",
        "According to Trevine Rodrigo, ‘Dance of the Lions’ showcased the lively spirit of the prestigious Kandy school, renowned for their proud reputation in academics and, more importantly, sports, where they have been much in the forefront during a rich history, among Sri Lankan educational institutions.",
        "Boxing, rugby, athletics and cricket has seen some outstanding sportsmen emerge from Trinity College. Says Trevine: “The Melbourne OBA added ‘excellent organisation’ to their CV with a memorable dinner dance which was complete, all round.",
        "“The Next Generation, a talented outfit, based in Melbourne, had the dance floor packed to capacity, and they were ably backed by DJ maestro Ash.",
        "“An excellent three-course meal, put on by the Grand, made it an immensely satisfying experience.”",
        "Johann Jayasinha, Media SNNI/Australia, mentioned to us that ‘Dance of the Lions’ is the flagship event of the Trinity College Kandy Melbourne OBA, and is held biannually, adding that the proceeds of the dance will be donated to the T150 project of Trinity College, Kandy, who are celebrating, this year (2022) 150 years of Education, Learning and Character Building.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melbourne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Old Boys",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trinity College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "their big night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cathies Lane",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melbourne",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 16th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trevine Rodrigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trinity College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Next Generation",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melbourne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DJ maestro Ash",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Grand",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johann Jayasinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Melbourne OBA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T150",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trinity College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Character Building",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යටින් සිංහයන්ගේ නැටුම",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ - මෙල්බර්න්, විශේෂයෙන් - සාදයට ප්‍රිය කරන බව සහතිකයි, ඔවුන් නිතිපතා කරන්නේ එයයි. මහනුවර ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ආදි ශිෂ්‍යයන්, ඔවුන්ගේ මහා රාත්‍රියේදී ඔවුන්ගේ පැමිණීම දැනෙන්නට විය. සිංහයන්ගේ නර්තනය,' මෙල්බර්න් හි කැතීස් පටුමගේ ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් හිදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙම සිදුවීම ජූලි 16 වන දින සිදු වූ අතර, සවස 7.00 සිට අලුයම 1.00 දක්වා බොහෝ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග තිබුණි.",
        "Trevine Rodrigo පවසන පරිදි, 'සිංහයන්ගේ නර්තනය' කීර්තිමත් මහනුවර පාසලේ සජීවී ආත්මය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කළ අතර, ශාස්ත්‍රීය හා වඩාත් වැදගත් ලෙස ක්‍රීඩාවේ සාඩම්බර කීර්තිය සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලයි. ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපන ආයතන.",
        "ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලයෙන් බොක්සිං, රග්බි, මලල ක්‍රීඩා සහ ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාවට විශිෂ්ට ක්‍රීඩකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු බිහිවී ඇත. Trevine පවසයි: “Melbourne OBA විසින් ඔවුන්ගේ CV එකට ‘විශිෂ්ට සංවිධානයක්’ එකතු කළේ අමතක නොවන රාත්‍රී භෝජන සංග්‍රහයක් සමඟින්, එය සම්පූර්ණ විය.",
        "“Next Generation, Melbourne පාදක කරගත්, දක්ෂ ඇඳුමක්, නැටුම් තලය ධාරිතාවයට අසුරා තිබූ අතර, DJ Maestro Ash ගේ සහාය ඔවුන්ට ලැබුණි.",
        "\"ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් විසින් සකස් කරන ලද විශිෂ්ට තුන්වේල ආහාර වේලක්, එය අතිශයින් තෘප්තිමත් අත්දැකීමක් බවට පත් කළේය.\"",
        "මහනුවර මෙල්බර්න් ආදි ශිෂ්‍ය සංගමයේ ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ප්‍රමුඛතම ඉසව්ව 'සිංහයන්ගේ නර්තනය' බව අප වෙත සඳහන් කළ SNNI/ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ මාධ්‍ය Johann Jayasinha, එම නර්තනයෙන් ලැබෙන ආදායම T150 ව්‍යාපෘතියට පරිත්‍යාග කරන බව පැවසීය. මහනුවර ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලය මේ වසරේ (2022) අධ්‍යාපනය, ඉගෙනීම සහ චරිත ගොඩනැගීමේ 150 වසර සමරයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙල්බර්න්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරණ කොල්ලෝ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔවුන්ගේ විශාල රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැතීස් පටුමග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙල්බර්න්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රෙවින් රොද්‍රිගෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පරම්පරාව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙල්බර්න්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DJ විශාරද ඈෂ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොහාන් ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර මෙල්බර්න් OBA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T150",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිත්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 150 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත ගොඩනැගීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கீழே சிங்கங்களின் நடனம்",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவில் - மெல்போர்னில் உள்ள இலங்கையர்கள், குறிப்பாக, விருந்துகளில் ஈடுபடுவதை விரும்புவார்கள், அதைத்தான் அவர்கள் தொடர்ந்து செய்து வருகின்றனர். கண்டி டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரியைச் சேர்ந்த பழைய மாணவர்கள், அவர்களின் பெருநாள் இரவு நேரத்தில் தங்கள் இருப்பை உணர்ந்தனர். சிங்கங்களின் நடனம்,' மெல்போர்னில் உள்ள கேதீஸ் லேனில் உள்ள கிராண்டில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வு ஜூலை 16 ஆம் தேதி நடந்தது, இரவு 7.00 மணி முதல் அதிகாலை 1.00 மணி வரை ஏராளமான நடவடிக்கைகள் இருந்தன.",
        "ட்ரெவின் ரோட்ரிகோவின் கூற்றுப்படி, 'டான்ஸ் ஆஃப் தி லயன்ஸ்' மதிப்புமிக்க கண்டி பள்ளியின் உயிரோட்டமான உணர்வை வெளிப்படுத்தியது, கல்வியாளர்கள் மற்றும் மிக முக்கியமாக, விளையாட்டுகளில் அவர்களின் பெருமைக்குரிய நற்பெயருக்காகப் புகழ்பெற்றது. இலங்கை கல்வி நிறுவனங்கள்.",
        "குத்துச்சண்டை, ரக்பி, தடகளம் மற்றும் கிரிக்கெட் ஆகியவற்றில் சில சிறந்த விளையாட்டு வீரர்கள் டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரியில் இருந்து வெளிவருகின்றனர். ட்ரெவின் கூறுகிறார்: \"மெல்போர்ன் OBA அவர்களின் CV யில் ஒரு மறக்கமுடியாத இரவு உணவு நடனத்துடன் 'சிறந்த அமைப்பை' சேர்த்தது, அது முழுமையடைந்தது.",
        "\"தி நெக்ஸ்ட் ஜெனரேஷன், மெல்போர்னை தளமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு திறமையான ஆடை, திறன் கொண்ட நடன தளத்தை நிரம்பியிருந்தது, மேலும் அவர்கள் DJ மேஸ்ட்ரோ ஆஷால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "\"கிராண்டால் போடப்பட்ட ஒரு சிறந்த மூன்று-வேளை உணவு, அதை மிகவும் திருப்திகரமான அனுபவமாக மாற்றியது.\"",
        "ஜொஹான் ஜெயசின்ஹா, மீடியா SNNI/Australia, 'டான்ஸ் ஆஃப் தி லயன்ஸ்' என்பது கண்டி டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரி மெல்போர்ன் OBA இன் முதன்மை நிகழ்வாகும், மேலும் இது இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு ஒருமுறை நடத்தப்படுகிறது, நடனத்தின் வருமானம் T150 திட்டத்திற்கு நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்படும் என்று கூறினார். கண்டி டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரி, இந்த ஆண்டு (2022) 150 வருட கல்வி, கற்றல் மற்றும் குணநலன்களை கட்டியெழுப்புகிறது.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்போர்ன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி ஓல்ட் பாய்ஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவர்களின் பெரிய இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேதீஸ் லேன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்போர்ன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 7.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிரெவின் ரோட்ரிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த தலைமுறை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்போர்ன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜே மேஸ்ட்ரோ ஆஷ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாபெரும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜொஹான் ஜெயசின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி மெல்போர்ன் OBA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T150",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரினிட்டி கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத்திர கட்டிடம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}