{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කථානායකට-ජනපතිධුරය-උපරිම-දින-30කට-පමණයි---පක්ෂ-නායක-රැස්වීමේදි-එකඟ-වූ-ප්‍රධාන-කරුණු-4/11-395265",
  "time_ut": 1657371907,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කථානායකට ජනපතිධුරය උපරිම දින 30කට පමණයි - පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදි එකඟ වූ ප්‍රධාන කරුණු 4",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speaker's presidency for a maximum of 30 days only - 4 main points agreed in the party leaders' meeting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been decided in the party leader meeting that the presidency will be offered to Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena for a maximum period of 30 days only. The party leaders have agreed on four basic points in this party leaders meeting.",
        "01 President Gotabhaya Rapaksha and Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe immediately resign from their posts.",
        "03 Election of a Member of Parliament as President by the Parliament for the rest of the term",
        "Explaining this on his Twitter account, the Member of Parliament Mr. Harsha de Silva said that an interim government will be established soon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "30 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "only - 4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rapaksha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කථානායකට ජනපතිධුරය උපරිම දින 30කට පමණයි - පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදි එකඟ වූ ප්‍රධාන කරුණු 4",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත ජනපතිධුරය පිරිනමන්නේ උපරිම වශයෙන් දින 30ක කාලයකට පමණක් බවට පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී තීරණය කර තිබේ. මෙම පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදි මූලික කරුණු  හතරක් පිළිබඳව පක්ෂ නායකයන් එකඟ වී තිබේ.",
        "01 ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාපක්ෂ මහතාත් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාත් වහාම සිය ධුරවලින් ඉවත්වීම",
        "03 ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් ජනපති ලෙස තෝරා ගැනීම",
        "මේ පිළිබදව සිය ට්විටර් ගිණුමෙන් පැහැදිලි කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවක් ඉක්මනින්ම පිහිටුවන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දින 30",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පමණක් - 4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சபாநாயகர் பதவி அதிகபட்சம் 30 நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுமே - கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் 4 முக்கிய விடயங்களுக்கு இணக்கம்!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு அதிகபட்சமாக 30 நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுமே ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வழங்கப்படுமென கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்தக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் நான்கு அடிப்படை விடயங்கள் குறித்து கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "01 ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ரபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் உடனடியாக தமது பதவிகளை இராஜினாமா செய்யவுள்ளனர்.",
        "03 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரை ஜனாதிபதியாக பாராளுமன்றத்தால் தெரிவு செய்தல்",
        "இது தொடர்பில் தனது டுவிட்டர் தளத்தில் விளக்கமளித்துள்ள நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, விரைவில் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படும் எனத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மட்டும் - 4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ரபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}