{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-says-all-its-MPs-with-Sajith/108-242118",
  "time_ut": 1659280455,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB says all its MPs with Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB says all its MPs with Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya ( SJB) whilst denying reports that some of its Members of Parliament will be joining the government said all it's party MPs are with its Leader Sajith Premadasa.",
        "\"No one will defy the decision of the Party Leader and will join the government unilaterally, an official statement from the Leader of Opposition said today.",
        "\"All MPs have decided to allow party leader Premadasa to make his own decision with regard to the future of SJB\" the statement added.",
        "Meanwhile SJB MP Chaminda Wijesiri who referred to the statement made by President Ranil Wickremesinghe on Saturday that all parties must come together and form an all party government said the latter has become a joke. \"Mr. Wickremesinghe is playing Mr. Bean's role ,\" he said.",
        "\"Mr. Wickremesinghe could be removed from power if all Sri Lankan people come together,\" he added. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Wijesiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bean",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB කියන්නේ තමන්ගේ සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරු සජිත් එක්ක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) තම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු රජයට එක්වන බවට පළවන වාර්තා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන අතරම, තම පක්ෂයේ සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සිටින්නේ තම නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සමඟ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“කිසිවෙකු පක්ෂ නායකයාගේ තීරණය නොතකා ඒකපාර්ශ්විකව රජයට එක්වන බව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගේ නිල ප්‍රකාශය අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "\"SJB හි අනාගතය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පක්ෂ නායක ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාට ඔහුගේම තීරණයක් ගැනීමට ඉඩ දීමට සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තීරණය කර ඇත\" යනුවෙන් එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මේ අතර සියලු පක්ෂ එකතු වී සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සෙනසුරාදා කළ ප්‍රකාශය ගැන සඳහන් කළ SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී චමින්ද විජේසිරි කියා සිටියේ දෙවැන්න විහිළුවක් වී ඇති බවයි. “මිස්ටර් බීන් ගේ චරිතය රඟපාන්නේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතායි.",
        "“සියලු ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාව එකතු වුවහොත් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බලයෙන් පහ කළ හැකියි,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද විජේසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝංචි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி தனது அனைத்து எம்.பி.க்களும் சஜித்துடன் இருப்பதாக கூறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) தனது சில நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணையவுள்ளதாக வெளியான தகவலை மறுத்துள்ள அதேவேளை, தமது கட்சியின் அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் அதன் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவுடன் இருப்பதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“கட்சித் தலைவரின் முடிவை யாரும் மீற மாட்டார்கள் மற்றும் ஒருதலைப்பட்சமாக அரசாங்கத்தில் சேருவார்கள் என்று எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ அறிக்கை இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"SJB இன் எதிர்காலம் தொடர்பாக கட்சித் தலைவர் பிரேமதாச தனது சொந்த முடிவை எடுக்க அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் முடிவு செய்துள்ளனர்\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, சகல கட்சிகளும் ஒன்றிணைந்து சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சனிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்த கருத்து தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சமிந்த விஜேசிறி, இது நகைச்சுவையாக மாறியுள்ளது. \"மிஸ்டர் விக்ரமசிங்கே மிஸ்டர் பீன் வேடத்தில் நடிக்கிறார்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "“இலங்கை மக்கள் அனைவரும் ஒன்றிணைந்தால் திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஆட்சியில் இருந்து அகற்ற முடியும்” என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த விஜேசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}