{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84534/japans-police-chief-resigns-over-ex-pm-assassination",
  "time_ut": 1661423160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan’s police chief resigns over ex-PM assassination",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan’s police chief resigns over ex-PM assassination",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japan’s police chief has said he will resign over the killing of former prime minister Shinzo Abe.",
        "Itaru Nakamura, head of the national police agency, said he wanted to take responsibility for the July 8 shooting.",
        "An investigation has found there were serious flaws in how the ex-PM was protected.",
        "Mr Abe was shot while speaking at a political campaign event in the city of Nara.",
        "The 41-year-old gunman was able to walk up behind Mr Abe and shoot him with a homemade gun as he was giving a speech.",
        "The 67-year-old suffered two bullet wounds to his neck and damage to his heart, doctors said.",
        "Local police have already acknowledged “undeniable” flaws in security for Mr Abe.",
        "“In the process of verifying our new security plan, we have come to realise that our security duties would need a fresh start,” Mr Nakamura told a news conference as he announced his resignation.",
        "Mr Abe was Japan’s best-known politician and longest-serving prime minister, but security was comparatively light as he delivered a stump speech on a street in the western region.",
        "Security experts who have reviewed footage of the attack have previously told news agency Reuters that bodyguards could have saved Mr Abe by shielding him or pulled him from the line of fire in the 2.5 seconds between a missed first shot and the second, fatal round of gunfire.",
        "The suspect, Tetsuya Yamagami, was arrested at the scene and admitted to shooting Mr Abe, police have said.",
        "He confessed that he targeted Mr Abe due to his belief that he was linked to a religious group - which Yamagami said had financially ruined his mother."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ex-PM",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Itaru Nakamura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "67-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nakamura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2.5 seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tetsuya Yamagami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yamagami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු අගමැති ඝාතනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජපානයේ පොලිස් ප්‍රධානියා ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ හිටපු අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේ ඝාතනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව එරට පොලිස් ප්‍රධානියා ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "ජාතික පොලිස් ඒජන්සියේ ප්‍රධානී Itaru Nakamura පැවසුවේ ජූලි 8 වෙඩි තැබීමේ වගකීම තමාට භාර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "හිටපු අගමැතිවරයා ආරක්‍ෂා කළ ආකාරයෙහි බරපතළ දෝෂ ඇති බව පරීක්‍ෂණයකින් හෙළිවී ඇත.",
        "නාරා නගරයේ පැවති දේශපාලන ප්‍රචාරක උත්සවයකදී අබේ මහතාට වෙඩි තබා ඇත.",
        "41 හැවිරිදි තුවක්කුකරු අබේ මහතා පිටුපසින් ගොස් දේශනයක් පවත්වමින් සිටියදී ගෙදර හැදූ තුවක්කුවකින් ඔහුට වෙඩි තැබීමට සමත් විය.",
        "67 හැවිරිදි ඔහුගේ ගෙල ප්‍රදේශයට වෙඩි උණ්ඩ දෙකක් වැදී ඇති අතර හදවතට හානි සිදුව ඇති බව වෛද්‍යවරු පවසති.",
        "ප්‍රාදේශීය පොලිසිය දැනටමත් අබේ මහතාගේ ආරක්ෂාවේ “ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ නොහැකි” අඩුපාඩු පිළිගෙන ඇත.",
        "\"අපගේ නව ආරක්ෂක සැලැස්ම සත්‍යාපනය කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේදී, අපගේ ආරක්ෂක රාජකාරි සඳහා නව ආරම්භයක් අවශ්‍ය බව අපට වැටහී ඇත,\" නකමුරා මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිවේදනය කරන විට ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "අබේ මහතා ජපානයේ වඩාත්ම ප්‍රසිද්ධ දේශපාලනඥයා සහ දීර්ඝතම අගමැති ධුරය දැරූ නමුත් ඔහු බටහිර කලාපයේ වීදියක කඩුල්ල මුවා කිරීමේ කතාවක් පවත්වද්දී ආරක්ෂාව සාපේක්ෂව සැහැල්ලු විය.",
        "ප්‍රහාරයේ දර්ශන සමාලෝචනය කළ ආරක්‍ෂක විශේෂඥයන් රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පවසා තිබුණේ අතපසු වූ පළමු වෙඩිල්ල සහ දෙවන මාරාන්තික වෙඩි වටය අතර තත්පර 2.5 ක කාලයකදී ආරක්‍ෂකයන්ට අබේ මහතා ආරක්‍ෂා කර හෝ ගිනි රේඛාවෙන් ඔහුව බේරා ගැනීමට හැකිව තිබූ බවයි. .",
        "සැකකාර ටෙට්සුයා යමගාමි එම ස්ථානයේදීම අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර අබේ මහතාට වෙඩි තැබූ බව පිළිගෙන ඇතැයි පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු ආගමික කණ්ඩායමකට සම්බන්ධ බවට ඇති විශ්වාසය නිසා තමා අබේ මහතා ඉලක්ක කළ බව ඔහු පාපොච්චාරණය කළේය - යමගාමි පැවසුවේ එය තම මව මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් විනාශ කළ බව ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හිටපු අගමැති",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Itaru Nakamura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "67 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නකමුරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර 2.5",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tetsuya Yamagami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yamagami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் படுகொலைக்காக ஜப்பான் காவல்துறை தலைவர் ராஜினாமா செய்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானின் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே கொலைக்கு காரணமான தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அந்நாட்டு காவல்துறை தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 8-ம் தேதி நடந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்துக்குப் பொறுப்பேற்க விரும்புவதாக தேசிய போலீஸ் ஏஜென்சியின் தலைவர் இடாரு நகமுரா கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் எவ்வாறு பாதுகாக்கப்பட்டார் என்பதில் கடுமையான குறைபாடுகள் இருப்பதாக விசாரணையில் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "திரு அபே நாரா நகரில் அரசியல் பிரச்சார நிகழ்வில் பேசும்போது சுடப்பட்டார்.",
        "41 வயதான துப்பாக்கிதாரி, திரு அபேயின் பின்னால் நடந்து சென்று, அவர் உரை நிகழ்த்திக் கொண்டிருந்தபோது வீட்டில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கியால் சுட முடிந்தது.",
        "67 வயதான அவரது கழுத்தில் இரண்டு புல்லட் காயங்கள் மற்றும் அவரது இதயம் சேதமடைந்துள்ளதாக மருத்துவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "திரு அபேயின் பாதுகாப்பில் உள்ள \"மறுக்க முடியாத\" குறைபாடுகளை உள்ளூர் போலீசார் ஏற்கனவே ஒப்புக்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "\"எங்கள் புதிய பாதுகாப்பு திட்டத்தை சரிபார்க்கும் செயல்பாட்டில், எங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு கடமைகளுக்கு ஒரு புதிய தொடக்கம் தேவை என்பதை நாங்கள் உணர்ந்துள்ளோம்,\" என்று திரு நகமுரா தனது ராஜினாமாவை அறிவித்தபோது செய்தியாளர் கூட்டத்தில் கூறினார்.",
        "திரு அபே ஜப்பானின் சிறந்த அரசியல்வாதி மற்றும் நீண்ட காலம் பிரதமராக இருந்தவர், ஆனால் அவர் மேற்கு பிராந்தியத்தில் ஒரு தெருவில் ஸ்டம்ப் உரையை ஆற்றியதால் பாதுகாப்பு ஒப்பீட்டளவில் குறைவாக இருந்தது.",
        "தாக்குதலின் காட்சிகளை மதிப்பாய்வு செய்த பாதுகாப்பு வல்லுநர்கள் முன்னதாக செய்தி நிறுவனமான ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம், மெய்க்காப்பாளர்கள் திரு அபேவைக் காப்பாற்றி அவரைக் காப்பாற்றியிருக்கலாம் அல்லது தவறவிட்ட முதல் ஷாட் மற்றும் இரண்டாவது அபாயகரமான துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு இடையில் 2.5 வினாடிகளில் அவரை நெருப்பிலிருந்து இழுத்திருக்கலாம் என்று கூறியுள்ளனர். .",
        "சந்தேக நபரான டெட்சுயா யமகாமி சம்பவ இடத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு திரு அபேவை சுட்டுக் கொன்றதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டதாக பொலிசார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அவர் ஒரு மதக் குழுவுடன் தொடர்புடையவர் என்ற அவரது நம்பிக்கையின் காரணமாக திரு அபேவை குறிவைத்ததாக அவர் ஒப்புக்கொண்டார் - இது அவரது தாயை நிதி ரீதியாக அழித்ததாக யமகாமி கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "முன்னாள் பிரதமர்",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Itaru Nakamura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "67 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நகாமுரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 வினாடிகள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tetsuya Yamagami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yamagami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}