{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131917",
  "time_ut": 1658370525,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கை சீன முதலீடுகளில் முட்டாள்தனமான பந்தயம்கட்டியது –   சிஐஏ தலைவர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka made a foolish bet on Chinese investments – CIA chief",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "CIA chief Phil Barnes said that Sri Lanka made a foolish bet on Chinese investments",
        "Bill Barnes, the head of America's CIA, said that Sri Lanka, a South Asian country, foolishly bet on China's investments.",
        "For the past few months, Sri Lanka has faced food fuel shortages, prolonged power outages and rising inflation due to lack of foreign exchange to import essential goods.",
        "In this situation, the CIA chief mentions that China's high debt investments made by Sri Lankan leaders are the reason for the decline of the South Asian country's economy. He also says that China has the strength to project itself and the ability to attract investment.",
        "The world countries should think about a country like Sri Lanka which has got a huge debt from China. Sri Lanka has foolishly bet on its economic future due to which the country has faced disastrous consequences politically and economically, said the CIA chief."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "CIA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Phil Barnes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bill Barnes",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීන ආයෝජන සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෝඩ ඔට්ටුවක් ගත්තේය - CIA ප්‍රධානියා",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "සීඅයිඒ ප්‍රධානී ෆිල් බාන්ස් පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීන ආයෝජන සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෝඩ ඔට්ටුවක් දැමූ බවයි",
        "ඇමරිකාවේ CIA ප්‍රධානී Bill Barnes කියා සිටියේ දකුණු ආසියාතික රටක් වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනයේ ආයෝජන වලට අනුවණ ලෙස ඔට්ටු අල්ලන බවයි.",
        "අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ ආනයනය කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය විදේශ විනිමය නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආහාර ඉන්ධන හිඟයකට, දිගුකාලීන විදුලිය ඇනහිටීම්වලට සහ උද්ධමනය ඉහළ යාමට මුහුණ දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයින් විසින් සිදු කරන ලද අධික ණය ආයෝජන දකුණු ආසියානු රටේ ආර්ථිකය පහත වැටීමට හේතුව බව CIA ප්‍රධානියා සඳහන් කරයි. චීනයට තමාව ප්‍රක්ෂේපණය කිරීමේ ශක්තිය සහ ආයෝජන ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමේ හැකියාව ඇති බවද ඔහු පවසයි.",
        "චීනයෙන් විශාල ණයක් ගත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි රටක් ගැන ලෝක රටවල් සිතිය යුතු බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තම ආර්ථික අනාගතය ගැන මෝඩ ලෙස ඔට්ටු ඇල්ලූ බවත්, ඒ නිසා රට දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික වශයෙන් විනාශකාරී ප්‍රතිවිපාකවලට මුහුණ දී ඇති බවත් CIA ප්‍රධානියා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "සීඅයිඒ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීඅයිඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිල් බාන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිල් බාන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඅයිඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීඅයිඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඅයිඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை சீன முதலீடுகளில் முட்டாள்தனமான பந்தயம்கட்டியது –   சிஐஏ தலைவர்",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சீன முதலீடுகளில்  முட்டாள்தனமான பந்தயம் கட்டியது என சிஐஏயின் தலைவர் பில்பேர்ன்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "அமெரிக்காவின் சிஐஏயின் தலைவரான பில்பேர்ன்ஸ் தென்னாசிய நாடான இலங்கை சீனாவின் முதலீடுகள் மீது முட்டாள்தனமாக பந்தயம் கட்டியதே இலங்கை தற்போது எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணம் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக அத்தியவாசிய பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான அந்நிய செலாவணி இல்லாததால் இலங்கை உணவு எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடுகளையம்இநீண்டநேர மின்துண்டிப்பையும் அதிகரித்துவரும் பணவீக்கத்தையும் எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் இலங்கை தலைவர்கள் மேற்கொண்ட சீனாவின் உயர் கடன் முதலீடுகளே தென்னாசியா நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் வீழ்ச்சியடைவதற்கு காரணம் என சிஐஏ தலைவர் குறிப்பிடுகின்றார். சீனாவிற்கு தன்னை முன்னிறுத்தும் வலிமையும் முதலீட்டை கவரும் திறனும் உள்ளதாகவும் அவர் தெரிவிக்கின்றார்.",
        "சீனாவிடம் மிகப்பெருமளவு கடனை பெற்றுள்ள இலங்கை போன்ற நாடு குறித்து உலகநாடுகள் சிந்திக்கவேண்டும்இலங்கை தனது பொருளாதார எதிர்காலம் குறித்து முட்டாள்தனமாக பந்தயம் கட்டியுள்ளதுஇதன் காரணமாக அரசியல்ரீதியிலும் பொருளாதாரரீதியிலும் பேரழிவான விளைவுகளை அந்த நாடு சந்தித்துள்ளது என சிஐஏ தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிஐஏ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஐஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில் பார்ன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பில் பார்ன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஐஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}