{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84736/seetha-arambepola-willing-to-give-up-mp-seat-for-former-president",
  "time_ut": 1662270960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Seetha Arambepola willing to give up MP seat for former President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Seetha Arambepola willing to give up MP seat for former President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) parliamentarian Dr. Seetha Arambepola says that if former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa requires to enter the Parliament, she is ready to resign from her National List MP seat in order to facilitate that.",
        "She stated that no request for that has been received from the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna or any other sections so far.",
        "However, she pointed out that she believes that former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has no intention of entering the Parliament.",
        "MP Arambepola also mentioned that there has been no discussion in this regard within the party."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Seetha Arambepola",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seetha Arambepola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arambepola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සීතා අරඹේපොල හිටපු ජනපතිට මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයක් දීමට සූදානම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් ඒ සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීම සඳහා තම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සූදානම් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෛද්‍ය සීතා අරඹේපොල මහත්මිය පවසයි.",
        "ඒ සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් හෝ වෙනත් කිසිදු පාර්ශ්වයකින් මෙතෙක් ඉල්ලීමක් ලැබී නොමැති බවයි ඇය සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීමේ අදහසක් නොමැති බව තමන් විශ්වාස කරන බවයි ඇය පෙන්වා දුන්නේ.",
        "ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පක්ෂය තුළ කිසිදු සාකච්ඡාවක් සිදුවී නොමැති බවද අරඹේපොල මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සීතා අරඹේපොල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතා අරඹේපොල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරඹේපොල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை விட்டுக்கொடுக்க சீதா அறம்பேபொல விருப்பம்!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு பாராளுமன்றம் பிரவேசிக்க வேண்டியிருந்தால், அதற்கு வசதியாக தனது தேசியப்பட்டியல் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யத் தயார் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டொக்டர் சீதா அரம்பேபொல தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிடமிருந்தோ அல்லது வேறு எந்தப் பிரிவினரிடமிருந்தோ இதுவரையில் அதற்கான எந்தவொரு கோரிக்கையும் வரவில்லை எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் பிரவேசிக்கும் எண்ணம் இல்லை என தான் நம்புவதாக அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் கட்சிக்குள் எந்த கலந்துரையாடலும் இடம்பெறவில்லை எனவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அரம்பேபொல மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீதா ஆரம்பேபொல",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீதா ஆரம்பேபொல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரம்பேபொல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}