{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/India-urges-its-citizens-to-examine-relevant-factors-before-undertaking-visit-to-Sri-Lanka/108-243748",
  "time_ut": 1661450208,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India urges its citizens to examine relevant factors before undertaking visit to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India urges its citizens to examine relevant factors before undertaking visit to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "India on Thursday urged its nationals planning to visit Sri Lanka to exercise caution and especially called on them to consider factors like currency convertibility and the fuel situation in that country before undertaking any essential travel.",
        "\"We have been following the developments there. Our understanding is that Indians are still the largest source of tourists for Sri Lanka,\" external affairs ministry spokesperson Arindam Bagchi said.",
        "As regards to the travel of Indians to Sri lanka in the current situation, let me emphasise that safety and well being of Indian nationals during their stay outside India including in Sri Lanka in this particular case, is always of prime interest to us,\" he said.",
        "Bagchi was replying to a question on the issue during his weekly media briefing.",
        "\"Our endeavour is to prevent any untoward incidents involving Indians outside India...we would, therefore, encourage Indians to exercise all care and caution while in Sri Lanka.",
        "\"They should examine all relevant factors including currency convertibility and the fuel situation before undertaking any essential travel to Sri Lanka,\" Bagchi added.(TOI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bagchi added.(TOI",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට පෙර අදාළ කරුණු සොයා බලන ලෙස ඉන්දියාව සිය පුරවැසියන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට සැලසුම් කරන තම ජාතිකයන්ගෙන් ප්‍රවේශම් සහගත ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සංචාරයක් කිරීමට පෙර එම රටේ මුදල් පරිවර්තනය සහ ඉන්ධන තත්ත්වය වැනි සාධක සලකා බලන ලෙස විශේෂයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi පැවසුවේ, \"අපි එහි වර්ධනයන් අනුගමනය කරමින් සිටිමු. අපගේ අවබෝධය වන්නේ තවමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරකයින්ගේ විශාලතම මූලාශ්‍රය ඉන්දියානුවන් බවයි.",
        "වත්මන් තත්ත්වය තුළ ඉන්දියානුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්, මෙම විශේෂිත අවස්ථාවෙහිදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළුව ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත රැඳී සිටින ඉන්දීය ජාතිකයින්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ යහපැවැත්ම සැමවිටම අපට ප්‍රමුඛ උනන්දුවක් දක්වන බව මම අවධාරණය කරමි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. කිව්වා.",
        "බග්චි සිය සතිපතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මේ පිළිබඳව ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දුන්නේය.",
        "\"අපගේ උත්සාහය ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත ඉන්දියානුවන් සම්බන්ධ කිසිදු අප්රසන්න සිදුවීම් වැලැක්වීමයි... එබැවින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින විට සියලු සැලකිල්ලෙන් සහ ප්‍රවේශමෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස අපි ඉන්දියානුවන් දිරිමත් කරන්නෙමු.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඕනෑම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සංචාරයක් කිරීමට පෙර ඔවුන් මුදල් පරිවර්තන හැකියාව සහ ඉන්ධන තත්ත්වය ඇතුළු අදාළ සියලු සාධක පරීක්ෂා කළ යුතුය,\" බග්චි තවදුරටත් පැවසීය.(TOI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බග්චි එකතු කළේය.(TOI",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொள்வதற்கு முன்னர் பொருத்தமான காரணிகளை ஆராயுமாறு இந்தியா தனது குடிமக்களை கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வியாழன் அன்று இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தரும் தனது நாட்டவர்களிடம் எச்சரிக்கையுடன் செயல்படுமாறு வலியுறுத்தியதுடன், அத்தியாவசியப் பயணங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கு முன்னர் அந்நாட்டின் நாணய மாற்றம் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் நிலைமை போன்ற காரணிகளைக் கருத்தில் கொள்ளுமாறு அவர்களுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி கூறுகையில், \"அங்குள்ள முன்னேற்றங்களை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து பின்பற்றி வருகிறோம். இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் மிகப்பெரிய ஆதாரமாக இந்தியர்கள் உள்ளனர் என்பது எங்கள் புரிதல்\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கான இந்தியர்களின் பயணத்தைப் பொறுத்தவரை, இந்த குறிப்பிட்ட சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் இலங்கை உட்பட இந்தியாவிற்கு வெளியே தங்கியிருக்கும் இந்தியப் பிரஜைகளின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் நல்வாழ்வு எப்பொழுதும் எங்களுக்கு முதன்மையானதாக இருக்கும் என்பதை நான் வலியுறுத்துகிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். கூறினார்.",
        "பாக்சி தனது வாராந்திர செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது இந்த பிரச்சினை குறித்த கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் முயற்சி இந்தியாவிற்கு வெளியே உள்ள இந்தியர்கள் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட எந்தவொரு விரும்பத்தகாத சம்பவங்களையும் தடுப்பதாகும்... எனவே, இலங்கையில் இருக்கும் போது அனைத்து அக்கறையுடனும் எச்சரிக்கையுடனும் செயல்படுமாறு இந்தியர்களை ஊக்குவிப்போம்.",
        "\"இலங்கைக்கு எந்தவொரு அத்தியாவசியப் பயணத்தையும் மேற்கொள்வதற்கு முன்னர் நாணய மாற்றம் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் நிலைமை உள்ளிட்ட அனைத்து தொடர்புடைய காரணிகளையும் அவர்கள் ஆராய வேண்டும்\" என்று பாக்சி மேலும் கூறினார்.(TOI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்சி மேலும் கூறினார்.(TOI",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}