{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83762/sri-lanka-parliament-elects-ranil-wickremesinghe-as-new-president",
  "time_ut": 1658301180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka parliament elects Ranil Wickremesinghe as new President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka parliament elects Ranil Wickremesinghe as new President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The parliament today (July 20) elected Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka.",
        "In a secret ballot that got underway in the House this morning, the Members of Parliament voted to elect a succeeding President to fill in the post left vacant after the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksa last week.",
        "The procedure for electing a new president by Parliament is provided in the Constitution and the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act (No. 2 of 1981), in the event of a vacancy in the office of the President before the end of the term.",
        "The 73-year-old faced off against Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) dissident and former minister Dullas Alahapperuma and leader of the National People’s Power (NPP) MP Anura Kumara Dissanayake in the election.",
        "His main opponent in the vote was Alahapperuma, a former journalist who was supported by the opposition including the main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), Tamil National Alliance (TNA), Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) and several independent MPs.",
        "Several other dissidents of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) had also opted to back Alahapperuma.",
        "Meanwhile, MP C.V. Vigenswaran, the former chief minister of the Northern Province and the leader and the only parliamentarian of the Tamil People’s National Alliance (TMTK), as well as the Ceylon Workers’ Congress (CWC) also backed Wickremesinghe in the vote.",
        "In the 225-member parliament, 223 had cast their votes and four were declared invalid. Two members namely MPs Selvaraja Gajendran and G.G. Ponnambalam abstained from voting.",
        "Wickremesinghe was elected to the office of President with a total of 134 votes, while Alahapperuma was polled second with 82 votes. Meanwhile, MP Dissanayake secured 03 votes.",
        "Wickremesinghe embarked on active politics in the mid-1970s representing the United National Party (UNP) and entered the parliament in 1977.",
        "He has been the leader of the UNP since 1994. The 73-year-old has held the office of prime minister six times although he never completed a term.",
        "His latest and shortest term in office as the prime minister was when former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appointed him to the position on July 13 this year, after his brother Mahinda Rajapaksa was forced to step down amidst growing public agitation over economic mismanagement and corruption allegations.",
        "After the former President resigned from his position effective from July 14, the parliamentary session was convened on the 16th, during which the Secretary-General of Parliament announced that the office of the President has become vacant.",
        "The presidential race was initially supposed to be a four-way contest before Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa withdrew his candidacy to support Alahapperuma in the presidential race.",
        "Subsequently, the parliament met again yesterday to accept nominations for the election. Accordingly, the names of Wickremesinghe, Alahapperuma and Dissanayake were proposed.",
        "The vote to appoint a succeeding President commenced earlier today after the parliamentary session began at 10.00 a.m. The Secretary-General of Parliament acted as the Returning Officer in this secret ballot.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena cast the first vote, followed by Acting President Wickremesinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Vigenswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil People’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TMTK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Workers’ Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvaraja Gajendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.G. Ponnambalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the mid-1970s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe, Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ තේරී පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (ජූලි 20) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී තේරී පත් විය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වන ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට අද පෙරවරුවේ සභා ගැබේ පැවති රහස් ඡන්දයේදී මන්ත්‍රීවරු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "ධූර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇති වුවහොත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ සහ ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ (1981 අංක 2) දක්වා ඇත.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි ඔහු මැතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) විසම්මුතික සහ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (NPP) නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකට එරෙහිව මුහුණ දුන්නේය.",
        "ඔහුගේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූයේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB), දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය (TNA), ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (SLFP) සහ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඇතුළු විපක්ෂයේ සහාය ලැබූ හිටපු මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු වූ අලහප්පෙරුම ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) තවත් විරුද්ධ මත දරන්නන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ද අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දැක්වීමට කැමැත්ත පළ කර තිබුණි.",
        "මේ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සී.වී. උතුරු පළාතේ හිටපු මහ ඇමති සහ දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානයේ (TMTK) නායකයා සහ එකම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා වන Vigenswaran මෙන්ම ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය (CWC) ද ඡන්දයේදී වික්‍රමසිංහට සහාය දැක්වීය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 223 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබූ අතර ඉන් 4 දෙනෙකු වලංගු නොවන බව ප්‍රකාශ කෙරුණා. මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන සෙල්වරාජා ගජේන්ද්‍රන් සහ ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම් ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියේය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මුළු ඡන්ද 134ක් ලබා ගනිමින් ජනාධිපති ධුරයට තේරී පත් වූ අතර අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ඡන්ද 82ක් ලබා ගනිමින් දෙවැනියා විය. මේ අතර දිසානායක මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට ඡන්ද 03ක් හිමිවිය.",
        "1970 දශකයේ මැද භාගයේදී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය (එජාප) නියෝජනය කරමින් ක්‍රියාකාරී දේශපාලනයට පිවිසි වික්‍රමසිංහ 1977 දී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය.",
        "ඔහු 1994 වසරේ සිට එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ නායකයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරයි. 73 හැවිරිදි ඔහු කිසි දිනක ධුර කාලයක් සම්පූර්ණ නොකළද හය වතාවක් අගමැති ධූරය හොබවා ඇත.",
        "ආර්ථික අවභාවිතය සහ දූෂණ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩෙන මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ මධ්‍යයේ ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරු මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බලකිරීමෙන් පසු, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ වසරේ ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඔහුව අගමැති ධුරයට පත් කිරීම ඔහුගේ නවතම සහ කෙටිම ධුර කාලයයි.",
        "ජූලි 14 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය පසුගිය 16 වැනිදා කැඳවා තිබූ අතර එහිදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරණ සටනේදී අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහය දැක්වීම සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් වූ අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරණ සටන සිව්කොන් තරගයක් වනු ඇතැයි මුලින් සිතිය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව මැතිවරණය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාරගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඊයේ යළි රැස්වුණා. ඒ අනුව වික්‍රමසිංහ, අලහප්පෙරුම සහ දිසානායකගේ නම් යෝජනා විය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය පෙරවරු 10.00 ට ආරම්භ වීමෙන් අනතුරුව අද දින පෙරවරු 10.00 ට ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වන ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත්කිරීමේ ඡන්ද විමසීම ආරම්භ වූ අතර මෙම රහස් ඡන්දයේ තේරීම් භාර නිලධාරියා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ප්‍රථම ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විගේශ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TMTK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වරාජා ගජේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1970 ගණන්වල මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ, අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் புதிய அதிபராக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கேவை நாடாளுமன்றம் தேர்வு செய்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே இன்று (ஜூலை 20) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்ததையடுத்து வெற்றிடமாக இருந்த அந்த பதவிக்கு அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கு இன்று காலை நடைபெற்ற ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வாக்களித்தனர்.",
        "பதவிக்காலம் முடிவதற்குள் ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவி காலியாக இருந்தால், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை பாராளுமன்றம் தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான நடைமுறை அரசியலமைப்பிலும் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்திலும் (எண். 2 1981) வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "73 வயதான அவர் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) அதிருப்தியாளரும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சருமான டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் (NPP) தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரை தேர்தலில் எதிர்கொண்டார்.",
        "வாக்கெடுப்பில் அவரது பிரதான எதிரியாக முன்னாள் ஊடகவியலாளர் அழகப்பெரும இருந்தார். இவர் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB), தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு (TNA), ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP) மற்றும் பல சுயேச்சை எம்.பி.க்கள் உட்பட எதிர்க்கட்சிகளால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் ஊடகவியலாளர் ஆவார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பல அதிருப்தியாளர்களும் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கத் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சி.வி. வடமாகாண முன்னாள் முதலமைச்சரும் தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் தலைவரும் ஒரே பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான விக்னேஸ்வரன் மற்றும் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸும் (CWC) வாக்கெடுப்பில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளித்தனர்.",
        "225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் 223 பேர் வாக்களித்திருந்த நிலையில் 4 பேர் செல்லாதவையாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டனர். பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன் மற்றும் ஜி.ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம் வாக்களிக்காமல் புறக்கணித்தார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க மொத்தம் 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார், அதேவேளை அழகப்பெரும 82 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பெற்றார். இதேவேளை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திஸாநாயக்க 03 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க 1970 களின் நடுப்பகுதியில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியை (UNP) பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி தீவிர அரசியலில் இறங்கினார் மற்றும் 1977 இல் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நுழைந்தார்.",
        "அவர் 1994 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவராக இருந்து வருகிறார். 73 வயதான அவர் ஆறு முறை பிரதமர் பதவியை வகித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி அவரை பிரதமராக நியமித்தது, அவரது சகோதரர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச, பொருளாதார முறைகேடு மற்றும் ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் காரணமாக அதிகரித்து வரும் பொது கிளர்ச்சிக்கு மத்தியில் பதவி விலக வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "ஜூலை 14 ஆம் திகதி முதல் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்ததையடுத்து, கடந்த 16 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு கூடியதுடன், ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகம் வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெறுவதற்கு முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல் நான்கு முனைப் போட்டியாக இருக்கும் என்று முதலில் கருதப்பட்டது.",
        "இதையடுத்து, தேர்தலுக்கான வேட்புமனுக்களை ஏற்க நேற்று நாடாளுமன்றம் மீண்டும் கூடியது. இதன்படி விக்கிரமசிங்க, அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்டன.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு முற்பகல் 10.00 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பமானதை அடுத்து ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று ஆரம்பமானது. இந்த இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பின் தேர்தல் அதிகாரியாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் செயற்பட்டார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன முதலாவது வாக்கெடுப்பை மேற்கொண்டார், அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து பதில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க வாக்களித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்களின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஎம்டிகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1970களின் மத்தியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க, அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}