{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-energy-minister-proposes-parliament-committee-on-fuel-coal-procurement-99135/",
  "time_ut": 1661748180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka energy minister proposes parliament committee on fuel, coal procurement",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka energy minister proposes parliament committee on fuel, coal procurement",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka Power & Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara has proposed that a  parliamentary committee be appointed on the procurement of fuel and coal to be chaired by an opposition member.",
        "Speaking in parliament on Monday August 29, Wijesekara said since President Ranil Wickremesinghe had said more committees be appointed, a committee on fuel and coal procurement should also be formed.",
        "“If the opposition is to take the chairmanship of such a committee, I propose — [independent MP and former Energy Minister] Champika Ranawaka and several other MPs have said that fuel can be procured and sold at very low prices.",
        "“As Minister of Power & Energy, I will fully support the setting up of such a committee and also ask that the opposition take up the chairmanship,” he said.",
        "Opposition MP and Chairman of the Committee on Public Finance said his committee is already empowered to look into fuel and coal procurement.",
        "Wijesekara responded that a committee chaired by a parliamentarian specifically on procurement would be appropriate as there is some conversation brewing in society that certain businessmen with an interest in fuel and coal are using various MPs to sling mud.",
        "Mp de Silva said that the 19th amendment to the constitution would see the appointment of independent commissions on government procurement and it would be best if the amendment was restored. (Colombo/Aug29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Power & Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday August 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Minister of Power & Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mp de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන, ගල් අඟුරු ප්‍රසම්පාදනය පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටුවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා යෝජනා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර විසින් ඉන්ධන සහ ගල් අඟුරු ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටුවක් විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පත් කළ යුතු බවට යෝජනා කර ඇත.",
        "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අදහස් දක්වමින් විජේසේකර කියා සිටියේ තවත් කමිටු පත් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පවසා ඇති බැවින් ඉන්ධන සහ ගල් අඟුරු ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කමිටුවක් ද පත් කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "“විපක්‍ෂය එවැනි කමිටුවක සභාපතිත්වය ගන්නවා නම් මම යෝජනා කරනවා - [ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රී සහ හිටපු බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය] චම්පික රණවක සහ තවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු පවසා ඇත්තේ ඉතා අඩු මිලට ඉන්ධන ලබාගෙන අලෙවි කළ හැකි බවයි.",
        "\"විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස එවැනි කමිටුවක් පිහිටුවීමට මම පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන අතර විපක්ෂයේ සභාපතිත්වය භාර ගන්නා ලෙසද ඉල්ලා සිටිමි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ රාජ්‍ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ සභාපති පැවසුවේ ඉන්ධන සහ ගල් අඟුරු ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බැලීමට තම කමිටුවට දැනටමත් බලය ලැබී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන සහ ගල් අඟුරු සම්බන්ධයෙන් උනන්දුවක් ඇති ඇතැම් ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් විවිධ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් යොදවා මඩ ගැසීමට කටයුතු කරන බවට සමාජය තුළ යම් කතාබහක් ඇතිවී තිබෙන බැවින් ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කමිටුවක් පත්කිරීම සුදුසු බව විජේසේකර ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 19 වැනි සංශෝධනයෙන් රජයේ ප්‍රසම්පාදන සම්බන්ධයෙන් ස්වාධීන කොමිෂන් සභා පත් කෙරෙනු ඇති බවත් එම සංශෝධනය යළි ලබා දෙන්නේ නම් වඩාත් හොඳ බවත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති ඇමති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්පී ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் மற்றும் நிலக்கரி கொள்வனவு தொடர்பான பாராளுமன்ற குழுவை இலங்கை எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் முன்மொழிந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் நிலக்கரியை கொள்வனவு செய்வது தொடர்பாக ஒரு பாராளுமன்ற குழுவை எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் தலைமையில் நியமிக்க வேண்டும் என முன்மொழிந்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உரையாற்றிய விஜேசேகர, ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மேலும் குழுக்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று கூறியிருப்பதால், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் நிலக்கரி கொள்வனவு தொடர்பான குழுவும் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "“எதிர்க்கட்சி அத்தகைய குழுவின் தலைவராக இருந்தால், நான் முன்மொழிகிறேன் - [சுயேட்சை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் முன்னாள் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சருமான] சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க மற்றும் பல எம்.பி.க்கள் எரிபொருளை மிகக் குறைந்த விலையில் கொள்வனவு செய்து விற்க முடியும் என்று கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "\"மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் என்ற முறையில், அத்தகைய குழுவை அமைப்பதை நான் முழுமையாக ஆதரிப்பேன், மேலும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தலைவர் பதவியை ஏற்கும்படி கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.யும், பொது நிதிக்கான குழுவின் தலைவருமான தனது குழு ஏற்கனவே எரிபொருள் மற்றும் நிலக்கரி கொள்முதல் குறித்து ஆராய அதிகாரம் பெற்றுள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "எரிபொருளிலும் நிலக்கரியிலும் ஆர்வமுள்ள சில வர்த்தகர்கள் பல்வேறு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி சேற்றை வாரி இறைப்பதாக சமூகத்தில் சில உரையாடல்கள் உருவாகி வருவதால் கொள்வனவு தொடர்பில் விசேடமாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரின் தலைமையில் குழுவொன்று பொருத்தமானது என விஜேசேகர பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 19 ஆவது திருத்தத்தின் பிரகாரம் அரசாங்க கொள்வனவுகள் தொடர்பில் சுயாதீன ஆணைக்குழுக்கள் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாகவும், அந்த திருத்தத்தை மீளப்பெற்றால் அது சிறந்ததெனவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்பி டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}