{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84654/last-soviet-leader-mikhail-gorbachev-dies-aged-91",
  "time_ut": 1661910360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Last Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev dies aged 91",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Last Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev dies aged 91",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mikhail Gorbachev, who ended the Cold War without bloodshed but failed to prevent the collapse of the Soviet Union, died on Tuesday at the age of 91, hospital officials in Moscow said.",
        "Gorbachev, the last Soviet president, forged arms reduction deals with the United States and partnerships with Western powers to remove the Iron Curtain that had divided Europe since World War Two and bring about the reunification of Germany.",
        "But his internal reforms helped weaken the Soviet Union to the point where it fell apart, a moment that President Vladimir Putin has called the “greatest geopolitical catastrophe” of the twentieth century.",
        "“Mikhail Gorbachev passed away tonight after a serious and protracted disease,” said Russia’s Central Clinical Hospital.",
        "Putin expressed “his deepest condolences”, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told Interfax. “Tomorrow he will send a telegram of condolences to his family and friends,” he said.",
        "Putin said in 2018 he would reverse the Soviet Union’s disintegration if he could, news agencies reported.",
        "World leaders were quick to pay tribute. European Commission chief Ursula von der Leyen said Gorbachev, who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1990, had opened the way for a free Europe.",
        "British Prime Minister Boris Johnson, citing Putin’s invasion of Ukraine, said Gorbachev’s “tireless commitment to opening up Soviet society remains an example to us all”.",
        "There was no immediate reaction from the White House or the U.S. State Department. Former U.S. Secretary of State James Baker described Gorbachev as “a giant who steered his great nation towards democracy”.",
        "After decades of Cold War tension and confrontation, Gorbachev brought the Soviet Union closer to the West than at any point since World War Two.",
        "“He gave freedom to hundreds of millions of people in Russia and around it, and also half of Europe,” said former Russian liberal opposition leader Grigory Yavlinsky. “Few leaders in history have had such a decisive influence on their time.”",
        "But Gorbachev saw his legacy wrecked late in life, as the invasion of Ukraine brought Western sanctions crashing down on Moscow, and politicians in both Russia and the West began to speak of a new Cold War.",
        "“Gorbachev died in a symbolic way when his life’s work, freedom, was effectively destroyed by Putin,” said Andrei Kolesnikov, senior fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.",
        "He will be buried in Moscow’s Novodevichy Cemetery next to his wife Raisa, who died in 1999, said Tass, citing the foundation that the ex-Soviet leader set up once he left office.",
        "“We are all orphans now. But not everyone realizes it,” said Alexei Venediktov, head of a liberal media radio outlet that closed down after coming under pressure over its coverage of the Ukraine war.",
        "When pro-democracy protests rocked Soviet bloc nations in communist Eastern Europe in 1989, Gorbachev refrained from using force - unlike previous Kremlin leaders who had sent tanks to crush uprisings in Hungary in 1956 and Czechoslovakia in 1968.",
        "But the protests fuelled aspirations for autonomy in the 15 republics of the Soviet Union, which disintegrated over the next two years in chaotic fashion.",
        "Gorbachev - who was briefly deposed in an August 1991 coup by party hardliners - struggled vainly to prevent that collapse.",
        "“The era of Gorbachev is the era of perestroika, the era of hope, the era of our entry into a missile-free world ... but there was one miscalculation: we did not know our country well,” said Vladimir Shevchenko, who headed Gorbachev’s protocol office when he was Soviet leader.",
        "“Our union fell apart, that was a tragedy and his tragedy,” RIA news agency cited him as saying.",
        "On becoming general secretary of the Soviet Communist Party in 1985, aged just 54, he had set out to revitalise the system by introducing limited political and economic freedoms, but his reforms spun out of control.",
        "“He was a good man - he was a decent man. I think his tragedy is in a sense that he was too decent for the country he was leading,” said Gorbachev biographer William Taubman, a professor emeritus at Amherst College in Massachusetts.",
        "Gorbachev’s policy of “glasnost” - free speech - allowed previously unthinkable criticism of the party and the state, but also emboldened nationalists who began to press for independence in the Baltic republics of Latvia, Lithuania, Estonia and elsewhere.",
        "Many Russians never forgave Gorbachev for the turbulence that his reforms unleashed, considering the subsequent plunge in their living standards too high a price to pay for democracy.",
        "Vladimir Rogov, a Russian-appointed official in a part of Ukraine now occupied by pro-Moscow forces, said Gorbachev had “deliberately led the (Soviet) Union to its demise” and called him a traitor.",
        "“He gave us all freedom - but we don’t know what to do with it,” liberal economist Ruslan Grinberg told the armed forces news outlet Zvezda after visiting Gorbachev in hospital in June."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Soviet",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "91",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 91",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War Two",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the twentieth century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Clinical Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kremlin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dmitry Peskov",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Interfax",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ursula von der",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leyen",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nobel Peace Prize",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "James Baker",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War Two",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "hundreds of millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Grigory Yavlinsky",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Andrei Kolesnikov",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Novodevichy Cemetery",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Raisa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tass",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ex-Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alexei Venediktov",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kremlin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hungary",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1956",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Czechoslovakia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Shevchenko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Communist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just 54",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "William Taubman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amherst College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Massachusetts",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baltic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latvia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Estonia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Rogov",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "pro-Moscow",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruslan Grinberg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zvezda",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අවසන් සෝවියට් නායක මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් මිය යන විට 91 විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සීතල යුද්ධය ලේ වැගිරීමකින් තොරව අවසන් කළ නමුත් සෝවියට් සංගමය බිඳවැටීම වැළැක්වීමට අපොහොසත් වූ මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් අඟහරුවාදා වයස අවුරුදු 91 දී මිය ගිය බව මොස්කව්හි රෝහල් බලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "අවසාන සෝවියට් ජනාධිපති ගොර්බචෙව්, දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයේ සිට යුරෝපය දෙකඩ කර තිබූ යකඩ තිරය ඉවත් කර ජර්මනිය යලි ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය හා බටහිර බලවතුන් සමඟ හවුල් ව්‍යාජ ආයුධ අඩු කිරීමේ ගනුදෙනු ඇති කළේය.",
        "එහෙත් ඔහුගේ අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සෝවියට් සංගමය බිඳ වැටුණු තැනට දුර්වල කිරීමට උපකාරී විය, ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් විසිවන සියවසේ “ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨතම භූ දේශපාලන ව්‍යසනය” ලෙස හැඳින්වූ මොහොතකි.",
        "රුසියාවේ මධ්‍යම සායනික රෝහල පැවසුවේ “මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් අද රාත්‍රියේ බරපතල හා දිග්ගැස්සුනු රෝගයකින් පසු අභාවප්‍රාප්ත විය.",
        "පුටින් “ඔහුගේ ගැඹුරු ශෝකය” ප්‍රකාශ කළේය, ක්‍රෙම්ලිනයේ ප්‍රකාශක දිමිත්‍රි පෙස්කොව් ඉන්ටර්ෆැක්ස් වෙත පැවසීය. \"හෙට ඔහු තම පවුලේ අයට සහ මිතුරන්ට ශෝක පණිවුඩයක් එවනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පුටින් 2018 දී කියා සිටියේ තමාට හැකි නම් සෝවියට් සංගමයේ බිඳවැටීම ආපසු හරවන බවයි.",
        "ලෝක නායකයෝ උපහාර දැක්වීමට ඉක්මන් වූහ. යුරෝපීය කොමිසමේ ප්‍රධානී Ursula von der Leyen පැවසුවේ 1990 වසරේ නොබෙල් සාම ත්‍යාගයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබූ Gorbachev නිදහස් යුරෝපයක් සඳහා මාවත විවර කළ බවයි.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන්, පුටින්ගේ යුක්රේනය ආක්‍රමණය උපුටා දක්වමින්, \"සෝවියට් සමාජය විවෘත කිරීමට ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ වෙහෙස නොබලා කැපවීම අප සැමට ආදර්ශයක්\" යැයි පැවසීය.",
        "ධවල මන්දිරයෙන් හෝ එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් ක්ෂණික ප්‍රතිචාරයක් නොමැත. හිටපු එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ජේම්ස් බේකර් ගොර්බචෙව් විස්තර කළේ \"ඔහුගේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨ ජාතිය ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය දෙසට යොමු කළ යෝධයෙක්\" ලෙසය.",
        "දශක ගනනාවක සීතල යුද්ධ ආතතියෙන් හා ගැටුම් වලින් පසුව, ගොර්බචෙව් දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයෙන් පසු ඕනෑම අවස්ථාවකට වඩා සෝවියට් සංගමය බටහිරට සමීප කළේය.",
        "\"ඔහු රුසියාවේ සහ ඒ අවට මිලියන සිය ගනනක් මිනිසුන්ට සහ යුරෝපයෙන් අඩකට නිදහස ලබා දුන්නේය\" යැයි හිටපු රුසියානු ලිබරල් විපක්ෂ නායක ග්‍රිගරි යව්ලින්ස්කි පැවසීය. \"ඉතිහාසයේ නායකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට ඔවුන්ගේ කාලය කෙරෙහි එවැනි තීරණාත්මක බලපෑමක් ඇති කර ඇත.\"",
        "නමුත් යුක්රේනය ආක්‍රමණය බටහිර සම්බාධක මොස්කව් වෙත කඩාවැටීමත් සමඟ රුසියාවේ සහ බටහිර රටවල දේශපාලනඥයන් නව සීතල යුද්ධයක් ගැන කතා කිරීමට පටන් ගත් විට ගොර්බචෙව් ඔහුගේ උරුමය විනාශ වී යනු දුටුවේය.",
        "\"Gorbachev ඔහුගේ ජීවිතයේ කාර්යය, නිදහස, පුටින් විසින් ඵලදායී ලෙස විනාශ කරන විට සංකේතාත්මක ආකාරයෙන් මිය ගියේය\" යනුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර සාමය සඳහා වූ Carnegie Endowment හි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන Andrei Kolesnikov පැවසීය.",
        "1999 දී මියගිය ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ රයිසා අසල මොස්කව්හි නොවොඩෙවිචි සුසාන භූමියේ ඔහුව මිහිදන් කරනු ඇති බව හිටපු සෝවියට් නායකයා ඔහු ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වූ පසු පිහිටුවන ලද පදනම උපුටා දක්වමින් ටාස් පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි හැමෝම දැන් අනාථයි. එහෙත්, සෑම දෙනාම එය වටහා නොගනිති,” යනුවෙන් ලිබරල් මාධ්‍ය ගුවන්විදුලි ආයතනයක ප්‍රධානී ඇලෙක්සි වෙනිඩික්ටොව් පැවසුවේ, යුක්රේන යුද්ධය පිළිබඳ එහි ආවරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පීඩනයට ලක්වීමෙන් පසු වසා දැමූ බවයි.",
        "1989 දී ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ගැති විරෝධතා කොමියුනිස්ට් නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපයේ සෝවියට් කඳවුරු ජාතීන් සොලවන විට, ගොර්බචෙව් බලය භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් වැළකුණි - 1956 දී හංගේරියාවේ සහ 1968 දී චෙකොස්ලොවැකියාවේ නැගිටීම් මර්දනය කිරීමට ටැංකි එවූ පෙර ක්‍රෙම්ලින් නායකයන් මෙන් නොව.",
        "එහෙත් විරෝධතා ව්‍යාකූල ආකාරයෙන් ඉදිරි වසර දෙක තුළ බිඳ වැටුණු සෝවියට් සංගමයේ සමූහාන්ඩු 15 තුළ ස්වයං පාලනයක් සඳහා වූ අභිලාෂයන් පෝෂණය කළේය.",
        "පක්ෂ දැඩි මතධාරීන් විසින් 1991 අගෝස්තු කුමන්ත්‍රණයකින් කෙටි කලකට නෙරපා හරින ලද ගොර්බචෙව් එම බිඳවැටීම වැළැක්වීමට නිෂ්ඵල ලෙස අරගල කළේය.",
        "\"ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ යුගය පෙරස්ත්‍රොයිකා යුගයයි, බලාපොරොත්තුවේ යුගයයි, මිසයිල රහිත ලෝකයකට අප පිවිසීමේ යුගයයි ... නමුත් එක් වැරදි ගණනය කිරීමක් විය: අපි අපේ රට හොඳින් දැන සිටියේ නැත,\" ව්ලැඩිමීර් ෂෙව්චෙන්කෝ පැවසීය. ඔහු සෝවියට් නායකයාව සිටියදී ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ ප්‍රොටෝකෝල කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධානියා විය.",
        "\"අපගේ සංගමය බිඳ වැටුණා, එය ඛේදවාචකයක් සහ ඔහුගේ ඛේදවාචකයක්\" යැයි RIA ප්‍රවෘත්ති ඒජන්සිය ඔහුව උපුටා දැක්වීය.",
        "1985 දී සෝවියට් කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් බවට පත් වූ පසු, යන්තම් වයස අවුරුදු 54 දී, සීමිත දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික නිදහසක් හඳුන්වා දීමෙන් පද්ධතිය පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීමට ඔහු කටයුතු කළ නමුත් ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පාලනයෙන් තොර විය.",
        "“ඔහු හොඳ මිනිසෙක් - ඔහු විනීත මිනිසෙකි. මම හිතන්නේ ඔහුගේ ඛේදවාචකය ඔහු නායකත්වය දුන් රටට ඔහු ඉතා විනීත වූවෙකු වීමයි. ”මැසචුසෙට්ස් හි ඇම්හර්ස්ට් විද්‍යාලයේ සම්මානනීය මහාචාර්යවරයෙකු වන ගොර්බචෙව් චරිතාපදාන විලියම් ටවුබ්මන් පැවසීය.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ “ග්ලාස්නොස්ට්” ප්‍රතිපත්තිය - නිදහස් කථනය - පක්ෂය සහ රාජ්‍යය පිළිබඳ කලින් සිතාගත නොහැකි විවේචනවලට ඉඩ දුන් අතර, ලැට්වියාව, ලිතුවේනියාව, එස්තෝනියාව සහ වෙනත් තැන්වල බෝල්ටික් ජනරජවල නිදහස සඳහා බලපෑම් කිරීමට පටන් ගත් ජාතිකවාදීන් ද ධෛර්යමත් කළේය.",
        "බොහෝ රුසියානුවන් ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ විසින් මුදා හරින ලද කැළඹීමට කිසි විටෙකත් සමාව නොදුන් අතර, පසුව ඔවුන්ගේ ජීවන තත්ත්වය පහත වැටීම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සඳහා ගෙවිය නොහැකි මිලක් ලෙස සලකයි.",
        "දැන් මොස්කව් හිතවාදී හමුදා විසින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටින යුක්රේනයේ කොටසක රුසියාව විසින් පත් කරන ලද නිලධාරියෙකු වන ව්ලැඩිමීර් රොගොව් පැවසුවේ ගොර්බචෙව් \"හිතාමතාම (සෝවියට්) සංගමය එහි විනාශය කරා ගෙන ගොස්\" ඔහු ද්‍රෝහියෙකු ලෙස හැඳින්වූ බවයි.",
        "\"ඔහු අපට සියලු නිදහස ලබා දුන්නේය - නමුත් අපි එය කරන්නේ කුමක්දැයි අපි නොදනිමු,\" ලිබරල් ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥ රුස්ලාන් ග්‍රින්බර්ග් ජුනි මාසයේදී ගොර්බචෙව් රෝහලට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු සන්නද්ධ හමුදා ප්‍රවෘත්ති අංශය වන ස්වේස්ඩාට පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෝවියට්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "91",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 91",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසිවන සියවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම සායනික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රෙම්ලිනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිමිත්‍රි පෙස්කොව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් ෆැක්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමයේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උර්සුලා වොන් ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේයන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොබෙල් සාම ත්‍යාගය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේම්ස් බේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රිගරි යව්ලින්ස්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Andrei Kolesnikov",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සාමය සඳහා වූ Carnegie දායාදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Novodevichy සුසාන භූමිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රයිසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිටපු සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්සි වෙනිඩික්ටොව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රෙම්ලිනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හංගේරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1956",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙකොස්ලොවැකියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1991 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් ෂෙව්චෙන්කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විලියම් ටවුබ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amherst College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැසචුසෙට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝල්ටික්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලැට්වියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්තෝනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් රොගොව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව් ගැති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුස්ලාන් ග්රින්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වේස්ඩා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் கடைசி தலைவர் மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் தனது 91வது வயதில் காலமானார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பனிப்போரை இரத்தம் சிந்தாமல் முடித்த மைக்கேல் கோர்பச்சேவ், சோவியத் யூனியனின் சரிவைத் தடுக்கத் தவறிவிட்டார், செவ்வாயன்று தனது 91 வயதில் இறந்தார் என்று மாஸ்கோவில் உள்ள மருத்துவமனை அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் கடைசி ஜனாதிபதியான கோர்பச்சேவ், இரண்டாம் உலகப் போருக்குப் பிறகு ஐரோப்பாவைப் பிளவுபடுத்திய இரும்புத்திரையை அகற்றி ஜெர்மனியை மீண்டும் ஒன்றிணைக்க அமெரிக்காவுடன் ஆயுதக் குறைப்பு ஒப்பந்தங்களையும் மேற்கத்திய சக்திகளுடன் கூட்டுறவையும் உருவாக்கினார்.",
        "ஆனால் அவரது உள் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் சோவியத் யூனியனை பலவீனப்படுத்த உதவியது.",
        "\"மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் தீவிரமான மற்றும் நீடித்த நோய்க்குப் பிறகு இன்று இரவு காலமானார்\" என்று ரஷ்யாவின் மத்திய மருத்துவ மருத்துவமனை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "புடின் \"அவரது ஆழ்ந்த இரங்கலை\" தெரிவித்தார், கிரெம்ளின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் டிமிட்ரி பெஸ்கோவ் Interfax இடம் கூறினார். \"நாளை அவர் தனது குடும்பத்தினருக்கும் நண்பர்களுக்கும் இரங்கல் தந்தி அனுப்புவார்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தன்னால் முடிந்தால் சோவியத் யூனியனின் சிதைவை மாற்றியமைப்பேன் என்று புடின் 2018 இல் கூறியதாக செய்தி நிறுவனங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "உலகத் தலைவர்கள் உடனடியாக அஞ்சலி செலுத்தினர். 1990ல் அமைதிக்கான நோபல் பரிசு பெற்ற கோர்பச்சேவ், சுதந்திர ஐரோப்பாவுக்கான வழியைத் திறந்துவிட்டதாக ஐரோப்பிய ஆணையத் தலைவர் உர்சுலா வான் டெர் லேயன் கூறினார்.",
        "பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சன், உக்ரைன் மீதான புடினின் படையெடுப்பை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, கோர்பச்சேவின் \"சோவியத் சமுதாயத்தைத் திறப்பதற்கான அயராத அர்ப்பணிப்பு நம் அனைவருக்கும் ஒரு எடுத்துக்காட்டு\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "வெள்ளை மாளிகை அல்லது அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறையிடம் இருந்து உடனடி எதிர்வினை எதுவும் இல்லை. முன்னாள் அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை செயலர் ஜேம்ஸ் பேக்கர் கோர்பச்சேவை \"தனது மகத்தான தேசத்தை ஜனநாயகத்தை நோக்கி வழிநடத்திய மாபெரும்\" என்று விவரித்தார்.",
        "பல தசாப்தங்களாக பனிப்போர் பதற்றம் மற்றும் மோதலுக்குப் பிறகு, கோர்பச்சேவ் சோவியத் யூனியனை இரண்டாம் உலகப் போருக்குப் பிறகு எந்த நேரத்திலும் இல்லாத வகையில் மேற்கு நாடுகளுக்கு நெருக்கமாக கொண்டு வந்தார்.",
        "\"ரஷ்யாவிலும் அதைச் சுற்றியுள்ள நூற்றுக்கணக்கான மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கும், ஐரோப்பாவின் பாதி மக்களுக்கும் அவர் சுதந்திரம் அளித்தார்\" என்று முன்னாள் ரஷ்ய தாராளவாத எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கிரிகோரி யாவ்லின்ஸ்கி கூறினார். \"வரலாற்றில் சில தலைவர்கள் தங்கள் காலத்தில் அத்தகைய தீர்க்கமான செல்வாக்கைக் கொண்டிருந்தனர்.\"",
        "ஆனால் உக்ரைன் படையெடுப்பு மேற்கத்திய பொருளாதாரத் தடைகளை மாஸ்கோ மீது வீழ்த்தியதால், அவரது மரபு வாழ்க்கையின் பிற்பகுதியில் சிதைந்ததை கோர்பச்சேவ் கண்டார், மேலும் ரஷ்யாவிலும் மேற்கு நாடுகளிலும் உள்ள அரசியல்வாதிகள் ஒரு புதிய பனிப்போரைப் பற்றி பேசத் தொடங்கினர்.",
        "\"கொர்பச்சேவ் தனது வாழ்க்கையின் பணி, சுதந்திரம், புடினால் திறம்பட அழிக்கப்பட்டபோது ஒரு அடையாள வழியில் இறந்தார்\" என்று சர்வதேச அமைதிக்கான கார்னகி எண்டோமென்ட்டின் மூத்த சக ஆண்ட்ரே கோல்ஸ்னிகோவ் கூறினார்.",
        "அவர் 1999 இல் இறந்த அவரது மனைவி ரைசாவுக்கு அடுத்துள்ள மாஸ்கோவின் நோவோடெவிச்சி கல்லறையில் அடக்கம் செய்யப்படுவார் என்று டாஸ் கூறினார், முன்னாள் சோவியத் தலைவர் பதவியை விட்டு வெளியேறியவுடன் அவர் அமைத்த அடித்தளத்தை மேற்கோள் காட்டி.",
        "“நாங்கள் அனைவரும் இப்போது அனாதைகள். ஆனால் எல்லோரும் அதை உணரவில்லை,” என்று ஒரு தாராளவாத ஊடக வானொலியின் தலைவர் அலெக்ஸி வெனெடிக்டோவ் கூறினார், அது உக்ரைன் போரைப் பற்றிய அழுத்தத்தின் கீழ் வந்த பின்னர் மூடப்பட்டது.",
        "1989 இல் கம்யூனிச கிழக்கு ஐரோப்பாவில் ஜனநாயக ஆதரவு எதிர்ப்புக்கள் சோவியத் முகாம் நாடுகளை உலுக்கியபோது, ​​​​கோர்பச்சேவ் சக்தியைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைத் தவிர்த்தார் - 1956 இல் ஹங்கேரி மற்றும் 1968 இல் செக்கோஸ்லோவாக்கியாவில் கிளர்ச்சிகளை நசுக்க டாங்கிகளை அனுப்பிய முந்தைய கிரெம்ளின் தலைவர்களைப் போலல்லாமல்.",
        "ஆனால் எதிர்ப்புக்கள் சோவியத் யூனியனின் 15 குடியரசுகளில் சுயாட்சிக்கான அபிலாஷைகளைத் தூண்டின, அவை குழப்பமான பாணியில் அடுத்த இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளில் சிதைந்தன.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவ் - ஆகஸ்ட் 1991 ஆட்சிக் கவிழ்ப்பில் கட்சி கடும்போக்காளர்களால் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டவர் - அந்த சரிவைத் தடுக்க வீணாகப் போராடினார்.",
        "\"கோர்பச்சேவின் சகாப்தம் பெரெஸ்ட்ரோயிகாவின் சகாப்தம், நம்பிக்கையின் சகாப்தம், ஏவுகணை இல்லாத உலகில் நாம் நுழைந்த சகாப்தம் ... ஆனால் ஒரு தவறான கணக்கீடு இருந்தது: எங்கள் நாட்டை நாங்கள் நன்கு அறிந்திருக்கவில்லை\" என்று விளாடிமிர் ஷெவ்செங்கோ கூறினார். அவர் சோவியத் தலைவராக இருந்தபோது கோர்பச்சேவின் நெறிமுறை அலுவலகத்திற்கு தலைமை தாங்கினார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் தொழிற்சங்கம் சிதைந்தது, அது ஒரு சோகம் மற்றும் அவரது சோகம்\" என்று RIA செய்தி நிறுவனம் அவரை மேற்கோளிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "1985 இல் சோவியத் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளராக ஆனபோது, ​​வெறும் 54 வயதில், அவர் வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார சுதந்திரங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் அமைப்பைப் புதுப்பிக்கத் தொடங்கினார், ஆனால் அவரது சீர்திருத்தங்கள் கட்டுப்பாட்டை மீறின.",
        "\"அவர் ஒரு நல்ல மனிதர் - அவர் ஒரு ஒழுக்கமான மனிதர். அவர் வழிநடத்தும் நாட்டிற்கு அவர் மிகவும் கண்ணியமானவர் என்ற அர்த்தத்தில் அவரது சோகம் இருப்பதாக நான் நினைக்கிறேன், ”என்று கோர்பச்சேவ் வாழ்க்கை வரலாற்றாசிரியர் வில்லியம் டாப்மேன் கூறினார்.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவின் \"கிளாஸ்னோஸ்ட்\" கொள்கை - பேச்சு சுதந்திரம் - கட்சி மற்றும் அரசு மீது முன்னர் நினைத்துப் பார்க்க முடியாத விமர்சனங்களை அனுமதித்தது, ஆனால் லாட்வியா, லிதுவேனியா, எஸ்டோனியா மற்றும் பிற இடங்களில் உள்ள பால்டிக் குடியரசுகளில் சுதந்திரத்திற்காக அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கத் தொடங்கிய தேசியவாதிகளையும் உற்சாகப்படுத்தியது.",
        "பல ரஷ்யர்கள் கோர்பச்சேவ் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் கட்டவிழ்த்துவிட்ட கொந்தளிப்பை ஒருபோதும் மன்னிக்கவில்லை, அதன்பிறகு அவர்களின் வாழ்க்கைத் தரம் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்ததைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு செலுத்த வேண்டிய விலை அதிகம்.",
        "இப்போது மாஸ்கோ சார்புப் படைகளால் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள உக்ரைனின் ஒரு பகுதியில் ரஷ்ய நியமித்த அதிகாரியான விளாடிமிர் ரோகோவ், கோர்பச்சேவ் \"(சோவியத்) யூனியனை வேண்டுமென்றே அதன் அழிவுக்கு இட்டுச் சென்றார்\" மேலும் அவரை துரோகி என்று அழைத்தார்.",
        "\"அவர் எங்களுக்கு எல்லா சுதந்திரத்தையும் கொடுத்தார் - ஆனால் அதை என்ன செய்வது என்று எங்களுக்குத் தெரியவில்லை\" என்று தாராளவாத பொருளாதார நிபுணர் ருஸ்லான் கிரின்பெர்க் ஜூன் மாதம் கோர்பச்சேவை மருத்துவமனையில் சந்தித்த பின்னர் ஆயுதப்படை செய்தி நிறுவனமான ஸ்வெஸ்டாவிடம் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சோவியத்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "91",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயது 91",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபதாம் நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய மருத்துவ மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரெம்ளின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிமிட்ரி பெஸ்கோவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்டர்ஃபாக்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உர்சுலா வான் டெர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லேயன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைதிக்கான நோபல் பரிசு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேம்ஸ் பேக்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரிகோரி யாவ்லின்ஸ்கி",
