{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/බෝට්ටුවෙන්-රට-යෑමට-තැත්-කළ-33ක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395627",
  "time_ut": 1658399451,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් රට යෑමට තැත් කළ 33ක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "33 people who tried to go to the country by boat were arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Navy conducted a special search operation in the sea area off Negombo this morning (21st) to arrest 33 people suspected of trying to illegally migrate from Sri Lanka to a foreign country by sea.",
        "The P 435 fast attack craft belonging to the fourth fast attack craft squadron attached to the Western Naval Command today (21st) during a search operation carried out in the sea area off Migomu observed and inspected a suspected multi-day fishing vessel.",
        "There, 33 persons, including four crew members of the multi-day fishing vessel, who were suspected of attempting to illegally migrate from the country to a foreign country by sea, were taken into custody by the navy.",
        "In this search operation, the people who were taken into custody by the navy and the people between the ages of 18 and 65 were identified as residents of Halawata, Marawila, Trincomalee, Batticaloa and Ampara, and the group is to be handed over to the Colombo Port Police for further investigations. have."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "33",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Migomu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "multi-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "multi-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between the ages of 18 and 65",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawata",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marawila",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Port Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බෝට්ටුවෙන් රට යෑමට තැත් කළ 33ක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව, මීගමුවට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ අද (21දා) අළුයම් කාලයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමක් මඟින්, නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයන් 33 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "බටහිර නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත හතරවන වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රා බලඝණයට අයත් පී 435 වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව අද (21දා) අළුයම් කාලයේ මිගමුවට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී සැකකටයුතු මෙරට බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කර පරීක්‍ෂාවට ලක් කරන ලදී.",
        "එහිදී, එම බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවේ සිටි නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයේ සිව් දෙනෙකු ඇතුළුව  පුද්ගලයන් 33 දෙනෙකු එම බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව සමඟ නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මෙම සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමේදි නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත්  වයස අවුරුදු 18 ත් 65 ත් අතර වයසේ පසුවන පුද්ගලයින් ඇතුළු පිරිස හලාවත, මාරවිල, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, මඩකලපුව සහ අම්පාර යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හී පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනා ගන්නා ලද අතර, එම පිරිස ඉදිරි විමර්ශන කටයුතු සඳහා කොළඹ වරාය පොලීසිය වෙත භාර දීමට නියමිතව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "33",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Migomu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 සහ 65 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාරවිල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "படகு மூலம் நாட்டுக்கு செல்ல முயன்ற 33 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 33 பேரை கைது செய்ய இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் இன்று (21) காலை நீர்கொழும்பு கடற்பகுதியில் விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்கு உட்பட்ட நான்காவது விரைவு தாக்குதல் கப்பல் படைக்கு சொந்தமான P 435 விரைவு தாக்குதல் கப்பல் இன்று (21) மிகோமு கடல் பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான பல நாள் மீன்பிடி கப்பலை அவதானித்து சோதனை செய்தது.",
        "அங்கு சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாட்டிற்கு செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் பல நாள் மீன்பிடி கப்பலின் நான்கு பணியாளர்கள் உட்பட 33 பேர் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் மற்றும் 18 வயதுக்கும் 65 வயதுக்கும் இடைப்பட்டவர்கள் ஹலவத்தை, மாரவில, திருகோணமலை, மட்டக்களப்பு மற்றும் அம்பாறை ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டு, குறித்த குழுவினர் வசம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட உள்ளனர். மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக கொழும்பு துறைமுக பொலிஸார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "33",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Migomu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 மற்றும் 65 வயதுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாரவில",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுக காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}