{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පාලකයන්ගේ-පව්-පොඩි-මිනිහාගේ-ඇඟ-උඩ-තියන්නේ-ඇයි-/1-618937",
  "time_ut": 1661756425,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාලකයන්ගේ පව් පොඩි මිනිහාගේ ඇඟ උඩ තියන්නේ ඇයි?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Why put the sins of the rulers on the body of the little man?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Vijitha Herath, Gampaha District Member of the National People's Power, said in the Parliament that the Electricity Board is suffering losses due to the wrong policy decisions of the rulers and the common poor people of the country are now responsible for those sins.",
        "Mr. Vijitha Herath said that the people cannot be held accountable for the mistakes of the rulers and said that the rulers who took wrong decisions are at large while the poor people are suffering.",
        "The MP also said that as a result of wrong policies and various actions of politicians, the prices of not only electricity but also gas, fuel etc. are increasing.",
        "Mr. Vijitha Herath said this while addressing the parliamentary adjournment debate on electricity bill increase."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාලකයන්ගේ පව් පොඩි මිනිහාගේ ඇඟ උඩ තියන්නේ ඇයි?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලි බල මණ්ඩලය පාඩු ලබන්නේ පාලකයන්ගේ වැරදි ප්‍රතිපත්ති තීරණ නිසා යැයි ද ඒ පව් වලට දැන් රටේ සාමාන්‍ය දුප්පත් ජනතාව වග උත්තරකරුවන් වී ඇතැයි ද ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "පාලකයන්ගේ වැරදි වලට ජනතාවට වග කියන්න නොහැකි බව කී විජිත හේරත් මහතා දුප්පත් ජනතාව දුක් විඳිද්දී වැරදි තීන්දු ගත්  පාලකයන් නිදැල්ලේ සිටින  බව කීය.",
        "වැරදි ප්‍රතිපත්ති හා දේශපාලනඥයන්ගේ විවිධ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග වල ප්‍රතිඵල ලෙස විදුලිය පමණක් නොව ගෑස් ,ඉන්ධන ආදී සියල්ලේ මිල වැඩි වෙමින් තිබෙන බවද මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීම පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කල් තැබීමේ විවාදය අමතමින් විජිත හේරත් මහතා මේ බව කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆட்சியாளர்களின் பாவங்களை சிறிய மனிதனின் உடலில் ஏன் போட வேண்டும்?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆட்சியாளர்களின் தவறான கொள்கை முடிவுகளினால் மின்சார சபை நட்டத்தை சந்தித்து வருவதாகவும், அந்த பாவங்களுக்கு தற்போது நாட்டின் சாதாரண ஏழை மக்களே காரணம் எனவும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் கம்பஹா மாவட்ட உறுப்பினர் திரு.விஜித ஹேரத் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆட்சியாளர்களின் தவறுகளுக்கு மக்கள் பொறுப்பேற்க முடியாது என தெரிவித்த திரு.விஜித ஹேரத், ஏழை மக்கள் துன்பப்படும் வேளையில் தவறான முடிவுகளை எடுத்த ஆட்சியாளர்கள் தலைமறைவாக உள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசியல்வாதிகளின் தவறான கொள்கைகளாலும் பல்வேறு நடவடிக்கைகளாலும் மின்சாரம் மட்டுமன்றி எரிவாயு, எரிபொருள் போன்றவற்றின் விலைகளும் அதிகரித்து வருவதாகவும் எம்.பி.",
        "மின்சார கட்டண அதிகரிப்பு தொடர்பான பாராளுமன்ற ஒத்திவைப்பு வேளை விவாதத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே திரு.விஜித ஹேரத் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சார வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}