{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මාගම්මන-ගින්නේ-සහ-හැවිරිදි-දියණියත්-මියයයි/1-615800",
  "time_ut": 1656864604,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මාගම්මන ගින්නේ සහ හැවිරිදි දියණියත් මියයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Magammana fire and one year old daughter also dies",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Kahathuduwa police, the six-year-old daughter who was receiving treatment at Borella Ridgeway Arya Children's Hospital has also died after suffering burns in a fire that broke out in a room on the ground floor of a two-storey house in Magammana area of ​​Homagama on the 25th night.",
        "The police say that the deceased was a six-year-old daughter named Ritushi Ranasinghe who lived in Homagama Magammana.",
        "The fire took place on the 25th at around 8.30 pm in a room on the ground floor of a two-storied house in Homagama Magammana area.",
        "At the time of the incident, the deceased six-year-old daughter's mother, father and elder sister were inside the room and they were admitted to Homagama Base Hospital and Colombo National Hospital for treatment.",
        "The father of the six-year-old daughter died on the same day, the mother died the next day and the elder sister died three days after the incident.",
        "Lasantha Buddhika 47, (father) Kalika Devi 35, (mother) and Kavindi Ranasinghe 19, (elder sister) died in this fire and the last rites of their dead bodies were held at Diyagama Flower Hall.",
        "The injured six-year-old daughter died while undergoing treatment at the Lady Ridgeway Children's Hospital and a post-mortem examination was conducted."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Magammana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "one year old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kahathuduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella Ridgeway Arya Children's Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ritushi Ranasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Magammana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 25th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Magammana",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Base Hospital and Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lasantha Buddhika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Devi 35",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kavindi Ranasinghe 19",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diyagama Flower Hall",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lady Ridgeway Children's Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාගම්මන ගින්නේ සහ හැවිරිදි දියණියත් මියයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෝමාගම මාගම්මන ප්‍රදේශයේ දෙමහල් නිවසක ඉකුත් 25 දා රාත්‍රි පහළ මාලයේ කාමරයක ඇතිවූ ගින්නෙන් පිළිස්සුම් තුවාල ලබා බොරැල්ල රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටි සය හැවිරිදි දියණිය ද මියගොස් ඇති බව කහතුඩුව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත්තේ හෝමාගම මාගම්මන පදිංචිව සිටි රිතුෂි රණසිංහ නමැති සය හැවිරිදි දියණියක බව පොලීසිය කියයි .",
        "මෙම ගින්න ඉකුත් 25 දා රාත්‍රී 8.30 පමණ හෝමාගම මාගම්මන ප්‍රදේශයේ දෙමහල් නිවසක පහළ මාලයේ කාමරයක් තුළ සිදු විය.",
        "සිද්ධිය වන අවස්ථාවේදී මියගිය සය හැවිරිදි දියණියගේ මව පියා වැඩිමහල් සොහොයුරිය කාමරය තුළ තුළ සිට ඇති අතර ඔවුන් ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහල සහ කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කෙරිණි .",
        "සිද්ධියෙන් සය හැවිරිදි දියණියගේ පියා එදිනම මියගිය අතර මව පසුදින මියගිය බවත් වැඩිමහල් සොහොයුරිය සිද්ධියෙන් දින තුනකට පසුව මිය ගොස් තිබුණි .",
        "මෙම ගින්නෙන් ලසන්ත බුද්ධික 47, (පියා) කාලිකා දේවී 35 , (මව) සහ කාවින්දි රණසිංහ 19, (වැඩිමල් සොයුරිය) මිය ගොස් තිබූ අතර ඔවුන්ගේ මෘත දේහයන් පිළිබඳ අවසන් කටයුතු ඉකුත් දා දියගම මල් ශාලාවකදී පැවැත්වුණි .",
        "තුවාල ලැබූ සය හැවිරිදි දියණිය රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇති අතර මෘත දේහය පිළිබඳ පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය සිදු කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාගම්මන",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුද්දක් වයස",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කහතුඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල රිජ්වේ ආර්ය ළමා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිතුෂි රණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මාගම්මන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මාගම්මන",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහල සහ කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලසන්ත බුද්ධික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේවි 35",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවින්දි රණසිංහ 19",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දියගම මල් ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மகம்மானா தீ மற்றும் ஒரு வயது மகளும் இறக்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மாகம்மன பிரதேசத்தில் இரண்டு மாடி வீடொன்றின் தரைத்தளத்தில் உள்ள அறையொன்றில் ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் எரிகாயமடைந்து பொரளை ரிட்ஜ்வே ஆர்யா சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த ஆறு வயது மகளும் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக கஹதுடுவ பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். 25 இரவு ஹோமாகம.",
        "ஹோமாகம மாகம்மன பிரதேசத்தில் வசித்து வந்த ரிதுஷி ரணசிங்க என்ற ஆறு வயது மகள் ஒருவரே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "கடந்த 25ஆம் திகதி இரவு 8.30 மணியளவில் ஹோமாகம மாகம்மன பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள இரண்டு மாடி வீடொன்றின் தரைத்தளத்தில் உள்ள அறையொன்றில் தீ விபத்து ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சம்பவத்தின் போது உயிரிழந்த ஆறு வயது மகளின் தாய், தந்தை மற்றும் மூத்த சகோதரி ஆகியோர் அறைக்குள் இருந்துள்ளதுடன் அவர்கள் ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை மற்றும் கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சைக்காக அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஆறு வயது மகளின் தந்தை அதே நாளில் இறந்தார், தாய் மறுநாள் இறந்தார் மற்றும் மூத்த சகோதரி சம்பவம் நடந்த மூன்று நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு இறந்தார்.",
        "லசந்த புத்திக 47, (தந்தை) காளிகா தேவி 35, (தாய்) மற்றும் காவிந்தி ரணசிங்க 19, (மூத்த சகோதரி) ஆகியோர் இந்த தீ விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்ததுடன், அவர்களது சடலங்களின் இறுதிக் கிரியைகள் டயகம மலர் மண்டபத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த ஆறு வயது மகள் ரிட்ஜ்வே லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த நிலையில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன் பிரேத பரிசோதனை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மகம்மன",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கஹதுடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை ரிட்ஜ்வே ஆர்யா சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிதுஷி ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம மகம்மன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 8.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம மகம்மன",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை மற்றும் கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லசந்த புத்திக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேவி 35",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிந்தி ரணசிங்க 19",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டயகம மலர் மண்டபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே குழந்தைகள் மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}