{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-appoints-committee-to-facilitate-repatriation-of-refugees-from-india-99472/",
  "time_ut": 1662377280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka appoints committee to facilitate repatriation of refugees from India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka appoints committee to facilitate repatriation of refugees from India",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has appointed a committee to facilitate and optimise the repatriation of Sri Lankans who had fled to India as war refugees.",
        "A statement from the president’s media division (PMD) said on Monday September 05 said about 58,000 Sri Lankan refugees are currently residing in Tamil Nadu, India, out of whom only 3,800 are ready to return to Sri Lanka at present.",
        "The committee, headed by Additional Secretary to the President Chandima Wickramasinghe, comprises the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration and senior officials of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Registrar General’s Department and the Ministry of Justice.",
        "The PMD statement said the decision to appoint the committee was reached at a discussion held at the President’s Office on Monday at the request of the Organisation for Eelam Refugees Rehabilitation (OFERR) to bring back the Sri Lankans who had fled to India as refugees due to the war. The discussion was chaired by Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake.",
        "The Sri Lanka Deputy High Commissioner’s Office in Chennai is coordinating the efforts in this regard, the statement said.",
        "Over 67,000 Sri Lankan refugees have been living in 107 camps scattered across Tamil Nadu, according to a 2019 report by the Refugee Studies Centre in the Oxford Department of International Development, University of Oxford.",
        "Just under 37,000 lived outside the camps at the time of the study.",
        "Sri Lankan Tamil refugees fled the government’s war with the separatist Tamil Tigers at various points of the 26-year conflict.",
        "“Although refugees are entitled to residence visas and work permits, prolonged life in the camps does not lead to resilience and empowerment, and these refugees consider themselves in limbo, belonging neither to Sri Lanka nor to India and unable to get on with their lives,” the report said.",
        "“Tamil refugees – especially youth – wish to be disassociated with the label of ‘refugee’, which they feel would improve quality of life for them, their families and their communities,” it added. (Colombo/Sep05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday September 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 58,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 3,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandima Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Registrar General’s Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Organisation for Eelam Refugees Rehabilitation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "67,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "107",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Refugee Studies Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Oxford Department of International Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Oxford",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Just under 37,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Tigers",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ සිට සරණාගතයින් ආපසු ගෙන්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - යුධ සරණාගතයින් ලෙස ඉන්දියාවට පලා ගිය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් නැවත ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීම සහ ප්‍රශස්ත කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කමිටුවක් පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ (PMD) ප්‍රකාශයක් සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගතයින් 58,000 ක් පමණ දැනට ඉන්දියාවේ තමිල්නාඩුවේ පදිංචිව සිටින අතර ඔවුන්ගෙන් 3,800 ක් පමණක් දැනට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට සූදානම්ව සිටින බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් චන්දිම වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් මෙම කමිටුව ආගමන විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්වරයා සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ, රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සහ අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වේ.",
        "සරණාගතයන් ලෙස ඉන්දියාවට පළා ගිය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මෙරටට ගෙන්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඊළාම් සරණාගතයන් පුනරුත්ථාපනය සඳහා වූ සංවිධානය (OFERR) කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව සඳුදා ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මෙම කමිටුව පත් කිරීමට තීරණය කළ බව PMD නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ. යුද්ධය. මෙම සාකච්ඡාව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කටයුතු සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරමින් සිටින බව එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධන ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සරණාගත අධ්‍යයන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ 2019 වාර්තාවකට අනුව තමිල්නාඩුව පුරා විසිරී ඇති කඳවුරු 107 ක ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගතයින් 67,000 කට අධික පිරිසක් ජීවත් වී ඇත.",
        "අධ්‍යයනය කරන අවස්ථාවේ කඳවුරුවලින් පිටත ජීවත් වූයේ 37,000කට අඩු පිරිසකි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ සරණාගතයින් 26 වසරක ගැටුමේ විවිධ අවස්ථා වලදී බෙදුම්වාදී දෙමළ කොටි සමඟ ආන්ඩුව ගෙන ගිය යුද්ධයෙන් පලා ගියහ.",
        "\"සරණාගතයින්ට පදිංචි වීසා සහ රැකියා බලපත්‍ර සඳහා හිමිකම් ඇතත්, කඳවුරුවල දිගුකාලීන ජීවිතය ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හා සවිබල ගැන්වීමට මග පාදන්නේ නැත, මෙම සරණාගතයින් තමන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හෝ ඉන්දියාවට අයත් නොවන අතර තම ජීවිතය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට නොහැකි ලෙස සලකයි. ” වාර්තාවේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "\"දෙමළ සරණාගතයින් - විශේෂයෙන්ම තරුණ - සරණාගතයින්\" යන ලේබලයෙන් ඈත් වීමට කැමති වන අතර, එය ඔවුන්ගේ, ඔවුන්ගේ පවුල්වල සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රජාවන්ගේ ජීවන තත්ත්වය වැඩිදියුණු කරනු ඇතැයි ඔවුන්ට හැඟේ. (කොළඹ/සැප්.05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,800 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම් සරණාගතයන් පුනරුත්ථාපනය සඳහා වූ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "67,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "107",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරණාගත අධ්‍යයන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ් ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37,000ට අඩුයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ කොටි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து அகதிகளை திருப்பி அனுப்புவதற்கு வசதியாக இலங்கை குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - போர் அகதிகளாக இந்தியாவுக்குத் தப்பிச் சென்ற இலங்கையர்களைத் திருப்பி அனுப்புவதை எளிதாக்குவதற்கும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் இலங்கை ஒரு குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) திங்கட்கிழமை செப்டம்பர் 05 அன்று வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கையில், சுமார் 58,000 இலங்கை அகதிகள் தற்போது இந்தியாவில் உள்ள தமிழ்நாட்டில் தங்கியுள்ளனர், அவர்களில் 3,800 பேர் மட்டுமே தற்போது இலங்கைக்குத் திரும்பத் தயாராக உள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் சந்திம விக்ரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான குழுவில் குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் நாயகம் மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு, பதிவாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் நீதியமைச்சின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் உள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்தியாவிற்கு அகதிகளாக தஞ்சமடைந்துள்ள இலங்கையர்களை மீள அழைத்து வருவதற்கான ஈழ அகதிகள் மறுவாழ்வு அமைப்பின் (OFERR) வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க, ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் திங்கட்கிழமை நடைபெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் இந்தக் குழுவை நியமிப்பதற்கான தீர்மானம் எட்டப்பட்டதாக PMD அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. போர். ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க தலைமையில் இந்த கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கை துணை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் அலுவலகம் இது தொடர்பான முயற்சிகளை ஒருங்கிணைத்து வருவதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "67,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட இலங்கை அகதிகள் தமிழகம் முழுவதும் 107 முகாம்களில் வாழ்கின்றனர் என்று ஆக்ஸ்போர்டு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் ஆக்ஸ்போர்டு சர்வதேச மேம்பாட்டுத் துறையின் அகதிகள் ஆய்வு மையத்தின் 2019 அறிக்கை தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "ஆய்வின் போது 37,000 க்கும் குறைவானவர்கள் முகாம்களுக்கு வெளியே வாழ்ந்தனர்.",
        "26 ஆண்டுகால மோதலின் பல்வேறு கட்டங்களில் பிரிவினைவாத தமிழ்ப் புலிகளுடனான அரசாங்கத்தின் போரில் இருந்து இலங்கைத் தமிழ் அகதிகள் வெளியேறினர்.",
        "“அகதிகளுக்கு வதிவிட விசா மற்றும் வேலை அனுமதிப்பத்திரங்களுக்கு உரிமையிருந்தாலும், முகாம்களில் நீண்ட காலம் வாழ்வது நெகிழ்ச்சி மற்றும் அதிகாரமளிக்க வழிவகுக்காது, மேலும் இந்த அகதிகள் தங்களை இலங்கைக்கும் அல்லது இந்தியாவுக்கும் சொந்தமானவர்கள் அல்ல, தங்கள் வாழ்க்கையைத் தொடர முடியாமல் திணறுகிறார்கள். ” என்று அந்த அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "\"தமிழ் அகதிகள் - குறிப்பாக இளைஞர்கள் - அகதிகள்' என்ற முத்திரையுடன் துண்டிக்கப்பட விரும்புகிறார்கள், இது அவர்கள், அவர்களின் குடும்பங்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களின் சமூகங்களின் வாழ்க்கைத் தரத்தை மேம்படுத்தும் என்று அவர்கள் நினைக்கிறார்கள்,\" என்று அது மேலும் கூறியது. (கொழும்பு/செப்05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 58,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,800 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திம விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈழ அகதிகள் மறுவாழ்வுக்கான அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "67,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "107",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகதிகள் ஆய்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வளர்ச்சிக்கான ஆக்ஸ்போர்டு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆக்ஸ்போர்டு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37,000 க்கு குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் புலிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}