{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Tuk-Tuk-fares-up-Rs-90-for-second-km-onwards/108-239802",
  "time_ut": 1656218197,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tuk Tuk fares up; Rs.90 for second km onwards",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tuk Tuk fares up; Rs.90 for second km onwards",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The three wheeler fare for the second kilometre has been increased to Rs. 90 from today, the All-Island Three-Wheeler Drivers' Union President Lalith Dharmasekera said.",
        "He told the Daily Mirror that the decision was made after the government's insistence on increasing fuel prices.",
        "The fare for the second km was at Rs.80, following the previous fuel price increase.",
        "Although there will be no fare revision in the first km, which stands at Rs.100, only the fares for the second km onwards have gone up, he said. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalith Dharmasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.80",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.100",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Tuk Tuk ගාස්තු ඉහළ යයි; දෙවන කිලෝමීටරයට රු.90 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙවන කිලෝමීටරයේ ත්‍රිරෝද රථ ගාස්තුව රු. 90 අද සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව සමස්ත ලංකා ත්‍රිරෝද රථ රියදුරන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ලලිත් ධර්මසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන මිල වැඩි කරන ලෙස රජය කළ බලකිරීමෙන් පසු මෙම තීරණය ගත් බව ඔහු ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත කියා සිටියේය.",
        "මීට පෙර ඉන්ධන මිල ඉහළ දැමීමත් සමඟ දෙවැනි කිලෝමීටරයේ ගාස්තුව රුපියල් 80ක් විය.",
        "රුපියල් 100ක් වන පළමු කිලෝමීටරයේ ගාස්තු සංශෝධනයක් සිදු නොකෙරෙන නමුත් දෙවැනි කිලෝමීටරයේ ගාස්තු පමණක් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලලිත් ධර්මසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 80යි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 100යි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Tuk Tuk கட்டணம் உயர்வு; இரண்டாவது கி.மீ.க்கு ரூ.90",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரண்டாவது கிலோமீட்டருக்கான முச்சக்கர வண்டி கட்டணம் ரூபாவாக அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 90 இன்று முதல் அகில இலங்கை முச்சக்கர வண்டி சாரதிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் லலித் தர்மசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் விலையை அதிகரிக்குமாறு அரசாங்கம் வலியுறுத்தியதன் பின்னரே இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக டெய்லி மிரருக்கு அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முந்தைய எரிபொருள் விலை உயர்வைத் தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது கி.மீ.க்கான கட்டணம் ரூ.80 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "முதல் கி.மீ.,க்கு, 100 ரூபாய் கட்டணம் இல்லை என்றாலும், இரண்டாவது கி.மீ.,க்கு மட்டுமே கட்டணம் உயர்த்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.இவ்வாறு அவர் கூறினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லலித் தர்மசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.80",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.100",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}