{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/US-concerned-about-actions-taken-against-protesters/108-241547",
  "time_ut": 1658457775,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US concerned about actions taken against protesters",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US concerned about actions taken against protesters",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "US Ambassador to Sri Lanka, Julie Chung today said that they are deeply concerned about actions taken against protesters at Galle Face in the middle of the night.",
        "In her official Twitter post, she said the US urges restraint by authorities and immediate access to medical attention for those injured.",
        "A tense situation was reported at the Galle Face protest site  near the Presidential Secretariat as police and troops moved in to remove protesters from the area. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the middle of the night",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව එක්සත් ජනපදය කනස්සල්ල පළ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව තමන් දැඩි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් අද ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ඇයගේ නිල ට්විටර් සටහනේ ඇය කියා සිටියේ බලධාරීන් විසින් සංයමයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙසත් තුවාල ලැබූවන් සඳහා වහාම වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා දෙන ලෙසත් එක්සත් ජනපදය ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අසල ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියේ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් වාර්තා වූයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් එම ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට පොලිසිය සහ භට පිරිස් ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමත් සමඟය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම රාත්රිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது எடுக்கப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து அமெரிக்கா கவலை கொண்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நள்ளிரவில் காலி முகத்திடலில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து கவலையடைவதாக இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் தனது அதிகாரப்பூர்வ ட்விட்டர் பதிவில், அதிகாரிகள் கட்டுப்பாட்டுடன் இருக்கவும், காயமடைந்தவர்களுக்கு உடனடியாக மருத்துவ உதவியை அணுகவும் அமெரிக்கா வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகிலுள்ள காலி முகத்திடலில் போராட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றுவதற்காக பொலிஸாரும் இராணுவத்தினரும் சென்றதால் அங்கு பதற்றமான சூழல் நிலவியது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நடு இரவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}