{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අන්තරේ-පාගමනට-කළ-ප්‍රහාරය-රනිල්-රාජපක්‍ෂ-ආණ්ඩුවේ-අවසානයේ-ආරම්භයයි/11-396430",
  "time_ut": 1660888170,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අන්තරේ පාගමනට කළ ප්‍රහාරය රනිල් රාජපක්‍ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ අවසානයේ ආරම්භයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The attack on the Antare march was the beginning of the end of the Ranil Rajapaksa government",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The National Bhikshu Peramuna says in a statement that the water and tear gas attacks and the baton attack on the protest march held by the Inter-University Student Union is the final attack of the Ranil Rajapaksa government. The front said in a statement that it strongly protested and condemned the attack.",
        "\"We as National Bhikshu Peramuna would like to point out that if the Ranil Pohottu government, which is unable to solve the problems of the people that arise day by day, is thinking of suppressing the demands of the people, it is a very foolish idea. Instead of looking for answers to the acute crises of the people, the President Wickremesinghe is trying to find answers to the acute crises of the people. The people are well aware that the camp is working to protect its existence and to protect criminals and corrupt people.",
        "It is the wish of the people to free the country from Ranilla and Rajapaksa and maintain it under populist rule. When 3 out of 10 families of the people of the country are starving, when people are dying due to lack of necessary medicines, the people have no choice but to take to the streets against the idiotic practices of the government which is issuing cabinet papers to give compensation to white cloth thieves, killers of Tamil children and central bank robbers.",
        "Pereida fishermen. Yesterday's students, tomorrow's farmers, by the next day all the masses will be on the streets. Must get off.",
        "Millions of Sri Lankan people who have lost their lives and livelihoods due to Ranilla's and Japakshala's brutal rule must demand their lives and fill all the avenues tomorrow to achieve their victories.",
        "The rulers who destroyed the country for 74 years should no longer be allowed to kill the people of Suwase. Therefore, except for the idiotic rulers of the corrupt Ranil Rajapaksa government and a handful of people who are helping it, everyone should take to the streets, struggle, kick out all kinds of corrupt people for 74 years, and build a populist government. For that, we request all Sri Lankans to stand up and come together without being afraid of the repressions of the anti-people government that has no popular opinion.",
        "We urge the government to immediately stop the repression of arresting people, including the convener, and to immediately release all those who were arrested."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Rajapaksa",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Bhikshu Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter-University Student Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Pohottu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranilla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pereida",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranilla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japakshala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suwase",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අන්තරේ පාගමනට කළ ප්‍රහාරය රනිල් රාජපක්‍ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ අවසානයේ ආරම්භයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය පැවැත්වූ විරෝධතා පාගමනට ඒල්ල කළ ජල හා කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර හා බැටන් ප්‍රහාරය රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ අවසානයේ ආරම්භක ප්‍රහාරය බව ජාතික භික්ෂු පෙරමුණ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසයි. මෙම ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන්ජ බලවත් විරෝධය පළකරන බවත් එය හෙළා දකින බවත් එම පෙරමුණ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසයි.",
        "\"දිනෙන් දින බුර බුරා පැනනගින ජනතා ගැටලූවලට විසඳුම් දිය නොහැකි රනිල් පොහොට්ටු ආණ්ඩුව මර්දනයෙන් ජනතා ඉල්ලීම් විසුණුකොට දමන්නට හිතන්නේ නම් එය ඉතා අඥාන කල්පනාවක් බවද ජාතික භික්‍ෂු පෙරමුණ ලෙස පෙන්වාදීමට අපි කැමැත්තෙමු. වේල් තුන කන්න දෙනවා යැයි පාරම්බාමින් ජනාධිපතිවූ වික‍්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනතාවගේ උග්‍ර අර්බුදයන්ට පිළිතුරු සොයනවා වෙනුවට රාජපක්‍ෂ කඳවුර සතුටුක කොට සිය පැවැත්ම ආරක්‍ෂා කරගැනීමටත්, අපරාධකාරයින්, දූෂිතයින් ආරක්‍ෂා කරන්නටත් කටයුතු කරනා බව ජනතාව හොඳින් දකිමින් ඇත.",
        "රනිල්ලා, රාජපක්ෂලා වැනසූ රට ඔවුන්ගෙන් මුදවාගෙන ජනතාවාදී පාලනයක් යටතේ පවත්වා ගැනීම ජනතාවගේ අභිලාෂයයි. රටේ ජනතාවගෙන් පවුල් 10න් 3 ක් බඩගින්නේ සිටිද්දී, අවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ නැතිකමින් ජනයා මැරී වැටෙද්දී, සුදු රෙදි හොරුන්ට, දෙමළ දරුවන් ඝාතකයින්ට, මහ බැංකු මංකොල්ලකරුවන්ට වන්‍දි ලබා දීමට කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකා දමන ආණ්ඩුවේ මුග්ධ පිළිවෙත් වලට එරෙහිව පාරට බහිනවා හැර ජනතාවට අන් මාවතක් නැත.",
        "පෙරෙයිදා ධීවරයින්. ඊයේ ශිෂ්‍යයින්, හෙට ගොවිජනයා අනිද්දා වන විට සියලූ මහජනයා මහමගට බසිනු ඇත. බැසිය යුතුමය.",
        "රනිල්ලාගේ, ජාපක්‍ෂලාගේ දුර්දාන්ත පාලනය විසින් ජීවිත අහිමිකර ඇති, ජීවන මාර්ග අහිමිකර ඇති ලක්‍ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනයා ජීවිත ඉල්ලා හෙට දින සියලූ මාවත් පුරවා සිය ජයග්‍රහණ අත්පත් කරගත යුතුය.",
        "74 වසරක් රට වැනසූ පාලකයින්ට තවදුරටත් සුවසේ ජනයා නොමරා මරන්නට ඉඩ දිය යුතු නැත. එහෙයින් දූෂිත රනිල් රාජපක්‍ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ මුග්ධ පාලකයින් හා ඊට අත්වැල් අල්ලන අතළොස්සක් හැර අන් සැම පාරට බැසිය යුතුය, අරගල කළ යුතුය, 74 වසරක සකලවිධ දූෂිතයින් පන්නා දැමිය යුතුය, ජනතාවාදී පාලනයක් ගොඩනගා ගත යුතුය. ඒ සඳහා ජනමතයක් නැති ජනතාද්‍රෝහී ආණ්ඩුවේ මර්දනයන්ට බිය නොවී එකාවන්ව නැගිට එන ලෙස සියලූ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ගෙන් අපි ඉල්ලා සිටින්නෙමු.",
        "ඇලෝසියස්ලාට මෙන්ඩිස් බලපත්‍ර නිදහස් කරන ආණ්ඩුව සාධාරණ ජනතා හඬ රැගෙන මහ මගට බැස්ස අන්තරේ කැඳවුම්කරු ඇතුලූ පිරිස් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනිමන් කරන මර්දනය වහා නවතන ලෙසත් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සියලූදෙනා වහා නිදහස් කරන ලෙසත් අපි ආණ්ඩුවට බලකර කියා සිටින්නෙමු.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික භික්ෂු පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරෙයිදා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්ලා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපක්ෂල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 74 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suwase",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 74 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அந்தரே அணிவகுப்பு மீதான தாக்குதல் ரணில் ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கத்தின் முடிவின் ஆரம்பம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் ஒன்றியம் நடத்திய ஆர்ப்பாட்ட பேரணியின் மீது நீர் மற்றும் கண்ணீர்ப்புகை தாக்குதல் மற்றும் தடியடி தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்டமை ரணில் ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தின் இறுதித் தாக்குதல் என தேசிய பிக்கு பெரமுன அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இந்த தாக்குதலுக்கு கடும் கண்டனமும், கண்டனமும் தெரிவிப்பதாக அந்த முன்னணி வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“நாளுக்கு நாள் எழும் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க முடியாத ரணில் பொதுஜன பெரமுன அரசாங்கம் மக்களின் கோரிக்கைகளை நசுக்க நினைப்பது மிகவும் முட்டாள்தனமான யோசனை என்பதை தேசிய பிக்கு பெரமுன என்ற வகையில் சுட்டிக்காட்ட விரும்புகிறோம். மக்களின் கடுமையான நெருக்கடிகளுக்கு விடை தேடுவதற்குப் பதிலாக ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க மக்களின் கடுமையான நெருக்கடிகளுக்கு விடை காண முற்படுகிறார்.முகாம் தனது இருப்பை பாதுகாக்கவும் குற்றவாளிகள் மற்றும் ஊழல்வாதிகளை பாதுகாக்கவும் செயற்படுவதை மக்கள் நன்கு அறிவர். மக்கள்.",
        "ரணில்லா மற்றும் ராஜபக்சேவிடம் இருந்து நாட்டை விடுவித்து, ஜனரஞ்சக ஆட்சியில் தக்கவைக்க வேண்டும் என்பதே மக்களின் விருப்பம். நாட்டு மக்களில் 10ல் 3 குடும்பங்கள் பட்டினியால் வாடும் போது, ​​தேவையான மருந்துகள் கிடைக்காமல் மக்கள் செத்து மடியும் போது, ​​வெள்ளையருக்கு இழப்பீடு வழங்க அமைச்சரவை பத்திரம் வெளியிடும் அரசின் முட்டாள்தனமான நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு எதிராக மக்கள் வீதியில் இறங்குவதை தவிர வேறு வழியில்லை. துணி திருடர்கள், தமிழ் குழந்தைகளை கொன்றவர்கள் மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி கொள்ளையர்கள்.",
        "பெரீடா மீனவர்கள். நேற்றைய மாணவர்கள், நாளைய விவசாயிகள், மறுநாள் மக்கள் அனைவரும் வீதிக்கு வருவார்கள். இறங்க வேண்டும்.",
        "ரணில்லா மற்றும் ஜபக்ஷலாவின் கொடூர ஆட்சியால் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை இழந்து தவிக்கும் இலட்சக்கணக்கான இலங்கை மக்கள் தமது வாழ்வாதாரத்தைக் கோரி நாளை தமது வெற்றிகளை அடைவதற்கான அனைத்து வழிகளையும் நிரப்ப வேண்டும்.",
        "74 ஆண்டுகளாக நாட்டை அழித்த ஆட்சியாளர்கள் இனி சுவாசே மக்களைக் கொல்ல அனுமதிக்கக் கூடாது. எனவே ஊழல் மிக்க ரணில் ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கத்தின் முட்டாள் ஆட்சியாளர்களையும் அதற்கு உதவி செய்யும் ஒரு சிலரையும் தவிர அனைவரும் வீதியில் இறங்கி போராடி 74 வருடங்களாக அனைத்து வகையான ஊழல்வாதிகளையும் உதைத்து ஜனரஞ்சக அரசை உருவாக்க வேண்டும். அதற்காக மக்கள் கருத்து இல்லாத மக்கள் விரோத அரசின் அடக்குமுறைகளுக்கு அஞ்சாமல் அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களும் எழுந்து நின்று ஒன்று சேருமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம்.",
        "கன்வீனர் உள்ளிட்டவர்களை கைது செய்யும் அடக்குமுறையை உடனடியாக நிறுத்தவும், கைது செய்யப்பட்ட அனைவரையும் உடனடியாக விடுவிக்கவும் அரசை வலியுறுத்துகிறோம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பிக்ஷு பெரமுனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் பொஹொட்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரீடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜபக்ஷலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suwase",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}