{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84622/cict-awards-winners-of-quay-crane-operator-competition",
  "time_ut": 1661827260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CICT awards winners of Quay Crane Operator competition",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CICT awards winners of Quay Crane Operator competition",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An awards ceremony organized by the Colombo International Container Terminals Limited (CICT) to celebrate the winners of its Competition for Quay Crane (QC) operators was held on Monday (29).",
        "It was reported that such an award ceremony was held for the first time in South Asia.",
        "The Gold Medal of the competition was won by QC operator Chathuranga Pushpakumara.",
        "China Merchants Group (CMG), the parent company of Colombo International Container Terminals Limited (CICT), is celebrating its 150th anniversary this year. To mark this milestone, the company is conducting 150 global competitions among its group.",
        "In an effort to recognize and reward the best operators within the company, Colombo International Container Terminals Limited, located in the south Harbour of Port of Colombo, had hosted the first ever Quay Crane (QC) operator competition in South Asia.",
        "The goal was to promote exceptional safety standards and continued skills development within all ranks of the QC operators.",
        "The competition was held within CICT contained 2 rounds. The Participation of all QC operators was mandatory in the 1st round, where overall skills and abilities were assessed based on strict standardized criteria applicable to all participants taking part.",
        "The top 30 performers from the 1st round had advanced to the 2nd round, which focused on exceptional skills. The participants were given an opportunity to demonstrate, to the best of their ability, skills and expertise in handling containers and operating their stations.",
        "After the 2nd round, 6 of the top-scoring QC operators from CICT receiveed awards and cash prices across three categories:",
        "1 Gold Winner received LKR 600,000/-, 2 Silver Winners received LKR 400,000/- each, and 3 Bronze Winners received LKR 200,000/- each.",
        "Colombo International Container Terminal (CICT}, which manages the South Terminal at the Port of Colombo, is the first deep water terminal in South Asia and the only one of its kind in operation within the region. Since its inception in 2014, the terminal has incrementally grown its volumes handled from 686,639 TEUs (in 2014} to just over 3.2 million TEUs in 2021; the highest done by a terminal in South Asia.",
        "CICT has been consistently recognized for exceptional levels of efficiency, driven on the ground by its QC operators, and has won the AFLAS award for Asia’s best container terminal under 4 million TEU’s for 5 consecutive years (2017-2021).Further, CICT has also won the award for Most Efficient Terminal 2021’ at the Global Ports Forum Awards. Thus, CICT is very keen on promoting and creating healthy competition amongst its QC operators whilst providing incentives to encourage exceptional excellence. CICT’s efficiency drive has positively impacted the stakeholders by reducing the port stay of the vessels which are impacted by the global challenges faced by the shipping industry. This has ultimately lead to remarkable efficiency, further strengthening the globally renowned position of the Port of Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CICT",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Quay Crane Operator",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo International Container Terminals Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quay Crane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chathuranga Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China Merchants Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo International Container Terminals Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo International Container Terminals Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quay Crane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gold Winner",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "600,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Silver Winners",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bronze Winners",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo International Container Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the South Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "686,639",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just over 3.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 consecutive years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017-2021).Further",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Global Ports Forum Awards",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Quay Crane Operator තරඟයේ ජයග්‍රාහකයින් සඳහා CICT සම්මාන ප්‍රදානය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සීමාසහිත Colombo International Container Terminals Limited (CICT) විසින් Quay Crane (QC) ක්‍රියාකරුවන් සඳහා වූ තරඟයේ ජයග්‍රාහකයින් සැමරීම සඳහා සංවිධානය කරන ලද සම්මාන උළෙලක් සඳුදා (29) දින පැවැත්විණි.",
        "දකුණු ආසියාවේ ප්‍රථම වතාවට මෙවැනි සම්මාන උළෙලක් පැවැත්වූ බවයි වාර්තා වුණේ.",
        "තරගයේ රන් පදක්කම QC ක්‍රියාකරු චතුරංග පුෂ්පකුමාර විසින් දිනා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "Colombo International Container Terminals Limited (CICT) හි මව් සමාගම වන China Merchants Group (CMG) මෙම වසරේ සිය 150 වැනි සංවත්සරය සමරයි. මෙම සන්ධිස්ථානය සනිටුහන් කිරීම සඳහා සමාගම සිය කණ්ඩායම අතර ගෝලීය තරඟ 150 ක් පවත්වයි.",
        "සමාගම තුළ සිටින හොඳම ක්‍රියාකරුවන් හඳුනාගෙන ත්‍යාග පිරිනැමීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයක් ලෙස, කොළඹ වරායේ දකුණු වරායේ පිහිටි Colombo International Container Terminals Limited, දකුණු ආසියාවේ ප්‍රථම Quay Crane (QC) ක්‍රියාකරු තරඟයක් පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "ඉලක්කය වූයේ QC ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සියලුම තරාතිරම්වල සුවිශේෂී ආරක්ෂණ ප්‍රමිතීන් සහ අඛණ්ඩ කුසලතා සංවර්ධනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමයි.",
        "තරඟය වට 2කින් සමන්විත CICT තුළ පැවැත්විණි. සහභාගී වන සියලුම සහභාගිවන්නන්ට අදාළ වන දැඩි ප්‍රමිතිගත නිර්ණායක මත පදනම්ව සමස්ත කුසලතා සහ හැකියාවන් තක්සේරු කරන ලද 1 වන වටයේදී සියලුම QC ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය අනිවාර්ය විය.",
        "සුවිශේෂී දස්කම් කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කළ පළමු වටයේ හොඳම දක්ෂතා දැක්වූ ක්‍රීඩකයින් 30 දෙනා 2 වැනි වටයට සුදුසුකම් ලබා තිබුණි. සහභාගිවන්නන්ට බහාලුම් හැසිරවීම සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ස්ථාන ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ උපරිම හැකියාව, කුසලතා සහ ප්‍රවීණත්වය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමට අවස්ථාවක් ලබා දෙන ලදී.",
        "2 වන වටයෙන් පසුව, CICT වෙතින් ඉහළම ලකුණු ලබා ගත් QC ක්‍රියාකරුවන් 6 දෙනෙකුට කාණ්ඩ තුනක් හරහා සම්මාන සහ මුදල් මිල ගණන් ලැබුණි:",
        "රන් ජයග්‍රාහකයින් 1 දෙනෙකුට රුපියල් 600,000/- බැගින් ද, රිදී ජයග්‍රාහකයින් 2 දෙනෙකුට රුපියල් 400,000/- බැගින් ද, ලෝකඩ ජයග්‍රාහකයින් 3 දෙනෙකුට රුපියල් 200,000/- බැගින් ද හිමි විය.",
        "කොළඹ වරායේ දකුණු පර්යන්තය කළමනාකරණය කරන කොළඹ ජාත්‍යන්තර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය (CICT}, දකුණු ආසියාවේ ප්‍රථම ගැඹුරු ජල පර්යන්තය වන අතර කලාපය තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන එවැනි එකම පර්යන්තයයි. 2014 වසරේ ආරම්භ කළ දා සිට පර්යන්තය 686,639 TEU සිට (2014 දී TEU මිලියන 3.2 කට වඩා 2021 දක්වා, දකුණු ආසියාවේ පර්යන්තයක් විසින් සිදු කරන ලද ඉහළම පරිමාවක් දක්වා ක්‍රමයෙන් වර්ධනය විය.",
        "CICT එහි QC ක්‍රියාකරුවන් විසින් බිම මත ධාවනය කරන ලද සුවිශේෂී කාර්යක්‍ෂමතා මට්ටම් සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව පිළිගැනීමට ලක්ව ඇති අතර, අඛණ්ඩව වසර 5ක් (2017-2021) සඳහා TEU මිලියන 4ක් යටතේ ආසියාවේ හොඳම බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය සඳහා AFLAS සම්මානය දිනා ගෙන ඇත. Global Ports Forum Awards හිදී වඩාත් කාර්යක්ෂම පර්යන්තය 2021' සඳහා වන සම්මානය දිනා ගන්නා ලදී. මේ අනුව, CICT සිය QC ක්‍රියාකරුවන් අතර සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න තරඟයක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට සහ නිර්මාණය කිරීමට ඉතා උනන්දු වන අතරම සුවිශේෂී විශිෂ්ටත්වය දිරිගැන්වීම සඳහා දිරිගැන්වීම් ලබා දෙයි. නාවික කර්මාන්තය මුහුණ දෙන ගෝලීය අභියෝග හේතුවෙන් බලපෑමට ලක් වූ යාත්‍රා වල වරාය රැඳීම අඩු කිරීම මගින් CICT හි කාර්යක්‍ෂමතා ක්‍රියාවලිය පාර්ශවකරුවන්ට ධනාත්මක ලෙස බලපා ඇත. මෙය අවසානයේදී කොළඹ වරායේ ගෝලීය වශයෙන් කීර්තිමත් තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කරමින් කැපී පෙනෙන කාර්යක්ෂමතාවයකට තුඩු දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CICT",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Quay Crane Operator",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත Colombo International Container Terminals",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quay Crane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චයිනා මර්චන්ට් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත Colombo International Container Terminals",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත Colombo International Container Terminals",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quay Crane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන් ජයග්රාහකයා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "600,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිදී ජයග්‍රාහකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝකඩ ජයග්රාහකයින්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාත්‍යන්තර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "686,639 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.2කට වැඩියි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව වසර 5 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017-2021).තවදුරටත්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Ports Forum සම්මාන උළෙල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குவே கிரேன் ஆபரேட்டர் போட்டியின் வெற்றியாளர்களுக்கு CICT விருதுகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட் (CICT) ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ள Quay Crane (QC) ஆபரேட்டர்களுக்கான போட்டியின் வெற்றியாளர்களைக் கொண்டாடும் வகையில் விருது வழங்கும் விழா திங்கட்கிழமை (29) நடைபெற்றது.",
        "தெற்காசியாவிலேயே முதன்முறையாக இதுபோன்ற விருது விழா நடத்தப்பட்டதாக தகவல் வெளியானது.",
        "போட்டியின் தங்கப் பதக்கத்தை QC நடத்துனர் சதுரங்க புஷ்பகுமார வென்றார்.",
        "Colombo International Container Terminals Limited (CICT) இன் தாய் நிறுவனமான China Merchants Group (CMG) இந்த ஆண்டு தனது 150வது ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் கொண்டாடுகிறது. இந்த மைல்கல்லைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில், நிறுவனம் தனது குழுவில் 150 உலகளாவிய போட்டிகளை நடத்துகிறது.",
        "நிறுவனத்திற்குள் சிறந்த ஆபரேட்டர்களை அங்கீகரித்து வெகுமதி அளிக்கும் முயற்சியில், கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் தெற்கு துறைமுகத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள Colombo International Container Terminals Limited, தெற்காசியாவில் முதல் Quay Crane (QC) ஆபரேட்டர் போட்டியை நடத்தியது.",
        "விதிவிலக்கான பாதுகாப்பு தரநிலைகளை ஊக்குவிப்பதும், QC ஆபரேட்டர்களின் அனைத்து தரவரிசைகளுக்குள்ளும் தொடர்ச்சியான திறன் மேம்பாட்டை மேம்படுத்துவதும் இலக்காக இருந்தது.",
        "CICT க்குள் 2 சுற்றுகளைக் கொண்ட போட்டி நடைபெற்றது. அனைத்து QC ஆபரேட்டர்களின் பங்கேற்பு 1வது சுற்றில் கட்டாயமாக இருந்தது, இதில் பங்கேற்கும் அனைத்து பங்கேற்பாளர்களுக்கும் பொருந்தக்கூடிய கடுமையான தரப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அளவுகோல்களின் அடிப்படையில் ஒட்டுமொத்த திறன்கள் மற்றும் திறன்கள் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டன.",
        "1 வது சுற்றில் இருந்து சிறந்த 30 வீரர்கள் 2 வது சுற்றுக்கு முன்னேறினர், இது விதிவிலக்கான திறமைகளை மையமாகக் கொண்டது. பங்கேற்பாளர்கள் கொள்கலன்களைக் கையாள்வதிலும் தங்கள் நிலையங்களை இயக்குவதிலும் தங்களின் திறன், திறன்கள் மற்றும் நிபுணத்துவம் ஆகியவற்றை வெளிப்படுத்தும் வாய்ப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2வது சுற்றுக்குப் பிறகு, CICT இலிருந்து அதிக மதிப்பெண் பெற்ற QC ஆபரேட்டர்களில் 6 பேர் மூன்று பிரிவுகளில் விருதுகள் மற்றும் பண விலைகளைப் பெற்றனர்:",
        "1 தங்க வெற்றியாளர் 600,000/- ரூபாயும், 2 வெள்ளி வெற்றியாளர்கள் தலா 400,000/- ரூபாயும், மற்றும் 3 வெண்கல வெற்றியாளர்கள் தலா 200,000/- ரூபாயும் பெற்றனர்.",
        "கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் தெற்கு முனையத்தை நிர்வகிக்கும் கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் முனையம் (CICT}, தெற்காசியாவின் முதல் ஆழமான நீர் முனையமாகும், மேலும் இந்த பிராந்தியத்திற்குள் செயல்படும் ஒரே மாதிரியான ஒன்றாகும். 2014 இல் தொடங்கப்பட்டதிலிருந்து, முனையம் உள்ளது. அதன் தொகுதிகள் 686,639 TEU களில் இருந்து (2014} இல் 2021 இல் 3.2 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான TEU களாகக் கையாளப்பட்டது; தெற்காசியாவில் ஒரு முனையத்தால் செய்யப்பட்ட மிக அதிகமான அளவு.",
        "CICT ஆனது அதன் QC ஆபரேட்டர்களால் தரையில் இயங்கும் விதிவிலக்கான செயல்திறனுக்காக தொடர்ந்து அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டு, தொடர்ந்து 5 ஆண்டுகளாக (2017-2021) 4 மில்லியன் TEU களின் கீழ் ஆசியாவின் சிறந்த கொள்கலன் முனையத்திற்கான AFLAS விருதை வென்றுள்ளது. மேலும், CICT ஆனது. குளோபல் போர்ட்ஸ் ஃபோரம் விருதுகளில் மிகவும் திறமையான டெர்மினல் 2021'க்கான விருதை வென்றது. எனவே, CICT ஆனது அதன் QC ஆபரேட்டர்களிடையே ஆரோக்கியமான போட்டியை ஊக்குவிப்பதிலும் உருவாக்குவதிலும் மிகவும் ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில் விதிவிலக்கான சிறப்பை ஊக்குவிப்பதற்காக ஊக்குவிப்புகளை வழங்குகிறது. CICT இன் செயல்திறன் இயக்கம், கப்பல் துறை எதிர்கொள்ளும் உலகளாவிய சவால்களால் பாதிக்கப்படும் கப்பல்களின் துறைமுகத் தங்குதலைக் குறைப்பதன் மூலம் பங்குதாரர்களை சாதகமாக பாதித்துள்ளது. இது இறுதியில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வினைத்திறனுக்கு வழிவகுத்ததுடன், கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் உலகளாவிய புகழ்பெற்ற நிலையை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CICT",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "குவே கிரேன் ஆபரேட்டர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவே கிரேன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா வணிகர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவே கிரேன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கம் வென்றவர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "600,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி வென்றவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெண்கல வெற்றியாளர்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு சர்வதேச கொள்கலன் முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "686,639",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TEUகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் 3.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017-2021).மேலும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோபல் போர்ட்ஸ் ஃபோரம் விருதுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}