{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83564/three-arrested-over-torching-pms-residence-remanded",
  "time_ut": 1657458480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three arrested over torching PM’s residence remanded",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three arrested over torching PM’s residence remanded",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The three suspects arrested over the incident of setting fire to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence in Colombo have been remanded until July 20 by the Fort Magistrate’s Court.",
        "On Sunday, Sri Lanka police arrested three people for setting Wickremesinghe’s private residence at Cambridge Place in Colombo on fire during the Saturday violence.",
        "Among the arrested suspects is a 19-year-old residing in Mount Lavinia. The other two suspects were identified as residents of Kadawatha and Galle areas, aged 24 and 28 respectively.",
        "More arrests are on the anvil, as the police have widened their scope of investigations, the police spokesman had said.",
        "Meanwhile the investigations into the incident have been handed over to the Criminal Investigations Department (CID) today.",
        "According to reports, protesters had stormed the PM’s private residence at Cambridge Place in Colombo late last night after which it had been set on fire, inflicting extensive damage to the property and damaging a luxury sedan.",
        "During a protest staged outside the prime minister’s private residence last night, a group of people had stormed the premises which was later set on fire.",
        "The residence was replete with a rare collection of books and old Buddha statues, most of which Wickremesinghe had inherited, a spokesperson of the Prime Minister’s Office said.",
        "The incident came hours after Wickremesinghe offered to resign to make way for an all-party government.",
        "Island-wide mass public protests were organized yesterday, demanding President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to resign immediately.",
        "Meanwhile the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) says that a special investigation is being conducted regarding the power outage in the vicinity of the Prime Minister’s private residence in Colombo at the time it was set on fire."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cambridge Place in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mount Lavinia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 and 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cambridge Place in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "late last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තිදෙනෙක් රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනා ලබන 20 වනදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය නියෝග කර තිබේ.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය අතරතුර වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කොළඹ කේම්බ්‍රිජ් පෙදෙසේ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය ඉරිදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත්තේය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් අතර ගල්කිස්ස ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකු ද වනවා. අනෙක් සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා කඩවත සහ ගාල්ල ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු 24 සහ 28 යන වයස්වල පසුවන්නන් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "පොලිසිය සිය විමර්ශන විෂය පථය පුළුල් කර ඇති බැවින් තවත් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් සිදුවෙමින් පවතින බව පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පවසා ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර සිද්ධියට අදාළ පරීක්ෂණ අද අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (CID) භාරදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "වාර්තාවලට අනුව, ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ කොළඹ කේම්බ්‍රිජ් පෙදෙසේ පිහිටි අගමැතිතුමාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට කඩා වැදුණු විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඊට ගිනි තබා දේපළවලට විශාල අලාභහානි සිදු කර සුඛෝපභෝගී සෙඩන් රථයකට අලාභහානි කර තිබේ.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ඉදිරිපිට ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ පැවති විරෝධතාවක් අතරතුර කිසියම් පිරිසක් එම පරිශ්‍රයට කඩා වැදී පසුව ගිනි තබා තිබෙනවා.",
        "වික‍්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට උරුම වූ දුර්ලභ ග‍්‍රන්ථ එකතුවකින් සහ පැරණි බුද්ධ ප‍්‍රතිමා වලින් එම නිවස පිරී තිබූ බව අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ ප‍්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආන්ඩුවකට ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා වික‍්‍රමසිංහ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ඉදිරිපත් වී පැය කිහිපයකට පසු මෙම සිදුවීම සිදුවිය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් දීප ව්‍යාප්ත මහජන විරෝධතා ඊයේ දිනයේදී සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි.",
        "මේ අතර අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තබන අවස්ථාවේ එම නිවස අවට විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශේෂ පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කේම්බ්‍රිජ් පෙදෙස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 සහ 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කේම්බ්‍රිජ් පෙදෙස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமரின் இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த வழக்கில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட மூவர் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவரையும் எதிர்வரும் 20 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை வன்முறையின் போது கொழும்பில் உள்ள கேம்பிரிட்ஜ் பிளேஸில் உள்ள விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்ததற்காக மூன்று பேரை ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர்களில் கல்கிசை பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் 19 வயதுடைய இளைஞரும் அடங்குவார். மற்றைய இரு சந்தேக நபர்களும் முறையே 24 மற்றும் 28 வயதுடைய கடவத்தை மற்றும் காலி பிரதேசங்களில் வசிப்பவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பொலிசார் விசாரணைகளை விரிவுபடுத்தியுள்ள நிலையில் மேலும் பல கைதுகள் தொடர்வதாக பொலிஸ் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, சம்பவம் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்திடம் (CID) இன்று ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அறிக்கைகளின்படி, கொழும்பில் கேம்பிரிட்ஜ் பிளேஸில் உள்ள பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தை நேற்றிரவு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டனர், பின்னர் அது தீ வைக்கப்பட்டது, சொத்துக்களுக்கு பாரிய சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது மற்றும் ஆடம்பர செடான் ஒன்றை சேதப்படுத்தியது.",
        "நேற்றிரவு பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே நடத்தப்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​ஒரு குழுவினர் வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து பின்னர் தீ வைத்து எரித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த இல்லத்தில் அரிய புத்தகங்கள் மற்றும் பழைய புத்தர் சிலைகள் நிரம்பியிருந்தன, அவற்றில் பெரும்பாலானவை விக்கிரமசிங்க மரபுரிமையாக இருந்ததாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வழி வகுக்கும் வகையில் ராஜினாமா செய்ய முன்வந்த சில மணி நேரங்களிலேயே இந்த சம்பவம் நடந்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் நேற்று பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "இதேவேளை, கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைக்கப்பட்ட போது அப்பகுதியில் ஏற்பட்ட மின் தடை தொடர்பில் விசேட விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட்டு வருவதாக இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றவியல் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள கேம்பிரிட்ஜ் பிளேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மற்றும் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள கேம்பிரிட்ஜ் பிளேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு தாமதமாக",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}