{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/PM-and-Cabinet-should-resign-and-form-an-all-party-govt-Dullas-writes-to-Prez/155-235515",
  "time_ut": 1650635474,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PM and Cabinet should resign and form an all party govt- Dullas writes to Prez",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PM and Cabinet should resign and form an all party govt- Dullas writes to Prez",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "PM and Cabinet should resign and form an all party govt- Dullas writes to Prez Former Minister Dullas Alahapperuma in a letter to the President says the Prime Minister and cabinet should resign immediately and form a new All Party government soon.",
        "In his two-page letter, the former minister stated that a small cabinet representing all parties in parliament should be appointed for at least one year period in order to find the immediate solution to the current crisis situation.",
        "While praising the President for appointing a cabinet with a majority of young MPs, the former Minister said that the decision could have taken much earlier and now it too late."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "All Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති සහ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඉල්ලා අස්වී සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි - ඩලස් ජනපතිට ලියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගමැති සහ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඉල්ලා අස්වී සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි - ඩලස් ජනපතිට ලිපියක් යවයි හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ජනපතිට ලිපියක් යවමින් පවසන්නේ අගමැති ඇතුළු කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඉක්මනින් නව සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයට කඩිනම් විසඳුම් සෙවීමට නම් අවම වශයෙන් වසරක කාලයකට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලු පක්ෂ නියෝජනය වන පරිදි කුඩා කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් පත් කළ යුතු බව හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා සිය පිටු දෙකකින් යුත් ලිපියේ සඳහන් කර තිබේ.",
        "තරුණ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් බහුතරයක් සිටින කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් පත්කිරීම පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ප්‍රශංසා කරන අතරේ හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ මෙම තීරණය මීට බොහෝ කලකට පෙර ගත හැකිව තිබූ බවත් දැන් ප්‍රමාද වැඩි බවත්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියලු පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් වසරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமரும் அமைச்சரவையும் ராஜினாமா செய்து அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சியை அமைக்க வேண்டும் - டல்லாஸ் பிரெஸுக்கு கடிதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமரும் அமைச்சரவையும் ராஜினாமா செய்து சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும்- பிரதமரும் அமைச்சரவையும் உடனடியாக இராஜினாமா செய்து புதிய சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை விரைவில் அமைக்க வேண்டும் என ஜனாதிபதிக்கு முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடி நிலைமைக்கு உடனடித் தீர்வைக் காண்பதற்கு குறைந்தபட்சம் ஒரு வருட காலத்திற்கு அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் வகையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சிறிய அமைச்சரவையொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டுமென முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் தனது இரண்டு பக்க கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பெரும்பான்மையான இளம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட அமைச்சரவையை நியமித்தமைக்காக ஜனாதிபதியை பாராட்டிய முன்னாள் அமைச்சர், இந்த தீர்மானத்தை மிகவும் முன்னதாகவே எடுத்திருக்க முடியும் எனவும் தற்போது தாமதமாகியுள்ளது எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}