{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/19/2021-a-l-practicals-from-today-19/",
  "time_ut": 1660881240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "2021 A/L Practicals from today (19)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "2021 A/L Practicals from today (19)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); G. C. E. Advanced Level Practical Examinations for candidates who missed it in 2021 will commence on Friday (19), said the Department of Examinations.",
        "Commissioner General of Examinations L.M.D Dharmasena told that the relevant practical tests will be held on Saturday (20) and Sunday (21) as well.",
        "Dharmasena said that due to the fuel crisis and problematic conditions, students were unable to appear for the practical tests.",
        "He said that the relevant examinations will be completed and the Advanced Level examination results will be released in two weeks.",
        "Meanwhile, Commissioner General of Examination L.M.D Dharmasena announced that the third phase of the evaluation of the answer sheets of the G.C.E Ordinary Level Examination will begin tomorrow (20).",
        "The deadline for accepting applications for the 2022 G.C.E Advanced Level Examination has been extended to the 26th of August.",
        "Pohottuwa wants Gotabaya back in Sri Lanka with security, and facilities"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2021",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "A/L Practicals",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E. Advanced Level Practical Examinations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday (19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Advanced Level",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "L.M.D Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E Advanced Level Examination",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2021 උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික අද (19) සිට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); G. C. E. උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික විභාග 2021 දී එය මඟ හැරුණු අයදුම්කරුවන් සඳහා සිකුරාදා (19) ආරම්භ වන බව විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ඊට අදාළ ප්‍රායෝගික පරීක්ෂණ සෙනසුරාදා (20) සහ ඉරිදා (21) යන දෙදින තුළද පැවැත්වෙන බව විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් L.M.D ධර්මසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ධර්මසේන පැවසුවේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය සහ ගැටලුකාරී තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් සිසුන්ට ප්‍රායෝගික පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා පෙනී සිටීමට නොහැකි වූ බවයි.",
        "අදාළ විභාග අවසන් කර සති දෙකකින් උසස් පෙළ විභාග ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කරන බව ද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර අධ්‍යයන පොදු සහතික පත්‍ර සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගයේ පිළිතුරු පත්‍ර ඇගයීමේ තුන්වන අදියර හෙට (20) ආරම්භ වන බව විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් L.M.D ධර්මසේන මහතා නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "2022 අධ්‍යයන පොදු සහතික පත්‍ර උසස් පෙළ විභාගය සඳහා අයදුම්පත් භාරගැනීමේ අවසන් දිනය අගෝස්තු 26 වැනිදා දක්වා දීර්ඝ කර ඇත.",
        "පොහොට්ටුවට අවශ්‍ය ගෝඨාභය ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ පහසුකම් සහිතව නැවත ලංකාවට පැමිණීමයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2021",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E. උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික විභාග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා (19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "උසස් පෙළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "L.M.D ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E උසස් පෙළ විභාගය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2021 A/L நடைமுறைகள் இன்று (19) முதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); G. C. E. உயர்தர நடைமுறைப் பரீட்சை 2021 இல் தவறிய பரீட்சார்த்திகளுக்கான பரீட்சைகள் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (19) ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ளதாக பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதற்கான நடைமுறைப் பரீட்சைகள் சனி (20) மற்றும் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (21) ஆகிய இரு தினங்களிலும் நடைபெறும் என பரீட்சைகள் ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி தர்மசேன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி மற்றும் பிரச்சினைக்குரிய நிலைமைகள் காரணமாக மாணவர்கள் நடைமுறைப் பரீட்சைக்குத் தோற்ற முடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக தர்மசேன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உரிய பரீட்சைகள் நிறைவடைந்து உயர்தரப் பரீட்சை பெறுபேறுகள் இரண்டு வாரங்களில் வெளியிடப்படும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, க.பொ.த சாதாரண தரப் பரீட்சையின் மூன்றாம் கட்ட விடைத்தாள் மதிப்பீட்டுப் பணிகள் நாளை (20) ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ளதாக பரீட்சை ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "2022 G.C.E உயர்தரப் பரீட்சைக்கான விண்ணப்பங்களை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதற்கான காலக்கெடு ஆகஸ்ட் 26 ஆம் தேதி வரை நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வசதிகளுடன் கோட்டாபய மீண்டும் இலங்கைக்கு வர வேண்டும் என்று பொஹொட்டுவா விரும்புகிறார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2021",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "A/L நடைமுறைகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E. உயர்நிலை நடைமுறைத் தேர்வுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேம்பட்ட நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.எம்.டி தர்மசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.சி.இ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E உயர்நிலைத் தேர்வு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}