{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/police-suspect-drug-feud-as-motive-for-balapitiya-murder/",
  "time_ut": 1661959620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Police suspect drug feud as motive for Balapitiya murder",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Police suspect drug feud as motive for Balapitiya murder",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A 28-year-old man was gunned down by unknown gunmen opposite the Balapitiya Hospital in Ambalangoda on Wednesday (31) evening.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said the victim was a resident of Wathugedara, and he was gunned down when traveling on his motorcycle.",
        "Sri Lanka Police believe a T-56 Assault Rifle was used to commit the murder, and suspect the shooting may be the result of an ongoing dispute between criminal gangs linked to drugs.",
        "However, Police said it is investigating leads to determine if this shooting has any link to the previous incidents of men being gunned down in Ambalangoda in recent days.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Balapitiya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Balapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday (31) evening",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wathugedara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a T-56 Assault Rifle",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "recent days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බලපිටිය ඝාතනයට හේතුව මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ආරවුලක් බවට පොලිසිය සැක කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බදාදා (31) සවස අම්බලන්ගොඩ, බලපිටිය රෝහල ඉදිරිපිටදී නාඳුනන තුවක්කුකරුවන් විසින් 28 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ මියගිය පුද්ගලයා වතුගෙදර ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු වන අතර ඔහු යතුරුපැදියෙන් ගමන් කරමින් සිටියදී වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "මෙම ඝාතනය සිදු කිරීම සඳහා T-56 ප්‍රහාරක රයිෆලයක් භාවිතා කර ඇති බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විශ්වාස කරන අතර, මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම මත්ද්‍රව්‍යවලට සම්බන්ධ අපරාධ කල්ලි අතර පවතින ආරවුලක ප්‍රතිඵලයක් විය හැකි බවට සැක කෙරේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පසුගිය දිනවල අම්බලන්ගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේදී වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කිරීමේ පෙර සිදුවීම්වලට මෙම වෙඩි තැබීමේ සම්බන්ධයක් තිබේද යන්න පිළිබඳව පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වන බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බලපිටිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා (31) සවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වතුගෙදර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56 ප්‍රහාරක රයිෆලයක්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෑත දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலபிட்டிய கொலைக்கான காரணம் போதைப்பொருள் விவகாரம் என பொலிஸார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புதன்கிழமை (31) மாலை அம்பலாங்கொட பலபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு முன்பாக இனந்தெரியாத ஆயுததாரிகளினால் 28 வயதுடைய நபர் ஒருவர் சுட்டுக்கொல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "பலியானவர் வத்துகெதர பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என்றும், அவர் தனது மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் பயணித்தபோது சுட்டுக்கொல்லப்பட்டதாகவும் இலங்கை போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்தக் கொலையைச் செய்வதற்கு T-56 தாக்குதல் துப்பாக்கி பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டதாக சிறிலங்கா பொலிசார் நம்புகின்றனர், மேலும் போதைப்பொருளுடன் தொடர்புடைய கிரிமினல் கும்பல்களுக்கு இடையே நிலவும் தகராறு காரணமாக துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அம்பலாங்கொடையில் அண்மைய நாட்களில் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்ட சம்பவங்களுக்கும் இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கும் தொடர்பு உள்ளதா என்பது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்தி வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பலபிட்டிய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை (31) மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்துகெதர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு T-56 தாக்குதல் துப்பாக்கி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}