{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-health-sector-union-leader-lands-new-job-under-president-98115/",
  "time_ut": 1659431760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka health sector union leader lands new job under president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka health sector union leader lands new job under president",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka trade union leader Saman Rathnapriya, who is affiliated with the United National Party (UNP), has been appointed Director General of Trade Unions by President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "A press release from the President’s Media Division confirmed the appointment on Tuesday August 02.",
        "Rathnapriya, who once represented the UNP in parliament, was President of the Government Nursing Officers’ Association. As a trade union leader, he was prominently active during the presidency of Gotabaya Rajapaksa throughout the COVID-19 public health emergency. (Colombo/Aug02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Rathnapriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rathnapriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සෞඛ්‍ය අංශයේ වෘත්තීය සමිති නායකයා ජනපති යටතේ නව රැකියාවකට යයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට (එජාප) සම්බන්ධ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෘත්තීය සමිති නායක සමන් රත්නප්‍රිය මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් වෘත්තීය සමිති අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් අගෝස්තු 02 අඟහරුවාදා පත්කිරීම තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "වරක් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කළ රත්නප්‍රිය රජයේ හෙද නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා ද විය. වෘත්තීය සමිති නායකයෙකු ලෙස, ඔහු ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ජනාධිපති සමයේදී COVID-19 මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථාව පුරාම කැපී පෙනෙන ලෙස ක්‍රියාකාරී විය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් රත්නප්‍රිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 02 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රත්නප්‍රිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை சுகாதாரத் துறை தொழிற்சங்கத் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதியின் கீழ் புதிய வேலையில் இறங்கினார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியுடன் (UNP) இணைந்திருக்கும் இலங்கை தொழிற்சங்கத் தலைவர் சமன் ரத்னபிரிய, ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் தொழிற்சங்கங்களின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகமாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவின் செய்திக்குறிப்பு ஆகஸ்ட் 02 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை இந்த நியமனத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "ஒரு காலத்தில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்திய இரத்தினப்பிரிய, அரசாங்க தாதி உத்தியோகத்தர் சங்கத்தின் தலைவராக இருந்தார். ஒரு தொழிற்சங்கத் தலைவராக, கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்தபோது, ​​COVID-19 பொது சுகாதார அவசரநிலை முழுவதும் அவர் முக்கியமாக செயலில் இருந்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ரத்னப்ரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 02 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரத்னப்ரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}