{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/president-of-crisis-hit-sri-lanka-asks-russian-leader-putin-for-fuel-credit-97038/",
  "time_ut": 1657106460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President of crisis-hit Sri Lanka asks Russian leader Putin for fuel credit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President of crisis-hit Sri Lanka asks Russian leader Putin for fuel credit",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Wednesday called Russian leader Vladimir Putin and requested for fuel credit after a recent diplomatic spat between the two nations.",
        "“Had a very productive telecon with the Russia President, Vladimir Putin. While thanking him for all the support extended by his government to overcome the challenges of the past, I requested an offer of credit support to import fuel to Sri Lanka in defeating the current economic challenges,” President Rajapaksa tweeted.",
        "“Further, I humbly made A request to restart @Aeroflot_World operations in Sri Lanka. We unanimously agreed that strengthening bilateral relations in sectors such as tourism, trade & culture was paramount in reinforcing the friendship our two nations share.”",
        "1/2Had a very productive telecon with the #Russia President, Vladimir Putin. While thanking him for all the support extended by his gvt to overcome the challenges of the past, I requested an offer of credit support to import fuel to #lka in defeating the current econ challenges.",
        "President’s call came after Sri Lanka’s action on detaining Russian aircraft Aeroflot in Colombo early in June had angered Russia, which later has threatened to halt bilateral trade and flight services to Sri Lanka, government officials have said.",
        "Russia is one of the top buyers of Sri Lankan tea, the country’s top agricultural commodity export which fetches around $1.5 billion export revenue.",
        "Sri Lanka also has been in the process to get Russian crude oil to manage the fuel crisis in the island nation. Thousands of motorists wait in queues for weeks to obtain limited fuel stocks in Sri Lanka as it has run out of dollars to import fuel.",
        "Sri Lanka before April had 90-day and 180-day fuel credits to purchase fuel. The state-run fuel retailer Ceylon Petroleum Corporation has to pay only after the agreed grace period.",
        "However, since Sri Lanka declared sovereign debt default on April 12, many oil firms are reluctant to extend credit to Sri Lanka amid foreign banks have rejecting to be the counterpart to open letter of credit for Sri Lankan buyers.",
        "As a result, the $84.5 billion economy is forced to pay the money upfront when ordering the fuel shipments, the power and energy ministry officials say.",
        "Sri Lanka managed limited fuel stocks from a $700 million credit line from India which exhausted with the last shipment on June 16.",
        "Sri Lanka’s efforts to secure fuel credits from the Middle Eastern countries have failed as some countries have said they will help only after an IMF deal is signed.",
        "Mahindananda Aluthgamage, who is a presidential advisor now, last week said President Rajapaksa called Putin last week without giving much details.",
        "Related: Sri Lanka President calls Russia’s Putin, to visit UAE to seek fuel – Aluthgamage",
        "The Aeroflot flight was detained following a court order obtained by Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited of Ireland, the owner of the aircraft, against Aeroflot in a Colombo court, over a lease dispute.",
        "Russia has sought an assurance from the Sri Lankan government of not repeating the diplomatic spat it followed including the legal action after grounding an aircraft operated by Russia’s Aeroflot in Colombo, former president Maithripala Sirisena told the parliament this week.",
        "Related: To resume flights, Russia has sought SL assurance of not repeating Aeroflot action-Sirisena",
        "Government officials are divided on the way Aeroflot issue was handled. Some say the government should have sought diplomatic channels while others say it was a legal issue hence the way it was handled was appropriate.",
        "On 2 June 2022, the Commercial High Court of the Western Province issued an enjoining order on the Aeroflot flight restraining it from taking off from Sri Lanka’s main airport near Colombo.",
        "Later the Sri Lankan Court suspended an order preventing the Aeroflot flight from leaving Sri Lanka. The order was suspended after the Colombo Commercial High Court considered a motion filed by the Attorney General.",
        "The Airbus A330-343 operated by Russian state-owned airline Aeroflot was denied permission to fly to Moscow as scheduled on June 2nd amid a legal dispute with a leasing company. The flight had more than 200 passengers onboard. (Colombo/July 06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Putin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1/2Had",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "#",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "around $1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$84.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle Eastern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahindananda Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commercial High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Airbus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A330-343",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා රුසියානු නායක පුටින්ගෙන් ඉන්ධන ණය ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බදාදා රුසියානු නායක ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් අමතා ජාතීන් දෙක අතර මෑත කාලීන රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුමකින් පසු ඉන්ධන ණය ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“රුසියාවේ ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් සමඟ ඉතා ඵලදායී ටෙලිකොන් එකක් තිබුණා. අතීත අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා තම රජය ලබාදුන් සියලු සහයෝගයට ස්තූතිය පුද කරන අතරම වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝග පරාජය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ණය ආධාරයක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස මම ඉල්ලා සිටියෙමි.",
        "තවද, @Aeroflot_World මෙහෙයුම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නැවත ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස මම නිහතමානීව ඉල්ලීමක් කළෙමි. සංචාරක, වෙළෙඳ සහ සංස්කෘතිය වැනි අංශවල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීම අපගේ ජාතීන් දෙක අතර පවතින මිත්‍රත්වය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛ වන බවට අපි ඒකමතිකව එකඟ වූවෙමු.",
        "1/2රුසියාවේ ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් සමඟ ඉතා ඵලදායී ටෙලිකොන් එකක් තිබුණා. අතීත අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා ඔහුගේ gvt ​​ලබා දුන් සියලු සහයෝගයට ස්තූති කරන අතරම, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝග පරාජය කිරීම සඳහා # lka වෙත ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ණය ආධාරයක් ලබා දෙන ලෙස මම ඉල්ලා සිටියෙමි.",
        "ජූනි මස මුලදී රුසියානු ගුවන් යානා Aeroflot කොළඹදී රඳවා තබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගත් ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය රුසියාව කෝපයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසුව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඇමතුම පැමිණ ඇති අතර, පසුව එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳ සහ ගුවන් සේවා නතර කරන බවට තර්ජනය කර ඇති බව රජයේ නිලධාරීන් පවසයි.",
        "රුසියාව ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 ක පමණ අපනයන ආදායමක් උපයන රටේ ඉහළම කෘෂිකාර්මික භාණ්ඩ අපනයනය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා තේවල ඉහළම ගැනුම්කරුවන්ගෙන් එකකි.",
        "දිවයිනේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද රුසියානු බොරතෙල් ලබා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක යෙදී සිටී. ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ඩොලර් අවසන් වී ඇති නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සීමිත ඉන්ධන තොග ලබාගැනීමට දහස් ගණන් වාහන හිමියන් සති ගණන් පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටිති.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අප්‍රේල් මාසයට පෙර ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා දින 90ක සහ දින 180ක ඉන්ධන බැර කිරීම් තිබුණි. රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ඉන්ධන සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දෙකු වන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට ගෙවීමට සිදුව ඇත්තේ එකඟ වූ සහන කාලයෙන් පසුවය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අප්‍රේල් 12 වන දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ස්වෛරී ණය පැහැර හැරීමක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ බැවින්, විදේශීය බැංකු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගැනුම්කරුවන් සඳහා විවෘත ණයවර ලිපියේ සහකරු වීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම මධ්‍යයේ බොහෝ තෙල් සමාගම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය ලබා දීමට මැලිකමක් දක්වයි.",
        "මේ නිසා ඩොලර් බිලියන 84.5 ක ආර්ථිකයට ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් ඇණවුම් කිරීමේදී මුදල් පෙර ගෙවීමට සිදුවී ඇති බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "ජුනි 16 දා අවසන් නැව්ගත කිරීමත් සමඟ අවසන් වූ ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 ක ණය මාර්ගයකින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සීමිත ඉන්ධන තොග කළමනාකරණය කළේය.",
        "මැදපෙරදිග රටවලින් ඉන්ධන ණය ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැරූ උත්සාහය අසාර්ථක වී ඇත්තේ සමහර රටවල් IMF ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කිරීමෙන් පසුව පමණක් උදව් කරන බව පැවසීම නිසාය.",
        "දැන් ජනාධිපති උපදේශකයෙකු ලෙස කටයුතු කරන මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ පසුගිය සතියේ කීවේ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ වැඩි විස්තර නොකියා පසුගිය සතියේ පුටින් ඇමතූ බවයි.",
        "ආශ්‍රිත: ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීම සඳහා එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති රුසියාවේ පුටින්ට කතා කරයි - අලුත්ගමගේ",
        "Aeroflot ගුවන් යානය රඳවා ගනු ලැබුවේ බදු ආරවුලක් මත Aeroflot සමාගමට එරෙහිව Aeroflot සමාගමට එරෙහිව ගුවන් යානයේ හිමිකරු වන Ireland හි Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited විසින් ලබාගත් අධිකරණ නියෝගයකට අනුවය.",
        "රුසියාවේ Aeroflot විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද ගුවන් යානයක් කොළඹට ගොඩබෑමෙන් පසු නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ඇතුළුව තමන් අනුගමනය කළ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුම නැවත සිදු නොකිරීමට රුසියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් සහතිකයක් ඉල්ලා ඇති බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා මේ සතියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "ආශ්‍රිත: ගුවන් ගමන් නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා රුසියාව Aeroflot ක්‍රියාව නැවත සිදු නොකරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහතිකය ඉල්ලා ඇත-සිරිසේන",
        "Aeroflot ප්‍රශ්නය හසුරුවන ආකාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ නිලධාරීන් බෙදී ඇත. ඇතැමුන් පවසන්නේ රජය රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මාර්ග සොයා යා යුතුව තිබූ බවයි. තවත් සමහරු පවසන්නේ එය නීතිමය ප්‍රශ්නයක් බැවින් එය හසුරුවන ආකාරය සුදුසු බවයි.",
        "2022 ජූනි 2 වැනි දින බස්නාහිර පළාතේ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය විසින් Aeroflot ගුවන් යානය කොළඹට ආසන්න ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් ගුවන්ගත වීම වළක්වමින් වාරණ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "පසුව Aeroflot ගුවන් යානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටවීම වළක්වාලමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය විසින් නිකුත් කර තිබූ නියෝගය අත්හිටුවනු ලැබුවා. කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය විසින් නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් ගොනු කරන ලද මෝසමක් සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව එම නියෝගය අත්හිටුවා ඇත.",
        "රුසියානු රජය සතු ගුවන් සමාගමක් වන Aeroflot විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලබන එයාර්බස් A330-343 ලීසිං සමාගමක් සමඟ ඇති වූ නීතිමය ආරවුලක් මධ්‍යයේ ජුනි 2 වැනිදා නියමිත පරිදි මොස්කව් වෙත පියාසර කිරීමට අවසර ලබා නොදෙන ලදී. ගුවන් යානයේ මගීන් 200 කට වැඩි පිරිසක් සිටියහ. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "පුටින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1/2 තිබුනා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": null,
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 180",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 84.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 ජූනි 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එයාර් බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A330-343",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 2 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கியுள்ள இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி ரஷ்ய தலைவர் புட்டினிடம் எரிபொருள் கடன் கேட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச புதன்கிழமை ரஷ்ய தலைவர் விளாடிமிர் புட்டினை அழைத்து, இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையில் சமீபத்தில் இராஜதந்திர சண்டையின் பின்னர் எரிபொருள் கடன் கோரினார்.",
        "\"ரஷ்யா ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடினுடன் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள தொலைத்தொடர்பு இருந்தது. கடந்த கால சவால்களை முறியடிக்க அவரது அரசாங்கம் வழங்கிய அனைத்து ஆதரவிற்கும் நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சவால்களை தோற்கடிப்பதற்காக இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு கடன் உதவியை வழங்குமாறு நான் கோரினேன், ”என்று ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "“மேலும், இலங்கையில் @Aeroflot_World செயற்பாடுகளை மீண்டும் ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு பணிவுடன் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தேன். சுற்றுலா, வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம் போன்ற துறைகளில் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது நமது இரு நாடுகளும் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ளும் நட்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதில் மிக முக்கியமானது என்பதை நாங்கள் ஒருமனதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டோம்.",
        "1/2 #ரஷ்யா ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடினுடன் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள தொலைத்தொடர்பு இருந்தது. கடந்த கால சவால்களை சமாளிக்க அவரது gvt வழங்கிய அனைத்து ஆதரவிற்கும் நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சவால்களை தோற்கடிப்பதற்காக #lka க்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய கடன் ஆதரவை கோரினேன்.",
        "ஜூன் மாத தொடக்கத்தில் கொழும்பில் ரஷ்ய விமானமான ஏரோஃப்ளோட்டை தடுத்து வைத்த இலங்கையின் நடவடிக்கை ரஷ்யாவை கோபப்படுத்தியதை அடுத்து ஜனாதிபதியின் அழைப்பு வந்தது, பின்னர் இலங்கைக்கான இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகளை நிறுத்த அச்சுறுத்தியது என்று அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "1.5 பில்லியன் டாலர் ஏற்றுமதி வருவாயைப் பெறுகின்ற நாட்டின் முதன்மையான விவசாயப் பொருட்களின் ஏற்றுமதியான இலங்கை தேயிலையை அதிகம் வாங்குபவர்களில் ரஷ்யாவும் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "தீவு நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை நிர்வகிப்பதற்கு ரஷ்யாவின் கச்சா எண்ணெயை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் நடவடிக்கையில் இலங்கையும் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது. இலங்கையில் எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான டொலர்கள் தீர்ந்துள்ளதால், மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் இருப்புக்களை பெற ஆயிரக்கணக்கான வாகன சாரதிகள் வாரக்கணக்கில் வரிசையில் காத்திருக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஏப்ரல் மாதத்திற்கு முன்னர் எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு 90 நாட்கள் மற்றும் 180 நாட்கள் எரிபொருள் கடன்கள் இருந்தன. அரசாங்கத்தால் நடத்தப்படும் எரிபொருள் சில்லறை விற்பனையாளரான இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் ஒப்புக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சலுகைக் காலத்திற்குப் பின்னரே செலுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இலங்கை ஏப்ரல் 12 அன்று இறையாண்மைக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாததாக அறிவித்ததிலிருந்து, பல எண்ணெய் நிறுவனங்கள் இலங்கைக்கு கடன் வழங்கத் தயங்குகின்றன, ஏனெனில் வெளிநாட்டு வங்கிகள் இலங்கை வாங்குபவர்களுக்கு கடன் கடிதத்தைத் திறக்க மறுத்துள்ளன.",
        "இதன் விளைவாக, 84.5 பில்லியன் டாலர் பொருளாதாரம் எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதிகளை ஆர்டர் செய்யும் போது பணத்தை முன்கூட்டியே செலுத்த வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் உள்ளது என்று மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சக அதிகாரிகள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "ஜூன் 16 அன்று கடைசியாக ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட்ட இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 700 மில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் வரியிலிருந்து இலங்கை மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் பங்குகளை நிர்வகித்தது.",
        "IMF ஒப்பந்தம் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்ட பின்னரே உதவுவோம் என சில நாடுகள் கூறியுள்ளதால், மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் வரவுகளைப் பெறுவதற்கான இலங்கையின் முயற்சிகள் தோல்வியடைந்துள்ளன.",
        "இப்போது ஜனாதிபதியின் ஆலோசகராக இருக்கும் மஹிந்தானந்த அலுத்கமகே, கடந்த வாரம் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ, கடந்த வாரம் புட்டினுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "தொடர்புடையது: எரிபொருளைத் தேடுவதற்காக ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸுக்கு விஜயம் செய்யுமாறு ரஷ்யாவின் புட்டினுக்கு இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி அழைப்பு – அலுத்கமகே",
        "விமானத்தின் உரிமையாளரான அயர்லாந்தின் செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் 10 லிமிடெட், ஏரோஃப்ளோட் நிறுவனத்திற்கு எதிராக, குத்தகை தகராறு தொடர்பாக, ஏரோஃப்ளோட் நிறுவனத்தால் பெறப்பட்ட நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை அடுத்து, ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கொழும்பில் ரஷ்யாவின் ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்தை தரையிறக்கிய பின்னர் சட்ட நடவடிக்கை உட்பட, தான் பின்பற்றிய இராஜதந்திர தகராறுகளை மீண்டும் செய்யக்கூடாது என்ற உத்தரவாதத்தை இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திடம் ரஷ்யா கோரியுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன இந்த வாரம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தொடர்புடையது: விமானங்களை மீண்டும் தொடங்க, ஏரோஃப்ளோட் நடவடிக்கையை மீண்டும் செய்ய மாட்டோம் என்று ரஷ்யா SL உத்தரவாதத்தை நாடியுள்ளது-சிறிசேன",
        "ஏரோஃப்ளாட் விவகாரம் கையாளப்பட்ட விதத்தில் அரசு அதிகாரிகள் பிளவுபட்டுள்ளனர். அரசாங்கம் இராஜதந்திர வழிகளை நாடியிருக்க வேண்டும் என்று சிலர் கூறுகின்றனர், மற்றவர்கள் இது ஒரு சட்டப் பிரச்சினை, எனவே அதைக் கையாண்ட விதம் பொருத்தமானது என்று கூறுகிறார்கள்.",
        "2 ஜூன் 2022 அன்று, மேல் மாகாணத்தின் வர்த்தக உயர் நீதிமன்றம், கொழும்புக்கு அருகிலுள்ள இலங்கையின் முக்கிய விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து புறப்படுவதைத் தடைசெய்து ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்திற்கு தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்தது.",
        "பின்னர் இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம் ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேற தடை விதித்தது. சட்டமா அதிபரினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவை கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்றம் பரிசீலித்ததை அடுத்து இந்த உத்தரவு இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரஷ்ய அரசுக்குச் சொந்தமான ஏரோஃப்ளோட் மூலம் இயக்கப்படும் ஏர்பஸ் ஏ330-343 லீசிங் நிறுவனத்துடனான சட்டப் பிரச்சனையின் காரணமாக ஜூன் 2ஆம் தேதி திட்டமிடப்பட்டபடி மாஸ்கோவிற்குப் பறக்க அனுமதி மறுக்கப்பட்டது. அந்த விமானத்தில் 200க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பயணிகள் இருந்தனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "புடின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1/2 இருந்தது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": null,
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $1.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$84.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏர்பஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A330-343",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}