{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/21/concealed-stocks-of-eggs-will-be-confiscated/",
  "time_ut": 1661083080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Concealed stocks of eggs will be confiscated",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Concealed stocks of eggs will be confiscated",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Trade and Consumer Protection says that measures will be taken to confiscate stocks of eggs by egg producers who conceal stocks to drive up market prices.",
        "Minister of Trade, Commerce and Food Security, Nalin Fernando said that the raids related to eggs being sold above the control price and illegal stockpiling will start from tomorrow (22).",
        "A maximum retail price of Rs 43/- was imposed for a white egg with effect from midnight yesterday (20).",
        "The maximum retail price of a brown and red eggs is Rs. 45/-.",
        "Sri Lanka: CID probes student Activists for anti govt conspiracy",
        "Do not sign detention order – UN Rapporteur calls on President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Trade and Consumer Protection",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trade, Commerce and Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "midnight yesterday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සඟවා ඇති බිත්තර තොග රාජසන්තක කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වෙළෙඳපොළ මිල ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා බිත්තර තොග සඟවා තබන බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදකයින් විසින් බිත්තර තොග රාජසන්තක කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන බව වෙළෙඳ හා පාරිභෝගික ආරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "පාලන මිලට වඩා බිත්තර අලෙවි කිරීම සහ නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස බිත්තර තොග ගබඩා කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැටලීම් හෙට (22) සිට ආරම්භ කරන බව වෙළඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඊයේ (20) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි සුදු බිත්තරයක් සඳහා රුපියල් 43/- ක උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලක් පනවා තිබේ.",
        "දුඹුරු සහ රතු බිත්තරයක උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල රු. 45/-කි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් CID ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විමර්ශනය කරයි",
        "රැඳවුම් නියෝගයට අත්සන් කරන්න එපා - එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ වාර්තාකරු ජනපතිගෙන් ඉල්ලයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳ හා පාරිභෝගික ආරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳ, වාණිජ සහ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்ட முட்டைகள் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சந்தை விலையை உயர்த்தும் வகையில் முட்டைகளை மறைத்து வைக்கும் முட்டை உற்பத்தியாளர்களிடம் இருந்து முட்டைகளை பறிமுதல் செய்ய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என வர்த்தக மற்றும் நுகர்வோர் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கட்டுப்பாட்டு விலைக்கு மேல் முட்டை விற்பனை மற்றும் சட்டவிரோத கையிருப்பு தொடர்பான சோதனைகள் நாளை (22) முதல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் என வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று (20) நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் வெள்ளை முட்டை ஒன்றின் அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை 43 ரூபாவாக நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு பழுப்பு மற்றும் சிவப்பு முட்டையின் அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை ரூ. 45/-.",
        "இலங்கை: அரசுக்கு எதிரான சதிக்காக மாணவர் ஆர்வலர்களிடம் CID விசாரணை",
        "தடுப்புக் காவலில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம் - ஐ.நா அறிக்கையாளர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அழைப்பு"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் நுகர்வோர் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம், வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}