{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/3000-bakeries-shut-down-in-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1656055020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "3,000 bakeries shut down in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "3,000 bakeries shut down in Sri Lanka",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association said that the prices of raw materials used in bakery products have increased by over 300%",
        "The Chairman of All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association N.K Jayawardana said that the price of a 50kg of wheat flour pack had risen by Rs.1000/- last week and the price of a pack of wheat flour had gone up to Rs. 14,000.",
        "He also said that nearly 3,000 bakeries have been shut down so far.",
        "In addition, Jayawardena said that Minister Kanchana Wijesekera was requested to provide immediate solutions to the shortage of diesel and petrol.",
        "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 300%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association N.K Jayawardana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.1000/-",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nearly 3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private Sector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බේකරි 3000ක් වසා දමයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බේකරි නිෂ්පාදන සඳහා භාවිත කරන අමුද්‍රව්‍යවල මිල 300% කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති එන්.කේ ජයවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ පසුගිය සතියේ තිරිඟු පිටි කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50ක මිළක් රුපියල් 1000/-කින් ඉහළ ගිය බවත් තිරිඟු පිටි පැකට්ටුවක මිල රු. 14,000 කි.",
        "මේ වන විට බේකරි 3000කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් වසා දමා ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මීට අමතරව ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් හිඟයට කඩිනම් විසඳුම් ලබාදෙන ලෙස අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බවද ජයවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ වැඩ කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය අංශයට වසර 5ක වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ද?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "300% කට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය N.K ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.1000/-",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் 3,000 பேக்கரிகள் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பேக்கரி உற்பத்திகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் மூலப்பொருட்களின் விலை 300% இற்கும் மேலாக அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் 50 கிலோகிராம் கோதுமை மா பொதி ஒன்றின் விலை 1000 ரூபாவினால் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகவும், கோதுமை மா பொதி ஒன்றின் விலை 100 ரூபாவாகவும் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் என்.கே ஜயவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். 14,000.",
        "இதுவரை கிட்டத்தட்ட 3,000 பேக்கரிகள் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளன என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோல் தட்டுப்பாடுக்கு உடனடி தீர்வுகளை வழங்குமாறு அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகரவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜயவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "தனியார் துறையில் பணிபுரிய பொதுத்துறைக்கு 5 ஆண்டு ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "300%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் என்.கே ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.1000/-",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "3,000 bakeries shut down in Sri Lanka",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); The All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association said that the prices of raw materials used in bakery products have increased by over 300%",
    "The Chairman of All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association N.K Jayawardana said that the price of a 50kg of wheat flour pack had risen by Rs.1000/- last week and the price of a pack of wheat flour had gone up to Rs. 14,000.",
    "He also said that nearly 3,000 bakeries have been shut down so far.",
    "In addition, Jayawardena said that Minister Kanchana Wijesekera was requested to provide immediate solutions to the shortage of diesel and petrol.",
    "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "3,000 bakeries shut down in Sri Lanka",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association said that the prices of raw materials used in bakery products have increased by over 300%",
        "The Chairman of All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association N.K Jayawardana said that the price of a 50kg of wheat flour pack had risen by Rs.1000/- last week and the price of a pack of wheat flour had gone up to Rs. 14,000.",
        "He also said that nearly 3,000 bakeries have been shut down so far.",
        "In addition, Jayawardena said that Minister Kanchana Wijesekera was requested to provide immediate solutions to the shortage of diesel and petrol.",
        "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 300%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "All Ceylon Bakery Owners Association N.K Jayawardana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.1000/-",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nearly 3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private Sector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බේකරි 3000ක් වසා දමයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බේකරි නිෂ්පාදන සඳහා භාවිත කරන අමුද්‍රව්‍යවල මිල 300% කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති එන්.කේ ජයවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ පසුගිය සතියේ තිරිඟු පිටි කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50ක මිළක් රුපියල් 1000/-කින් ඉහළ ගිය බවත් තිරිඟු පිටි පැකට්ටුවක මිල රු. 14,000 කි.",
        "මේ වන විට බේකරි 3000කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් වසා දමා ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මීට අමතරව ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් හිඟයට කඩිනම් විසඳුම් ලබාදෙන ලෙස අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බවද ජයවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ වැඩ කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය අංශයට වසර 5ක වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ද?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "300% කට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය N.K ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.1000/-",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் 3,000 பேக்கரிகள் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பேக்கரி உற்பத்திகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் மூலப்பொருட்களின் விலை 300% இற்கும் மேலாக அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் 50 கிலோகிராம் கோதுமை மா பொதி ஒன்றின் விலை 1000 ரூபாவினால் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகவும், கோதுமை மா பொதி ஒன்றின் விலை 100 ரூபாவாகவும் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் என்.கே ஜயவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். 14,000.",
        "இதுவரை கிட்டத்தட்ட 3,000 பேக்கரிகள் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளன என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோல் தட்டுப்பாடுக்கு உடனடி தீர்வுகளை வழங்குமாறு அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகரவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜயவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "தனியார் துறையில் பணிபுரிய பொதுத்துறைக்கு 5 ஆண்டு ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "300%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் என்.கே ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.1000/-",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}