{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/CMA-signs-MoU-with-SLASSCOM-to-build-knowledge-economy/34-739226",
  "time_ut": 1661730950,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CMA signs MoU with SLASSCOM to build knowledge economy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CMA signs MoU with SLASSCOM to build knowledge economy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "CMA Sri Lanka President Prof. Lakshman R. Watawala presents the MoU to SLASSCOM Chairman Ashique M. Ali in Colombo on 16 August in the presence of Jehan Perimpanayagam, Shanaka Fernando, Chaminda de Silva and Eranga Wijayasinghe representing SLASSCOM Board and Management, and Kosala Dissanayake, Sumudu Pagoda and Jinandi Chandrarathne representing CMA Sri Lanka",
        "The Institute of Certified Management Accounts of Sri Lanka (CMA) has signed an MoU with the Sri Lanka Association for Software Services Companies (SLASSCOM) to promote ICT and knowledge economy in the training of ICT and accounting professionals.",
        "The signing of this MoU will enable collaboration between member companies of SLASSCOM such as BPO and ICT companies with CMA Sri Lanka to train professionals required for these industrial sectors. This will set out the respective roles and responsibilities of the parties in working cooperatively to further each other’s objectives for their mutual interests.",
        "Furthermore, one of the main focuses will be regional expansion creating focused industry-specific training and awareness of the global potential of the IT-BPM industry. Moreover, according to this agreement, both parties will work together to provide access to CMA professional e-based learning resources, training and development initiatives combined with job opportunities.",
        "In addition to that, it is also to explore and create new pathways for students to further their education and enhance their careers in IT-BPM and BPM a major foreign exchange earner to Sri Lanka.",
        "Through this mutual agreement, both organisations will explore other potential areas where cooperation would be of mutual benefit."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLASSCOM",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Watawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashique M. Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Perimpanayagam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanaka Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Wijayasinghe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kosala Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumudu Pagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jinandi Chandrarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Institute of Certified Management Accounts of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Association for Software Services Companies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දැනුම ආර්ථිකය ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා CMA SLASSCOM සමඟ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "CMA ශ්‍රී ලංකා සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ලක්ෂ්මන් ආර්. වටවල විසින් SLASSCOM සභාපති Ashique M. Ali වෙත SLASSCOM මණ්ඩලය සහ කළමනාකාරිත්වය නියෝජනය කරමින් ජෙහාන් පෙරිම්පනායගම්, ශානක ප්‍රනාන්දු, චමින්ද ද සිල්වා සහ එරංග විජයසිංහ සහ කෝසල දිසානායක යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් ඉදිරියේ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම අගෝස්තු 16 වන දින කොළඹදී පිළිගන්වන ලදී. , CMA Sri Lanka නියෝජනය කරමින් සුමුදු පාගොඩ සහ ජිනන්දි චන්ද්‍රරත්න",
        "ICT සහ ගිණුම්කරණ වෘත්තිකයන් පුහුණු කිරීමේදී ICT සහ දැනුම ආර්ථිකය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහතික කළ කළමනාකරණ ගිණුම් ආයතනය (CMA) ශ්‍රී ලංකා මෘදුකාංග සේවා සමාගම් සඳහා වූ සංගමය (SLASSCOM) සමඟ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුම අත්සන් කිරීම මඟින් මෙම කාර්මික අංශ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය වෘත්තිකයන් පුහුණු කිරීම සඳහා SLASSCOM හි සාමාජික සමාගම් වන BPO සහ ICT සමාගම් අතර සහයෝගීතාවය CMA Sri Lanka සමඟ ඇති කර ගැනීමට හැකි වේ. මෙය ඔවුන්ගේ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා එකිනෙකාගේ අරමුණු ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට සහයෝගීව කටයුතු කිරීමේදී පාර්ශවයන්ගේ අදාළ භූමිකාවන් සහ වගකීම් සකසනු ඇත.",
        "තවද, IT-BPM කර්මාන්තයේ ගෝලීය විභවයන් පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරන ලද කර්මාන්තයට විශේෂිත පුහුණුවක් සහ දැනුවත් කිරීමක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම කලාපීය ව්‍යාප්තිය ප්‍රධාන අවධානයට ලක් වේ. එපමණක් නොව, මෙම ගිවිසුමට අනුව, CMA වෘත්තීය විද්‍යුත් පාදක ඉගෙනුම් සම්පත්, රැකියා අවස්ථා සමඟ ඒකාබද්ධ වූ පුහුණු සහ සංවර්ධන මුලපිරීම් සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය ලබා දීමට දෙපාර්ශවයම එක්ව කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "ඊට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රධාන විදේශ විනිමය උපයා දෙන තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ-BPM සහ BPM තුළ සිසුන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ අධ්‍යාපනය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ වෘත්තීන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට නව මංපෙත් ගවේෂණය කිරීම සහ නිර්මාණය කිරීම ද වේ.",
        "මෙම අන්‍යෝන්‍ය ගිවිසුම හරහා, ආයතන දෙකම සහයෝගීතාවය අන්‍යෝන්‍ය වශයෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන ගත හැකි වෙනත් විභව ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගවේෂණය කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLASSCOM",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වටවල ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashique M. අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් පෙරිම්පනායගම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශානක ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරංග විජයසිංහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝසල දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමුදු පාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනන්දි චන්ද්‍රරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහතික කළ කළමනාකරණ ගිණුම් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෘදුකාංග සේවා සමාගම් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அறிவுப் பொருளாதாரத்தை உருவாக்குவதற்கு SLASSCOM உடன் CMA புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிஎம்ஏ ஸ்ரீலங்காவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் லக்ஷ்மன் ஆர். வட்டவல SLASSCOM தலைவர் ஆஷிக் எம். அலியிடம் ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று கொழும்பில் ஜெஹான் பேரிம்பநாயகம், ஷானக பெர்னாண்டோ, சமிந்த டி சில்வா மற்றும் எரங்க விஜயசிங்க ஆகியோர் முன்னிலையில் SLASSCOM வாரியம் மற்றும் நிர்வாகத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி, கோசலா திசாநாயக்க ஆகியோருக்கு புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தை வழங்கினார். , சுமுது பகோடா மற்றும் ஜினாந்தி சந்திரரத்னே ஆகியோர் CMA இலங்கையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகின்றனர்",
        "இலங்கையின் சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட முகாமைத்துவ கணக்குகள் நிறுவனம் (CMA) ICT மற்றும் கணக்கியல் நிபுணர்களின் பயிற்சியில் ICT மற்றும் அறிவு பொருளாதாரத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக இலங்கை மென்பொருள் சேவை நிறுவனங்களுக்கான சங்கத்துடன் (SLASSCOM) புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம் கையெழுத்தானது, SLASSCOM இன் அங்கத்துவ நிறுவனங்களான BPO மற்றும் ICT நிறுவனங்களுக்கு இடையே CMA ஸ்ரீலங்காவுடன் இணைந்து இந்த தொழில்துறை துறைகளுக்கு தேவையான நிபுணர்களுக்கு பயிற்சி அளிக்க உதவும். இது அவர்களின் பரஸ்பர நலன்களுக்காக ஒருவரையொருவர் நோக்கங்களை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு ஒத்துழைப்பதில் கட்சிகளின் அந்தந்த பாத்திரங்கள் மற்றும் பொறுப்புகளை அமைக்கும்.",
        "மேலும், முக்கிய கவனம் செலுத்துவது பிராந்திய விரிவாக்கம், கவனம் செலுத்தும் தொழில் சார்ந்த பயிற்சி மற்றும் IT-BPM தொழில்துறையின் உலகளாவிய திறன் பற்றிய விழிப்புணர்வை உருவாக்கும். மேலும், இந்த ஒப்பந்தத்தின்படி, CMA தொழில்முறை மின்-அடிப்படையிலான கற்றல் வளங்கள், வேலை வாய்ப்புகளுடன் இணைந்து பயிற்சி மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு முயற்சிகளை அணுகுவதற்கு இரு தரப்பினரும் இணைந்து செயல்படுவார்கள்.",
        "அதுமட்டுமல்லாமல், இலங்கைக்கு அந்நிய செலாவணியை ஈட்டித்தரும் முக்கிய நிறுவனமான IT-BPM மற்றும் BPM ஆகியவற்றில் மாணவர்களின் கல்வியை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான புதிய பாதைகளை ஆராய்ந்து உருவாக்குவதும் ஆகும்.",
        "இந்த பரஸ்பர உடன்படிக்கையின் மூலம், இரு நிறுவனங்களும் பரஸ்பர நன்மை பயக்கும் மற்ற சாத்தியமான பகுதிகளை ஆராயும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLASSCOM",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.வடவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஷிக் எம். அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் பேரிம்பநாயகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷனக பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரங்க விஜயசிங்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோசல திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமுது பகோடா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜினாந்தி சந்திரரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட முகாமைத்துவ கணக்குகள் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மென்பொருள் சேவை நிறுவனங்களுக்கான இலங்கை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிஓ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎம்ஏ இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}