{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/ministry-clarifies-on-public-sector-retirement-age/",
  "time_ut": 1662100320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ministry clarifies on public sector retirement age",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ministry clarifies on public sector retirement age",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils, and Local Government says the decision to lower the retirement age to 60 years will NOT apply to selected essential professions.",
        "Ministry Secretary, M.M.P.K. Mayadunne says the 60-year retirement age will NOT apply to professions such as medicine, nursing, and engineering.",
        "He said new amendments will be presented to the Cabinet to raise the retirement age of such professions to 63 years.",
        "He said that for other sectors in the Public Service, all those over the age of 60 years will be sent on retirement with effect from the 31st of December 2022, and the respective circular will be issued within two weeks.",
        "Accordingly, over 20,000 employees in Public Services will be sent on retirement by the end of 2022.",
        "The Interim Budget by President Ranil Wickremesinghe proposed to reduce the retirement age of public sector and semi-governmental employees to 60 years.",
        "Earlier, the government decided to raise the mandatory retirement age of public sector employees to 65 years and that of semi-governmental employees to 62 years.",
        "Those who have been employed beyond 60 years of age at present in the government and semi-government sectors will be retired as of 31.12.2022.",
        "Promptly Resolve Fuel, Gas and Paddy Issues – Senior Advisor to the President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "age to 60 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "M.M.P.K. Mayadunne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 60 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 31st of December 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.12.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ විශ්‍රාම වයස පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍යාංශය පැහැදිලි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසන්නේ විශ්‍රාම යන වයස අවුරුදු 60 දක්වා අඩු කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය තෝරාගත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වෘත්තීන් සඳහා අදාළ නොවන බවයි.",
        "අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්, එම්.එම්.පී.කේ. වෛද්‍ය, හෙද සහ ඉංජිනේරු වැනි වෘත්තීන් සඳහා අවුරුදු 60 විශ්‍රාම යන වයස අදාළ නොවන බව මායාදුන්නේ පවසයි.",
        "එවැනි වෘත්තීන්හි විශ්‍රාම යන වයස අවුරුදු 63 දක්වා ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා නව සංශෝධන කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රාජ්‍ය සේවයේ අනෙකුත් අංශ සඳහා 2022 දෙසැම්බර් 31 වැනි දින සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි වයස අවුරුදු 60 ට වැඩි සියලුම දෙනා විශ්‍රාම ගැන්වීමට කටයුතු කරන බවත් අදාළ චක්‍රලේඛය සති දෙකක් ඇතුළත නිකුත් කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව 2022 වසර අවසන් වන විට රාජ්‍ය සේවයේ 20,000කට අධික සේවක පිරිසක් විශ්‍රාම යාමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතුරු අයවැයෙන් රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සහ අර්ධ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ගේ විශ්‍රාම යන වයස අවුරුදු 60 දක්වා අඩු කිරීමට යෝජනා කර ඇත.",
        "රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයන්ගේ අනිවාර්ය විශ්‍රාම වයස අවුරුදු 65 දක්වාත් අර්ධ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ගේ විශ්‍රාම වයස අවුරුදු 62 දක්වාත් ඉහළ නැංවීමට රජය මීට පෙර තීරණය කළේය.",
        "දැනට රාජ්‍ය සහ අර්ධ රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ වයස අවුරුදු 60 ට වැඩි රැකියාවල නිරත වූවන් 2022.12.31 දිනට විශ්‍රාම ගනු ඇත.",
        "ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් සහ කුඹුරු ගැටලු කඩිනමින් විසඳන්න – ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 60 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්.එම්.පී.කේ. මායාදුන්නේ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 60ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 63 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 60 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 දෙසැම්බර් 31 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 60 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 65 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 62 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 60 කි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.12.31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுத்துறை ஓய்வு வயது குறித்து அமைச்சகம் தெளிவுபடுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சு, ஓய்வுபெறும் வயதை 60 ஆகக் குறைக்கும் தீர்மானம், தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட அத்தியாவசியத் தொழில்களுக்குப் பொருந்தாது என்று கூறுகிறது.",
        "அமைச்சக செயலாளர், ம.ம.பொ.க. மருத்துவம், செவிலியர் மற்றும் பொறியியல் போன்ற தொழில்களுக்கு 60 வயது ஓய்வு வயது பொருந்தாது என்று மாயாதுன்னே கூறுகிறார்.",
        "அத்தகைய தொழில்களின் ஓய்வு வயதை 63 ஆக உயர்த்த புதிய திருத்தங்கள் அமைச்சரவையில் முன்வைக்கப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "பொதுச் சேவையில் உள்ள பிற துறைகளுக்கு, 60 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட அனைவரும் 2022 டிசம்பர் 31 முதல் ஓய்வு பெறுவதற்கு அனுப்பப்படுவார்கள் என்றும், அந்தந்த சுற்றறிக்கை இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் வெளியிடப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அதன்படி, 2022ஆம் ஆண்டு இறுதிக்குள் பொதுச் சேவைகளில் 20,000க்கும் மேற்பட்ட ஊழியர்கள் ஓய்வு பெறுவார்கள்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் அரச மற்றும் அரை அரச ஊழியர்களின் ஓய்வு வயதை 60 ஆகக் குறைக்க முன்மொழியப்பட்டது.",
        "முன்னதாக, பொதுத்துறை ஊழியர்களின் கட்டாய ஓய்வு வயதை 65 ஆகவும், அரை அரசு ஊழியர்களின் கட்டாய ஓய்வு வயதை 62 ஆகவும் உயர்த்த அரசு முடிவு செய்தது.",
        "தற்போது 60 வயதுக்கு மேல் அரசு மற்றும் அரை அரசுத் துறைகளில் பணிபுரிந்து வருபவர்கள் 31.12.2022 அன்று ஓய்வு பெறுவார்கள்.",
        "எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு மற்றும் நெல் பிரச்சினைகளை உடனடியாக தீர்க்கவும் – ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்ளூர் அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயது முதல் 60 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ம.ம.பொ.க. மாயாதுன்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 31, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.12.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}