{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83971/spain-reports-first-monkeypox-related-death-in-europe",
  "time_ut": 1659150240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Spain reports first monkeypox-related death in Europe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Spain reports first monkeypox-related death in Europe",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Spain has reported what is thought to be Europe’s first monkeypox-related death in the current outbreak of the disease.",
        "Brazil reported earlier on Friday the first monkeypox-related death outside Africa in the current wave.",
        "According to a World Health Organization report from 22 July, only five deaths had been reported worldwide, all in Africa.",
        "The WHO last Saturday declared the rapidly spreading outbreak a global health emergency, its highest level of alert.",
        "In its latest report, the Spanish health ministry said 4,298 cases had been confirmed in the country, only 64 of these were women.",
        "Of the 3,750 patients it had information on, it said 120 had been hospitalised and one had died.",
        "A spokesperson for Spain’s health ministry declined to give further details on the deceased person.",
        "The Brazilian victim was a 41-year-old man who, according to the health ministry, also suffered from lymphoma and a weakened immune system.",
        "It added that the patient was hospitalised in the southeastern city of Belo Horizonte and died from septic shock after being taken to the intensive care unit."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Spain",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Europe",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Spain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Brazil",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier on",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "only five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spanish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,298",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,750",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "health ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Brazilian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "41-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the health ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Belo Horizonte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වඳුරු උවදුර හේතුවෙන් යුරෝපයේ පළමු මරණය ස්පාඤ්ඤයෙන් වාර්තා වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ස්පාඤ්ඤය වඳුරු උවදුර හේතුවෙන් යුරෝපයේ ප්‍රථම මරණය ලෙස සැලකෙන වත්මන් රෝගය පැතිර යාමේ සිද්ධිය වාර්තා කර ඇත.",
        "වත්මන් රැල්ල තුළ අප්‍රිකාවෙන් පිටත වඳුරු උවදුරට සම්බන්ධ පළමු මරණය බ්‍රසීලය සිකුරාදා වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ජූලි 22 සිට ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ වාර්තාවකට අනුව, ලොව පුරා මරණ පහක් පමණක් වාර්තා වී ඇති අතර, සියල්ල අප්‍රිකාවෙන්.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය පසුගිය සෙනසුරාදා සීඝ්‍රයෙන් පැතිර යන වසංගතය ගෝලීය සෞඛ්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථාවක් ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය, එය එහි ඉහළම මට්ටමේ අනතුරු ඇඟවීමකි.",
        "එහි නවතම වාර්තාවේ ස්පාඤ්ඤ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය පැවසුවේ රට තුළ රෝගීන් 4,298 ක් තහවුරු වී ඇති අතර ඉන් 64 ක් පමණක් කාන්තාවන් බවයි.",
        "එහි තොරතුරු ඇති රෝගීන් 3,750 න් 120 ක් රෝහල් ගත කර ඇති අතර එක් අයෙකු මිය ගොස් ඇති බව එහි සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු මියගිය පුද්ගලයා පිළිබඳ වැඩිදුර තොරතුරු ලබා දීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයට අනුව, බ්‍රසීලියානු වින්දිතයා 41 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකි, ඔහු ලිම්ෆෝමාවෙන් ද දුර්වල ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණ පද්ධතියකින් ද පීඩා විඳිති.",
        "ගිනිකොනදිග නගරයක් වන Belo Horizonte හි රෝගියා රෝහල් ගත කර ඇති අතර දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයට ගෙන යාමෙන් පසු සෙප්ටික් කම්පනයෙන් මිය ගිය බව එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "යුරෝපය",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,298 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,750 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "41 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Belo Horizonte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐரோப்பாவில் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட முதல் மரணம் ஸ்பெயினில் பதிவாகியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்பெயின், தற்போது குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள ஐரோப்பாவின் முதல் மரணம் என்று கருதப்படுவதைப் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய அலையில் ஆப்பிரிக்காவுக்கு வெளியே குரங்குப்பழம் தொடர்பான முதல் மரணத்தை பிரேசில் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை முன்னதாக அறிவித்தது.",
        "ஜூலை 22 முதல் உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் அறிக்கையின்படி, உலகம் முழுவதும் ஐந்து இறப்புகள் மட்டுமே பதிவாகியுள்ளன, அனைத்தும் ஆப்பிரிக்காவில்.",
        "கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை WHO வேகமாகப் பரவி வரும் வெடிப்பை உலகளாவிய சுகாதார அவசரநிலை என்று அறிவித்தது, அதன் மிக உயர்ந்த எச்சரிக்கை.",
        "அதன் சமீபத்திய அறிக்கையில், ஸ்பெயினின் சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் நாட்டில் 4,298 வழக்குகள் உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், அவர்களில் 64 பேர் மட்டுமே பெண்கள் என்றும் கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "3,750 நோயாளிகளில் 120 பேர் மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் ஒருவர் இறந்துவிட்டதாகவும் அது கூறியது.",
        "ஸ்பெயினின் சுகாதார அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் இறந்த நபர் குறித்த கூடுதல் விவரங்களைத் தெரிவிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டார்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பிரேசிலிய நபர் 41 வயதுடையவர், அவர் சுகாதார அமைச்சின் கூற்றுப்படி, லிம்போமா மற்றும் பலவீனமான நோயெதிர்ப்பு மண்டலத்தால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நோயாளி தென்கிழக்கு நகரமான பெலோ ஹொரிசோண்டேவில் மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார் மற்றும் தீவிர சிகிச்சை பிரிவுக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட பின்னர் செப்டிக் அதிர்ச்சியால் இறந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்பெயின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பெயின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேசில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேர்ல்ட் ஹெல்த் ஆர்கனைசேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பானிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,298",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,750",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பெயின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேசிலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "41 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Belo Horizonte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}