{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/UPDATE-GR-still-in-the-country-meets-defence-leaders/108-240856",
  "time_ut": 1657540440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UPDATE - GR still in the country, meets defence leaders",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UPDATE - GR still in the country, meets defence leaders",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is still in the country and met the tri force commanders today morning, the Daily Mirror learns.",
        "Rajapaksa who was aboard a naval vessel within the territorial waters of Sri Lanka following the July 9 protest, returned back to land today and met the tri force commanders and Chief of Defense staff in the morning.",
        "Rajapaksa will resign from the Presidency on July 13 and will leave for overseas later this week. (Jamila Husain)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "later this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jamila Husain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම - GR තවමත් රට තුළ, ආරක්ෂක නායකයින් හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තවමත් දිවයිනේ සිටින අතර අද පෙරවරුවේ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් හමුවූ බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ජූලි 9 විරෝධතාවයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුහුදු සීමාව තුළ නාවික යාත්‍රාවක නැඟී සිටි රාජපක්ෂ අද යළි ගොඩබිමට පැමිණ උදෑසන ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් සහ ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී හමුවිය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන අතර මේ සතිය අගදී විදේශ ගතවීමට නියමිතය. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතියේ පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජමිලා හුසේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதுப்பிப்பு - GR இன்னும் நாட்டில் இருக்கிறார், பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவர்களை சந்திக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்னும் நாட்டில் இருப்பதாகவும், இன்று காலை முப்படைத் தளபதிகளை சந்தித்ததாகவும் டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 9 போராட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து இலங்கையின் கடல் எல்லைக்குள் கடற்படைக் கப்பலில் இருந்த ராஜபக்சே, இன்று மீண்டும் தரையிறங்கி, முப்படைத் தளபதிகள் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தளபதிகளை காலையில் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 13-ம் தேதி அதிபர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்யும் ராஜபக்சே, இந்த வார இறுதியில் வெளிநாடு செல்வார். (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜமீலா ஹுசைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}