{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ත්‍රස්තවාදය-වැළැක්වීමේ-පනතට-මුවාවී-ගෙනයන-මර්දනයට-එරෙහිව-ජිනීවා-යනවා/1-618643",
  "time_ut": 1661266588,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනතට මුවාවී ගෙනයන මර්දනයට එරෙහිව ජිනීවා යනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Geneva is going against the crackdown under the guise of the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ceylon Teachers Association said that measures are being taken to make the suppression of people's opposition using the Prevention of Terrorism Act a major issue at the 51st Geneva Human Rights Conference to be held in September. General Secretary Joseph Stalin said today (23).",
        "Mr. Stalin said this at the special press conference held yesterday at Maradana Social and Peace Center organized by the Inter-University Student Council.",
        "Mr. Mujibar Rahman, Member of Parliament of the Sami People's Force, said at the press conference that Mr. Ranil Wickremesinghe is using the Prevention of Terrorism Act to control the current popular uprising and that shows the duplicity of Mr. Wickremesinghe.",
        "The press conference was attended by many political and civil activists including Pubudu Jayagoda, Education Secretary of Vanguard Socialist Party, Duminda Nagamuwa, Organizing Secretary of Vanguard Socialist Party, Eranga Gunasekara, National Organizer of Socialist Youth Organization and actor Jehan Appuhami."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Geneva",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Teachers Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva Human Rights Conference",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maradana Social and Peace Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter-University Student Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mujibar Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sami People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pubudu Jayagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vanguard Socialist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duminda Nagamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vanguard Socialist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Organizer of Socialist Youth Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Appuhami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනතට මුවාවී ගෙනයන මර්දනයට එරෙහිව ජිනීවා යනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යොදාගෙන ජනතා විරෝධය මර්දනය කිරීම සැප්තැම්බර් මස පැවැත්වෙන 51 වැනි ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් සමු`ඵවේදී ප්‍රධාන කරුණක් බවට පත්කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු කරන බවත් බේරෙ වැවට තල්ලු කරපු අය කවුද කියලා සෙව්ව ද මැයි 9 ගහපු අයට එරෙහිව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක නොවීම බරපතල තත්වයක් බවත් ලංකා ගුරු සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජෝශප් ස්ටාලින් මහතා අද (23) පැවසීය.",
        "අන්තර් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයීය ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ සංවිධානයෙන් මරදාන සමාජ හා සාමයික කේන්ද්‍රයේදී ඊයේ පැවැති විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී ස්ටාලින් මහතා එසේ පැවසීය.",
        "වර්තමාන ජනතා නැගිටීම පාලන කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත පාවිච්චි කරන බවත් ඒ තුළින් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ දෙබිඩි පිළිවෙත ප්‍රදර්ශනය වන බවත් එම මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී සමඟි ජනබලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මුජිබර් රහුමාන් මහතා කීය.",
        "මෙම මාධ්‍ය හමුවට පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්‍ෂයේ අධ්‍යාපන ලේකම් පුබුදු ජයගොඩ, පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්‍ෂයේ සංවිධායක ලේකම් දුමින්ද නාගමුව, සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංවිධානයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක එරංග ගුණසේකර සහ රංගන ශිල්පී ජෙහාන් අප්පුහාමි ඇතුළු දේශපාලන සහ සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් රැසක් සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජිනීවා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගුරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් සමුළුව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප් ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරදාන සමාජ හා සාමයික මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමි ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුබුදු ජයගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද නාගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංවිධානයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Appuhami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜெனீவாவில் பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம் என்ற போர்வையில் அடக்குமுறைக்கு எதிராகச் செல்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் நடைபெறவுள்ள 51 ஆவது ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் மாநாட்டில் பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி மக்களின் எதிர்ப்பை நசுக்குவதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. பொதுச் செயலாளர் ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின் இன்று (23) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் பேரவையின் ஏற்பாட்டில் மருதானை சமூக மற்றும் அமைதி நிலையத்தில் நேற்று நடைபெற்ற விசேட செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டிலேயே திரு.ஸ்டாலின் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தற்போதைய மக்கள் எழுச்சியைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தை திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பயன்படுத்துவதாகவும், இது திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் இரட்டை வேடத்தையே காட்டுகிறது எனவும் சாமி மக்கள் படையின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.முஜிபர் ரஹ்மான் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் வான்கார்ட் சோசலிச கட்சியின் கல்வி செயலாளர் புபுது ஜயகொட, வான்கார்ட் சோசலிச கட்சியின் அமைப்பு செயலாளர் துமிந்த நாகமுவ, சோசலிச இளைஞர் அமைப்பின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் எரங்க குணசேகர, நடிகர் ஜெஹான் அப்புஹாமி உட்பட அரசியல் மற்றும் சிவில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் பலர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜெனீவா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஆசிரியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் மாநாடு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருதானை சமூக மற்றும் அமைதி மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஜிபர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாமி மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புபுது ஜயகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வான்கார்ட் சோசலிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த நாகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வான்கார்ட் சோசலிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோசலிச இளைஞர் அமைப்பின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Appuhami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}