{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/01/navy-arrests-47-on-illegal-migration-attempt/",
  "time_ut": 1659335040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy arrests 47 on illegal migration attempt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy arrests 47 on illegal migration attempt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A special operation carried out by the Navy and Wennappuwa Police in the town area of Wennappuwa on the night of 31st July 2022, led to the apprehension of 47 individuals suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country via sea.",
        "The coordinated operation was mounted by the Western Naval Command and Wennappuwa Police, based on information received by the Sri Lanka Navy.  The group of individuals, suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country via sea, were nabbed after searching 03 suspicious vans in Wennappuwa in the dark hours of 31st July. Among the apprehended persons were; 37 males and 06 females over 18 years and 04 individuals below 18 years. The 03 vans used for these illegal activities were also taken into custody.",
        "The apprehended persons were identified as residents of Jaffna, Vavuniya, Trincomalee, Kalmunai, Batticaloa, Puttalam, Chilaw, Marawila, Mahawewa, Mundalama, and Wellawatta. They were handed over to Wennappuwa Police for onward investigation.",
        "It is observed that human smugglers organize this kind of racket to make fast money.",
        "Against such a backdrop, the Navy urges the public to refrain from risking their lives by engaging in perilous sea voyages and be victims before the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31st July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours of 31st July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 males",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna, Vavuniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalmunai, Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chilaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahawewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mundalama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawatta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ 47 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදා අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නාවික හමුදාව සහ වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය එක්ව 2022 ජුලි 31 වැනි දින රාත්‍රියේ වෙන්නප්පුව නගර ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් විදේශ රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 47 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවට ලැබුණු තොරතුරක් මත බස්නාහිර නාවික විධානය සහ වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය එක්ව මෙම සම්බන්ධීකරණ මෙහෙයුම දියත් කර ඇත. නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් විදේශ රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන මෙම පිරිස ජුලි 31 වැනි දින අඳුරු පැයේදී වෙන්නප්පුව ප්‍රදේශයේදී සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථ 03ක් සෝදිසි කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයන් අතර; වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි පිරිමි 37 ක් සහ ගැහැණු 06 ක් සහ අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු පුද්ගලයින් 04 ක්. මෙම නීතිවිරෝධී කටයුතු සඳහා යොදාගත් වෑන් රථ 03ක් ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයින් යාපනය, වවුනියාව, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, කල්මුණේ, මඩකලපුව, පුත්තලම, හලාවත, මාරවිල, මහවැව, මුන්දලම සහ වැල්ලවත්ත යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. ඔවුන් ඉදිරි විමර්ශන සඳහා වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මිනිස් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් වේගයෙන් මුදල් ඉපයීමට මෙවැනි ජාවාරමක් සංවිධානය කරන බව නිරීක්ෂණය වේ.",
        "මෙවන් පසුබිමක් තුළ අනතුරුදායක මුහුදු ගමන්වල නිරත වෙමින් තම ජීවිත අවදානමට ලක් කිරීමෙන් වළකින ලෙසත් නීතිය ඉදිරියේ ගොදුරු බවට පත්වන ලෙසත් නාවික හමුදාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 31 පැය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි 37යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය, වවුනියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ, මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භලාවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහවැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුන්දලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சியில் 47 பேரை கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை 31 ஆம் திகதி இரவு வென்னப்புவ நகரப் பகுதியில் கடற்படை மற்றும் வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாரால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் கடல் வழியாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 47 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை மற்றும் வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாரால் ஒருங்கிணைந்த நடவடிக்கை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. கடந்த ஜூலை 31 ஆம் திகதி வென்னப்புவ பிரதேசத்தில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான 03 வேன்களை சோதனையிட்டதன் பின்னர் கடல் வழியாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில்; 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட 37 ஆண்கள் மற்றும் 06 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 18 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட 04 நபர்கள். இந்த சட்டவிரோத நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட 03 வான்களும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் யாழ்ப்பாணம், வவுனியா, திருகோணமலை, கல்முனை, மட்டக்களப்பு, புத்தளம், சிலாபம், மாரவில, மஹாவெவ, முந்தலம மற்றும் வெள்ளவத்தை ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர். அவர்கள் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "மனித கடத்தல்காரர்கள் வேகமாக பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக இதுபோன்ற மோசடியை ஏற்பாடு செய்வதை அவதானிக்க முடிகிறது.",
        "இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியில், ஆபத்தான கடல் பயணங்களில் ஈடுபடுவதன் மூலம் உயிரைப் பணயம் வைத்து சட்டத்தின் முன் பலியாவதைத் தவிர்த்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு கடற்படை பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக் கொள்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 31 இன் மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம், வவுனியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை, மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாவெவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முண்டலமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}