{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Table-IMF-staff-level-agreement-in-Parliament-Harsha-tells-President/342-244290",
  "time_ut": 1662305177,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Table IMF staff level agreement in Parliament: Harsha tells President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Table IMF staff level agreement in Parliament: Harsha tells President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP and Chairman of Public Finance Committee Dr. Harsha de Silva today requested President Ranil Wickremesinghe to table the staff level agreement with IMF before Parliament on Tuesday.",
        "\"I will use my powers as Chairman of Public Finance Committee and get the document out, if President fails to do so on that day,\" Dr. de Silva said during a media conference today.",
        "\"We need to know what the government had agreed to do it in accordance with the staff level agreement. We understand that the government will have to get into agreement with creditors on restructuring debts. All citizens will be affected if domestic debt is to be restructured. The press release of IMF says that Sri Lanka will have to convert the capital account deficit into a surplus by 2025. This could result in huge tax regime and expenditure cuts,\" he said.",
        "\"Also we need to know the new legal structures which the President is going to introduce to curb correlation as well,\" he added. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Public Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මේසයට: හර්ෂ ජනපතිට කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ඇති කර ගත් මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම අඟහරුවාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කමිටුවේ සභාපති ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා අද ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ජනාධිපතිවරයා එසේ කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වුවහොත් මම රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස මගේ බලතල භාවිතා කර ලේඛනය එළියට ගන්නවා\" යැයි ආචාර්ය ද සිල්වා මහතා අද පැවති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "“කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමට අනුව රජය එය කිරීමට එකඟ වූයේ කුමක්දැයි අපට දැනගත යුතුය. ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයට ණයහිමියන් සමඟ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණීමට සිදුවන බව අපට වැටහෙනවා. දේශීය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කළහොත් සියලුම පුරවැසියන්ට බලපානු ඇත. 2025 වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රාග්ධන ගිණුමේ හිඟය අතිරික්තයක් බවට පත් කිරීමට සිදුවනු ඇති බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ. මේ හේතුවෙන් විශාල බදු තන්ත්‍රයක් සහ වියදම් කප්පාදුවක් සිදු විය හැකි බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඒ වගේම සහසම්බන්ධතාවය මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිතුමා හඳුන්වා දීමට යන නව නීතිමය ව්‍යුහයන් පිළිබඳවත් අපි දැනගත යුතුයි,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஊழியர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தம்: ஜனாதிபதியிடம் ஹர்ஷா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை செவ்வாய்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் பொது நிதிக் குழுவின் தலைவருமான கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா இன்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "“அன்றைய தினம் ஜனாதிபதி அவ்வாறு செய்யத் தவறினால், பொது நிதிக் குழுவின் தலைவர் என்ற எனது அதிகாரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி, ஆவணத்தை வெளிக்கொணருவேன்” என இன்று இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது கலாநிதி டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"ஊழியர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தின்படி அரசாங்கம் என்ன செய்ய ஒப்புக்கொண்டது என்பதை நாம் அறிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும். கடன்களை மறுசீரமைப்பதில் கடன் வழங்குபவர்களுடன் அரசாங்கம் உடன்பாடு செய்ய வேண்டும் என்பதை நாங்கள் புரிந்துகொள்கிறோம். உள்நாட்டுக் கடனை மறுசீரமைத்தால் அனைத்து குடிமக்களும் பாதிக்கப்படுவார்கள். 2025 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் இலங்கை மூலதனக் கணக்குப் பற்றாக்குறையை உபரியாக மாற்ற வேண்டும் என்று சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் செய்திக்குறிப்பு கூறுகிறது.",
        "\"அத்துடன் தொடர்புகளைத் தடுக்க ஜனாதிபதி அறிமுகப்படுத்தப் போகும் புதிய சட்டக் கட்டமைப்புகளையும் நாம் அறிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}