{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83419/pucsl-recommends-probe-into-power-interruption-due-to-ceb-union-action-on-june-9",
  "time_ut": 1656922680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PUCSL recommends probe into power interruption due to CEB union action on June 9",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PUCSL recommends probe into power interruption due to CEB union action on June 9",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera says he has received a letter from the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) recommending to conduct an inquiry in to the power interruption due to CEB union action on 9th of June.",
        "He said according to the letter received this morning, the PUCSL has concluded that a cost of Rs. 320 million had been incurred by operating fuel power plants when Hydro power could have been generated on the same day.",
        "In a tweet, the minister added that on the 10th of June, he had instructed the Chairman and the General Manager of the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) to internally investigate the incidents.",
        "He said they were also instructed to assist the CID in their investigations and to temporally remove the alleged persons responsible from the positions to carry out an impartial inquiry and take appropriate legal steps."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "June 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "320 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hydro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 10th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජූනි 9 වැනි දින ලංවිම වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය හේතුවෙන් විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීම ගැන සොයා බලන ලෙස මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම නිර්දේශ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ වෘත්තීය සමිති ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය හේතුවෙන් ජූනි 9 වැනිදා විදුලිය විසන්ධි වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස නිර්දේශ කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවෙන් ලිපියක් ලැබී ඇති බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු කියා සිටියේ අද පෙරවරුවේ ලැබුණු ලිපියට අනුව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ නිගමනය වී ඇත්තේ රු. එදිනම ජල විදුලිය උත්පාදනය කළ හැකිව තිබියදී ඉන්ධන බලාගාර ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 320ක් වැය වී තිබුණි.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේ, මෙම සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අභ්‍යන්තරව විමර්ශනය කරන ලෙස ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (ලංවිම) සභාපතිවරයාට සහ සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයාට ජුනි 10 වනදා තමා උපදෙස් දුන් බවයි.",
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට ඔවුන්ගේ පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා සහය වන ලෙසත්, අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා සුදුසු නීතිමය පියවර ගැනීමට වගකිව යුතු යැයි කියන පුද්ගලයන් තාවකාලිකව එම තනතුරුවලින් ඉවත් කරන ලෙසට ද උපදෙස් දුන් බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූනි 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 320 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හයිඩ්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூன் 9 ஆம் தேதி CEB தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கை காரணமாக மின்சாரம் தடைபட்டது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்த PUCSL பரிந்துரைக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடமிருந்து ஜூன் மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி மின்சார சபையின் தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையினால் ஏற்பட்ட மின் தடை தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு சிபாரிசு செய்து கடிதம் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று காலை கிடைத்த கடிதத்தின்படி, PUCSL முடிவு செய்துள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார். ஒரே நாளில் நீர் மின்சாரம் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்பட்டிருக்கக்கூடிய எரிபொருள் மின் நிலையங்களை இயக்குவதன் மூலம் 320 மில்லியன் ரூபாய்கள் செலவழிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அமைச்சர் தனது டுவிட்டர் பதிவில், ஜூன் 10 ஆம் திகதி, இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பொது முகாமையாளருக்கு, இந்த சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் உள்ளக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு பணிப்புரை விடுத்ததாக மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரின் விசாரணைகளுக்கு உதவுமாறும், பாரபட்சமற்ற விசாரணையை மேற்கொள்வதற்கும், உரிய சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுப்பதற்கும் பொறுப்பான நபர்களை தற்காலிகமாக பதவிகளில் இருந்து நீக்குமாறும் அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூன் 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "320 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹைட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}