{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/caption_story/80-air-tickets-for-workers-leaving-for-Japan/110-239969",
  "time_ut": 1656423393,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "80 air tickets for workers leaving for Japan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "80 air tickets for workers leaving for Japan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Air tickets were handed over to 80 young workers through the IRO College of Education technical intern recruit Sri Lankan workers in Japan. The air tickets were handed over at the Gangaramaya temple in Colombo today. After receiving the tickets, the students were blessed by the Deputy Incumbent Gangaramaya Temple Dr. Kirinde Assaji Thera. Pix by Pradeep Dilrukshana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IRO College of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gangaramaya temple",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirinde Assaji Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානය බලා පිටත්ව යන කම්කරුවන් සඳහා ගුවන් ටිකට්පත් 80 ක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ IRO College of Education තාක්‍ෂණික සීමාවාසික බඳවා ගැනීමේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ශ්‍රමිකයින් හරහා තරුණ ශ්‍රමිකයින් 80 දෙනෙකු වෙත ගුවන් ටිකට්පත් ප්‍රදානය කෙරිණි. අද කොළඹ ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානයේදී ගුවන් ටිකට්පත් භාරදීම සිදුකෙරුණා. ප්‍රවේශපත්‍ර ලබා ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව නියෝජ්‍ය විහාරාධිපති ගංගාරාම විහාරාධිපති ආචාර්ය කිරින්දේ අස්සජි හිමියන් විසින් සිසුන්ට ආශිර්වාද කළහ. Pix by Pradeep Dilrukshana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRO අධ්‍යාපන විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංගාරාම විහාරස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirinde Assaji Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் செல்லும் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு 80 விமான டிக்கெட்டுகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானில் உள்ள IRO காலேஜ் ஆப் எஜுகேஷன் டெக்னிகல் இன்டர்ன் ஆட்சேர்ப்பு இலங்கை பணியாளர்கள் மூலம் 80 இளம் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு விமான டிக்கெட்டுகள் வழங்கப்பட்டன. இந்த விமானப் பயணச்சீட்டுகள் இன்று கொழும்பு கங்காராமய ஆலயத்தில் கையளிக்கப்பட்டன. சீட்டுக்களை பெற்றுக்கொண்ட பின்னர் மாணவர்களுக்கு உப அதிபதி கங்காராமய ஆலய கலாநிதி கிரிந்தே அஸ்ஸாஜி தேரர் ஆசி வழங்கினார். Pix by Pradeep Dilrukshana"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRO கல்வியியல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்காராமய கோவில்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirinde Assaji Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}