{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Elephant-reportedly-not-seriously-injured-officials/108-240257",
  "time_ut": 1656871563,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Elephant reportedly not seriously injured – officials",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Elephant reportedly not seriously injured – officials",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Following the elephant-cab accident at Thalawa in Anuradhapura, injuring three persons including veteran artiste Jackson Anthony, the elephant has not reportedly been seriously injured due to the accident, a wildlife official confirmed today.",
        "According to initial reports and eyewitnesses, the elephant had fled to the nearby jungle following the accident, and eyewitnesses have not noticed any difference in the elephant's walking style, so we hope that the elephant's injuries are not serious, a senior wildlife officer said.",
        "“Some villagers had seen that the elephant had fled to the jungle and rejoined with its herd and apparently the elephant has not been fatally injured. But our team is already dispatched to locate the animal and treat it. Until we find the elephant, we cannot say how bad the injuries are,” the official told the Daily Mirror.",
        "Actor Anthony and two persons were seriously injured after the double cab they were travelling in, hit a wild elephant at Thalawa in Anuradhapura, on Saturday night.",
        "According to hospital sources, two bones of the neck of the actor have been dislocated, its membranes are damaged, and also both lungs are damaged. Due to the condition of his neck, he was transferred to Colombo,  a senior hospital spokesman said.",
        "Two other people are currently being treated at the Anuradhapura Hospital and one of them is in the ICU. (Sunil Jayasiri)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thalawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Anuradhapura Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Jayasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අලියාට බරපතල තුවාල සිදුවී නොමැති බව වාර්තා වේ - නිලධාරීන්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අනුරාධපුර, තලාව ප්‍රදේශයේදී අලි කැබ් රථ අනතුරකින් ප්‍රවීණ කලාකරු ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී ඇතුළු තිදෙනෙකුට තුවාල සිදු වූ අතර, එම අනතුරින් වන අලියාට බරපතල තුවාල සිදුවී නොමැති බව වනජීවී නිලධාරියෙකු අද තහවුරු කළා.",
        "මූලික වාර්තාවලට අනුව සහ ඇසින් දුටු සාක්ෂිකරුවන්ට අනුව අනතුරත් සමඟ අලියා අසල කැලයට පලාගොස් ඇති අතර ඇතාගේ ඇවිදීමේ විලාසයේ වෙනසක් ඇසින් දුටු සාක්ෂිකරුවන්ට නොපෙනී ඇති නිසා අලියාගේ තුවාල බරපතළ නොවන බව අප විශ්වාස කරන බව ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ වනජීවී නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "“සමහර ගම්මුන් දැකලා තියෙනවා අලියා කැලේට පැනලා ආපහු රංචුව එක්ක එකතු වෙලා, අලියාට මාරාන්තික තුවාල වෙලා නැහැ. නමුත් අපේ කණ්ඩායම දැනටමත් එම සත්වයා සොයාගෙන ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීමට පිටත් කර යවා ඇත. අලියා සොයා ගන්නා තුරු තුවාල කොතරම් දරුණු දැයි කියන්න බැහැ” යැයි එම නිලධාරියා ඩේලි මිරර් පුවත්පතට පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය සෙනසුරාදා රාත්‍රියේ අනුරාධපුර තලාව ප්‍රදේශයේදී වල් අලියකුගේ ඩබල් කැබ් රථයක් ගැටීමෙන් රංගන ශිල්පී ඇන්තනී සහ පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු බරපතල තුවාල ලබා ඇත.",
        "රෝහල් ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසන පරිදි නළුවාගේ බෙල්ලේ අස්ථි දෙකක් විස්ථාපනය වී ඇති අතර එහි පටල වලට හානි සිදුවී ඇති අතර පෙනහළු දෙකටම හානි සිදුවී ඇත. ඔහුගේ බෙල්ලේ තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ඔහු කොළඹට මාරු කර යවා ඇති බව රෝහල් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "තවත් දෙදෙනෙකු මේ වන විට අනුරාධපුර රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන අතර එක් අයෙකු දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ සිටී. (සුනිල් ජයසිරි)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් ජයසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யானைக்கு பலத்த காயம் ஏற்படவில்லை - அதிகாரிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அநுராதபுரம், தலாவ பகுதியில் இடம்பெற்ற யானை வண்டி விபத்தினால், மூத்த கலைஞர் ஜாக்சன் அந்தோணி உட்பட மூவர் காயமடைந்துள்ள நிலையில், யானைக்கு பெரிய காயம் ஏற்படவில்லை என, வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரி ஒருவர் இன்று உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "முதற்கட்ட அறிக்கைகள் மற்றும் நேரில் கண்ட சாட்சிகளின்படி, யானை விபத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து அருகிலுள்ள காட்டிற்கு ஓடிவிட்டதாகவும், யானையின் நடைபாதையில் எந்த வித்தியாசத்தையும் நேரில் பார்த்தவர்கள் கவனிக்கவில்லை, எனவே யானையின் காயங்கள் பெரிதாக இல்லை என்று நம்புகிறோம் என்று மூத்த வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "யானை காட்டிற்கு ஓடியதையும் அதன் கூட்டத்துடன் மீண்டும் சேர்ந்ததையும் சில கிராமவாசிகள் பார்த்துள்ளனர், மேலும் யானைக்கு எந்தவிதமான காயமும் ஏற்படவில்லை. ஆனால் விலங்கைக் கண்டுபிடித்து சிகிச்சை அளிக்க எங்கள் குழு ஏற்கனவே அனுப்பப்பட்டுள்ளது. யானையைக் கண்டுபிடிக்கும் வரை, காயங்கள் எவ்வளவு மோசமானவை என்று எங்களால் கூற முடியாது,” என்று அந்த அதிகாரி டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை இரவு அனுராதபுரம் தலைவா என்ற இடத்தில் காட்டு யானை மீது இரட்டை வண்டி மோதியதில் நடிகர் அந்தோணி மற்றும் இருவர் படுகாயமடைந்தனர்.",
        "மருத்துவமனை வட்டாரங்களின்படி, நடிகரின் கழுத்தில் இரண்டு எலும்புகள் சிதைந்துள்ளன, அதன் சவ்வுகள் சேதமடைந்துள்ளன, மேலும் இரண்டு நுரையீரல்களும் சேதமடைந்துள்ளன. அவரது கழுத்தின் நிலை காரணமாக, அவர் கொழும்புக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டதாக மருத்துவமனையின் மூத்த பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும் இருவர் தற்போது அனுராதபுரம் வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாகவும் அவர்களில் ஒருவர் தீவிர சிகிச்சை பிரிவில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (சுனில் ஜயசிறி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்தோணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.யு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் ஜயசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}