{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බන්ධනාගාර-රැදවියෝ-දෙදෙනෙක්-උසස්-පෙළ-සමත්-වෙති/101-618954",
  "time_ut": 1661767836,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බන්ධනාගාර රැදවියෝ දෙදෙනෙක් උසස් පෙළ සමත් වෙති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two prison inmates pass A-level",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the prison portal, two prisoners, including LTTE inmates of the special category who appeared for the Merawa High Level examination, have passed.",
        "Prison Media Spokesman, Control and Rehabilitation Commissioner Mr. Chandana Ekanayake said that three prisoners appeared in the examination center of Magazine Prison in the subject stream this year.",
        "The prison media spokesman said that with the full intervention of the prison department, the prisoners were presented for examination with the main objective of rehabilitating the inmates who are sent to prison on various charges and making them socialize as good citizens.",
        "The 38-year-old resident of Kilinochchi area, a special category LTTE detainee who appeared for the examination, passed in Geography - Honors Pass C, Hindu Civilization - Honors Pass C and Tamil Language - General Pass S The prison media spokesperson said that there has been.",
        "He said that the 46-year-old detainee, a resident of Kegalle, who appeared from Welikada prison, had obtained and passed Political Science-General Pass S, Buddhist Civilization-General Pass S, and Sinhala-General Pass S."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Control",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rehabilitation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandana Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magazine Prison",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "38-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi area",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Political Science-General Pass S",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist Civilization-General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pass S",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-General Pass S.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බන්ධනාගාර රැදවියෝ දෙදෙනෙක් උසස් පෙළ සමත් වෙති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙරව උසස් පෙළ විභාගයට  පෙනී සිටි විශේෂ ගනයේ  එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ රැඳවියන් ඇතුලු  බන්ධනාගාර රැදවියන් දෙදෙනකු  ඉන් සමත් වී ඇති බව   බන්ධනාගාර පොර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "රැදවියන් තිදෙනකු මැගසින් බන්ධනාගාරයේ විභාග මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ දී   මෙවර උසස් පෙළ විභාගයේ කළා  විෂය ධාරාවෙන්    පෙනී සිටි බවද බන්ධනාගාර මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක පාලන හා පුනරුත්ථාපන කොමසාරිස් චන්දන ඒකනායක මහතා පවසයි.",
        "විවිධ චෝදනා ලබා බන්ධනාගාර ගත වන රැඳවියන් පුනරුත්ථාපනය කර යහපත් පුරවැසියන් ලෙස සමාජ ගත කිරීම  ප්‍රධාන අරමුණින් බන්ධනාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පූර්ණ මැදිහත්වීම මත රැඳවියන් විභාගය සදහා ඉදිරිපත් කළ බව බන්ධනාගාර මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කීය.",
        "විභාගයට පෙනී සිටි  විශේෂ ගනයේ එල් .ටී.ටී.ඊ රැඳවියෙකු වන කිලිනොච්චිය ප්‍රදේශයෙහි පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු  38 ක්  වන රැඳවියා විසින් භුගෝල විද්‍යාව- සම්මාන සාමාර්ථ C ද, හින්දු ශිෂ්ඨාචාරය- සම්මාන සාමාර්ථ Cද, දමිළ භාෂාව - සාමාන්‍ය සාමාර්ථ S ද, ලබා ගනිමින් සමත් වී ඇති අතර   බව බන්ධනාගාර මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කියා සිටියේය.",
        "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පෙනී සිටි කෑගල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු 46 ක රැඳවියා විසින් දේශපාලන විද්‍යාව-සාමාන්‍ය  සාමාර්ථ S  ද,  බෞද්ධ ශිෂ්ඨාචාරය-සාමාන්‍ය සාමාර්ථ S ද,  සිංහල - සාමාන්‍ය  සාමාර්ථ S ද,  ලබාගෙන සමත් වී ඇති බවද හෙතෙම කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලනය කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුනරුත්ථාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දන ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැගසින් බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චිය ප්‍රදේශයේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශපාලන විද්‍යාව-සාමාන්‍ය සමත් එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ ශිෂ්ටාචාරය-සාමාන්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමත් එස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල පොදු සාමාර්ථය එස්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு சிறைக் கைதிகள் ஏ-தரத்தில் தேர்ச்சி பெற்றுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மெரவா உயர்தரப் பரீட்சைக்குத் தோற்றிய விடுதலைப் புலிகளின் சிறப்புப் பிரிவைச் சேர்ந்த கைதிகள் உட்பட இரு கைதிகள் சித்தியடைந்துள்ளதாக சிறைச்சாலை வாசலில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மகசீன் சிறைச்சாலையின் பரீட்சை நிலையத்தில் இந்த வருடம் பாடப்பிரிவில் மூன்று கைதிகள் தோற்றியதாக சிறைச்சாலை ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் புனர்வாழ்வு ஆணையாளர் திரு.சந்தன ஏக்கநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சிறைச்சாலை திணைக்களத்தின் பூரண தலையீட்டுடன் பல்வேறு குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் சிறைக்கு அனுப்பப்படும் கைதிகளுக்கு புனர்வாழ்வு அளித்து அவர்களை நல்ல குடிமக்களாக மாற்றும் முக்கிய நோக்கத்துடன் கைதிகள் பரிசோதனைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டதாக சிறைச்சாலை ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பரீட்சைக்கு தோற்றிய விடுதலைப் புலிகளின் விசேட கைதியான 38 வயதுடைய கிளிநொச்சி பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த இவர் புவியியல் - கௌரவ சித்தி சி, இந்து நாகரிகம் - கௌரவ சித்தி சி மற்றும் தமிழ் மொழி - ஜெனரல் பாஸ் எஸ் ஆகிய பாடங்களில் சித்தியடைந்துள்ளதாக சிறைச்சாலை ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் அங்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இருந்திருக்கிறது.",
        "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் இருந்து தோன்றிய கேகாலையை வசிப்பிடமாகக் கொண்ட 46 வயதான கைதி, அரசியல் விஞ்ஞானம்-பொதுப் பாஸ் எஸ், பௌத்த நாகரிகம்-பொதுப் பாஸ் எஸ், சிங்கள-பொதுப் பாஸ் எஸ் ஆகியவற்றைப் பெற்று சித்தியடைந்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுப்பாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனர்வாழ்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தன ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இதழ் சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி பிரதேசம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியல் அறிவியல்-பொது தேர்ச்சி எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த நாகரிகம்-பொது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ் எஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள-ஜெனரல் பாஸ் எஸ்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}