{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84649/visiting-imf-delegates-call-on-opposition-leader",
  "time_ut": 1661866860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Visiting IMF delegates call on Opposition Leader",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Visiting IMF delegates call on Opposition Leader",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) called on Sri Lanka’s Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa this morning (Aug 30).",
        "The delegation consisted of Mission Chief Peter Breuer, Deputy Chief Masahiro Nozaki and IMF’s Resident Representative Dr. Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan.",
        "The two sides held a discussion about solving the island nation’s ongoing financial crisis.",
        "The IMF delegation is in Colombo from August 24 to 31 to finalize a staff-level agreement for a possible USD 3 billion bailout package for Sri Lanka, including restructuring debt of about USD 29 billion.",
        "Last week, the delegation held several rounds of talks with President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the officials of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka.",
        "An @IMFNews delegation consisting of Senior Mission Chief Peter Breuer, Deputy Chief Masahiro Nozaki & Permanent Rep. Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan called on the Leader of the Opposition @sajithpremadasa this morning (30) to discuss solving the current Sri Lankan financial crisis. 🇱🇰 pic.twitter.com/uf4A1bogHy— Samagi Jana Balawegaya (@sjbsrilanka) August 30, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24 to 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about USD 29 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki & Permanent",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Feridhanusetyawan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයින් විපක්ෂ නායක හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සංචාරයක නිරත වූ නියෝජිත පිරිස අද (අගෝස්තු 30) පෙරවරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "දූත පිරිස සමන්විත වූයේ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර්, නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධානී මසාහිරෝ නොසාකි සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නේවාසික නියෝජිත ආචාර්ය ටුබාගස් ෆෙරිධනුසෙටියාවන් යන අයගෙනි.",
        "දිවයිනේ පවතින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය විසඳීම පිළිබඳව දෙපාර්ශවය අතර සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ඩොලර් බිලියන 29 ක පමණ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 ක ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා IMF නියෝජිත පිරිස අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා කොළඹට පැමිණ සිටිති.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ එම නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "වත්මන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය විසඳීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බ්‍රූවර්, නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධානී මසාහිරෝ නොසාකි සහ ස්ථිර නියෝජිත ටුබාගස් ෆෙරිධනුසෙට්‍යාවන් යන අයගෙන් සමන්විත @IMFNews නියෝජිත පිරිසක් අද (30) පෙරවරුවේ විපක්ෂ නායක @sajithpremadasa මහතා හමුවිය. 🇱🇰 pic.twitter.com/uf4A1bogHy— සමගි ජන බලවේගය (@sjbsrilanka) 2022 අගෝස්තු 30"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF හි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 29ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki & Permanent",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරිධනුසෙට්යාවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வருகை தந்துள்ள IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரை சந்திக்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 30) ​​காலை இலங்கையின் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "தூதுக்குழுவில் மிஷன் சீஃப் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், துணைத் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி மற்றும் IMFன் வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி டாக்டர். டுபாகஸ் ஃபெரிதனுசெட்யவான் ஆகியோர் இருந்தனர்.",
        "தீவு நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண்பது குறித்து இரு தரப்பினரும் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை கொழும்பில் இலங்கைக்கு 3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்கான பணியாளர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை இறுதி செய்ய உள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி அதிகாரிகளுடன் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு பல சுற்றுப் பேச்சுக்களை நடத்தியது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண்பது குறித்து ஆலோசிப்பதற்காக, சிரேஷ்ட தூதுவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், பிரதித் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி மற்றும் நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதி டுபாகஸ் பெரிதானுசெட்யவான் ஆகியோரைக் கொண்ட @IMFNews தூதுக்குழு இன்று (30) காலை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் @sajithpremadasa அவர்களைச் சந்தித்தது. 🇱🇰 pic.twitter.com/uf4A1bogHy— சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (@sjbsrilanka) ஆகஸ்ட் 30, 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF இன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 29 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki & Permanent",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரிதானுசேத்யவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}