{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/15/a-leader-with-consensus-needed-patali/",
  "time_ut": 1657889700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "A Leader with consensus needed: Patali",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A Leader with consensus needed: Patali",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Parliamentarian Patali Champika Ranawaka emphasizes that a Leader with a consensus should become the President",
        "Pointing out that the people had to force the President to resign, the Parliamentarian said that the protestors have no right to surround the Parliament, as the legislature of the country should be empowered to function now, and Sri Lankans should give an opportunity for the legislative to function uninterrupted as well.",
        "Moreover, he stated that the legislature too should acknowledge the protests led by Sri Lankans for over a month.",
        "He further says that the functions of the present Government should continue as follows; a People’s Assembly must be formed in order to enable the inclusion of ideas of activists and trade unionists. Secondly, MP Ranwaka said that all 224 MPs within the Parliament with the exception of the Prime Minister should function in line with Ministries, which they are assigned to. Thirdly, all parties to agree to a minmum amount of policies.",
        "The MP also said that tno party can continue to remain in the shadows with regard to their policies, citing varied number of policies which arose over IMF assistance to Sri Lanka, said that while some parties continue to oppose going forward with the IMF program, they have not underlined a proper alternative in that regard.",
        "FUTA wants Ranil to step down & NOT contest election in Parliament for President",
        "New President : MPs now represent entire electorate of Sri Lanka, says BASL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Patali Champika Ranawaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "People’s Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secondly",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranwaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "224",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thirdly",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සම්මුතියක් ඇති නායකයෙක් අවශ්‍යයි: පාඨලී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සම්මුතියක් ඇති නායකයෙක් ජනාධිපති විය යුතු බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ජනතාවට බල කිරීමට සිදු වූ බව පෙන්වා දුන් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා, රටේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයට දැන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට බලය දිය යුතු බැවින් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වට කිරීමට අයිතියක් නොමැති බවත්, ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසීන්ට අවස්ථාවක් දිය යුතු බවත් සඳහන් කළේය. බාධාවකින් තොරව ද ක්‍රියා කිරීමට.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, මාසයකට අධික කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් විසින් මෙහෙයවන ලද විරෝධතා ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය ද පිළිගත යුතු බව ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පවසන්නේ වත්මන් රජයේ කාර්යයන් පහත පරිදි ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා යුතු බවයි. ක්‍රියාකාරීන්ගේ සහ වෘත්තීය සමිතිකරුවන්ගේ අදහස් ඇතුළත් කිරීමට හැකිවන පරිදි මහජන සභාවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුය. දෙවනුව, අගමැති හැර පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ සිටින මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 224 දෙනාම තමන්ට පැවරෙන අමාත්‍යාංශවලට අනුකූලව කටයුතු කළ යුතු බව රන්වක මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය. තෙවනුව, සියලුම පාර්ශවයන් අවම ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රමාණයකට එකඟ වීම.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ආධාර සම්බන්ධයෙන් මතු වූ විවිධ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සඳහන් කරමින් ටී.එන්.ඒ. පක්‍ෂයට තම ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවදුරටත් සෙවනැල්ලේ සිටිය නොහැකි බව පැවසූ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩපිළිවෙළ ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට ඇතැම් පාර්ශ්ව දිගින් දිගටම විරුද්ධ වන බව ද පැවසීය. ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් නිසි විකල්පයක් අවධාරණය කර නැත.",
        "FUTA ට අවශ්‍ය වී ඇත්තේ රනිල් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සහ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් නොවීමයි",
        "නව ජනාධිපති : පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමස්ත මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාසයම නියෝජනය කරන බව BASL පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවනුව",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranwaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "224",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍යාංශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවනුව",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒருமித்த தலைவர் தேவை: பாடலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஒருமித்த தலைவரே ஜனாதிபதியாக வர வேண்டுமென நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய மக்கள் வற்புறுத்த வேண்டும் என சுட்டிக்காட்டிய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், பாராளுமன்றத்தை முற்றுகையிட ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு உரிமை இல்லை, ஏனெனில் நாட்டின் சட்டமன்றத்திற்கு இப்போது செயல்பட அதிகாரம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும், மேலும் இலங்கையர்கள் சட்டமன்றத்திற்கு வாய்ப்பளிக்க வேண்டும். தடையின்றி செயல்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "மேலும், ஒரு மாதத்திற்கும் மேலாக இலங்கையர்கள் நடத்திய போராட்டங்களை சட்டமன்றமும் அங்கீகரிக்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவர் மேலும் கூறுகையில், தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தின் செயல்பாடுகள் பின்வருமாறு தொடர வேண்டும்; ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் தொழிற்சங்கவாதிகளின் யோசனைகளைச் சேர்க்கும் வகையில் மக்கள் பேரவை உருவாக்கப்பட வேண்டும். இரண்டாவதாக, பிரதமர் தவிர்ந்த 224 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் தங்களுக்கு ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அமைச்சுக்களுக்கு அமைவாக செயற்பட வேண்டும் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரன்வக தெரிவித்தார். மூன்றாவதாக, அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளும் குறைந்தபட்ச அளவு கொள்கைகளை ஒப்புக்கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் உதவி தொடர்பில் எழுந்த பல்வேறு கொள்கைகளை மேற்கோள்காட்டி, தமது கொள்கைகள் தொடர்பில் தமிழ் கட்சியினால் தொடர்ந்தும் இருளில் இருக்க முடியாது என தெரிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், சில தரப்பினர் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் வேலைத்திட்டத்தை முன்னெடுப்பதற்கு தொடர்ந்தும் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். இது சம்பந்தமாக சரியான மாற்றீட்டை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டவில்லை.",
        "FUTA ரணில் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட வேண்டாம்",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி: பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இப்போது இலங்கையின் முழு வாக்காளர்களையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகின்றனர் என்று BASL தெரிவித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவதாக",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranwaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "224",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சுக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவதாக",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}