{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/20/dullas-g-l-visit-anuradhapura/",
  "time_ut": 1661004120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dullas, G.L. visit Anuradhapura",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dullas, G.L. visit Anuradhapura",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A group of MPs who supported MP Dullas Alahapperuma in the recent vote for President at the Parliament visited Anuradhapura to engage in religious activities.",
        "The group of MPs worshipped the Sri Maha Bodhi, as well as the Ruwanweliseya and obtained blessings.",
        "Former Minister and the Chairman of the SLPP, Prof. G.L. Peiris, speaking at the event stated that the visit marks the beginning of a new journey in the near future, as they have to make several important decisions for the country.",
        "MP Alahapperuma too speaking at the event said that the 6.9 million people who voted for the Government should not be blamed, as it was their greatest hope to work for the betterment of the country, and added that although the Government indeed failed in its promise, the trust of the people should be protected at all costs.",
        "Sumanthiran condemns detention orders on protestors, calls for PTA to be repealed"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "G.L.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Anuradhapura",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Maha Bodhi",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwanweliseya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්, ජී.එල් අනුරාධපුරයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පසුගියදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට සහය පළ කළ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් අනුරාධපුරයට පැමිණ ආගමික වතාවත්වල නිරත වුණා.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිස ශ්‍රී මහා බෝධීන් වහන්සේ වැඳපුදාගෙන රුවන්වැලිසෑය වැඳපුදාගෙන ආශිර්වාද ලබාගත්තා.",
        "එහිදී අදහස් දැක්වූ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් කියා සිටියේ මෙම සංචාරය නුදුරු අනාගතයේ නව ගමනක ආරම්භය සනිටුහන් කරන බවත් ඔවුන්ට රට වෙනුවෙන් වැදගත් තීරණ කිහිපයක් ගැනීමට සිදුවන බවත්ය.",
        "මෙහිදී අදහස්‌ දැක්‌වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාද, රජයට ඡන්දය දුන් ලක්‍ෂ 69 ක ජනතාවක්‌ රටේ අභිවෘද්ධිය වෙනුවෙන් කටයුතු කිරීම ඔවුන්ගේ ලොකුම බලාපොරොත්තුව බැවින් ඔවුන්ට දොස්‌ නොතැබිය යුතු බව පැවසූ අතර, රජය දුන් පොරොන්දුව සැබෑ ලෙසම පැහැර හරින ලද නමුත්, ජනතාවගේ විශ්වාසය කෙසේ හෝ ආරක්ෂා විය යුතුයි.",
        "සුමන්තිරන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් රඳවා තබා ගැනීමේ නියෝග හෙළා දකියි, ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අහෝසි කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජී.එල්.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී මහා බෝධිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්වැලිසෑය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டலஸ், ஜி.எல் அனுராதபுரத்திற்கு விஜயம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அண்மையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதிக்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று அனுராதபுரத்திற்கு சமய நிகழ்வுகளில் ஈடுபட்டது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவினர் ஸ்ரீ மஹா போதி மற்றும் ருவன்வெலிசேயாவை வழிபட்டு ஆசிர்வாதம் பெற்றனர்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய முன்னாள் அமைச்சரும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவருமான பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ், இந்த விஜயமானது நாட்டிற்காக பல முக்கிய தீர்மானங்களை மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டியுள்ள நிலையில் எதிர்வரும் காலங்களில் புதிய பயணமொன்றை ஆரம்பிப்பதாக குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் உரையாற்றிய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அழகப்பெரும, அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வாக்களித்த 6.9 மில்லியன் மக்கள் நாட்டின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக பாடுபடுவதே அவர்களின் மிகப்பெரிய நம்பிக்கை என்பதால் அவர்களைக் குறை கூறக்கூடாது என்றும், அரசாங்கம் உண்மையில் தனது வாக்குறுதியை தவறவிட்டாலும், மக்களின் நம்பிக்கை எந்த விலையிலும் பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீதான தடுப்புக்காவல் உத்தரவுக்கு கண்டனம் தெரிவித்துள்ள சுமந்திரன், பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தை ரத்து செய்ய வேண்டும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ மஹா போதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவன்வெலிசேய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}