{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බ්‍රේක්-නැති-පා-පැදියකින්-පල්ලමේ-ගිය-දරුවා-මරුට/101-618396",
  "time_ut": 1660896429,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බ්‍රේක් නැති පා පැදියකින් පල්ලමේ ගිය දරුවා මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A child who fell down a hill without a brake was killed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Dickwella Police, two 13-year-old school students who were traveling on a bicycle on the steep road crashed into a wall due to the fact that the brakes of the bicycle went off and they could not control the speed.",
        "13-year-old Gayeshan Dinuja Hasmika, the only child of the family, who is studying at Dikwella Vijitha Madhya Maha Vidyalaya, has died in this accident which happened on Dikwella Dodampahala Udadeniya road.",
        "The police say that the accident happened when the mother went with her mother to participate in an extra class and was cycling with her friends on the side roads before the class started.",
        "Although the child who was injured in the accident was immediately admitted to Dikwella Government Hospital, the student who suffered serious head injuries died."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dickwella Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayeshan Dinuja Hasmika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dikwella Vijitha Madhya Maha Vidyalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dikwella Dodampahala Udadeniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dikwella Government Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රේක් නැති පා පැදියකින් පල්ලමේ ගිය දරුවා මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බෑවුම් සහිත මාර්ගය පාපැදියෙන් ගමන් කළ 13 හැවිරිදි පාසල් සිසුන් දෙදෙනකු පා පැදියේ තිරිංග ක්‍රියාවිරහිත වී වේගය පාලනය කරගත නොහැකිව තාප්පයක ගැටී එක් සිසුවකු මියගොස්   අනෙක් සිසුවා තුවාල ලබා කරාපිටිය රෝහලට අතුළත්කර ඇතැයි දික්වැල්ල පොලසිය පවසයි.",
        "දික්වැල්ල දොඩම්පහල උඩදෙණිය මාර්ගයේ සිදුවූ මෙම අනතුරින් දික්වැල්ල විජිත මධ්‍ය මහා විද්‍යාලයේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන 13 හැවිරිදි  ගයේෂන් දිනුජ හස්මික නැමැති පවුලේ එකම දරුවා මරණයට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "අමතර පන්තියකට සහභාගි වීම සඳහා මවද සමග ගොස් සිටියදී පන්තිය පටන් ගැනීමට පෙර අතුරු මාර්ගවල යහළුවන් සමග බයිසිකල් පදිමින් සිටියදී මෙම අනතුර සිදුවී ඇති බව පොලිසිය කියයි .",
        "අනතුරින් තුවාල ලැබූ දරුවා වහා දික්වැල්ල රජයේ රෝහලට ඇතුලත් කළද හිසට බරපතල තුවාල සිදුවූ සිසුවා මරණයට පත්ව තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයේෂාන් දිනුජ හස්මික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල විජිත මධ්‍ය මහා විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල දොඩම්පහල උඩදෙණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල රජයේ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரேக் போடாமல் மலையிலிருந்து தவறி விழுந்த குழந்தை உயிரிழந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "செங்குத்தான வீதியில் துவிச்சக்கரவண்டியில் பயணித்த 13 வயதுடைய பாடசாலை மாணவர்கள் இருவர் சைக்கிளின் பிரேக் செயலிழந்து வேகத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்த முடியாமல் சுவரில் மோதி விபத்துக்குள்ளானதாக திக்வெல்ல பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "திக்வெல்ல தொடம்பஹல உடதெனிய வீதியில் இடம்பெற்ற இந்த விபத்தில் திக்வெல்ல விஜித மத்திய மகா வித்தியாலயத்தில் கல்வி கற்கும் குடும்பத்தின் ஒரே பிள்ளையான 13 வயதுடைய கயேஷான் தினுஜா ஹஸ்மிக உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலதிக வகுப்பில் பங்கேற்பதற்காக தாய் தனது தாயுடன் சென்று வகுப்பு ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு முன்னர் பக்கவாட்டு வீதிகளில் தனது நண்பர்களுடன் சைக்கிளில் சென்றுகொண்டிருந்த போதே இவ்விபத்து இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "விபத்தில் படுகாயமடைந்த குழந்தையை உடனடியாக திக்வெல்ல அரச வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதித்த போதும், தலையில் பலத்த காயம் அடைந்த மாணவன் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திக்வெல்ல பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயேசன் தினுஜா ஹஸ்மிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திக்வெல்ல விஜித மத்திய மகா வித்தியாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திக்வெல்ல தொடம்பஹல உடதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "திக்வெல்ல அரசு மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}