{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/cse-slips-in-mid-morning-trade-ahead-of-interim-budget-presentation/",
  "time_ut": 1661791680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CSE slips in mid-morning trade ahead of interim budget presentation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CSE slips in mid-morning trade ahead of interim budget presentation",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s share market evinced some downward trends yesterday as it slipped in mid-morning trade after having opened stronger ahead of the 2022 interim budget, to be presented in parliament by President Ranil Wickremesinghe as Finance Minister today.",
        "Both indices moved downwards. All- Share Price Index went down by 60.92 points and S and P SL20 declined by 29.1 points. Turnover stood at Rs 1.2 billion with no crossings. In the retail market top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were; Expolanka Holdings Rs 244 million (1.5 million shares traded), Lanka- IOC, Rs 153 million (929,000 shares traded), Lankem Development Rs 40.5 million (1.5 million shares traded), Bogawanthalawa Plantations Rs 36.2 million (538,000 shares traded), Aitken Spence Rs 33.3 million (268,000 shares traded), CTC Rs 30.4 million (49,000 shares traded) and Hayleys Fabrics Rs 29.4 million (829,000 shares traded). During the day 51.3 million share volumes changed hands in 20000 share transactions.",
        "Yesterday the Central Bank’s dollar buying rate was Rs 357.80 and the selling rate Rs368.78.",
        "Sri Lanka’s children paying the steepest price in the current crisis – UNICEF Regional Director for South Asia",
        "$18 trillion wiped off global markets in first half of 2022, WFE data reveals",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "mid-morning",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60.92",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "244 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka- IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "153 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "929,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankem Development Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bogawanthalawa Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "538,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aitken Spence Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "268,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "829,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "357.80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$18 trillion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first half of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අතුරු අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට පෙර මධ්‍යම උදෑසන වෙළඳාමේදී CSE ලිස්සා යයි",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද දින මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත 2022 අතුරු අයවැයට පෙර ශක්තිමත්ව විවෘත කිරීමෙන් පසු මධ්‍යම උදෑසන වෙළඳාමේ දී ලිස්සා යාම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොටස් වෙළඳපොළ ඊයේ යම් පහත වැටීමක් පෙන්නුම් කළේය.",
        "දර්ශක දෙකම පහළට ගමන් කළේය. සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 60.92 කින් පහළ ගිය අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 29.1 කින් පහළ ගියේය. හරස් මාර්ග නොමැතිව පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 1.2 ක් විය. සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ සමාගම් හත වූයේ; එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 244 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.5 ක් ගනුදෙනු), ලංකා-අයිඕසී, රුපියල් මිලියන 153 (කොටස් මිලියන 929,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), ලංකෙම් ඩිවලොප්මන්ට් රුපියල් මිලියන 40.5 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.5 ක් ගනුදෙනු), බගවන්තලාව වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 36.2 (538,000) කොටස් වෙළෙඳාම. රුපියල් මිලියන 33.3 (කොටස් 268,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), CTC රුපියල් මිලියන 30.4 (කොටස් 49,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු) සහ හේලීස් ෆැබ්රික්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 29.4 (කොටස් 829,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ කොටස් ගනුදෙනු 20000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 51.3 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "ඊයේ මහ බැංකුවේ ඩොලරයේ ගැනුම් අනුපාතිකය රුපියල් 357.80 ක් වූ අතර විකුණුම් මිල රුපියල් 368.78 ක් විය.",
        "වත්මන් අර්බුදය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුවන් දැඩිම මිල ගෙවනවා - යුනිසෙෆ් දකුණු ආසියාවේ කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ",
        "2022 පළමු භාගයේදී ඩොලර් ට්‍රිලියන 18ක් ගෝලීය වෙලඳපොලවල් අතුගා දැමූ බව WFE දත්ත හෙළි කරයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මධ්යම උදෑසන",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60.92 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 244 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා - IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 153 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "929,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකෙම් සංවර්ධන රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 40.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බගවන්තලාව වැවිලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 36.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "538,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aitken Spence රු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 33.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "268,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 30.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 29.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "829,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 51.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "357.80 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් ට්‍රිලියන 18 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் சமர்ப்பணத்திற்கு முன்னதாக காலை வர்த்தகத்தில் சிஎஸ்இ நழுவியது",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நிதியமைச்சராக இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள 2022 இடைக்கால வரவுசெலவுத்திட்டத்திற்கு முன்னதாக வலுவாக திறக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், நேற்றைய காலை வர்த்தகத்தில் நழுவியுள்ள இலங்கையின் பங்குச்சந்தை நேற்றைய தினம் சில கீழ்நோக்கிய போக்குகளை வெளிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "இரண்டு குறியீடுகளும் கீழ் நோக்கி நகர்ந்தன. அனைத்துப் பங்கு விலைச் சுட்டெண் 60.92 புள்ளிகளாலும், S மற்றும் P SL20 29.1 புள்ளிகளாலும் சரிந்தன. விற்றுமுதல் ரூ.1.2 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சந்தையில் முதன்மையான ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள் விற்றுமுதல் பங்களித்தன; எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 244 மில்லியன் (1.5 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), லங்கா- ஐஓசி, ரூ 153 மில்லியன் (929,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), லங்கெம் டெவலப்மென்ட் ரூ 40.5 மில்லியன் (1.5 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பொகவந்தலாவ பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் ரூ 36.2 மில்லியன் (538,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), ஏஐடி பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம் ரூ 33.3 மில்லியன் (268,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), CTC ரூ 30.4 மில்லியன் (49,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் ஹேலிஸ் ஃபேப்ரிக்ஸ் ரூ 29.4 மில்லியன் (829,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்). நாளின் போது 20000 பங்கு பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 51.3 மில்லியன் பங்கு அளவுகள் மாறின.",
        "நேற்று மத்திய வங்கியின் டொலர் கொள்வனவு விலை 357.80 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை விலை 368.78 ரூபாவாகவும் இருந்தது.",
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியில் இலங்கையின் பிள்ளைகள் அதிக விலை கொடுக்கின்றனர் - யுனிசெஃப் தெற்காசியாவின் பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர்",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் பாதியில் $18 டிரில்லியன் உலகளாவிய சந்தைகளை அழித்துவிட்டது, WFE தரவு வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நண்பகல்",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நண்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60.92",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "244 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா- ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "153 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "929,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கெம் அபிவிருத்தி ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொகவந்தலாவ தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "538,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எய்ட்கன் ஸ்பென்ஸ் ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "268,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "829,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "357.80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$18 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}