{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/All-time-record-prices-of-tea-Siyaka-Catalogues/34-736865",
  "time_ut": 1656531370,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All-time record prices of tea – Siyaka Catalogues",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All-time record prices of tea – Siyaka Catalogues",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In the Uva Medium category, Dickwella Estate of Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC improved on its own record by selling an Invoice of BOPFSP at Rs. 2,350 per kg to Inter Tea Ltd. Similarly, this Estate’s FBOP sold at a new all-time high of Rs. 2,900 per kg to Sunshine Teas Ltd.",
        "This estate is in the capable care of Regional Manager Chaminda Perera and under the supervision of veteran A.M. Shajahan. Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC was the auctioneer of these teas.",
        "Oodoowerre Estate, owned by Hapugastenne Plantations PLC, a member of the LOLC Group and managed by Shammi Upendra, achieved a record price of Rs. 2,150 per kg for BOPSP grade this week.",
        "This tea was purchased by Akbar Brother Ltd., and marketed by Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC.",
        "In the Premium Flowery catalogues, Balangoda Estate under the selling mark of Maratenne FBOPFEXSP improved its own record for this type of tea by achieving Rs. 9,800 per kg. This tea was purchased by Divine Nature Teas Ltd.",
        "This Estate belongs to Balangoda Plantations PLC, a member of Melsta Corp. with the supervision of the Manager Lal Ekanayake. This tea was sold by Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Siyaka Catalogues",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva Medium",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dickwella Estate of Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Invoice of BOPFSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inter Tea Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Estate’s FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,900",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.M. Shajahan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oodoowerre Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hapugastenne Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the LOLC Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shammi Upendra",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Akbar Brother Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premium Flowery",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Balangoda Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maratenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divine Nature Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Balangoda Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melsta Corp.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lal Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තේවල සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල - සියකා නාමාවලිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඌව මධ්‍ය කාණ්ඩයේ, මල්වත්ත වැලි වැවිලි ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී හි දික්වැල්ල වතුයාය, BOPFSP හි ඉන්වොයිසියක් රු. ඉන්ටර් ටී ලිමිටඩ් වෙත කිලෝග්‍රෑමයක් රුපියල් 2,350 කි. ඒ හා සමානව, මෙම වතුයායේ FBOP නව සර්වකාලීන ඉහළම රු. Sunshine Teas Ltd වෙත කිලෝග්‍රෑම් එකක් රුපියල් 2,900 කි.",
        "මෙම වත්ත ප්‍රාදේශීය කළමනාකාර චමින්ද පෙරේරා මහතාගේ දක්‍ෂ රැකවරණය යටතේ පවතින අතර ප්‍රවීණ ඒ.එම්. ෂාජහාන්. Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC මෙම තේ වෙන්දේසිකරුවා විය.",
        "LOLC සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන හපුගස්තැන්නේ වැවිලි සමාගමට අයත්, ශම්මි උපේන්ද්‍ර විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන Oodoowerre Estate, රු. මෙම සතියේ BOPSP ශ්‍රේණිය සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට 2,150.",
        "මෙම තේ අක්බාර් බ්‍රදර් ලිමිටඩ් විසින් මිල දී ගෙන ඇති අතර එය අලෙවි කරනු ලැබුවේ Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC විසිනි.",
        "ප්‍රිමියම් මල් නාමාවලියෙහි, මාරතැන්නේ FBOPFEXSP හි විකුණුම් ලකුණ යටතේ බලංගොඩ වතුයාය මෙම තේ වර්ගය සඳහා රු. 9,800 කි. මෙම තේ Divine Nature Teas Ltd විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම වතුයාය කළමනාකරු ලාල් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ අධීක්‍ෂණය යටතේ මෙල්ස්ටා කෝපරේෂන් හි සාමාජික බලංගොඩ වැවිලි සමාගමට අයත් වේ. මේ තේ අලෙවි කළේ Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සියකා නාමාවලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල්වත්ත වැලි වැවිලි PLC හි දික්වැල්ල වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPFSP හි ඉන්වොයිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,350 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ටර් ටී ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වතුයායේ FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,900 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.එම්. ෂාජහාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩ පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oodoowerre වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හපුගස්තැන්නේ වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂම්මි උපේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,150 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අක්බාර් බ්‍රදර් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරික මල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලංගොඩ වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාරතැන්නේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,800 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divine Nature Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලංගොඩ වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melsta Corp.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාල් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேயிலையின் அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலைகள் - சியாக்கா பட்டியல்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஊவா மீடியம் பிரிவில், மல்வத்தை வேலி பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சியின் டிக்வெல்ல எஸ்டேட், BOPFSPயின் விலைப்பட்டியலை ரூ. ரூபாய்க்கு விற்பனை செய்து அதன் சொந்த சாதனையை மேம்படுத்தியது. இன்டர் டீ லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்திற்கு கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 2,350 ரூபாய். அதேபோன்று, இந்த எஸ்டேட்டின் FBOP ஆனது, இதுவரை இல்லாத அளவுக்கு புதிய ரூ. சன்ஷைன் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் ஒரு கிலோவுக்கு 2,900.",
        "இந்த தோட்டமானது பிராந்திய முகாமையாளர் சமிந்த பெரேராவின் திறமையான பராமரிப்பில் மற்றும் மூத்த இராணுவ வீரர் ஏ.எம். ஷாஜஹான். ஏசியா சியாக்கா கமாடிடிஸ் பிஎல்சி இந்த தேயிலைகளை ஏலத்தில் எடுத்தது.",
        "LOLC குழுமத்தின் அங்கத்தவரும், ஷம்மி உபேந்திராவால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும் ஹபுகஸ்தென்ன பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சிக்கு சொந்தமான ஊடூவெர்ரே தோட்டம், ரூ. சாதனை விலையை எட்டியது. இந்த வாரம் BOPSP தரத்திற்கு ஒரு கிலோவுக்கு 2,150 ரூபாய்.",
        "இந்த தேநீர் அக்பர் பிரதர் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் ஆசியா சியாக்கா கமாடிடீஸ் பிஎல்சியால் சந்தைப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "பிரீமியம் ஃப்ளவர்ரி பட்டியல்களில், மரதன்னே FBOPFEXSP இன் விற்பனை அடையாளத்தின் கீழ் பலாங்கொட தோட்டம், இந்த வகை தேயிலைக்கான தனது சொந்த சாதனையை மேம்படுத்தி ரூ. ஒரு கிலோ 9,800. இந்த தேநீரை டிவைன் நேச்சர் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் வாங்கியது.",
        "முகாமையாளர் லால் ஏக்கநாயக்கவின் மேற்பார்வையில் மெல்ஸ்டா கார்ப்பரேஷனின் உறுப்பினரான பலாங்கொட பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சிக்கு இந்த தோட்டம் சொந்தமானது. இந்த தேநீரை Asia Siyaka Commodities PLC விற்பனை செய்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சியாக்கா பட்டியல்கள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா மீடியம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC இன் டிக்வெல்ல தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPFSP இன்வாய்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இண்டர் டீ லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்டேட்டின் FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,900",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான். ஷாஜஹான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருட்கள் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடூவெர்ரே எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hapugastenne Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷம்மி உபேந்திரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOPSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்பர் பிரதர் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா சியாக்கா கமாடிடிஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரீமியம் பூக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொடை தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரதன்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிவைன் நேச்சர் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொட பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்ஸ்டா கார்ப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லால் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா சியாக்கா கமாடிடிஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}