{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/navy-nabs-03-suspects-with-smuggled-gold/",
  "time_ut": 1658816280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy nabs 03 suspects with smuggled gold",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy nabs 03 suspects with smuggled gold",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Sri Lanka Navy seized about 470 g of gold and a conch shell (Valampuri) attempted to be smuggled from the country, during a special operation carried out on seas off Kurusapadu in Pesalai, Mannar in the dark hours of 25th July 2022.",
        "The operation also led to the apprehension of 03 suspects in connection to the racket.",
        "The Navy remains ever alert to prevent wide-ranging illegal activities taking place via sea routes, by conducting regular search operations and patrols in coastal areas of the island.",
        "As an extension of these efforts, SLNS Thammanna in the North Central Naval Command mounted this special operation off Kurusapadu on the night of 25th July. The seizure was made after inspecting a suspicious dinghy that left Kurusapadu Beach.",
        "The search for the dinghy led to the recovery of about 470 g of gold and a conch shell (Valampuri) suspected to be smuggled from the country.  The Navy also nabbed 03 suspects involved in this racket and the dinghy used to smuggle those items.",
        "Meanwhile, the market value of gold being held in this operation is believed to be over Rs. 09 million.",
        "The suspects held by the Navy were identified as residents of the Puttalam and Pesalai areas, who are from 24 to 39 years of age. The accused together with gold, conch shell, and dinghy were handed over to the Customs Office in Jaffna for onward legal action.",
        "IGP & Senior Cops failed to protect peaceful protestors – HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "03",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valampuri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the dark hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Thammanna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of 25th July",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu Beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valampuri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "09 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 to 39 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "conch shell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Customs Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IGP & Senior Cops",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී රත්‍රං සමඟ සැකකරුවන් 03 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදාව අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) – මන්නාරම, පේසාලේ කුරුසපාඩු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ 25 වැනි දින අඳුරු පැයේදී සිදුකළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටින් රැගෙන යාමට තැත් කළ රත්‍රං ග්‍රෑම් 470ක් සහ හක් කටුවක් (වාලම්පුරි) නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. 2022 ජූලි.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමෙන් ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවන් 03 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ද හැකි විය.",
        "දිවයිනේ වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල නිරන්තර සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුම් සහ මුර සංචාර සිදු කරමින්, මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ සිදුවන පුළුල් පරාසයක නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියා වැළැක්වීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව නිරතුරුව සීරුවෙන් සිටී.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රයත්නයේ දිගුවක් ලෙස උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්මැන්නා විසින් ජුලි මස 25 වන දින රාත්‍රියේ කුරුසපාඩු ඔබ්බෙන් මෙම විශේෂ මෙහෙයුම දියත් කරන ලදී. කුරුසපාඩු වෙරළ තීරයෙන් පිටත්ව ගිය සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් පරීක්ෂා කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදුකර ඇත්තේ.",
        "ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව සෙවීමේදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටින් රැගෙන ආ බවට සැක කෙරෙන රත්‍රං ග්‍රෑම් 470 ක් සහ හක් කටුවක් (වාලම්පුරි) සොයා ගැනීමට හැකි විය. මෙම ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවන් 03 දෙනෙකු සහ එම භාණ්ඩ නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට යොදාගත් ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "මේ අතර, මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී රඳවාගෙන සිටින රත්‍රංවල වෙළඳපල වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ. මිලියන 09 කි.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් පුත්තලම සහ පේසාලෙයි ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි අවුරුදු 24 සිට 39 දක්වා වයස්වල පසුවන්නන් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. සැකකරුවන් රත්‍රං, හක්ක සහ ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව සමඟ ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා යාපනය රේගු කාර්යාලය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන් ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට පොලිස්පති සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් අසමත් විය - HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "03",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "470 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලම්පුරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඳුරු පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්මැන්නා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25 රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "470 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලම්පුරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 09 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 24 සිට 39 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හක්ගෙඩිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடத்தப்பட்ட தங்கத்துடன் 03 சந்தேக நபர்களை கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): மன்னார் பேசாலை குருசபாடு கடற்பரப்பில் கடந்த 25ஆம் திகதி இருளில் மூழ்கிய வேளையில் இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் நாட்டிலிருந்து கடத்த முயன்ற சுமார் 470 கிராம் தங்கம் மற்றும் சங்கு (வலம்புரி) கைப்பற்றினர். ஜூலை 2022.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் மோசடியுடன் தொடர்புடைய 03 சந்தேக நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "தீவின் கரையோரப் பகுதிகளில் வழக்கமான தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கைகள் மற்றும் ரோந்துப் பணிகளை மேற்கொள்வதன் மூலம் கடல் வழிகள் வழியாக நடைபெறும் பரந்த அளவிலான சட்டவிரோதச் செயல்களைத் தடுக்க கடற்படை எப்போதும் விழிப்புடன் உள்ளது.",
        "இந்த முயற்சிகளின் விரிவாக்கமாக, வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையில் உள்ள SLNS தம்மன்னா ஜூலை 25 இரவு குருசபாடு பகுதியில் இந்த சிறப்பு நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டது. குருசபாடு கடற்கரையில் இருந்து சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வகையில் பயணித்த டிங்கி படகு ஒன்றை ஆய்வு செய்த பின்னரே இவ்வாறு கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "டிங்கி படகை தேடும் பணியில் நாட்டிலிருந்து கடத்தப்பட்டதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் சுமார் 470 கிராம் தங்கம் மற்றும் சங்கு (வலம்புரி) ஆகியவை மீட்கப்பட்டன. இந்த மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 03 சந்தேக நபர்களையும், அந்த பொருட்களை கடத்த பயன்படுத்திய டிங்கி படகையும் கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்தனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இந்த நடவடிக்கையில் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட தங்கத்தின் சந்தை மதிப்பு ரூ. 09 மில்லியன்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 24 முதல் 39 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட புத்தளம் மற்றும் பேசாலை பிரதேசங்களை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர். குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டவர்கள் தங்கம், சங்கு மற்றும் டிங்கி படகுகளுடன் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் உள்ள சுங்க அலுவலகத்தில் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்களை பாதுகாக்க ஐஜிபி மற்றும் மூத்த போலீசார் தவறிவிட்டனர் - HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "03",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலம்புரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருண்ட நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS தம்மன்னா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலம்புரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "09 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 முதல் 39 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஜிபி & மூத்த போலீசார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}