{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගිනි-තැබුවේ-රනිල්-රාජකීය-විද්‍යාලයට-පරිත්‍යාග-කළ-නිවසයි/11-395277",
  "time_ut": 1657387870,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගිනි තැබුවේ රනිල් රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයට පරිත්‍යාග කළ නිවසයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The house that Ranil had donated to Royal College was set on fire",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A group of saboteurs disguised as protesters set fire to the house of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, located at Fifth Lane, Colombo, where there were antiques.",
        "The Prime Minister has also issued a last will and testament donating this house to the Royal College of Colombo after him.",
        "Even though Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe is the person who held the office of Prime Minister the most number of times in the country, he never moved to the Colombo Temple Tree House, which was the official residence of the Prime Minister.",
        "Although he went to Temple Tree House for official work, he spent his life in this house. It is also said that some of the books in this house were available in Sri Lanka only in the library of that house.",
        "The Prime Minister as well as his wife Prof. Maithrie Wickramasinghe also spent her life in this house. This house was inherited by the Prime Minister and was built according to the old architecture."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Royal College",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fifth Lane, Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Royal College of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Temple Tree House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Temple Tree House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithrie Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගිනි තැබුවේ රනිල් රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයට පරිත්‍යාග කළ නිවසයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ පස්වන පටුමගේ පිහිටි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට අයත් පෞරාණික භාණ්ඩ තිබූ නිවස විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට මුවා වී සිටි කඩාකප්පල්කාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් ගිනි තැබිමට කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "තමගෙන් පසු මෙම නිවස කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය වෙත පරිත්‍යාග කරමින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා අන්තිම කැමති පත්‍රයක්ද නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මෙරට වැඩිම අවස්ථා ගණනක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යධුරය දැරූ පුද්ගලයා වුවත් ඔහු කිසිම අවස්ථාවක අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නිල නිවස වූ කොළඹ අරලිය ගහ මන්දිරයේ පදිංචියට නොගියේය.",
        "ඔහු රාජකාරී කටයුතු වෙනුවෙන් අරලිය ගහ මන්දිරයට ගියත් ජීවිතය ගත කළේ මෙම නිවසේය. මෙම නිවසේ තිබූ ඇතැම් ග්‍රන්ථ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තිබි ඇත්තේ එම නිවසේ පුස්තකාලයේම පමණක් බවද සඳහන් වෙයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යරයා මෙන්ම ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ වන මහාචාර්ය මෛත්‍රී වික්‍රමසිංහ මහත්මියද සිය ජිවිතය ගත කළේ මෙම නිවසේදීය. මෙම නිවස අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට පරම්පරාවෙන් ලැබී තිබුණ අතර එය පැරිණි ගෘහ නිර්මාණශිල්පය අනුව නිමවා තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන පටුමග, කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රී වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "றோயல் கல்லூரிக்கு ரணில் வழங்கிய வீடு தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு ஐந்தாவது லேனில் அமைந்துள்ள பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வீட்டிற்கு, பழங்காலப் பொருட்கள் இருந்த இடத்திற்கு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் போல் மாறுவேடமிட்ட நாசகாரர்கள் குழுவொன்று தீ வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "தனக்குப் பின்னர் கொழும்பு றோயல் கல்லூரிக்கு இந்த வீட்டை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குவதற்கான கடைசி உயிலையும் பிரதமர் வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டிலேயே அதிக தடவைகள் பிரதமர் பதவியை வகித்தவர் திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க என்ற போதிலும், பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமாக இருந்த கொழும்பு டெம்பிள் ட்ரீ ஹவுஸுக்கு அவர் ஒருபோதும் இடம் பெயர்ந்ததில்லை.",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ வேலைக்காக டெம்பிள் ட்ரீ ஹவுஸுக்குச் சென்றாலும், இந்த வீட்டிலேயே தனது வாழ்க்கையைக் கழித்தார். இந்த வீட்டில் உள்ள சில புத்தகங்கள் அந்த வீட்டின் நூலகத்தில் மட்டுமே இலங்கையில் கிடைத்ததாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "பிரதமர் மற்றும் அவரது மனைவி பேராசிரியர் மைத்திரி விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் இந்த வீட்டில்தான் தனது வாழ்நாளைக் கழித்தார். இந்த வீடு பிரதமரால் மரபுரிமையாக பெறப்பட்டு பழைய கட்டிடக்கலைப்படி கட்டப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராயல் கல்லூரி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது பாதை, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு ராயல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு டெம்பிள் ட்ரீ ஹவுஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெம்பிள் ட்ரீ ஹவுஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரி விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}