{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-cabinet-nod-for-cost-based-cooking-gas-pricing-formula-98360/",
  "time_ut": 1660026660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka cabinet nod for cost-based cooking gas pricing formula",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka cabinet nod for cost-based cooking gas pricing formula",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s cabinet of ministers has approved a proposal to introduce a cost-based pricing formula for cooking gas that will liquid petroleum (LP) gas prices received once a month.",
        "The proposal, made by President Ranil Wickremesinghe in his capacity as the Minister of Finance, will see gas prices revised on the fifth of every month according to the formula, reflecting cost.",
        "The goal of this decision is to ensure an interrupted supply of domestic gas, a statement from the government information department said on Tuesday August 09. (Colombo/Aug09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the government information department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පිරිවැය මත පදනම් වූ ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් මිල සූත්‍රයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - මසකට වරක් ලැබෙන ද්‍රව පෙට්‍රෝලියම් (LP) ගෑස් මිල ගණන් ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සඳහා පිරිවැය මත පදනම් වූ මිල සූත්‍රයක් හඳුන්වා දීමේ යෝජනාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇත.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද යෝජනාවට අනුව සෑම මසකම පස්වැනිදා ගෑස් මිල සූත්‍රයට අනුව පිරිවැය පිළිබිඹු කරමින් සංශෝධනය කෙරේ.",
        "මෙම තීරණයේ ඉලක්කය වනුයේ ගෘහස්ථ ගෑස් සැපයුම අත්හිටුවීම සහතික කිරීම බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිවේදනයක් අගෝස්තු 09 අඟහරුවාදා (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 09 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விலை அடிப்படையிலான சமையல் எரிவாயு விலை சூத்திரத்திற்கு இலங்கை அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - மாதம் ஒருமுறை பெறப்படும் திரவ பெட்ரோலியம் (LP) எரிவாயு விலையை குறைக்கும் சமையல் எரிவாயுக்கான செலவு அடிப்படையிலான விலை சூத்திரத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்தும் முன்மொழிவுக்கு இலங்கையின் அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது.",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணையில், செலவை பிரதிபலிக்கும் வகையில் எரிவாயு விலை சூத்திரத்தின்படி ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும் ஐந்தாம் திகதி திருத்தப்படும்.",
        "இந்த முடிவின் இலக்கானது உள்நாட்டு எரிவாயு விநியோகத்தில் தடைபடுவதை உறுதி செய்வதாகும் என அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தின் அறிக்கை ஒன்று ஆகஸ்ட் 09 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு தகவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 09 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}