{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131148",
  "time_ut": 1657358688,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்  பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அவசர கடிதம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Members of Parliament Urgent Letter to the President",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "A group of 16 members of parliament of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna have sent a letter demanding the immediate resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "In this case, in the said letter, they have requested to give an opportunity to an experienced leader who has no corruption charges.",
        "They also pointed out the need to give a chance to a leader who can win a clear parliamentary majority representing the Parliament.",
        "It is noteworthy that the group of parliamentarians of the said Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna includes Dulles Alagaperuma, Channa Jayasumana and Nalaka Kodahewa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament Urgent Letter",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Kodahewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ජනපතිට හදිසි ලිපියක්",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 16 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් ලිපියක් යවා තිබේ.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී දූෂණ චෝදනා නොමැති පළපුරුදු නායකයෙකුට අවස්ථාවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඔවුන් එම ලිපියෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන පැහැදිලි පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරයක් දිනාගත හැකි නායකයෙකුට අවස්ථාවක් ලබාදීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය ද ඔවුන් පෙන්වා දුන්නා.",
        "එම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායමට ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම, චන්න ජයසුමන සහ නාලක කොඩහේවා ඇතුළත් වීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ හදිසි ලිපිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක කොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்  பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அவசர கடிதம்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் 16  பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி கடிதமொன்றை அனுப்பியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் குறித்த கடிதத்தில், ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் இல்லாத அனுபவமுள்ள  தலைவருக்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்குமாறு கோரியுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் தெளிவான பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை வெல்லக்கூடிய தலைவருக்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தையும் அவர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "குறித்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவில் டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும, சன்ன ஜயசுமண மற்றும் நாலக கொடஹேவா ஆகியோர் அடங்குகின்றமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்ற அவசர கடிதம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}