{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/20/parliament-to-elect-new-president-today-20/",
  "time_ut": 1658280720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament to elect new President today (20)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament to elect new President today (20)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Parliament is scheduled to convene today (20) at 10.00 AM to elect a new President.",
        "The names of three Members of Parliament were proposed and seconded in the Parliament yesterday (19) for the vacancy of the Presidency, with the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Accordingly, the names of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, Member of Parliament Dullas Alahapperuma and Member of Parliament Anura Kumara Dissanayake were proposed.",
        "Member of Parliament Dullas Alahapperuma’s name was proposed by the Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa and Member of Parliament (Prof.) G.L. Peiris seconded it. Ranil Wickremesinghe’s name was proposed by the Leader of the House and Minister Dinesh Gunawardena and the Member of Parliament Manusha Nanayakkara seconded it. Also, Member of Parliament Anura Kumara Dissanayake was proposed by the Member of Parliament Vijitha Herath and Member of Parliament (Dr.) Harini Amarasuriya seconded it.",
        "Subsequently, the Secretary General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake announced that the nominations of these three candidates were accepted for Succeeding President following the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981.",
        "Thus, today (20) one of these three MPs is to be elected as the Succeeding President by the votes of the Members of Parliament.",
        "Last week (14) the former President sent his resignation letter to the Speaker. Accordingly, the Parliament was summoned on the 16th and the Secretary General of the Parliament announced to the House that the office of the President has become vacant. Also, he announced that nominations will be accepted by the Members of Parliament to fill the vacancy. Accordingly, yesterday (19) nominations for the post of President were accepted.",
        "After the election Parliament will convene again on the 27th Wednesday.",
        "Sajith & Dullas sit together for first press conference after nomination",
        "National Fuel Pass QR program island-wide implementation from 25th July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 AM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dullas Alahapperuma’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Succeeding",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith & Dullas",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද (20)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද (20) පෙරවරු 10.00 ට රැස්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ නම් ඊයේ (19) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී යෝජනා වී ස්ථිර කෙරිණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් යෝජනා විය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාගේ නම විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කළ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතා එය ස්ථිර කළේය. එහිදී සභානායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා එය ස්ථිර කළේය. එමෙන්ම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා විසින් අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මන්ත්‍රීවරයා යෝජනා කළ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (ආචාර්ය) හරිනි අමරසූරිය මහත්මිය එය ස්ථිර කළාය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා නිවේදනය කළේ 1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතට අනුව මෙම අපේක්ෂකයින් තිදෙනාගේ නාමයෝජනා සාර්ථක ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා පිළිගත් බවයි.",
        "මේ අනුව අද (20) මෙම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනාගෙන් එක් අයෙකු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඡන්දයෙන් අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ (14) හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායකවරයා වෙත යොමු කළා. ඒ අනුව පසුගිය 16 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවූ අතර එහිදී ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා සභාවට දැනුම් දුන්නා. එමෙන්ම පුරප්පාඩු වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරය සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් නාමයෝජනා භාර ගන්නා බවද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළා. ඒ අනුව ඊයේ (19) ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "මැතිවරණයෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව 27 වැනි බදාදා යළි රැස්වේ.",
        "නාමයෝජනා දීමෙන් පසු පළමු මාධ්‍ය හමුවට සජිත් සහ ඩලස් එකට වාඩි වෙති",
        "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍ර QR වැඩසටහන ජූලි 25 සිට දිවයින පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක කෙරේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුමගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාර්ථක වෙනවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් සහ ඩලස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இன்று (20) புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (20) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமாவை அடுத்து வெற்றிடமான ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு மூன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர்கள் நேற்று (19) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்டு உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "இதன்படி, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்டன.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயர் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவினால் முன்மொழியப்பட்டதுடன், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார். ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பெயரை சபைத் தலைவர் மற்றும் அமைச்சர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன முன்மொழிந்தார் மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார அதனை ஆதரித்தார். அத்துடன், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத் முன்மொழிந்ததோடு, நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (டாக்டர்) ஹரிணி அமரசூரிய அதனை ஆதரித்தார்.",
        "அதனையடுத்து, 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்திற்கு அமைய இந்த மூன்று வேட்பாளர்களின் வேட்புமனுக்கள் வெற்றிகரமான ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க அறிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்தவகையில் இன்று (20) இந்த மூன்று எம்.பி.க்களில் ஒருவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வாக்குகளினால் வெற்றிகரமான ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட உள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் (14) முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்பியுள்ளார். இதன்படி கடந்த 16ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றம் கூட்டப்பட்டு ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகம் வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் சபைக்கு அறிவித்தார். மேலும், வெற்றிடத்தை நிரப்புவதற்கு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஏற்கப்படும் என்றும் அவர் அறிவித்தார். அதன்படி நேற்று (19) ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டன.",
        "தேர்தலின் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றம் மீண்டும் 27ஆம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "சஜித் & டல்லாஸ் நியமனத்திற்குப் பிறகு முதல் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் ஒன்றாக அமர்ந்துள்ளனர்",
        "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR திட்டம் ஜூலை 25 முதல் நாடு முழுவதும் செயல்படுத்தப்படுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெற்றி பெறுகிறது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் & டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}