{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131484",
  "time_ut": 1657850447,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாவின் பதவி விலகலை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக இன்று அறிவிப்பார் சபாநாயகர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Speaker will officially announce President Kota's resignation today",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena will officially announce the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa this morning.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has sent a letter of resignation to the Speaker yesterday (14) following the intensification of the people's protest.",
        "The letter regarding the Speaker has been sent to the Legislature for legal advice and it is expected that the Speaker will officially announce the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to the people today.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who left the country for the Maldives after protesters besieged the Presidential Palace, announced his resignation through the Speaker after arriving in Singapore on Thursday (14) evening.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa is considered to be the first president since Sri Lanka's independence to resign before the end of his term."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kota",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති කොටාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායකවරයා විසින් අද නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරනු ඇත",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් අද පෙරවරුවේ නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරනු ඇත.",
        "ජනතා විරෝධය උත්සන්න වීමත් සමඟ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ (14) කථානායකවරයා වෙත ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියක් යවා තිබේ.",
        "කථානායකවරයාට අදාළ ලිපිය නීති උපදෙස් සඳහා ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය වෙත යවා ඇති අතර, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායකවරයා විසින් අද දිනයේදී නිල වශයෙන් ජනතාවට ප්‍රකාශ කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය වටලා ගැනීමත් සමඟ රටින් පිටව ගොස් මාලදිවයිනට ගිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (14) සවස සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු කතානායකවරයා මාර්ගයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු සිය ධුර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර ඉල්ලා අස් වූ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සැලකේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොටා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாவின் பதவி விலகலை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக இன்று அறிவிப்பார் சபாநாயகர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவிவிலகினார் என்பதை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன இன்று காலை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "மக்கள் போராட்டம் தீவிரமடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யும் கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகருக்கு நேற்று வியாழக்கிழமை (14) அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "சட்ட ஆலோசனைகளுக்காக சபாநாயகர் குறித்த கடிதத்தை சட்டமாதிபருபக்கு அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளதுடன் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி விலகல் தொடர்பில் சபாநாயகர் நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக இன்று அறிவிப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "போராட்டகாரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்டதை தொடர்ந்து நாட்டிலிருந்து மாலைதீவிற்கு வெளியேறிய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ அங்கிருந்து நேற்று வியாழக்கிழமை (14) மாலை சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து தனது பதவி விலகலை சபாநாயகர் ஊடாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற காலத்திற்கு பின்னர் பதவி காலம் நிறைவடைவதற்கு முன்னர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்த முதலாவது ஜனாதிபதியாக கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ  கருதப்படுகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}