{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Number-of-vehicles-can-now-be-registered-under-BRN-under-NFP-ICTA/108-242995",
  "time_ut": 1660453770,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Number of vehicles can now be registered under BRN under NFP: ICTA",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Number of vehicles can now be registered under BRN under NFP: ICTA",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Information and Communication Technology Agency of Sri Lanka (ICTA) today said Businesses with large fleet of vehicles can now be registered with their Business Registration Numbers (BRN) from today under the National Fuel Pass (NFP).",
        "They said government institutes, organizations and businesses can register their fleet of vehicles under BRN category through one or multiple mobile numbers under one BRN.",
        "Such vehicles will be given a specific QR code through the portal after verification.",
        "The Power and Energy Ministry said the government institutions will be given a set of guidelines upon BRNs assigned to them.",
        "Meanwhile, the ministry requested the public to register with the new Fuel Pass System as early as they can, and not to misuse the system to obtain fuel by illegal means.",
        "Moreover, they said the fuel requirements for machinery must be registered with the respective Divisonal Secretariats citing the weekly fuel requirement. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "BRN",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "NFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Information and Communication Technology Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Fuel Pass",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Power and Energy Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Divisonal Secretariats",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වාහන සංඛ්‍යාව දැන් BRN යටතේ NFP: ICTA යටතේ ලියාපදිංචි කළ හැක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ නියෝජිතායතනය (ICTA) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ විශාල වාහන තොගයක් ඇති ව්‍යාපාරවලට ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රය (NFP) යටතේ අද සිට ඔවුන්ගේ ව්‍යාපාර ලියාපදිංචි අංක (BRN) සමඟ ලියාපදිංචි විය හැකි බවයි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන, සංවිධාන සහ ව්‍යාපාරවලට BRN කාණ්ඩය යටතේ ජංගම දුරකථන අංක එකක් හෝ කිහිපයක් හරහා BRN යටතේ ලියාපදිංචි කළ හැකි බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "එවැනි වාහන සත්‍යාපනය කිරීමෙන් පසු ද්වාරය හරහා නිශ්චිත QR කේතයක් ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන වෙත පවරා ඇති BRN පිළිබඳ මාර්ගෝපදේශ මාලාවක් ලබා දෙන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, නව ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍ර ක්‍රමයට හැකි ඉක්මනින් ලියාපදිංචි වන ලෙසත්, නීති විරෝධී ක්‍රම මගින් ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා එම පද්ධතිය අවභාවිත නොකරන ලෙසත් අමාත්‍යාංශය ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා.",
        "තවද, සතිපතා ඉන්ධන අවශ්‍යතාවය සඳහන් කරමින් යන්ත්‍රෝපකරණ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන අවශ්‍යතා අදාළ ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලවල ලියාපදිංචි කළ යුතු බව ද ඔවුහු පැවසූහ. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "BRN",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "NFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ නියෝජිතායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BRN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "NFP: ICTA இன் கீழ் BRN இன் கீழ் வாகனங்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை இப்போது பதிவு செய்யலாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தகவல் மற்றும் தொடர்பாடல் தொழிநுட்ப முகவர் நிறுவனம் (ICTA) இன்று முதல் தேசிய எரிபொருள் அனுமதிச் சீட்டின் (NFP) கீழ் பெருமளவிலான வாகனங்களைக் கொண்ட வணிகங்கள் தங்களது வணிகப் பதிவு எண்களுடன் (BRN) பதிவு செய்ய முடியும் என இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அரசு நிறுவனங்கள், நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் வணிகங்கள் BRN பிரிவின் கீழ் தங்கள் வாகனங்களை ஒரு BRN இன் கீழ் ஒன்று அல்லது பல மொபைல் எண்கள் மூலம் பதிவு செய்யலாம் என்று அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அத்தகைய வாகனங்கள் சரிபார்த்த பிறகு போர்டல் மூலம் குறிப்பிட்ட QR குறியீடு வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம், அரசு நிறுவனங்களுக்கு ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட BRN கள் குறித்த வழிகாட்டுதல்களின் தொகுப்பு வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "இதேவேளை, புதிய எரிபொருள் அனுமதிச் சீட்டு முறைமையுடன் கூடிய விரைவில் பதிவு செய்யுமாறும், சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் எரிபொருளைப் பெறுவதற்கு முறையற்ற முறையில் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம் என்றும் அமைச்சு பொதுமக்களிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், இயந்திரங்களுக்கான எரிபொருள் தேவைகள் வாராந்த எரிபொருள் தேவையை மேற்கோள் காட்டி அந்தந்த பிரதேச செயலகங்களில் பதிவு செய்யப்பட வேண்டும் என்று அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிஆர்என்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "NFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தகவல் மற்றும் தொடர்பு தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஆர்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஆர்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஆர்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}