{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/adani-given-approval-for-two-wind-projects/",
  "time_ut": 1660667160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Adani given approval for Two Wind Projects",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Adani given approval for Two Wind Projects",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera said that Adani Green Energy was issued Provisional Approvals for two Wind projects of 286 MW in Mannar & 234 MW in Pooneryn for an Investment of over USD 500 Million.",
        "The Minister met officials of CEB & the Sustainable Development Authority today (16) to discuss the progress of renewable energy projects.",
        "In addition, 21 of 46 Projects that were delayed due to CEB Act amendments will enter into Public-Private agreements next week, he tweeted.",
        "\"26 Renewable proposals from EOIs that were given Provisional Approvals to be expedited with Grid clearance & transmission plans,\" he added.",
        "Other proposals are to be evaluated within 30 days, Minister Kanchana tweeted.",
        "The land may divide us, but the sky and the ocean unites us all: Wimal at the welcome ceremony for Yuan Wang 5",
        "Polish man arrested with Rs. 245 Mn worth Cocaine by Customs"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "286",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar & 234",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pooneryn",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB & the Sustainable Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 Renewable",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cocaine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Adani සුලං ව්‍යාපෘති දෙකකට අනුමැතිය දුන්නා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මන්නාරමේ මෙගාවොට් 286 ක සහ පුනරින් මෙගාවොට් 234 ක සුළං ව්‍යාපෘති දෙකක් සඳහා ඇ.ඩො. මිලියන 500 කට වැඩි ආයෝජනයක් සඳහා ඇඩානි ග්‍රීන් එන්ජි සමාගමට තාවකාලික අනුමැතිය ලබා දුන් බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ව්‍යාපෘතිවල ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා අමාත්‍යවරයා අද (16) විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ සහ තිරසාර සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ නිලධාරීන් හමුවිය.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ලංවිම පනත් සංශෝධන හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රමාද වූ ව්‍යාපෘති 46 න් 21 ක් ලබන සතියේ රාජ්‍ය-පෞද්ගලික ගිවිසුම්වලට එළැඹෙන බව ඔහු ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"EOI වෙතින් පුනර්ජනනීය යෝජනා 26ක් ජාල නිෂ්කාශනය සහ සම්ප්‍රේෂණ සැලසුම් සමඟ කඩිනම් කිරීම සඳහා තාවකාලික අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "අනෙකුත් යෝජනා දින 30ක් ඇතුළත ඇගයීමට ලක් කිරීමට නියමිත බව අමාත්‍ය කාංචන ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ගොඩබිම අපිව බෙදන්න පුළුවන්, නමුත් අහසයි සාගරයයි අපි හැමෝම එකතු කරනවා: යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයේදී විමල්",
        "රුපියල් කෝටි 1000ක් සමඟ පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට මිලියන 245ක් වටිනා කොකේන් රේගුවෙන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "286",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම සහ 234",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුනරීන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම සහ තිරසර සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 පුනර්ජනනීය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොකේන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு காற்று திட்டங்களுக்கு அதானி ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அதானி கிரீன் எனர்ஜி மன்னாரில் 286 மெகாவாட் மற்றும் பூனேரியில் 234 மெகாவாட் திறன் கொண்ட இரண்டு காற்றாலை திட்டங்களுக்கு 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கும் அதிகமான முதலீட்டில் தற்காலிக அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி திட்டங்களின் முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக அமைச்சர் இன்று (16) CEB மற்றும் நிலையான அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் அதிகாரிகளை சந்தித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், CEB சட்டத் திருத்தங்களால் தாமதமான 46 திட்டங்களில் 21 திட்டங்கள் அடுத்த வாரம் பொது-தனியார் ஒப்பந்தங்களில் கையெழுத்திடப்படும் என்று அவர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"26 EOI களின் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க முன்மொழிவுகள், கிரிட் கிளியரன்ஸ் மற்றும் டிரான்ஸ்மிஷன் திட்டங்களுடன் விரைவுபடுத்தப்படுவதற்கு தற்காலிக ஒப்புதல்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டன,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "மற்ற திட்டங்கள் 30 நாட்களுக்குள் மதிப்பீடு செய்யப்படும் என்று அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "நிலம் நம்மைப் பிரிக்கலாம், ஆனால் வானமும் கடலும் நம்மை ஒன்றிணைக்கிறது: யுவான் வாங் 5-க்கு வரவேற்பு விழாவில் விமல்",
        "போலந்து நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த நபர் ரூ. சுங்கத்தால் 245 மில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள கோகோயின்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "286",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் & 234",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூனேரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB & நிலையான அபிவிருத்தி ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்கது",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போலிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகோயின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}