{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83590/over-225kg-of-kerala-cannabis-seized-in-mannar",
  "time_ut": 1657570680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Over 225kg of Kerala cannabis seized in Mannar",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Over 225kg of Kerala cannabis seized in Mannar",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Navy has seized over 225kg of Kerala cannabis, during special operations conducted in the beach area of Thewampiddi and Sand Banks in Mannar on Monday (11). The operations also led to the apprehension of a suspect in connection to one of the incidents.",
        "SLNS Buwaneka in the North Central Naval Command had searched a suspicious dinghy arrived at the Thewampiddi Beach. The search of the dinghy led to the seizure of about 203kg of Kerala cannabis in 99 packages which had been concealed in a fishing net. Along with the consignment, the Navy also took hold of 01 suspect and the dinghy used to smuggle narcotics.",
        "Meanwhile, a group of SLN Marines attached to SLNS Thammanna in the North Central Naval Command also made a recovery of 05 packages of Kerala cannabis, weighing about 22kg and 140g (wet weight) washed ashore, during a patrol carried out at Mannar Sand Banks.",
        "The gross street value of seized Kerala cannabis is believed to be over Rs. 67 million.",
        "The suspect, who was taken into custody by the Navy with Kerala cannabis in Mulankavil area, was identified as a 45-year-old resident of Thewampiddi. The suspect along with Kerala cannabis and the dinghy will be handed over to Illuppukadawai Police for onward legal action.",
        "Kerala cannabis held at Sand Banks has been kept in naval custody until it is produced for onward legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "225kg",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mannar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thewampiddi and Sand Banks in Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Buwaneka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thewampiddi Beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 203kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN Marines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Thammanna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 22kg and 140",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar Sand Banks",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thewampiddi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Illuppukadawai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sand Banks",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්නාරමේදී කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 225කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් පෙරේදා (11) දින මන්නාරම තේවම්පිඩ්ඩි සහ වැලි ඉවුර ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු කළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 225 කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. එක් සිද්ධියකට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ද මෙම මෙහෙයුම් හේතු විය.",
        "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා බුවනෙක නෞකාව තේවම්පිඩ්ඩි වෙරළ තීරයට පැමිණි සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් සෝදිසි කර ඇත. ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව සෝදිසි කිරීමේදී ධීවර දැලක සඟවා තිබූ අසුරණ 99ක තිබී කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 203ක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. එම තොගය සමඟ සැකකරුවන් 01 දෙනෙකු සහ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට යොදාගත් ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්මැන්නා වෙත අනුයුක්ත නාවිකයන් පිරිසක් ද මන්නාරම වැලි ඉවුරේ සිදුකළ මුර සංචාරයකදී වෙරළට ගසාගෙන ආ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 22 යි ග්‍රෑම් 140 ක් පමණ බර (තෙත් බර) පැකේජ 05 ක් සොයා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයේ දළ වීදි වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ. මිලියන 67 කි.",
        "මුලන්කාවිල් ප්‍රදේශයේදී කේරළ ගංජා සමඟ නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු තේවම්පිඩ්ඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 45 හැවිරිදි අයෙක්. සැකකරු සහ කේරළ ගංජා තොගය සහ ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඉලුප්පුකඩවායි පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "වැලි ඉවුරේ රඳවාගෙන සිටි කේරළ ගංජා ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කරන තෙක් නාවික හමුදා භාරයේ තබාගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "225kg",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මන්නාරම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරමේ තේවම්පිඩ්ඩි සහ වැලි ඉවුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා බුවනෙක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේවම්පිඩ්ඩි වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "203kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN මැරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්මැන්නා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22kg සහ 140 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම වැලි ඉවුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 67 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේවම්පිඩ්ඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලුප්පුකඩවායි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලි බැංකු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மன்னாரில் 225 கிலோகிராம் கேரள கஞ்சா கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் மன்னார், தேவம்பிடி கடற்கரை மற்றும் மணல் கரை பகுதியில் திங்கட்கிழமை (11) மேற்கொண்ட விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் போது 225 கிலோகிராம் கேரள கஞ்சாவை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர். இந்த நடவடிக்கைகள் ஒரு சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சந்தேகத்திற்குரிய ஒருவரைப் பிடிக்கவும் வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையில் உள்ள SLNS புவனேகா, தேவம்பிடி கடற்கரைக்கு வந்த சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான படகு ஒன்றை சோதனையிட்டுள்ளது. டிங்கி படகு சோதனையில் மீன்பிடி வலையில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 99 பொதிகளில் இருந்த சுமார் 203 கிலோ கேரள கஞ்சா பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டது. இந்தச் சரக்குகளுடன், 01 சந்தேக நபர் மற்றும் போதைப்பொருள் கடத்துவதற்குப் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட டிங்கி படகும் கடற்படையினரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையின் SLNS தம்மன்னாவுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட SLN கடற்படையினர் குழு மன்னார் மணல் கரையில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட ரோந்து நடவடிக்கையின் போது 22 கிலோ 140 கிராம் (ஈரமான எடை) எடையுள்ள 05 கேரள கஞ்சா பொதிகளையும் மீட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த மதிப்பு ரூ. ரூ. 67 மில்லியன்.",
        "முழங்காவில் பகுதியில் கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர் 45 வயதுடைய தேவம்பிடி பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என தெரியவந்துள்ளது. சந்தேகநபர் மற்றும் கேரள கஞ்சா மற்றும் டிங்கி படகு ஆகியவை இலுப்புக்கடவை பொலிஸாரிடம் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளன.",
        "மணல் வங்கிகளில் வைத்திருந்த கேரள கஞ்சா, சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படும் வரை கடற்படை காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "225 கிலோ",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மன்னார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னாரில் உள்ள தேவம்பிடி மற்றும் மணல் கரைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS புவனேகா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேவம்பிடி கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 203 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN கடற்படையினர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS தம்மன்னா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 22 கிலோ மற்றும் 140",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் மணல் கரைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேவம்பிடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலுப்புக்கடவாய் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணல் வங்கிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}