{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මහජන-උපයෝගීතා-කොමිසමේ-සභාපති-ඉවත්-කරන්නැයි-ඉල්ලයි/1-615922",
  "time_ut": 1657035886,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මහජන උපයෝගීතා කොමිසමේ සභාපති ඉවත් කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Chairman of the Public Utilities Commission is requested to be removed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At the ruling party meeting held yesterday (04), a group of MPs have requested that the chairman of the Public Utilities Commission, Mr. Janaka Ratnayake, be removed from that position.",
        "The MPs have pointed out that the government is also embarrassed by the misleading statements made by the Chairman of the Public Utility Commission at the press conference.",
        "Therefore, the MPs have requested the President and the Prime Minister to take steps to remove him immediately",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe who has replied to this has stated that if he hands over a letter signed by 113 Members of Parliament, steps can be taken to remove him."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utility Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහජන උපයෝගීතා කොමිසමේ සභාපති ඉවත් කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහජන උපයෝගීතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා එම ධුරයෙන් ඉවත්කරන්නැයි මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් පෙරේදා (04) පැවති ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ රැස්වීමේදී ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇත.",
        "මහජන උපයෝගීතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා මාධ්‍ය හමුවට පැමිණ කරන ජනතාව නොමග යවන ප්‍රකාශ වලින් ආණ්ඩුවද අපහසුතාවට පත්වන බව එම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පෙන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් ඔහු වහාම ඉවත් කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නැයි මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් සහ අගමැතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත",
        "ඊට පිළිතුරු දී ඇති අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 113කගේ අත්සන් සහිත ලිපියක් භාර දෙන්නේ නම් ඔහු ඉවත් කිරීමට පියවර ගත හැකි බව සඳහන් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவரை நீக்குமாறு கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் திரு.ஜானக ரத்நாயக்கவை அந்தப் பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்குமாறு நேற்று (04) இடம்பெற்ற ஆளும் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்தில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் பொதுப் பயன்பாட்டு ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் வெளியிட்ட தவறான கருத்துக்களால் அரசாங்கமும் தர்மசங்கடத்திற்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே அவரை உடனடியாக பதவி நீக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரிடம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்",
        "இதற்கு பதிலளித்துள்ள பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 113 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் கையொப்பமிடப்பட்ட கடிதத்தை கையளித்தால் அவரை நீக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க முடியும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}