{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/complaint-filed-against-slpp-mps-comments/",
  "time_ut": 1661529180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Complaint filed against SLPP MPs’ comments",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Complaint filed against SLPP MPs’ comments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A Sri Lankan Engineer filed a complaint with the Criminal Investigation Department regarding a recent statement made by Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna MP Sanath Nishantha.",
        "Accordingly, Engineer Tilak Pattiyakumbura lodged the relevant complaint, alleging the MP committed Contempt of Court in his recent statements to the media.",
        "He pointed out that protecting the judicial system of a country is a right of the people and citizens, and therefore he filed a complaint in this regard.",
        "Pattiyakumbura requested authorities to conduct an investigation regarding the relevant statement and to impose a suitable punishment against the MP.",
        "Linking lives and villages: Gammadda launches bridge construction in remote Kegalle",
        "Children need to be at heart of resolving SL crisis: UNICEF regional director"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pattiyakumbura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Contempt of Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pattiyakumbura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ප්‍රකාශවලට එරෙහිව පැමිණිල්ලක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත පසුගියදා සිදුකළ ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉංජිනේරුවරයෙකු අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කළා.",
        "ඒ අනුව මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පසුගියදා මාධ්‍ය වෙත කළ ප්‍රකාශවලින් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බවට චෝදනා කරමින් ඉංජිනේරු තිලක් පට්ටියකුඹුර අදාළ පැමිණිල්ල ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "රටක අධිකරණ පද්ධතිය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම ජනතාවගේ සහ පුරවැසියන්ගේ අයිතිවාසිකමක් බවත්, එබැවින් ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කළ බවත් ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "අදාළ ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට එරෙහිව සුදුසු දඩුවමක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස පට්ටියක්ඹුර බලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියා.",
        "ජීවිත සහ ගම් සම්බන්ධ කිරීම: ගම්මැද්ද දුර බැහැර කෑගල්ලේ පාලම් ඉදිකිරීම ආරම්භ කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අර්බුදය විසඳීමේ හදවතේ දරුවන් සිටිය යුතුයි: යුනිසෙෆ් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පට්ටියක්ඹුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණයට අපහාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පට්ටියක්ඹුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் கருத்துக்கு எதிராக முறைப்பாடு பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த அண்மையில் வெளியிட்ட கருத்து தொடர்பில் இலங்கை பொறியியலாளர் ஒருவர் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்தில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதற்கமைய, பொறியியலாளர் திலக் பட்டியகும்புர, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அண்மையில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு வழங்கிய அறிக்கைகளில் நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாகக் கூறி உரிய முறைப்பாட்டை தாக்கல் செய்தார்.",
        "ஒரு நாட்டின் நீதித்துறையை பாதுகாப்பது மக்கள் மற்றும் குடிமக்களின் உரிமை எனவும், எனவே இது தொடர்பில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "குறித்த அறிக்கை தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்தி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருக்கு தகுந்த தண்டனை வழங்குமாறு பட்டியாகும்புர அதிகாரிகளிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "வாழ்க்கையையும் கிராமங்களையும் இணைக்கிறது: கேகாலை தொலைவில் பாலம் கட்டும் பணியை கம்மத்தா தொடங்கினார்",
        "இலங்கை நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதில் குழந்தைகள் இதயத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டும்: யுனிசெஃப் பிராந்திய இயக்குநர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பட்டியகும்புர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பட்டியகும்புர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}