{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Cabinet-Sub-Committee-tasked-to-plan-75th-Independence-Day-celebrations/56-738781",
  "time_ut": 1660688531,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cabinet Sub-Committee  tasked to plan 75th Independence Day celebrations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cabinet Sub-Committee  tasked to plan 75th Independence Day celebrations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "National anthem to be sung in official languages of Sinhala and Tamil",
        "The Government has appointed a Cabinet Sub-Committee to organise celebrations of the 75th Independence Day next year with plans underway to recommence singing the national anthem in the official languages of Sinhala and Tamil.",
        "The Committee comprises President Ranil Wickremesinghe, and Subject Minister and Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardana.",
        "The Committee also includes; Ministers Douglas Devananda, Susil Premajayantha, Bandula Gunawardena, Keheliya Rambukwella, Ali Sabry, Vidura Wickramanayaka, Kanchana Wijesekera, and Tiran Alles.",
        "The proposal to this effect was submitted by Premier Gunawardena in his capacity as the Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils, and Local Government Minister, and was approved by the Cabinet of Ministers on Monday.",
        "“The national anthem will be sung as usual in both Sinhala and Tamil, as both are national languages,” Cabinet Co-Spokesman and Minister Bandula Gunawardena told journalists in response to a query at the post-Cabinet meeting media briefing held yesterday.",
        "The national anthem was not sung in Tamil at an Independence Day celebration since the change of Government in November 2019 following the election of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cabinet Sub-Committee",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "75th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Independence Day",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Sub-Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidura Wickramanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tiran Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "75 වැනි නිදහස් දින සැමරුම සැලසුම් කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුකමිටුවට පැවරී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ගීය සිංහල සහ දෙමළ යන රාජ්‍ය භාෂාවලින් ගායනා කෙරේ",
        "ලබන වසරේ 75 වැනි ජාතික නිදහස් දින සැමරුම් උත්සව සංවිධානය කිරීම සඳහා රජය විසින් කැබිනට් අනුකමිටුවක් පත් කර ඇති අතර ජාතික ගීය සිංහල සහ දෙමළ රාජ්‍ය භාෂාවලින් ගායනා කිරීම ආරම්භ කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම කමිටුවට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ විෂය භාර අමාත්‍ය සහ අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "කමිටුවට ඇතුළත් වන්නේ; අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද, සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, අලි සබ්රි, විදුර වික්‍රමනායක, කාංචන විජේසේකර සහ ටිරාන් අලස්.",
        "ඒ සඳහා වූ යෝජනාව රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද අතර, සඳුදා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කරන ලදී.",
        "\"සිංහල සහ දෙමළ භාෂා දෙකම ජාතික භාෂා බැවින් ජාතික ගීය සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි ගායනා කරන බව\" කැබිනට් සම ප්‍රකාශක සහ අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ඊයේ පැවති කැබිනට් රැස්වීමෙන් පසු මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් කළ විමසීමකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තේරී පත්වීමෙන් පසු 2019 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී ආණ්ඩු වෙනස් වීමෙන් පසු ජාතික ගීය දෙමළ භාෂාවෙන් ගායනා නොකළ නිදහස් දින උත්සවයකදීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කැබිනට් අනුකමිටුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "75 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් අනුකමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුර වික්‍රමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිරාන් අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "75வது சுதந்திர தின விழாவை திட்டமிட அமைச்சரவை துணைக்குழு பணித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய கீதம் சிங்களம் மற்றும் தமிழ் ஆகிய உத்தியோகபூர்வ மொழிகளில் பாடப்பட வேண்டும்",
        "அடுத்த ஆண்டு 75 ஆவது சுதந்திர தின கொண்டாட்டங்களை ஏற்பாடு செய்வதற்கு அரசாங்கம் அமைச்சரவை உபகுழுவொன்றை நியமித்துள்ளதுடன், தேசிய கீதத்தை சிங்களம் மற்றும் தமிழ் ஆகிய உத்தியோகபூர்வ மொழிகளில் மீண்டும் பாடுவதற்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் அமைச்சர் மற்றும் பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் அங்கம் வகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "குழுவும் அடங்கும்; அமைச்சர்களான டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா, சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, பந்துல குணவர்தன, கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, அலி சப்ரி, விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்க, காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, டிரன் அலஸ்.",
        "பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சர் என்ற ரீதியில் பிரதமர் குணவர்தனவினால் இதற்கான பிரேரணை சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டு, திங்கட்கிழமை அமைச்சரவையினால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்திற்குப் பின்னரான ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த அமைச்சரவை இணைப் பேச்சாளரும் அமைச்சருமான பந்துல குணவர்தன, “சிங்களம் மற்றும் தமிழ் ஆகிய இரு மொழிகளிலும் வழமை போன்று தேசிய கீதம் பாடப்படும்.",
        "2019 நவம்பரில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஆட்சி மாற்றம் ஏற்பட்டதில் இருந்து சுதந்திர தின கொண்டாட்டத்தில் தேசிய கீதம் தமிழில் பாடப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமைச்சரவை துணைக்குழு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "75வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை துணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விதுர விக்கிரமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரன் அலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}