{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131832",
  "time_ut": 1658245115,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் 10 அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் டலஸை ஆதரிக்க தீர்மானம் - விமல் வீரவன்ச",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All 10 independent political parties resolve to support Dalas - Vimal Weerawansa",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "All the members of the 10 independent political parties in the Parliament have decided to support the presidential candidate Dalas Alagaperuma. National Freedom Front leader Vimal Weerawansa insisted that the People's Liberation Front should be united in the all-party government.",
        "He said the above while attending a press conference in Colombo today (19).",
        "Thanks must be given to Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasha. The Leader of the Opposition has taken the best decision considering the current critical situation without prioritizing his personal position regarding the presidency.",
        "It is to be welcomed that Sri Lanka Podujana Peramana Vice President Professor GL Peiris has confirmed that Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa proposed the name of Dulles Alagaperuma.",
        "Prof. GL Peiris' decision has made the ruling parties who had decided to extend support to Ranil Wickremesinghe think twice.",
        "If Dulles Aagaperuma is elected as the president, the government led by opposition leader Sajith Premadasa will be formed by uniting all political parties. People's Liberation Front leader should join the all-party government.",
        "All parties should work together to find a solution to the current economic and social crisis. 225 Parliamentarians should respect the aspirations of the people and take the best decision.",
        "All the members of the 10 independent political parties in Parliament have decided to support the presidential candidate Dalas Alagaperuma. He said that no problem can be solved without establishing a government in which the people of the country trust."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dalas - Vimal Weerawansa",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peramana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dulles Aagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්වාධීන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ 10 ම ඩලස්ට සහය දීමට තීරණය කරයි - විමල් වීරවංශ",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ 10ක මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා.ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවට එක්විය යුතු බව ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණේ නායක විමල් වීරවංශ අවධාරණය කළා.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ අද (19) කොළඹ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාට ස්තුතිය පුද කළ යුතුයි. විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ජනාධිපති ධූරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තම පෞද්ගලික ස්ථාවරයට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය නොදී වත්මන් තීරණාත්මක තත්ත්වය සලකා බලා හොඳම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ උප සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතා තහවුරු කිරීම පිළිගත යුතුය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දීමට තීරණය කර තිබූ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ දෙපාරක් සිතන්නට මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.",
        "ඩලස් අගපෙරුම මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත් වුවහොත් සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ එකතු කර විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවනු ඇත.මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායකයා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවට එක්විය යුතුයි.",
        "පවතින ආර්ථික හා සමාජීය අර්බුදයට සියලු පාර්ශ්ව එක්ව විසඳුම් සෙවිය යුතුයි.පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225ක් ජනතා අපේක්ෂාවන්ට ගරු කරමින් හොඳම තීරණය ගත යුතුයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ 10ක සියලු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා. රටේ ජනතාව විශ්වාස කරන රජයක් පිහිටුවීමෙන් තොරව කිසිදු ප්‍රශ්නයක් විසඳිය නොහැකි බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස් - විමල් වීරවංශ",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் 10 அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் டலஸை ஆதரிக்க தீர்மானம் - விமல் வீரவன்ச",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் 10 அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் உறுப்பினர்கள் அனைவரும் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் டலஸ் அழகபெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளோம்.சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியினர் ஒன்றினைய வேண்டும் என தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் தலைவர் விமல் வீரவன்ச வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துக்கொண்டு கருத்துரைக்கையில் மேற்கண்டவாறு குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஷவிற்கு நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். ஜனாதிபதி பதவி தொடர்பில் தனது தனிப்பட்ட நிலைப்பாட்டிற்கு முன்னுரிமையளிக்காமல் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையினை கருத்திற்கொண்டு எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சிறந்த தீர்மானத்தை முன்னெடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "டலஸ் அழகபெருமவின் பெயரை எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஷ முன்மொழிந்ததை ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமனவின் தவிசாளர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ் உறுதிப்படுத்தியமை வரவேற்கத்தக்கது.",
        "பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸின் தீர்மானம் ரணில் விக்கிரமசி;ங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க தீர்மானித்திருந்த ஆளும் தரப்பினர்களை பலமுறை சிந்திக்க வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "டலஸ் அழகபெரும ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யபட்டால் எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கம் சகல அரசியல் கட்சிகளையும் ஒன்றிணைத்து ஸ்தாபிக்கப்படும்.மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் தலைவர் சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் ஒன்றினைய வேண்டும்.",
        "சகல தரப்பினரும் ஒன்றினைந்து தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண வேண்டும்.225 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் நாட்டு மக்களின் அபிலாசைகளுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து சிறந்த தீர்மானத்தை முன்னெடுக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் 10 அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் உறுப்பினர்கள் அனைவரும் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் டலஸ் அழகபெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளோம். நாட்டு மக்கள் நம்பிக்கை கொள்ளும் அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிக்காவிடின் எப்பிரச்சினைகளுக்கும் தீர்வு காண முடியாது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "டலஸ் - விமல் வீரவன்ச",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரமனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் ஆகப்பெருமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}