{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/uncategorized/යුද-හමුදාවෙන්-ස්වයංක්‍රීය-විෂබීජ-හරණ-යන්ත්‍රයක්/1-381143",
  "time_ut": 1625570383,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යුද හමුදාවෙන් ස්වයංක්‍රීය විෂබීජ හරණ යන්ත්‍රයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An automatic sterilizer from the Army",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An automatic hand sanitizer machine produced by the Army's Research, Analysis and Development Unit was introduced to President Gotabaya Rajapaksa this morning (06th) at the Presidential Office.",
        "The machine has the capacity to disinfect the hands of 600 people by storing four liters of disinfectant liquid and can operate automatically for forty-eight hours after charging.",
        "It is possible to manufacture this machine in the country at low cost compared to import. Therefore, the Army Research Unit is ready to produce the machines for the orders received and to provide the knowledge about it to the interested parties.",
        "Army Commander and Chief of Defense Staff General Shavendra Silva, Additional Secretary to the President Major General (Retired) K.B. Mr. Egodawele and Brigadier Sudath Udayasena were present on this occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "forty-eight hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egodawele",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brigadier Sudath Udayasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුද හමුදාවෙන් ස්වයංක්‍රීය විෂබීජ හරණ යන්ත්‍රයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුද හමුදාවේ පර්යේෂණ, විශ්ලේෂණ හා සංවර්ධන ඒකකය නිෂ්පාදනය කළ දෑත් විෂබීජ හරණය කිරීමේ ස්වයංක්‍රීය යන්ත්‍රයක් අද (06දා) පෙරවරුවේ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත හඳුන්වා දෙනු ලැබිණ.",
        "විෂබීජ හරණ දියර ලීටර් හතරක ප්‍රමාණයක් ගබඩා කිරීමෙන් පුද්ගලයන් 600කගේ දෑත් විෂබීජ හරණයටත්, විදුලි ආරෝපණයෙන් පසු පැය හතළිස් අටක් ස්වයංක්‍රීයව ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමේ හැකියාවත් යන්ත්‍රය සතුය.",
        "ආනයනය කිරීමට සාපේක්ෂව අඩු පිරිවැයකින් මෙම යන්ත්‍රය රට තුළදී නිෂ්පාදනයට හැකියාව පවතී. එම නිසා ලැබෙන ඇණවුම් වෙනුවෙන් යන්ත්‍ර නිෂ්පාදනයට සහ ඒ පිළිබඳ දැනුම අවශ්‍ය පාර්ශ්ව වෙත ලබාදීමට යුද හමුදා පර්යේෂණ ඒකකය  සූදානම්ව සිටී.",
        "යුද හමුදාපති සහ ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා, ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් මේජර් ජනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) කේ.බී. එගොඩවෙලේ සහ බ්‍රිගේඩියර් සුදත් උදයසේන යන මහත්වරු මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය හතළිස් අටක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එගොඩවෙල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිගේඩියර් සුදත් උදයසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ராணுவத்திடம் இருந்து ஒரு தானியங்கி ஸ்டெரிலைசர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இராணுவத்தின் ஆராய்ச்சி, பகுப்பாய்வு மற்றும் அபிவிருத்திப் பிரிவினால் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட தானியங்கி கை சுத்திகரிப்பு இயந்திரம் இன்று (06) முற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அவர்களுக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த இயந்திரம் நான்கு லிட்டர் கிருமிநாசினி திரவத்தை சேமித்து 600 பேரின் கைகளை கிருமி நீக்கம் செய்யும் திறன் கொண்டது மற்றும் சார்ஜ் செய்த பிறகு நாற்பத்தெட்டு மணி நேரம் தானாகவே செயல்படும்.",
        "இறக்குமதியை விட குறைந்த செலவில் இந்த இயந்திரத்தை நாட்டிலேயே தயாரிக்க முடியும். எனவே, பெறப்பட்ட ஆர்டர்களுக்கான இயந்திரங்களைத் தயாரிக்கவும், ஆர்வமுள்ள தரப்பினருக்கு அதைப் பற்றிய அறிவை வழங்கவும் இராணுவ ஆராய்ச்சிப் பிரிவு தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "இராணுவத் தளபதி மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா, ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு பெற்ற) கே.பி. இந்நிகழ்வில் திரு.எகொடவெலே மற்றும் பிரிகேடியர் சுதத் உதயசேன ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாற்பத்தெட்டு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகொடவெலே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிகேடியர் சுதத் உதயசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}