{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ගාලු-කුමාරියේ-එන්න-ටිකට්-ගත්-අයට-සල්ලිත්-නෑ-ටිකට්-එකෙන්-වැඩකුත්-නෑ/101-618162",
  "time_ut": 1660572100,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගාලු කුමාරියේ එන්න ටිකට් ගත් අයට සල්ලිත් නෑ ටිකට් එකෙන් වැඩකුත් නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Those who bought tickets to come to Galle Kumari have no money and no use for the tickets",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The people are accusing the station master of Galle station of not taking action to provide relief to the passengers who were inconvenienced after the 'Gallu Kumari' train, which was running from Beliatte to Maradana, was stopped at Galle station due to the Ruhunu Kumari train derailing in Bussa area today (15) morning.",
        "Stopping the train in the middle of the train is not a weakness of the passengers, so the people asked the station master of Galle to pay for the tickets, but the station master said that he does not have the authority to do so.",
        "It is also reported that even though the police intervened to provide relief to the people, it did not work. In the first class reserved seats of the 'Galu Kumari' train, passengers had reserved seats by paying a lot of money and some people were traveling by paying more than 9000 rupees for all the family members.",
        "A large number of people, including foreigners, who were traveling in 'Galu Kumari' were inconvenienced after suddenly being informed that the train was late for a long time.",
        "In view of that situation, the passengers have to spend a lot of money and travel by bus again.",
        "When asked about this from the Secretary of the Railway Station Master's Association Mr. Kasun Chamara, he said that despite the continuous requests of the station masters to prepare a system to avoid inconvenience to the passengers in such cases, the authorities failed to do so.",
        "Railway Commercial Superintendent Mr. Vajira Polwattage tried to be contacted by phone to inquire about this situation, but he refused to answer the phone."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Galle Kumari",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gallu Kumari'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beliatte",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maradana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruhunu Kumari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bussa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galu Kumari'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 9000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galu Kumari'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Railway Station Master's Association",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kasun Chamara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Polwattage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගාලු කුමාරියේ එන්න ටිකට් ගත් අයට සල්ලිත් නෑ ටිකට් එකෙන් වැඩකුත් නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුහුණු කුමාරි දුම්රිය බූස්ස ප්‍රදේශයේදී අද (15) පෙරවරුවේ පිලී පැනීම හේතුවෙන් බෙලිඅත්තේ සිට මරදාන දක්වා ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබූ ‘ගාලු කුමාරි’ දුම්රිය ගාල්ල දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේ නතර කිරීමෙන් පසු අපහසුතාවට පත්වූ මගීන්ට ගාල්ල දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා සහන සැලසීමට ක්‍රියානොකිරීම පිළිබඳව ජනතාව චෝදනා කරති.",
        "දුම්රිය අතරමඟ නතර කිරීම මගී ජනතාවගේ දුර්වලතාවක් නොවන නිසා තමන්ට ප්‍රවේශපත්වල මුදල් ගෙවන ලෙස එහිදී ජනතාව ගාල්ල දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිය ද තමන්ට ඒ සඳහා බලයක් නොමැති බවට ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ජනතාවට සහන සැළසීමට එහිදී පොලිසිය මැදිහත් වුවද එය ද පළක් නොවූ බව ද වාර්තා වේ. ‘ගාලු කුමාරී’ දුම්රියේ පළමු පංතියේ වෙන්කළ ආසනවල මගීන් විශාල මුදලක් ගෙවා ආසන වෙන්තරගෙන සිටි අතර ඇතැම් පුද්ගලයන් පවුලේ සියලුම සාමාජිකයන්ට රුපියල් 9000 කට අධික මුදලක් ගෙවා ආසන්න වෙන්කරගෙන ගමන් කරමින් සිටියේය.",
        "හිටි හැටියේ දුම්රිය බොහෝ වේලාවක් ප්‍රමාද බව දැනුම්දීමෙන් පසු ‘ගාලු කුමාරී’ ගමන් කරමින් සිටි විදේශිකයන් ඇතුළු විශාල පිරිසක් අපහසුතාවට පත්වූහ.",
        "එම තත්වය හමුවේ මගී ජනතාවට නැවත විශාල මුදලක් වියදම් කර බස් රථයේ ගමන් කිරීමට සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති සංගමයේ ලේකම් කසුන් චාමර මහතාගෙන් මේ පිළිබඳව කළ විමසුමකදී පැවසුවේ එවැනි අවස්ථාවලදී මගී ජනතාවට වන අපහසුතාව මඟ හැරීමට ක්‍රමයක් සකස් කරන ලෙස ස්ථානාධිපතිවරු අඛණ්ඩව ඉල්ලීම් කළ ද බලධාරීන් එය මඟහැරි බවයි.",
        "මෙම තත්වය පිළිබඳව විසමසීමට දුම්රිය වාණිජ අධිකාරී වජිර පොල්වත්තගේ මහතාගේ මහතා දුරථනයෙන් සම්බන්ධ කරගැනීමට උත්සහ කළ ද ඔහු දුරකථනයට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වා කථා කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගාල්ල කුමාරි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ලු කුමාරි'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලිඅත්තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරදාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුහුණු කුමාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුස්සා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගලු කුමාරි'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගලු කුමාරි'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති සංගමය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කසුන් චාමර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර පොල්වත්තගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காலி குமரிக்கு வர டிக்கெட் வாங்கியவர்களிடம் பணமும் இல்லை, டிக்கெட்டுகளால் உபயோகமும் இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ருஹுனு குமாரி புகையிரதத்தினால் பெலியத்தையிலிருந்து மருதானை நோக்கி பயணித்த 'கல்லுகுமாரி' புகையிரதம் காலி நிலையத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டதையடுத்து அசௌகரியங்களுக்கு உள்ளான பயணிகளுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்கு காலி நிலையத்தின் நிலைய அதிபர் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவில்லை என மக்கள் குற்றம் சுமத்துகின்றனர். இன்று (15) காலை புஸ்ஸா பகுதியில் தடம் புரண்டது.",
        "புகையிரதத்தை நடுவில் நிறுத்துவது பயணிகளின் பலவீனம் அல்ல, எனவே பயணச்சீட்டை செலுத்துமாறு காலி நிலைய அதிபரிடம் மக்கள் கேட்டுள்ளனர், ஆனால் அதற்கு தமக்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லை என நிலைய அதிபர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பொலிசார் தலையிட்டு மக்களுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்கினாலும் அது பலனளிக்கவில்லை எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது. 'கலு குமாரி' ரயிலின் முதல் வகுப்பு முன்பதிவு இருக்கைகளில், பயணிகள் அதிக பணம் கொடுத்து இருக்கைகளை முன்பதிவு செய்திருந்தனர், மேலும் சிலர் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் அனைவருக்கும் 9000 ரூபாய்க்கு மேல் செலுத்தி பயணம் செய்தனர்.",
        "திடீரென ரயில் நீண்ட நேரம் தாமதமாக வந்ததாக 'கழுகுமரி'யில் பயணம் செய்த வெளிநாட்டினர் உட்பட ஏராளமானோர் சிரமப்பட்டனர்.",
        "அந்த சூழ்நிலையை கருத்தில் கொண்டு பயணிகள் அதிக பணம் செலவழித்து மீண்டும் பஸ்சில் பயணம் செய்ய வேண்டியுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் புகையிரத நிலைய அதிபர்கள் சங்கத்தின் செயலாளர் திரு.கசுன் சாமரவிடம் கேட்டபோது, ​​இவ்வாறான சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் பயணிகளுக்கு அசௌகரியங்களைத் தவிர்க்கும் வகையில் அமைப்பைத் தயாரிக்குமாறு நிலைய அதிபர்கள் தொடர்ச்சியாக கோரிக்கை விடுத்தும் அதிகாரிகள் அதனைச் செய்யத் தவறியதாகத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிலை குறித்து விசாரிக்க புகையிரத வர்த்தக அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.வஜிர பொல்வத்தகேவை தொலைபேசியில் தொடர்பு கொள்ள முயற்சித்த போதிலும் அவர் தொலைபேசிக்கு பதிலளிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காலி குமாரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்லு குமாரி'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலியட்டே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருதானை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருஹுனு குமாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலு குமாரி'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கலு குமாரி'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில் நிலைய மாஸ்டர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கசுன் சாமர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர பொல்வத்தகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}