{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ස්ථාවර-තැන්පතු---ණය-පහසුකම්වල-පොලී-අනුපාත-වැඩි-කරයි/101-615987",
  "time_ut": 1657171667,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු - ණය පහසුකම්වල පොලී අනුපාත වැඩි කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fixed Deposits – Increases interest rates on credit facilities",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Taking into account the current and expected macroeconomic developments in Sri Lanka, the Monetary Board of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka decided to raise interest rates on fixed deposits and credit facilities in a meeting held yesterday (06), the Central Bank announced today (07) in a statement.",
        "The Central Bank's Monetary Board has decided to raise the Fixed Deposit Facility Rate and Fixed Credit Facility Rate by 100 basis points, 14.50 percent and 15.50 percent respectively.",
        "Also, according to the statement issued by the Central Bank, the Monetary Board has decided to maintain the statutory reserve ratio at the current level of 4 percent."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monetary Board of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Central Bank's Monetary Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fixed Deposit Facility Rate and Fixed Credit Facility Rate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monetary Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු - ණය පහසුකම්වල පොලී අනුපාත වැඩි කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්තමාන සහ අපේක්ෂිත  සාර්ව ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනයන් සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය ඊයේ (06)පැවති රැස්වීමකදී ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු සහ ණය පහසුකම්වල පොලී අනුපාත ඉහළ දැමීමට තීරණය කළ බව අද (07) නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් මහ බැංකුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනූව මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය  ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු පහසුකම් අනුපාතිකය සහ ස්ථාවර ණය පහසුකම් අනුපාතිකය පදනම් අංක 100 කින්, පිළිවෙලින් සියයට 14.50 කින් සහ සියයට 15.50 කින් ඉහළ දැමීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "එසේම ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත සංචිත අනුපාතිකය පවතින සියයට 4 මට්ටමේ පවත්වාගෙන යාමට මුදල් මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කර ඇතිබව මහ බැංකුව නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථාවර තැන්පතු පහසුකම් අනුපාතිකය සහ ස්ථාවර ණය පහසුකම් අනුපාතිකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 14.50 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15.50 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிலையான வைப்பு - கடன் வசதிகள் மீதான வட்டி விகிதங்களை அதிகரிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய மற்றும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்திகளை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணயச் சபை நேற்று (06) நடைபெற்ற கூட்டத்தில் நிலையான வைப்பு மற்றும் கடன் வசதிகளுக்கான வட்டி விகிதங்களை உயர்த்த தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக மத்திய வங்கி இன்று (07) அறிவித்துள்ளது. ) ஒரு அறிக்கையில்.",
        "நிலையான வைப்பு வசதி வீதம் மற்றும் நிலையான கடன் வசதி வீதம் முறையே 100 அடிப்படைப் புள்ளிகளாலும், 14.50 வீதத்தாலும், 15.50 வீதத்தாலும் உயர்த்த மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணயச் சபை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "அத்துடன், மத்திய வங்கியினால் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையின்படி, சட்டரீதியான கையிருப்பு விகிதத்தை தற்போதைய 4 சதவீதமாக பேணுவதற்கு நாணயச் சபை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணய சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணய வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையான வைப்பு வசதி விகிதம் மற்றும் நிலையான கடன் வசதி விகிதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாணய வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}