{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/13/pm-taking-oppressive-decisions-akd/",
  "time_ut": 1657704300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PM taking oppressive decisions: AKD",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PM taking oppressive decisions: AKD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The country is currently spending its most decisive hours, says the National People’s Power Leader, Anura Kumara Dissanayake.",
        "Issuing a statement, Dissanayake states that neither the Prime Minister nor the President have issued their resignations as of yet, in addition to the Prime Minister being observed to misuse the power granted to him as the Acting President.",
        "Pointing out that the President has not yet stepped down as previously stated, Dissanayake alleges that the Prime Minister is attempting to misuse the power granted to him in a very oppressive, exemplified by the imposition of curfew and the emergency law.",
        "“What does this portray? This only portrays that the group including Ranil Wickremesinghe is attempting to exercise their power in an oppressive manner as much as the Constitution allows them,” he stated.",
        "Dissanayake emphasized that if a group including the Prime Minister does not take steps without heeding the people’s pleas, that would push the country into a worse state.",
        "Therefore, he appealed for the rulers, Police and the Tri-forces to act in a sympathetic manner, while listening to the voice and the aspirations of the people, as otherwise the entire country would remain at the mercy of a single individual and theit thirst for power.",
        "“Do not aim your batons and tear gas at the people,” he also appealed the Police.",
        "President Rajapaksa confirms that he would step down today (13)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People’s Power Leader",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති පීඩාකාරී තීරණ ගනී: AKD",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ වන විට රට ගත කරන්නේ තීරණාත්මක පැය කිහිපය බව ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා පවසයි.",
        "දිසානායක මහතා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසන්නේ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ලබාදී ඇති බලය අවභාවිත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීමට අමතරව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා හෝ ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙතෙක් ඔවුන්ගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් නිකුත් කර නොමැති බවයි.",
        "මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙතෙක් ඉවත් වී නොමැති බව පෙන්වා දෙන දිසානායක, ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීම සහ හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීම වැනි කරුණුවලින් පැහැදිලි වන පරිදි අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා තමාට ලබාදී ඇති බලය ඉතා පීඩාකාරී ලෙස අවභාවිත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බවටද චෝදනා කරයි.",
        "“මෙය නිරූපණය කරන්නේ කුමක්ද? රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් ඉඩ ලැබෙන තරමට තමන්ගේ බලය පීඩාකාරී ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව තමයි මෙයින් නිරූපණය වෙන්නේ,” ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අගමැතිවරයා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ජනතා ඉල්ලීම් නොසලකමින් පියවර නොගතහොත් එය රට තවත් නරක තත්ත්වයකට තල්ලු කරන බව දිසානායක මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "එම නිසා මුළු රටම එකම පුද්ගලයකුගේ සහ පිපාසයෙන් පෙළෙන බැවින් ජනතාවගේ හඬට හා ජනතා අභිලාෂයට සවන් දෙමින් පාලකයන්, පොලිසිය සහ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව සානුකම්පිතව කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. බලය සඳහා.",
        "“ඔබේ බැටන් පොලු සහ කඳුළු ගෑස් ජනතාවට එල්ල කරන්න එපා,” ඔහු පොලිසියෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "තමන් අද (13) ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනපති තහවුරු කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ නායකයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் அடக்குமுறை முடிவுகளை எடுக்கிறார்: ஏகேடி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாடு தற்போது மிகவும் தீர்க்கமான நேரத்தைக் கழிப்பதாக தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி என்ற ரீதியில் தமக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரத்தை பிரதமர் துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்வதாக அவதானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், பிரதமரோ அல்லது ஜனாதிபதியோ இதுவரை தமது இராஜினாமாக்களை வழங்கவில்லை என திஸாநாயக்க அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "முன்னர் கூறியது போன்று ஜனாதிபதி இன்னும் பதவி விலகவில்லை என சுட்டிக்காட்டிய திஸாநாயக்க, ஊரடங்கு சட்டம் மற்றும் அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டமை போன்றவற்றை எடுத்துக்காட்டி, தனக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட அதிகாரத்தை மிகவும் அடக்குமுறையாகப் பயன்படுத்த பிரதமர் முயற்சிப்பதாகக் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "\"இது எதைக் காட்டுகிறது? ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் தமது அதிகாரத்தை அரசியல் சாசனம் அனுமதிக்கும் அளவுக்கு அடக்குமுறையான முறையில் பிரயோகிக்க முயல்வதையே இது சித்தரிக்கிறது” என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதமர் உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் மக்களின் கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு செவிசாய்க்காமல் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்காவிட்டால், அது நாட்டை மோசமான நிலைக்கு தள்ளும் என திஸாநாயக்க வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "எனவே, ஆட்சியாளர்களும், காவல்துறையினரும், முப்படையினரும் அனுதாபத்துடன், மக்களின் குரலுக்கும், அபிலாஷைகளுக்கும் செவிசாய்த்து, இல்லையேல் முழு நாடும் ஒரு தனி மனிதனின் தயவில், தாகத்தில் தவிக்கும் என்பதால், அனுதாபத்துடன் செயல்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார். அதிகாரத்திற்காக.",
        "\"மக்கள் மீது தடியடி மற்றும் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை குறிவைக்காதீர்கள்\" என்றும் அவர் காவல்துறையிடம் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்தார்.",
        "இன்று (13) பதவி விலகப் போவதாக ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி தலைவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}