{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132338",
  "time_ut": 1658905254,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தூத்துக்குடியில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கடத்தவிருந்த வலி நிவாரண மாத்திரைகள் மீட்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Recovery of pain reliever pills that were to be smuggled from Tuticorin to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Tamil Nadu Q Division police have seized the pain relief pills that were being smuggled from Tamil Nadu to Sri Lanka.",
        "The Q Division police received information that pain relief pills were being smuggled to Sri Lanka from Threspuram beach in Thoothukudi district.",
        "After this, the Q Division police searched a suspiciously parked country boat without a registration number on the Threspuram beach.",
        "Out of which 4430 pain relief pills were recovered in about 443 cards for smuggling to Sri Lanka.",
        "Q Division police handed over the recovered painkillers and the country boat to the customs officials."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Threspuram",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoothukudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Threspuram",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4430",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 443",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තූත්තුකුඩියේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රැගෙන ඒමට නියමිතව තිබූ වේදනා නාශක පෙති තොගයක් සොයා ගැනේ.",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමිල්නාඩුවේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රැගෙන යමින් තිබූ වේදනා නාශක පෙති තොගය තමිල්නාඩු Q කොට්ඨාශ පොලීසිය භාරයට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "තූතුකුඩි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ත්‍රෙස්පුරම් වෙරළ තීරයේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වේදනා නාශක පෙති ජාවාරම් කරන බවට Q කොට්ඨාශ පොලිසියට තොරතුරක් ලැබිණි.",
        "මෙයින් පසු ත්‍රෙස්පුරම් වෙරළ තීරයේ ලියාපදිංචි අංකයක් නොමැතිව සැකකටයුතු ලෙස නවතා තිබූ රට යාත්‍රාවක් Q කොට්ඨාශ පොලිසිය විසින් පරීක්ෂා කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ඉන් වේදනා නාශක පෙති 4430ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හොර රහසේ ගෙන ඒම සඳහා කාඩ්පත් 443ක පමණ තිබී සොයා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සොයාගත් වේදනා නාශක පෙති සහ රට යාත්‍රාව Q කොට්ඨාශ පොලිසිය විසින් රේගු නිලධාරීන් වෙත භාර දෙන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රෙස්පුරම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූතුකුඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රෙස්පුරම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4430",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "443 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தூத்துக்குடியில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கடத்தவிருந்த வலி நிவாரண மாத்திரைகள் மீட்பு",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழகத்தில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கடத்த இருந்த வலி நிவாரண மாத்திரைகளை தமிழக க்யூ பிரிவு பொலிஸார் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தூத்துக்குடி மாவட்டம்   திரேஸ்புரம் கடற்கரையில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு வலி நிவாரண மாத்திரைகள் கடத்தப்படவுள்ளதாக  க்யூ பிரிவு பொலிஸாருக்கு தகவல் கிடைத்தது.",
        "இதனையடுத்து  க்யூ பிரிவு பொலிஸார் திரேஸ்புரம் கடற்கரை பகுதியில் நிறுத்திப்பட்டிருந்த பதிவெண் இல்லாமல் சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமான முறையில் தரித்து நின்ற  நாட்டு படகினை  சோதனை செய்தனர்.",
        "அதில்  இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக சுமார் 443 அட்டைகளில் 4430 வலி நிவாரண மாத்திரைகள் மீட்கப்பட்டன.",
        "க்யூ பிரிவு பொலிஸாரினால் மீட்கப்பட்ட வலி நிவாரண மாத்திரைகள் மற்றும்  நாட்டுபடகு என்பவற்றை சுங்கத்துறை அதிகாரிகளடம்  ஓப்படைத்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரேஸ்புரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரேஸ்புரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4430",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 443",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}