{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Reports-on-War-Game-between-Sri-Lanka-Navy-and-Pakistan-Navy-are-fallacious-Navy-responds/108-243004",
  "time_ut": 1660464160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Reports on ‘War Game’ between Sri Lanka Navy and Pakistan Navy are fallacious; Navy responds",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Reports on ‘War Game’ between Sri Lanka Navy and Pakistan Navy are fallacious; Navy responds",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Responding to certain reports relating to scheduled naval exercise with the Pakistan Navy Ship (PNS) Taimur which arrived in Sri Lanka on a formal visit, the Sri Lanka Navy said they conduct Passage Exercises as a routine engagement when their visiting naval ships depart the island after making official port calls.",
        "The 134m-long PNS Taimur arrived at the Colombo on a formal visit on August 12.",
        "The ship is expected to remain in the island until 15th August and the crew of the ship will take part in several programmes organized by the Sri Lanka Navy to promote cooperation and goodwill between two navies.",
        "Further, PNS Taimur is expected to conduct a naval exercise with the Sri Lanka Navy in western seas on its departure on August 15.",
        "“In this backdrop, certain media reports circulating about a ‘War Game’ between Sri Lanka Navy and Pakistan Navy are fallacious,” the Sri Lanka Navy said.",
        "The prime motive of these exercises is to enhance interoperability, partnerships and goodwill as well as exchange best practices with foreign navies.",
        "As part of this Passage Exercise, PNS Taimur and SLNS Sindurala are expected to conduct Maneuvering exercises and Search and Rescue exercise.",
        "Sri Lanka Navy said it has conducted similar Passage Exercises with the navies of countries such as India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Japan, Germany, U.K., Russia and Australia on a number of previous occasions.",
        "Conducting similar naval exercises with regional and extra-regional navies will enable each partner to overcome common maritime challenges in the future, through enhanced cooperation. In addition, such engagements will also be vital for its own maritime operations of Sri Lanka Navy.(Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Pakistan Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Pakistan Navy Ship",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134m-long PNS Taimur",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a ‘War Game’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Sindurala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Search and Rescue",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.K.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සහ පාකිස්තාන නාවික හමුදාව අතර ‘යුද්ධ ක්‍රීඩාව’ පිළිබඳ වාර්තා සාවද්‍ය ය; නාවික හමුදාව ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විධිමත් සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි පාකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාවට අයත් (PNS) Taimur නෞකාව සමඟ සැලසුම් කර ඇති නාවික අභ්‍යාසයට අදාළ ඇතැම් වාර්තාවලට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඔවුන්ගේ සංචාරය කරන නාවික නෞකා ඉන් අනතුරුව දිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව යන විට සාමාන්‍ය කටයුත්තක් ලෙස අභ්‍යාස අභ්‍යාස සිදුකරන බවයි. නිල වරාය ඇමතුම් ලබා ගැනීම.",
        "134m දිග ​​PNS Taimur අගෝස්තු 12 වන දින විධිමත් සංචාරයක් සඳහා කොළඹට පැමිණියේය.",
        "නෞකාව අගෝස්තු මස 15 වනදා දක්වා දිවයිනේ රැඳී සිටීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර, නාවික හමුදාවන් දෙකක් අතර සහයෝගීතාවය සහ සුහදතාවය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් සංවිධානය කරනු ලබන වැඩසටහන් කිහිපයකට නෞකාවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහභාගී වනු ඇත.",
        "තවද, PNS Taimur අගෝස්තු 15 වන දින පිටත්ව යන විට බටහිර මුහුදේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සමඟ නාවික අභ්‍යාසයක් පැවැත්වීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "\"මෙම පසුබිම තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සහ පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව අතර 'යුද්ධ ක්‍රීඩාවක්' ගැන පැතිර යන ඇතැම් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා සාවද්‍ය බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "මෙම අභ්‍යාසවල මූලික අභිප්‍රාය වන්නේ අන්තර් ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය, හවුල්කාරිත්වය සහ සුහදතාවය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම මෙන්ම විදේශීය නාවික හමුදා සමඟ හොඳම භාවිතයන් හුවමාරු කර ගැනීමයි.",
        "මෙම ඡේද අභ්‍යාසයේ කොටසක් ලෙස, PNS Taimur සහ SLNS Sindurala උපාමාරු අභ්‍යාස සහ සෙවීම් සහ ගලවා ගැනීමේ අභ්‍යාස පැවැත්වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව මීට පෙර අවස්ථා ගණනාවකදීම ඉන්දියාව, පකිස්ථානය, බංග්ලාදේශය, ජපානය, ජර්මනිය, එක්සත් රාජධානිය, රුසියාව සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව වැනි රටවල නාවික හමුදා සමඟ මෙවැනිම අභ්‍යාස අභ්‍යාස පවත්වා ඇති බව පැවසීය.",
        "කලාපීය සහ බාහිර කලාපීය නාවික හමුදාවන් සමඟ සමාන නාවික අභ්‍යාස පැවැත්වීම තුළින් සෑම හවුල්කරුවෙකුටම අනාගතයේ දී පොදු සමුද්‍රීය අභියෝග ජය ගැනීමට හැකි වනු ඇත. මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ තමන්ගේම සමුද්‍රීය මෙහෙයුම් සඳහා ද මෙවැනි කටයුතු ඉතා වැදගත් වේ.(දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාවට අයත් නෞකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134m-දිග PNS Taimur",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'යුද ක්‍රීඩාවක්'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සිඳුරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙවීම සහ ගැලවීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.K.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடற்படைக்கும் பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படைக்கும் இடையிலான ‘போர் விளையாட்டு’ பற்றிய அறிக்கைகள் தவறானவை; கடற்படை பதில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ விஜயமொன்றை மேற்கொண்டு இலங்கை வந்துள்ள பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படைக் கப்பலான (பிஎன்எஸ்) தைமூர் உடனான திட்டமிடப்பட்ட கடற்படைப் பயிற்சி தொடர்பான சில தகவல்களுக்குப் பதிலளித்த இலங்கை கடற்படையினர், தமது வருகை தரும் கடற்படைக் கப்பல்கள் தீவை விட்டுப் புறப்படும்போது, ​​வழக்கமான ஈடுபாட்டாக கடவுப் பயிற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வதாகக் கூறியது. அதிகாரப்பூர்வ போர்ட் அழைப்புகள்.",
        "134 மீ நீளமுள்ள PNS தைமூர் ஆகஸ்ட் 12 அன்று ஒரு முறையான பயணமாக கொழும்பு வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "இந்த கப்பல் ஆகஸ்ட் 15 ஆம் தேதி வரை தீவில் இருக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, மேலும் இரு கடற்படைகளுக்கு இடையேயான ஒத்துழைப்பையும் நல்லுறவையும் மேம்படுத்தும் வகையில் இலங்கை கடற்படை ஏற்பாடு செய்யும் பல நிகழ்ச்சிகளில் கப்பலின் பணியாளர்கள் பங்கேற்பார்கள்.",
        "மேலும், பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர் ஆகஸ்ட் 15 ஆம் தேதி புறப்படும்போது மேற்கு கடல் பகுதியில் இலங்கை கடற்படையுடன் கடற்படை பயிற்சியை நடத்தும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த பின்னணியில், இலங்கை கடற்படைக்கும் பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படைக்கும் இடையே ‘போர் விளையாட்டு’ பற்றி பரப்பப்படும் சில ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் தவறானவை” என்று இலங்கை கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த பயிற்சிகளின் முக்கிய நோக்கம், வெளிநாட்டு கடற்படைகளுடன் செயல்படும் திறன், கூட்டாண்மை மற்றும் நல்லெண்ணத்தை மேம்படுத்துவது மற்றும் சிறந்த நடைமுறைகளை பரிமாறிக்கொள்வதாகும்.",
        "இந்தப் பயிற்சிப் பயிற்சியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, PNS தைமூர் மற்றும் SLNS சிந்தூரலா ஆகியவை சூழ்ச்சிப் பயிற்சிகள் மற்றும் தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பயிற்சிகளை நடத்தும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்தியா, பாகிஸ்தான், பங்களாதேஷ், ஜப்பான், ஜேர்மனி, இங்கிலாந்து, ரஷ்யா மற்றும் அவுஸ்திரேலியா போன்ற நாடுகளின் கடற்படைகளுடன் இதற்கு முன்னர் பல தடவைகள் இதேபோன்ற கடவுப் பயிற்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிராந்திய மற்றும் கூடுதல் பிராந்திய கடற்படைகளுடன் இதேபோன்ற கடற்படை பயிற்சிகளை நடத்துவது, ஒவ்வொரு கூட்டாளியும் எதிர்காலத்தில் பொதுவான கடல்சார் சவால்களை மேம்பட்ட ஒத்துழைப்பின் மூலம் சமாளிக்க உதவும். மேலும், இலங்கை கடற்படையின் சொந்த கடல் நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கும் இத்தகைய ஈடுபாடுகள் இன்றியமையாததாக இருக்கும்.(தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134 மீ நீளமுள்ள PNS தைமூர்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு 'போர் விளையாட்டு'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS சிந்தூரலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.கே.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}