{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83771/special-gazette-issued-declaring-ranil-as-new-sri-lanka-president",
  "time_ut": 1658321160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Special gazette issued declaring Ranil as new Sri Lanka President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Special gazette issued declaring Ranil as new Sri Lanka President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A special gazette was published today (July 20) officially declaring the election of Ranil Wickremesinghe to the office of President.",
        "The communiqué was issued by Secretary-General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake, pursuant to Section 17 of the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act, No. 2 of 1981.",
        "Earlier today, the 225-member Sri Lankan parliament voted in Wickremesinghe as the 8th Executive President of the country, with majority votes.",
        "A total of 223 members had cast their votes and four were declared invalid. Two members, namely MPs Selvaraja Gajendran and G.G. Ponnambalam, meanwhile abstained from voting.",
        "Wickremesinghe was elected to the office of President with a total of 134 votes, while his main opponent SLPP’s dissident MP Dullas Alahapperuma was polled second with 82 votes. National People’s Power leader MP Anura Kumara Dissanayake managed to secure only 03 votes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 17",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvaraja Gajendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.G. Ponnambalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපති ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් අති විශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් නිකුත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට තේරී පත් වූ බව නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් අති විශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් අද (ජුලි 20) ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කෙරිණි.",
        "1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ 17 වැනි වගන්තියට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක විසින් මෙම නිවේදනය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "අද දිනට පෙර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රටේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වැඩි ඡන්දයෙන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සභිකයින් 223 දෙනෙකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබූ අතර ඉන් 4 දෙනෙකු වලංගු නොවන බව ප්‍රකාශ කෙරුණා. මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන සෙල්වරාජා ගජේන්ද්‍රන් සහ ජී.ජී. මේ අතර පොන්නම්බලම් ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියේය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මුළු ඡන්ද 134ක් ලබා ගනිමින් ජනාධිපති ධුරයට තේරී පත් වූ අතර ඔහුගේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ විසම්මුතික මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ඡන්ද 82ක් ලබා ගනිමින් දෙවැනියා විය. ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට ලබාගත හැකි වූයේ ඡන්ද 03ක් පමණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වරාජා ගජේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ජී. පොන්නම්බලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் புதிய அதிபராக ரணிலை அறிவித்து விசேட வர்த்தமானி வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கும் விசேட வர்த்தமானி இன்று (ஜூலை 20) வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் 17 ஆவது பிரிவின்படி, நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்கவினால் இந்த அறிக்கை வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இன்று முன்னதாக, 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில், பெரும்பான்மை வாக்குகளுடன் நாட்டின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக விக்ரமசிங்கே வாக்களித்தார்.",
        "மொத்தம் 223 உறுப்பினர்கள் வாக்களித்தனர், நான்கு பேர் செல்லாதவையாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டனர். பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன் மற்றும் ஜி.ஜி. இதற்கிடையில் பொன்னம்பலம் வாக்களிக்காமல் புறக்கணித்தார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க மொத்தம் 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார், அதேவேளை அவரது பிரதான எதிரியான ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் அதிருப்தி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும 82 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பெற்றார். தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 03 வாக்குகளை மாத்திரமே பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடிந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 17",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.ஜி. பொன்னம்பலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}