{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/main_image/කෙහෙල්බද්දර-තරුණයා-ඝාතනයට-පහක්-සැකපිට/47-618878",
  "time_ut": 1661682120,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෙහෙල්බද්දර තරුණයා ඝාතනයට පහක් සැකපිට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Five suspects for the murder of Kehelbaddara youth",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Gampaha police said that five people, including a 36-year-old woman, were arrested with a firearm in connection with the murder of a person in Kehelbaddara, Udugampola, Gampaha.",
        "This man was killed at a hair cutting place on the 6th of last day by two people who came on a motorcycle.",
        "After arresting these suspects and the female suspect, a group of officers from the Police Special Task Force Gonahena camp have taken steps to hand them over to the Gampaha headquarters police.",
        "Police say that the suspect and the suspect are residents of Nadagamuwa, Tammita, Makevita, Pethiagoda and Kotuguda and are aged between 29-35 years.",
        "The police said that they have been detained on 48-hour detention orders and have taken steps to interrogate them further."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kehelbaddara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kehelbaddara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udugampola",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 6th of last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nadagamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tammita",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makevita",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pethiagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotuguda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 29-35 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "48-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෙහෙල්බද්දර තරුණයා ඝාතනයට පහක් සැකපිට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගම්පහ උඩුගම්පොල, කෙහෙල්බද්දර දී පුද්ගලයකු ඝාතනය කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගිනි අවියක් සමග 36 හැවිරිදි කාන්තාවක් ඇතුලු පස් දෙනකු අත් අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ගම්පහ පොලීසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "යතුරු පැදියකින් පැමිණි දෙදෙනකු විසින් ඉකුත් 6 වැනි දින  සිදු කළ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් කොණ්ඩය කැපීමේ ස්ථානයක සිටි මෙම පුද්ගලයා ඝාතනය කොට තිබිණි.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකා ගෝනහේන කඳවුරෙහි නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක්  මෙම සැකකරුවන් සහ සැකකාරිය අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව ගම්පහ මූලස්ථාන පොලීසියට බාරදීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරු සහ සැකකාරිය නැදගමුව, තම්මිට ,මාකෙවිට , පෙතියාගොඩ සහ කොටුගොඩ පදිංචිකරුවන් වන බවත් අවුරුදු 29 - 35 ත් අතර වයසේ පසුවන්නවුන් බවත් පොලීසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "මොවුන් පැය 48 ක රැඳවුම් නියෝග මත රදවාගෙන වැඩි දුර ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බවද පොලීසිය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෙහෙල්බද්දර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙල්බද්දර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩුගම්පොල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 6 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාඩගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්මිට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකේවිට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙතියාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුගුඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 29-35 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "48-පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கெஹல்பத்தர இளைஞன் கொலையில் ஐந்து சந்தேகநபர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கம்பஹா, உடுகம்பொல, கெஹெல்பத்தரவில் நபரொருவர் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் 36 வயதுடைய பெண் உட்பட ஐவர் துப்பாக்கியுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கம்பஹா பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த நபர் கடந்த 6ஆம் திகதி மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இருவரினால் முடி வெட்டும் இடத்தில் வைத்து படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சந்தேக நபர்களையும் பெண் சந்தேக நபர்களையும் கைது செய்த பின்னர், பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் கொனஹேன முகாமின் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று கம்பஹா தலைமையக பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேக நபரும், சந்தேகநபரும் நடகமுவ, தம்மிட, மகேவிட்ட, பெதியகொட மற்றும் கொட்டுகுடா ஆகிய பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் எனவும், அவர்கள் 29-35 வயதுடையவர்கள் எனவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "48 மணித்தியால விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இவர்கள் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ள நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கெஹெல்பத்தர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹெல்பத்தர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடுகம்பொல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாளான 6ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நடகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேவிதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெத்தியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடுகுடா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "29-35 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "48-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}