{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-expolanka-profit-skyrockets-over-200-on-exports-rupee-depreciation-98042/",
  "time_ut": 1659211140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s Expolanka profit skyrockets over 200% on exports, rupee depreciation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Expolanka profit skyrockets over 200% on exports, rupee depreciation",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Profit in Sri Lanka’s market heavyweight Expolanka Holdings with a network of",
        "logistics units in the US, EU, Asia and Africa for the June 2022 quarter rose more than 220 percent due to its logistics business and exchange rate gain after rupee collapsed in the quarter.",
        "The group recorded a profit of 20.1 billion rupees in the June quarter, 220.6 percent increase from 6.3 billion rupees a year earlier. The June quarter’s profit was less than the March quarter’s bottom line of 31.4 billion rupees.",
        "Expolanka group reported earnings of 10.31 rupees per share for the quarter, compared to 3.22 rupees in the same quarter in the previous year.",
        "The group said during the period under review, with the rupee continued to depreciate, the firm made",
        "6.9 billion rupees in the exchange gain, increasing the net asset value of the company by 25 billion",
        "The group recorded a revenue of 235.1 billion rupees, an increase of 145.7 percent from a year earlier while the cost of sales have increased by 143.8 percent to 198.2 billion rupees resulting the gross profit of 36.9 billion rupees, a gain of 155.7 percent.",
        "“The Air Freight product saw volumes tailing off during the quarter, a result of lower demand witnessed",
        "across our key markets. EFL origins were nonetheless able to augment the sales efforts by ensuring",
        "exceptional service, capacity availability, and transparency,” Group Chief Executive Hanif Yusuf told",
        "“The Ocean Freight product continued to gain traction and delivered satisfactory growth during the",
        "Yusuf said whilst focusing primarily on its international freight forwarding business, EFL has been able to enhance its capabilities across domestic logistics portfolio in key locations particularly in the North",
        "“Global market conditions remained volatile during the period under review. Consumer demand was",
        "tempered in our North America market, a result of potential Inflationary impacts, whilst the global",
        "energy crisis resulted in increased pressure on oil prices. Extended lock downs in China resulted in",
        "reduced supply and further intensified supply chain pressure,” Yusuf said.",
        "“Correction in freight rates were visible across both Air &amp; Ocean Freight as capacity returned to the",
        "“Origins such as Vietnam, India, Indonesia, Thailand and Sri Lanka continued to deliver strong results,",
        "reflecting the success of the infrastructure investments made into these markets over the last several",
        "Selling and distribution expenses increased by almost 300 percent to 1.9 billion rupees.",
        "Finance cost increased by 467.6 percent to 552.3 million rupees while the Finance income increased at a",
        "Total assets of the group increased by 16.4 percent to 344.9 million rupees.",
        "Given the uncertain market conditions, the macro environment is expected to evolve, particularly with",
        "changing consumer demand patterns, nimble supply chains and increased digitization (Colombo/July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Expolanka",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "over 200%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 220 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20.1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the June quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.3 billion rupees",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The June quarter’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than the March quarter’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.9 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "235.1 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "145.7 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "143.8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "198.2 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.9 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "155.7 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Air Freight",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hanif Yusuf",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ocean Freight",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yusuf",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "North America",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yusuf",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Air &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ocean Freight",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "almost 300 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.9 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "467.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "552.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16.4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "344.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/July",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අපනයන, රුපියල අවප්‍රමාණය වීම මත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්ස්පෝලංකා ලාභය 200% ඉක්මවයි",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජාලයක් සහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙළෙඳපොළ හෙවිවේට් එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් හි ලාභය",
        "2022 ජූනි කාර්තුව සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය, යුරෝපා සංගමය, ආසියාව සහ අප්‍රිකාව යන රටවල සැපයුම් ඒකක සියයට 220 ට වඩා වැඩි වූයේ එහි සැපයුම් ව්‍යාපාර සහ කාර්තුවේදී රුපියල කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු විනිමය අනුපාතිකය ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙනි.",
        "සමූහය ජුනි කාර්තුවේදී රුපියල් බිලියන 20.1 ක ලාභයක් වාර්තා කර ඇති අතර එය පෙර වසරේ රුපියල් බිලියන 6.3 සිට සියයට 220.6 ක වැඩිවීමකි. ජුනි කාර්තුවේ ලාභය මාර්තු කාර්තුවේ පහළම අගය වූ රුපියල් බිලියන 31.4 ට වඩා අඩු විය.",
        "එක්ස්පෝලංකා සමූහය මෙම කාර්තුව සඳහා කොටසකට රුපියල් 10.31 ක ඉපැයීමක් වාර්තා කර ඇති අතර එය පෙර වසරේ එම කාර්තුවේ රුපියල් 3.22 ට සාපේක්ෂව ය.",
        "සමාලෝචිත කාලසීමාව තුළ රුපියල දිගින් දිගටම අවප්‍රමාණය වීමත් සමඟ සමාගම සිදු කළ බව සමූහය පැවසීය",
        "රුපියල් බිලියන 6.9 ක විනිමය ලාභයක් ලබා ගනිමින් සමාගමේ ශුද්ධ වත්කම් වටිනාකම බිලියන 25 කින් වැඩි විය",
        "සමූහය රුපියල් බිලියන 235.1 ක ආදායමක් වාර්තා කර ඇති අතර එය පෙර වසරට වඩා සියයට 145.7 ක වැඩිවීමක් වන අතර විකුණුම් පිරිවැය සියයට 143.8 කින් රුපියල් බිලියන 198.2 ක් දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස දළ ලාභය රුපියල් බිලියන 36.9 ක් වන අතර එය සියයට 155.7 ක වර්ධනයකි.",
        "“එයාර් ෆ්‍රයිට් නිෂ්පාදනය කාර්තුව තුළ පරිමාව අඩු වූ අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ඉල්ලුම අඩු විය",
        "අපගේ ප්රධාන වෙළෙඳපොළ හරහා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, EFL මූලාරම්භය සහතික කිරීම මගින් විකුණුම් ප්රයත්නයන් වැඩි කිරීමට සමත් විය",
        "සුවිශේෂී සේවාවක්, ධාරිතා ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව සහ විනිවිදභාවය,\" සමූහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක හනීෆ් යූසුෆ් පැවසීය.",
        "“සාගර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය නිෂ්පාදනය අඛණ්ඩව කම්පනය ලබා ගත් අතර එම කාලය තුළ සතුටුදායක වර්ධනයක් ලබා දුන්නේය",
        "යූසුෆ් පැවසුවේ මූලික වශයෙන් සිය ජාත්‍යන්තර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ව්‍යාපාරය කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන අතරම, විශේෂයෙන් උතුරේ ප්‍රධාන ස්ථානවල දේශීය සැපයුම් කළඹ හරහා සිය හැකියාවන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට EFL සමත් වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "“සමාලෝචනයට ලක්වන කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ ගෝලීය වෙළෙඳපොළ තත්ත්වයන් අස්ථායීව පැවතුණි. පාරිභෝගික ඉල්ලුම විය",
        "ගෝලීය වශයෙන් ඇති විය හැකි උද්ධමන බලපෑම් වල ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස, අපගේ උතුරු ඇමරිකානු වෙළඳපොලේ මෘදු වී ඇත",
        "බලශක්ති අර්බුදය තෙල් මිල මත පීඩනය වැඩි කිරීමට හේතු විය. චීනයේ දීර්ඝ කළ අගුලු දැමීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලය විය",
        "සැපයුම අඩු කිරීම සහ සැපයුම් දාම පීඩනය තවදුරටත් තීව්‍ර කිරීම,\" යූසුෆ් පැවසීය.",
        "\"භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු නිවැරදි කිරීම ගුවන් සහ amp; ධාරිතාව අනුව සාගර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය ආපසු",
        "වියට්නාමය, ඉන්දියාව, ඉන්දුනීසියාව, තායිලන්තය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි සම්භවයන් අඛණ්ඩව ශක්තිමත් ප්‍රතිඵල ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "පසුගිය කීපය තුළ මෙම වෙලඳපොලවල් වෙත කරන ලද යටිතල පහසුකම් ආයෝජනවල සාර්ථකත්වය පිළිබිඹු කරයි",
        "විකුණුම් සහ බෙදාහැරීමේ වියදම් රුපියල් බිලියන 1.9 දක්වා සියයට 300 කින් පමණ වැඩි විය.",
        "මූල්‍ය පිරිවැය රුපියල් මිලියන 552.3 ක් දක්වා සියයට 467.6 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර මූල්‍ය ආදායම අ",
        "සමූහයේ මුළු වත්කම් රුපියල් මිලියන 344.9 ක් දක්වා සියයට 16.4 කින් වැඩි විය.",
        "අවිනිශ්චිත වෙළඳපල තත්ත්වයන් සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන, සාර්ව පරිසරය විශේෂයෙන් පරිණාමය වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
        "පාරිභෝගික ඉල්ලුම රටා වෙනස් කිරීම, වේගවත් සැපයුම් දාම සහ ඩිජිටල්කරණය වැඩි කිරීම (කොළඹ/ජූලි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "200% ට වැඩි",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 220කට වඩා වැඩියි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 20.1 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 220.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 6.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු කාර්තුවට වඩා අඩුය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 31.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 235.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 145.7 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 143.8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 198.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 36.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 155.7 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හනීෆ් යූසුෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගර භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යූසුෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු ඇමෙරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යූසුෆ්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වායු &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර භාණ්ඩ ප්රවාහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 300ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 467.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 552.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 16.4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 344.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் எக்ஸ்போலங்காவின் இலாபமானது ஏற்றுமதி, ரூபாயின் பெறுமதி சரிவு ஆகியவற்றால் 200% க்கும் அதிகமாக உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் சந்தை ஹெவிவெயிட் எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸில் ஒரு வலையமைப்புடன் இலாபம்",
        "ஜூன் 2022 காலாண்டில் அமெரிக்கா, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம், ஆசியா மற்றும் ஆப்பிரிக்காவில் உள்ள தளவாட அலகுகள் அதன் தளவாட வணிகம் மற்றும் காலாண்டில் ரூபாய் சரிவுக்குப் பிறகு மாற்று விகித அதிகரிப்பு காரணமாக 220 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமாக உயர்ந்தன.",
        "குழுவானது ஜூன் காலாண்டில் 20.1 பில்லியன் ரூபாயைப் பதிவுசெய்துள்ளது, இது முந்தைய வருடத்தின் 6.3 பில்லியன் ரூபாயிலிருந்து 220.6 வீத அதிகரிப்பு. ஜூன் காலாண்டின் லாபம் மார்ச் காலாண்டின் அடிமட்டமான 31.4 பில்லியன் ரூபாயை விட குறைவாக இருந்தது.",
        "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா குழுமம், முந்தைய ஆண்டின் இதே காலாண்டில் 3.22 ரூபாயுடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது, ​​இந்த காலாண்டில் பங்கு ஒன்றின் வருமானம் 10.31 ரூபாவாக பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "மதிப்பாய்வின் போது, ​​ரூபாயின் மதிப்பு தொடர்ந்து சரிந்து வருவதால், நிறுவனம் செய்ததாக குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
        "6.9 பில்லியன் ரூபா பரிவர்த்தனை ஆதாயத்தைப் பெற்று, நிறுவனத்தின் நிகர சொத்து மதிப்பு 25 பில்லியனால் அதிகரித்துள்ளது",
        "குழுமம் 235.1 பில்லியன் ரூபா வருமானத்தைப் பதிவு செய்துள்ளது, இது முந்தைய ஆண்டை விட 145.7 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து விற்பனைச் செலவு 143.8 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து 198.2 பில்லியன் ரூபாயாக 198.2 பில்லியனாக உள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக மொத்த லாபம் 36.9 பில்லியன் ரூபாவாகும், இது 155.7 சதவீதம் லாபமாக உள்ளது.",
        "\"ஏர் சரக்கு தயாரிப்பு இந்த காலாண்டில் அளவு குறைந்துள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக குறைந்த தேவை காணப்பட்டது",
        "எங்கள் முக்கிய சந்தைகள் முழுவதும். இருப்பினும் EFL தோற்றம் உறுதி செய்வதன் மூலம் விற்பனை முயற்சிகளை அதிகரிக்க முடிந்தது",
        "விதிவிலக்கான சேவை, திறன் இருப்பு மற்றும் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை, ”என்று குழுமத்தின் தலைமை நிர்வாகி ஹனிஃப் யூசுப் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஓஷன் சரக்கு தயாரிப்பு தொடர்ந்து இழுவை பெற்று, திருப்திகரமான வளர்ச்சியை அளித்தது",
        "அதன் சர்வதேச சரக்கு அனுப்புதல் வணிகத்தில் முதன்மையாக கவனம் செலுத்தும் அதே வேளையில், EFL ஆனது உள்நாட்டு தளவாடங்கள் போர்ட்ஃபோலியோவில் குறிப்பாக வடக்கில் உள்ள முக்கிய இடங்களில் அதன் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்த முடிந்தது என்று யூசுப் கூறினார்.",
        "“மதிப்பாய்வு செய்யப்பட்ட காலகட்டத்தில் உலகளாவிய சந்தை நிலைமைகள் நிலையற்றதாகவே இருந்தது. நுகர்வோர் தேவை இருந்தது",
        "நமது வட அமெரிக்க சந்தையில், உலகளாவிய அளவில், சாத்தியமான பணவீக்க தாக்கங்களின் விளைவாக",
        "எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடி எண்ணெய் விலையில் அழுத்தத்தை அதிகரித்தது. சீனாவில் நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட லாக் டவுன்கள் விளைந்தன",
        "விநியோகம் குறைக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் விநியோகச் சங்கிலி அழுத்தத்தை மேலும் தீவிரப்படுத்தியது\" என்று யூசுப் கூறினார்.",
        "“சரக்குக் கட்டணங்களில் திருத்தம் விமானம் & ஆம்ப்; கொள்ளளவுக்கு கடல் சரக்கு திரும்பியது",
        "\"வியட்நாம், இந்தியா, இந்தோனேஷியா, தாய்லாந்து மற்றும் இலங்கை போன்ற தோற்றங்கள் தொடர்ந்து வலுவான முடிவுகளை வழங்குகின்றன.",
        "கடந்த பல ஆண்டுகளாக இந்த சந்தைகளில் செய்யப்பட்ட உள்கட்டமைப்பு முதலீடுகளின் வெற்றியை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது",
        "விற்பனை மற்றும் விநியோக செலவுகள் கிட்டத்தட்ட 300 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து 1.9 பில்லியன் ரூபாயாக இருந்தது.",
        "நிதிச் செலவு 467.6 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து 552.3 மில்லியன் ரூபாவாகும் அதேவேளை நிதி வருமானம் ஏ",
        "குழுமத்தின் மொத்த சொத்துக்கள் 16.4 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்து 344.9 மில்லியன் ரூபாவாகும்.",
        "நிச்சயமற்ற சந்தை நிலைமைகளின் அடிப்படையில், மேக்ரோ சூழல் உருவாகும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, குறிப்பாக",
        "மாறிவரும் நுகர்வோர் தேவை முறைகள், வேகமான விநியோகச் சங்கிலிகள் மற்றும் அதிகரித்த டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கல் (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "200%க்கு மேல்",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20.1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "220.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.3 பில்லியன் ரூபாய்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் காலாண்டை விட குறைவாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "235.1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "145.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "143.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "198.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "155.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமான சரக்கு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹனிஃப் யூசுப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடல் சரக்கு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூசுப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வட அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூசுப்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காற்று &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் சரக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 300 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "467.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "552.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "344.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}