{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/චාජර්-ගෙනයන්න-හැදූ-රැඳවියා-මාට්ටු/101-618709",
  "time_ut": 1661401030,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චාජර් ගෙනයන්න හැදූ රැඳවියා මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The inmate who tried to move the charger was caught",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police Special Task Force says that an inmate who tried to take two mobile phones, two batteries and two battery chargers (chargers) into the Welikada remand prison was arrested.",
        "Police say that the officers of the Welikada Prison Police Special Task Force camp found these chargers and batteries hidden in the trouser pockets while checking the inmates.",
        "Police Sergeant 6083 Wickramasinghe of the Welikada prison camp arrested the suspects on the instructions of the Special Task Force Commander DIG Attorney General Varuna Jayasundara."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Prison Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Varuna Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චාජර් ගෙනයන්න හැදූ රැඳවියා මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැලිකඩ රිමාන්ඩ් බන්ධනාගාරය තුළට ජංගම දුරකථන දෙකක්, බැටරි දෙකක් සහ බැටරි ආරෝපණ දෙකක් ( චාජර) රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ දැරූ රැඳවියකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය කියයි.",
        "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාර පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකා කඳවුරේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් රැඳවියන් පරික්ෂා කිරීමේදී කලිසම් සාක්කුවේ සඟවාගෙන සිටි මෙම චාජර සහ බැටරි සොයාගත් බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකා අණදෙන නිලධාරී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති නීතිඥ වරුණ ජයසුන්දර මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාර කඳවුරේ පොලිස් සැරයන්6083 වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත්හ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාර පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරුණ ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சார்ஜரை நகர்த்த முயன்ற கைதி பிடிபட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரண்டு கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகள், இரண்டு மின்கலங்கள் மற்றும் இரண்டு பேட்டரி சார்ஜர்கள் (சார்ஜர்கள்) ஆகியவற்றை வெலிக்கடை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்க முற்பட்ட கைதி ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை முகாமின் அதிகாரிகள் கைதிகளை சோதனையிட்ட போது காற்சட்டை பைகளில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த இந்த சார்ஜர்கள் மற்றும் பேட்டரிகள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் கட்டளைத் தளபதி பிரதி பொலிஸ்மா அதிபர் சட்டத்தரணி வருண ஜயசுந்தரவின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை முகாமின் பொலிஸ் சார்ஜன்ட் 6083 விக்கிரமசிங்க சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருண ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}