{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84347/govt-says-former-president-not-using-state-funds-on-expenses-abroad",
  "time_ut": 1660669740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Govt says former President not using state funds on expenses abroad",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Govt says former President not using state funds on expenses abroad",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is spending for his current foreign travels through his personal funds and not through state funds, the Government Information Department said today.",
        "Issuing a statement, it said former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa does not spend government money on any expenses he makes abroad and that all such expenses shall be borne by the personal funds of the former President.",
        "At the press conference held today (16) at the Government Information Department’s auditorium to announce the weekly cabinet decisions, media persons had raised a question about the foreign expenses of the former President, who is currently in Thailand after brief stays in Maldives and Singapore.",
        "Minister Bandula Gunawardena’s response that former and current presidents are legally entitled to certain privileges, had been reported by some media in a manner that insinuates that state funds were being spent for the foreign expenses of the former president, the communiqué said.",
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa informed that the reports published by some media about his overseas expenses are incorrect and emphasized that his personal funds are spent for all the expenses."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා විදේශ වියදම් සඳහා රාජ්‍ය මුදල් භාවිත නොකරන බව රජය පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වත්මන් විදේශ සංචාර සඳහා වියදම් කරන්නේ රාජ්‍ය මුදල්වලින් නොව ඔහුගේ පෞද්ගලික මුදලින් බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් එහි දැක්වෙන්නේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තමන් විදේශයන්හි කරන කිසිදු වියදමක් සඳහා රජයේ මුදල් වැය නොකරන බවත්, එම සියලු වියදම් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික මුදලින් දැරිය යුතු බවත්ය.",
        "සතිපතා කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම් දීම සඳහා රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ශ්‍රවණාගාරයේ අද (16) පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මාලදිවයිනේ සහ සිංගප්පූරුවේ කෙටි නවාතැන් ගෙන මේ වනවිට තායිලන්තයට ගොස් සිටින හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විදේශ වියදම් පිළිබඳව මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් මතු කර තිබුණා.",
        "හිටපු සහ වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරුන්ට නීත්‍යානුකූලව යම් වරප්‍රසාද හිමිවන බවට අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධනගේ ප්‍රතිචාරය ඇතැම් මාධ්‍ය විසින් වාර්තා කර තිබුණේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විදේශ වියදම් සඳහා රාජ්‍ය මුදල් වැය කරන බවට ඉඟි පළ කරන ආකාරයෙන් බවද එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "තමාගේ විදෙස් වියදම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇතැම් මාධ්‍ය පළ කරන වාර්තා වැරදි බව දන්වා සිටින හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සියලු වියදම් සඳහා වැය කරන්නේ තම පෞද්ගලික මුදල් බවද අවධාරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி வெளிநாட்டு செலவுகளுக்கு அரச நிதியை பயன்படுத்தவில்லை என அரசாங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது தற்போதைய வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணங்களுக்காக தனது தனிப்பட்ட நிதியின் ஊடாக செலவழித்து வருகின்றார் என அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வெளிநாட்டில் மேற்கொள்ளும் எந்தவொரு செலவுக்கும் அரசாங்கப் பணத்தைச் செலவிடுவதில்லை எனவும், அந்தச் செலவுகள் அனைத்தும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட நிதியினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் எனவும் அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்கள கேட்போர் கூடத்தில் இன்று (16) இடம்பெற்ற வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில், மாலைதீவு மற்றும் சிங்கப்பூரில் சிறிது காலம் தங்கியிருந்து தாய்லாந்தில் தங்கியுள்ள முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் வெளிநாட்டு செலவுகள் குறித்து ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் கேள்வி எழுப்பினர்.",
        "முன்னாள் மற்றும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதிகளுக்கு சட்டரீதியாக சில சலுகைகள் உண்டு என அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்த பதிலை, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் வெளிநாட்டு செலவினங்களுக்காக அரச நிதி செலவிடப்படுவதாக சில ஊடகங்கள் ஊடாக செய்தி வெளியிட்டிருந்ததாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது வெளிநாட்டு செலவுகள் குறித்து சில ஊடகங்கள் வெளியிட்ட செய்திகள் தவறானவை என தெரிவித்ததோடு, அனைத்து செலவுகளுக்கும் தனது தனிப்பட்ட நிதியே செலவிடப்படுவதாக வலியுறுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}