{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84291/four-more-sri-lankans-reach-tn-on-illegal-vessel",
  "time_ut": 1660454460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Four more Sri Lankans reach TN on illegal vessel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four more Sri Lankans reach TN on illegal vessel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four more persons from Sri Lanka landed in the Indian waters on an illegal vessel in the wee hours of Saturday, owing to the economic crisis in the island nation, the Hindu reported.",
        "After surveillance teams from the Central and State agencies alerted the Tamil Nadu Marine Police, the four foreign nationals were taken for interrogation.",
        "According to police, Jayamalini, 50, wife of Somasundaram of Trincomalee district in Sri Lanka, said there were no jobs and survival had become difficult. Prices were too high, she said, adding that they decided to hire a vessel and reach Mandapam in Tamil Nadu.",
        "Along with her two sons– S. Pathurjan, 26, and S. Hamsikan, 22– and daughter S. Padushika, 19, she boarded a vessel and reached Tamil Nadu around 4 a.m.",
        "A senior officer, who questioned them, said they had registered themselves as inmates at the Mandapam Refugee Camp in 2006 and had left for Sri Lanka in 2019.",
        "They were handed over to revenue authorities at the Mandapam Rehabilitation Centre, where already about 120 people, including women and children were staying.",
        "Last month, an aged woman from Sri Lanka passed away after she was admitted to Government Rajaji Hospital, Madurai.",
        "The Tamil Nadu government had been providing food and shelter to people who had arrived in the state from Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the wee hours of Saturday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Nadu Marine Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamalini",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam in Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S. Pathurjan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Hamsikan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Padushika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Mandapam Refugee Camp",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Mandapam Rehabilitation Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madurai",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් හතර දෙනෙක් නීතිවිරෝධී යාත්‍රාවකින් TN වෙත ළඟා වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් සෙනසුරාදා අලුයම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිට තවත් පුද්ගලයින් සිව් දෙනෙකු නීතිවිරෝධී යාත්‍රාවකින් ඉන්දීය මුහුදු සීමාවට ගොඩ බැස ඇති බව හින්දු පුවත්පත වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "මධ්‍යම සහ ප්‍රාන්ත නියෝජිතායතනවල නිරීක්ෂණ කණ්ඩායම් තමිල්නාඩු සමුද්‍ර පොලිසියට දැනුම් දීමෙන් පසුව, විදේශීය ජාතිකයන් හතර දෙනා ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම සඳහා රැගෙන යන ලදී.",
        "පොලිසියට අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ සෝමසුන්දරම්ගේ බිරිඳ වන 50 හැවිරිදි ජයමාලිනී පැවසුවේ රැකියාවක් නොමැති බවත් පැවැත්ම දුෂ්කර වී ඇති බවත්ය. මිල වැඩියි, ඔවුන් යාත්‍රාවක් කුලියට ගෙන තමිල්නාඩුවේ මණ්ඩපම් වෙත ළඟා වීමට තීරණය කළ බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඇගේ පුතුන් දෙදෙනා - එස්. පතුර්ජන්, 26, සහ එස්. හම්සිකන්, 22- සහ දියණිය එස්. පදුෂිකා, 19, සමඟ ඇය යාත්‍රාවකට නැඟ අලුයම 4 ට පමණ තමිල්නාඩුවට පැමිණියාය.",
        "ඔවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කළ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසුවේ ඔවුන් 2006 වසරේ මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත කඳවුරේ රැඳවියන් ලෙස ලියාපදිංචි වී 2019 වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි බවයි.",
        "ඔවුන් මණ්ඩපම් පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ ආදායම් බලධාරීන් වෙත භාර දී ඇති අතර, ඒ වන විටත් කාන්තාවන් සහ ළමුන් ඇතුළු 120 දෙනෙකු පමණ එහි රැඳී සිට ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වයස්ගත කාන්තාවක් මදුරෙයි රජයේ රාජාජි රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසු මිය ගියාය.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිට ප්‍රාන්තයට පැමිණි ජනතාවට ආහාර සහ නවාතැන් සපයා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා අලුයම",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු මැරීන් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයමාලිනී",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුවේ මණ්ඩපයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස් පතුර්ජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් හම්සිකන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් පදුෂිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 4",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත කඳවුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "120 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය මාසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මදුරෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேலும் நான்கு இலங்கையர்கள் சட்டவிரோத கப்பலில் தமிழ்நாட்டை அடைந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தீவு நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இலங்கையைச் சேர்ந்த மேலும் நான்கு பேர் சனிக்கிழமை அதிகாலை சட்டவிரோத கப்பலொன்றில் இந்திய கடற்பரப்பில் தரையிறங்கியதாக தி ஹிந்து செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய மற்றும் மாநில ஏஜென்சிகளின் கண்காணிப்பு குழுக்கள் தமிழக மரைன் போலீசாருக்கு தகவல் கொடுத்ததையடுத்து, நான்கு வெளிநாட்டவர்களும் விசாரணைக்கு அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டனர்.",
        "காவல்துறையின் கூற்றுப்படி, இலங்கையில் திருச்சி மாவட்டத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சோமசுந்தரத்தின் மனைவி ஜெயமாலினி (50), வேலை இல்லை என்றும், பிழைப்பு கடினமாகிவிட்டது என்றும் கூறினார். விலைகள் மிக அதிகமாக இருந்ததால், ஒரு கப்பலை வாடகைக்கு எடுத்து தமிழ்நாட்டில் உள்ள மண்டபத்தை அடைய முடிவு செய்ததாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தனது இரண்டு மகன்களான எஸ்.பதுர்ஜன், 26, மற்றும் எஸ்.ஹம்சிகன், 22- மற்றும் மகள் எஸ். பாதுஷிகா, 19 ஆகியோருடன், அவர் ஒரு கப்பலில் ஏறி, அதிகாலை 4 மணியளவில் தமிழகத்தை அடைந்தார்.",
        "அவர்களிடம் விசாரித்த மூத்த அதிகாரி ஒருவர், அவர்கள் 2006-ம் ஆண்டு மண்டபம் அகதிகள் முகாமில் தங்களைக் கைதிகளாகப் பதிவு செய்துவிட்டு 2019-ம் ஆண்டு இலங்கைக்குப் புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றதாகத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஏற்கனவே பெண்கள், குழந்தைகள் உட்பட 120 பேர் தங்கியிருந்த மண்டபம் மறுவாழ்வு மையத்தில் வருவாய்த்துறை அதிகாரிகளிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "கடந்த மாதம், இலங்கையைச் சேர்ந்த வயதான பெண் ஒருவர் மதுரை அரசு ராஜாஜி மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு உயிரிழந்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து தமிழகம் வந்தவர்களுக்கு தமிழக அரசு உணவு மற்றும் தங்குமிடம் வழங்கி வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு மரைன் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமாலினி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாட்டில் மண்டபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.பதுர்ஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஹம்சிகன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். பாதுஷிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 4 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் அகதிகள் முகாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}