{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-appoints-committee-to-probe-taisei-linked-allegation-97827/",
  "time_ut": 1658551560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President appoints committee to probe Taisei-linked allegation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President appoints committee to probe Taisei-linked allegation",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Ranil Wickremesinghe has appointed a committee headed by a retired High Court judge to probe an allegation that a minister had demanded a bribe from Japan’s Taisei construction company.",
        "Former Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva had requested a formal investigation after opposition leader Sajith Premadada made the allegation in parliament and there were also social media reports, the President’s media office said.",
        "Though a minister was not named, de Silva said Taisei was involved in a Colombo airport contract, and by implication the allegations pointed to him and wanted a formal probe.",
        "The committee will be headed by Retired High Court Judge and President’s Counsel Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena.",
        "Retired Senior Deputy Inspector General of Police S M Wickremasinghe, a retired Special Grade Officer of Sri Lanka Administrative Service S M G K Perera will be the other two members.",
        "Minister de Silva resigned after the allegation was made, denying any involvement."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Taisei",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadada",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Taisei",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarojini Weerawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Special Grade Officer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Administrative Service S M",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Taisei සම්බන්ධ චෝදනාව විමර්ශනය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජපානයේ Taisei ඉදිකිරීම් සමාගමෙන් ඇමතිවරයෙකු අල්ලසක් ඉල්ලා ඇති බවට එල්ල වූ චෝදනාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා විශ්‍රාමික මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරයෙකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කමිටුවක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "විපක්‍ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී එම චෝදනාව සිදුකිරීමත් සමග හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා විධිමත් පරීක්‍ෂණයක් ඉල්ලා ඇති අතර ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා ද පළ වූ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයකු නම් නොකළද, ටයිසේ කොළඹ ගුවන් තොටුපළ කොන්ත්‍රාත්තුවකට සම්බන්ධ බව ද සිල්වා මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය.",
        "විශ්‍රාමලත් මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු සහ ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ කුසලා සරෝජනී වීරවර්ධන මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කමිටුව කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "විශ්‍රාමික ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති එස්.එම් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවයේ විශ්‍රාමික විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ නිලධාරියෙකු වන එස්.එම්.ජී.කේ.පෙරේරා සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් දෙදෙනා වේ.",
        "චෝදනාව එල්ල වීමත් සමග ද සිල්වා අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වූයේ කිසිදු සම්බන්ධයක් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටයිසේයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටයිසේයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටයිසේයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරෝජිනී වීරවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ නිලධාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවයේ එස්.එම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Taisei தொடர்பான குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரிக்க இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜப்பானின் Taisei கட்டுமான நிறுவனத்திடம் அமைச்சர் ஒருவர் லஞ்சம் கேட்டதாக எழுந்த குற்றச்சாட்டை விசாரிக்க ஓய்வு பெற்ற உயர்நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி தலைமையில் ஒரு குழுவை இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாதா இந்தக் குற்றச்சாட்டை முன்வைத்ததையடுத்து, சமூக வலைத்தளங்களில் செய்திகள் வெளியானதையடுத்து, முறையான விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு அமைச்சர் பெயர் குறிப்பிடப்படவில்லை என்றாலும், தைசே கொழும்பு விமான நிலைய ஒப்பந்தத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளார் என்றும், உட்குறிப்பு மூலம் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் அவரை சுட்டிக்காட்டி முறையான விசாரணையை விரும்புவதாகவும் டி சில்வா கூறினார்.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற உயர் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதியும் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணியுமான குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன தலைமையில் இந்தக் குழு அமைக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் எஸ்.எம்.விக்ரமசிங்க, இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவையின் ஓய்வுபெற்ற விசேட தர அதிகாரி எஸ்.எம்.ஜி.கே.பெரேரா ஆகியோர் ஏனைய இரு அங்கத்தவர்களாக இருப்பர்.",
        "குற்றச்சாட்டு முன்வைக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, அமைச்சர் டி சில்வா, அதற்குத் தொடர்பில்லை என மறுத்து இராஜினாமா செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தைசி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தைசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு தர அலுவலர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவை எஸ்.எம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}