{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/24/president-s-head-of-security-at-inquiry-over-assault-on-journalists/",
  "time_ut": 1661353560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President’s Head of Security at inquiry over assault on journalists",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President’s Head of Security at inquiry over assault on journalists",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President's Head of Security at inquiry over assault on journalists",
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); SSP Nizam Jamaldeen, the current Director of the President's Security Division, and the Former Director of the Prime Minister's Security Division was summoned to the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka on Wednesday (24), with regard to the complaint filed by MTV Channel (PVT) Limited over the assault on News 1st journalists who were reporting on the protests that took place opposite Ranil Wickremesinghe's Private Residence on the 9th of July 2022.",
        "The inquiry took place in the presence of the Chairman of the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka Retired Supreme Court Judge Rohini Marasinghe and Human Rights Commissioner Anusuya Shanmuganathan.",
        "The SSPs party had requested the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka to allow for submissions to be made after the Fundamental Rights application filed over the incident it taken up at the Supreme Court. However, that request was turned down.",
        "The HRCSL emphasized if SSP Nizam Jamaldeen does not provide a statement, it will be considered as he has nothing to submit to the commission with regard to the assault on journalists.",
        "Accordingly, SSP Nizam Jamaldeen was notified to appear at the commission again on the 9th of September.",
        "President's Counsel Ronald Perera appearing on behalf of SSP Nizam Jamaldeen revealed that his client had made him aware over the phone on Tuesday (23) evening that a case had been filed with the Supreme Court over the violation of Fundamental Rights.",
        "The counsel apprised the commission that SSP Jamaldeen is unwilling to provide a statement until case records are assessed and advice is sought from his client.",
        "President's Counsel Ronald Perera also noted he believes his client will be prejudiced if a statement is provided on Wednesday (24) adding he had advised his client to refrain from providing such a statement.",
        "Counsel representing MTV Channel Private Limited Damitha Karunarathne said the petition filed at the Supreme Court and the probe at the HRCSL are two separate examinations, pointing out that no court or institution had issued an injunction to halt the commission's investigation.",
        "Attorney at Law Damitha Karunarathne added the rights of the MTV Channel Private Limited and its journalists will be seriously affected if the inquiry is postponed.",
        "He requested that a final decision be announced as soon as possible.",
        "After considering the facts, the Chairman of the Commission stated she had it was her understanding that President's Counsel Ronald Perera had presented facts without fully comprehending facts provided in Act no.21 of the Human Rights Commission.",
        "She noted, that Supreme Court's case and the investigation conducted by the HRCSL were conducted in two separate contexts.",
        "Quoting certain clauses, Chairman Rohini Marasinghe said the HRCSL's probe should not be halted in light of the Supreme Court's examination, elaborating that the HRCSL probe should continue.",
        "The Chairman emphasized that SSP Jamaldeen refraining from providing testimony when it is of paramount importance to the probe, should not be done so according to the Act.",
        "SL Police cites specific UN Security Council Resolution as relevant in PTA arrests",
        "President’s Head of Security at inquiry over assault on journalists",
        "Activist Senadhi Guruge arrested; Opp. Leader not allowed to see activist"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Nizam Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel (PVT) Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka Retired Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohini Marasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anusuya Shanmuganathan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The SSPs party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Nizam Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Nizam Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Nizam Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel Private Limited Damitha Karunarathne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Law Damitha Karunarathne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channel Private Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Quoting",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohini Marasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Jamaldeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN Security Council Resolution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opp",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම ගැන ජනපතිගේ ආරක්ෂක ප්‍රධානියා පරීක්ෂණයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති ආරක්ෂක අංශ ප්‍රධානියා පරීක්ෂණයක",
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV නාලිකාව (PVT) විසින් ගොනු කරන ලද පැමිණිල්ලට අදාළව ජනාධිපති ආරක්ෂක අංශයේ වත්මන් අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ආරක්ෂක අංශයේ හිටපු අධ්‍යක්ෂ බදාදා (24) ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව වෙත කැඳවා තිබුණි. ) 2022 ජූලි 9 වන දින රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ඉදිරිපිට පැවති විරෝධතා වාර්තා කරමින් සිටි News 1st මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සීමා",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ සභාපති විශ්‍රාමලත් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු රෝහිණී මාරසිංහ සහ මානව හිමිකම් කොමසාරිස් අනුසුයා ෂන්මුගනාදන් යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් ඉදිරියේ මෙම පරීක්ෂණය සිදු විය.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී පාර්ශවය ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ තමන් විසින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ කැඳවූ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අයදුම්පතෙන් පසු කරුණු දැක්වීමට අවසර දෙන ලෙසයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එම ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප විය.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් මහතා මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොමිසමට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට කිසිවක් නොමැති බැවින් ඔහුගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා නොදෙන්නේ නම් ඒ පිළිබඳව සලකා බලන බව මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් මහතාට සැප්තැම්බර් මස 09 වැනිදා යළි කොමිසමේ පෙනී සිටින ලෙස දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා අනාවරණ කළේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ නඩුවක් පවරා ඇති බව තම සේවාදායකයා අඟහරුවාදා (23) සවස දුරකථනයෙන් තමා දැනුවත් කළ බවයි.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ජමාල්ඩීන් මහතා සිය සේවාදායකයාගෙන් නඩු වාර්තා තක්සේරු කර උපදෙස් ලබා ගන්නා තෙක් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීමට අකමැති බව නීතිඥවරයා කොමිසමට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "බදාදා (24) ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීමෙන් තම සේවාදායකයාට අගතියක් සිදුවනු ඇතැයි තමන් විශ්වාස කරන බවද සඳහන් කළ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා, එවැනි ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස තම සේවාදායකයාට උපදෙස් දුන් බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "MTV Channel Private Limited වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතීඥ දමිතා කරුණාරත්න කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම සහ HRCSL හි විමර්ශනය වෙන වෙනම විභාග දෙකක් බවත්, කොමිසමේ විමර්ශන නතර කිරීමට කිසිදු අධිකරණයක් හෝ ආයතනයක් වාරණ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කර නොමැති බවත් පෙන්වා දෙමිනි.",
        "එම්ටීවී චැනල් ප්‍රයිවට් ලිමිටඩ් හි අයිතිය පිළිබඳව නීතිඥ දමිතා කරුණාරත්න වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කර ඇති අතර, පරීක්ෂණය කල් දැමුවහොත් එහි මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වනු ඇති බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඒ පිළිබඳ අවසන් තීරණය කඩිනමින් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලෙස ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කරුණු සලකා බැලූ කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අංක 21 පනතේ දක්වා ඇති කරුණු සම්පූර්ණයෙන් අවබෝධ කර නොගෙන ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව තමාට වැටහී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ නඩුව සහ මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම විසින් පවත්වනු ලබන විමර්ශනය වෙන වෙනම සන්දර්භ දෙකකින් පවත්වන ලද බව ඇය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "ඇතැම් වගන්ති උපුටා දක්වමින් සභාපති රෝහිණී මාරසිංහ කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ විභාගය හමුවේ මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ විමර්ශනය නතර නොකළ යුතු බව පවසමින් මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ පරීක්ෂණය අඛණ්ඩව පැවැත්විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ජමාල්ඩීන් මහතා විමර්ශනයට ඉතා වැදගත් වන විට සාක්ෂි ලබාදීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීම පනතට අනුව සිදු නොකළ යුතු බව සභාපතිවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය අදාළ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ නිශ්චිත යෝජනාව උපුටා දක්වයි",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම ගැන ජනපතිගේ ආරක්ෂක ප්‍රධානියා පරීක්ෂණයට",
        "ක්‍රියාකාරි සේනධි ගුරුගේ අත්අඩංගුවට; විරුද්ධ නායකයාට ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු බැලීමට අවසර නැත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel (PVT) Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව විශ්‍රාමික ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිණී මාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුසුයා ෂන්මුගනාදන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්එස්පී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිසාම් ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel Private Limited දමිතා කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිය දමිතා කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චැනල් පුද්ගලික සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උපුටා ගැනීම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිණී මාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ජමාල්ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලයේ යෝජනාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරුද්ධ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதியின் பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவர் விசாரணை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பாக ஜனாதிபதியின் பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவர் விசாரணையில்",
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV சேனல் (PVT) செய்த முறைப்பாடு தொடர்பில், ஜனாதிபதியின் பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவின் தற்போதைய பணிப்பாளர் SSP நிசாம் ஜமால்தீன் மற்றும் பிரதமரின் பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவின் முன்னாள் பணிப்பாளர் ஆகியோர் புதன்கிழமை (24) இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வாசஸ்தலத்திற்கு எதிரே நடைபெற்ற போராட்டங்களைப் பற்றி செய்தி வெளியிட்ட நியூஸ் 1ஸ்ட் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் ஓய்வுபெற்ற உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி ரோஹினி மாரசிங்க மற்றும் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையாளர் அனுசுயா சண்முகநாதன் முன்னிலையில் இந்த விசாரணை இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுவின் பின்னர் சமர்ப்பிப்புகளை சமர்ப்பிக்க அனுமதிக்குமாறு SSPs தரப்பினர் இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்திருந்தனர். ஆனால், அந்த கோரிக்கை நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் தாக்கப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் ஆணைக்குழுவில் சமர்பிக்க எதுவுமில்லை என சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிசாம் ஜமால்டீன் அறிக்கையொன்றை வழங்காவிடின் அது பரிசீலிக்கப்படும் என மனித உரிமை ஆணையம் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி மீண்டும் ஆணைக்குழுவில் ஆஜராகுமாறு சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிசாம் ஜமால்டீனுக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் தொடர்பில் உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தனது கட்சிக்காரர் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (23) மாலை தொலைபேசி ஊடாக தனக்குத் தெரியப்படுத்தியதாக சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிசாம் ஜமால்டீன் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வழக்குப் பதிவுகள் மதிப்பீடு செய்யப்பட்டு, தனது வாடிக்கையாளரிடம் இருந்து ஆலோசனை பெறப்படும் வரை, எஸ்எஸ்பி ஜமால்தீன் அறிக்கை அளிக்கத் தயாராக இல்லை என்று ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் வழக்கறிஞர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா, புதன்கிழமை (24) அறிக்கையொன்றை வழங்கினால், தனது வாடிக்கையாளருக்கு பாரபட்சம் ஏற்படும் என தாம் நம்புவதாகவும், அவ்வாறான அறிக்கையை வழங்குவதைத் தவிர்க்குமாறு தனது வாடிக்கையாளருக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "எம்டிவி சேனல் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி தமிதா கருணாரத்ன, உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவும், மனித உரிமை ஆணையத்தின் விசாரணையும் இரண்டு தனித்தனியான பரீட்சைகள் என்றும், ஆணைக்குழுவின் விசாரணையை நிறுத்துவதற்கு எந்தவொரு நீதிமன்றமும் அல்லது நிறுவனமும் தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கவில்லை என்றும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "சட்டத்தரணி தமிதா கருணாரத்ன, எம்டிவி சேனல் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்டின் உரிமைகள் மற்றும் விசாரணை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டால் அதன் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்படுவார்கள் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இறுதி முடிவை விரைவில் அறிவிக்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "உண்மைகளை பரிசீலித்த ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர், மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் சட்ட எண்.21 இல் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள உண்மைகளை முழுமையாக புரிந்து கொள்ளாமல் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா உண்மைகளை முன்வைத்துள்ளார் என்பது தாம் புரிந்துகொண்டதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் வழக்கும் மனித உரிமை ஆணையத்தால் நடத்தப்பட்ட விசாரணையும் இரண்டு வெவ்வேறு சூழல்களில் நடத்தப்பட்டதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "சில ஷரத்துகளை மேற்கோள் காட்டிய தலைவர் ரோஹினி மாரசிங்க, உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் பரீட்சையின் வெளிச்சத்தில் HRCSL இன் விசாரணையை நிறுத்தக்கூடாது, HRCSL விசாரணை தொடர வேண்டும் என்று விளக்கினார்.",
        "விசாரணைக்கு மிகவும் முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த சாட்சியங்களை வழங்குவதிலிருந்து எஸ்.எஸ்.பி ஜமால்தீன், சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் அவ்வாறு செய்யக்கூடாது என தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "PTA கைதுகளில் தொடர்புடையது என குறிப்பிட்ட UN பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானத்தை SL போலீஸ் மேற்கோள் காட்டுகிறது",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதியின் பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவர் விசாரணை",
        "செயற்பாட்டாளர் சேனாதி குருகே கைது; எதிர் செயல்பாட்டாளரைப் பார்க்க தலைவர் அனுமதிக்கப்படவில்லை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல் (பிவிடி) லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு ஓய்வுபெற்ற உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹினி மாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுசுயா சண்முகநாதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஜாம் ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV சேனல் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் தமிதா கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டம் தமித கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேனல் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தரகு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கோள் காட்டுதல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹினி மாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி ஜமால்தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}