{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83502/sltb-workers-threaten-to-withdraw-from-duties",
  "time_ut": 1657257900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLTB workers threaten to withdraw from duties",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLTB workers threaten to withdraw from duties",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) workers will withdraw from duties if they are not provided with the required amount of fuel to report to work, the General Secretary to the All-Ceylon Transport Employees’ Association, Sepal Liyanage says.",
        "If the authorities fail to introduce a mechanism this morning to provide fuel for SLTB employees to report for work, they will resort to their trade union action after 12.00 noon today (08), he added.",
        "Meanwhile, Gemunu Wijeratne, the chairman of All-Ceylon Private Bus Owners’ Association, mentioned that private buses will not operate near the areas where protests are taking place, in order to use the available stocks of fuel economically.",
        "Ananda Ratnayake, the chairman of Water Supply & Drainage Board Employees’ Union, stressed that the authorities should take necessary steps to provide fuel for the employees of the Board amid the current situation.",
        "The Chairman of Station Masters’ Union Sumedha Somarathne stated that if there is no proper arrangement to supply fuel to the railway employees, the train services will be called off without prior notice."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.00 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ananda Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Water Supply & Drainage Board Employees’ Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Station Masters’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumedha Somarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංගම සේවකයන් රාජකාරීවලින් ඉවත් වන බවට තර්ජනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) සේවකයින්ට සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන ප්‍රමාණය ලබා නොදුනහොත් ඔවුන් සේවයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව සමස්ත ලංකා ප්‍රවාහන සේවක සංගමයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සේපාල් ලියනගේ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ලංගම සේවකයින්ට සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමේ යාන්ත්‍රණයක් අද පෙරවරුවේ හඳුන්වාදීමට බලධාරීන් අපොහොසත් වුවහොත් අද (08) දහවල් 12.00 න් පසු සිය වෘත්තීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයට එළඹෙන බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර, පවතින ඉන්ධන තොග ආර්ථික වශයෙන් භාවිත කිරීම සඳහා විරෝධතා පැවැත්වෙන ප්‍රදේශ ආසන්නයේ පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ ධාවනය නොකරන බව සමස්ත ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "පවතින තත්ත්වය හමුවේ ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන මණ්ඩලයේ සේවකයන්ට අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට බලධාරීන් පියවර ගත යුතු බව ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන මණ්ඩලයේ සේවක සංගමයේ සභාපති ආනන්ද රත්නායක මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දුම්රිය සේවකයින්ට ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට නිසි වැඩපිළිවෙළක් නොමැති වුවහොත් පෙර දැනුම්දීමකින් තොරව දුම්රිය ධාවනය නතර කරන බව දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති සුමේධ සෝමරත්න ප්‍රකාශ කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12.00",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන මණ්ඩලයේ සේවක සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේධා සෝමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை ஊழியர்கள் கடமைகளில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக அச்சுறுத்தல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை ஊழியர்கள் பணிக்கு வருவதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படாவிட்டால் அவர்கள் கடமைகளில் இருந்து விலகுவார்கள் என அகில இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து ஊழியர் சங்கத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சேபால் லியனகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை ஊழியர்களை வேலைக்குச் செல்வதற்கான எரிபொருளை வழங்கும் பொறிமுறையை அதிகாரிகள் இன்று காலை அறிமுகப்படுத்தத் தவறினால், இன்று (08) நண்பகல் 12.00 மணிக்குப் பின்னர் தமது தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபடவுள்ளதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, கையிருப்பில் உள்ள எரிபொருளை சிக்கனமாக பயன்படுத்துவதற்காக, போராட்டம் நடைபெறும் பகுதிகளுக்கு அருகில் தனியார் பஸ்கள் இயங்காது என அகில இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போதைய நிலைமைக்கு மத்தியில் சபை ஊழியர்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குவதற்கு அதிகாரிகள் தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்க வேண்டுமென நீர் வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகாலமைப்பு சபை ஊழியர் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ஆனந்த ரத்நாயக்க வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "புகையிரத ஊழியர்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குவதற்கு முறையான ஏற்பாடுகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படாவிட்டால், முன்னறிவிப்பின்றி ரயில் சேவைகள் நிறுத்தப்படும் என நிலைய அதிபர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் சுமேத சோமரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 12.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர் வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகால் சபை ஊழியர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டேஷன் மாஸ்டர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேதா சோமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}