{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Bar-Association-calls-for-swift-political-stability-and-public-restraint/56-737279",
  "time_ut": 1657361969,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bar Association calls for swift political stability and public restraint",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bar Association calls for swift political stability and public restraint",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) today called upon President Gotabhaya Rajapakse to consider whether he can continue to fulfil his obligations and the powers and duties as the President of Sri Lanka any longer.",
        "BASL's poser was in the light of the happenings that unfolded this morning  where protesting members of the public have entered and occupied the Presidential Secretariat and the President’s House.",
        "BASL  Executive Committee also called upon the Prime Minister, Speaker, Cabinet of Ministers and Members of Parliament to immediately ensure that political stability of the nation is secured forthwith. \"There  should be no delay in ensuring such a transition,\" BASL added..",
        "It also called upon the Police and the Armed Forces to ensure that no further harm is caused to the people who are engaged in the protest.",
        "\"We call upon the members of the public to protect public property – especially to the Presidential Secretariat and the President’s House which are historical sites in Sri Lanka and to ensure that no harm is caused to any person,\" BASL appealed to the public."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bar Association",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL  Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඩිනම් දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ මහජන සංයමය අවශ්‍ය බව නීතිඥ සංගමය ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තවදුරටත් තම වගකීම් සහ බලතල සහ යුතුකම් ඉටු කිරීමට ඔහුට හැකි දැයි සලකා බලන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) අද ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "BASL හි ඉරියව්ව වූයේ අද උදෑසන සිදු වූ සිදුවීම්වල ආලෝකයෙනි  විරෝධතා දක්වන මහජනතාව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට සහ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වී වාඩිලාගෙන සිටිති.",
        "BASL  විධායක කමිටුව, ජාතියේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය කඩිනමින් සුරක්ෂිත කිරීම සඳහා වහාම සහතික කරන ලෙස අගමැති, කථානායක, අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. \"එවැනි සංක්‍රාන්තියක් සහතික කිරීමට ප්‍රමාද නොවිය යුතුය,\" BASL වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "විරෝධතාවයේ නියැලී සිටින ජනතාවට මින් ඉදිරියට කිසිදු හානියක් සිදු නොවන බවට වග බලා ගන්නා ලෙස ද එය පොලිසියෙන් සහ ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "\"අපි මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ පොදු දේපළ - විශේෂයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඓතිහාසික ස්ථාන වන ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට සහ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ කිසිඳු පුද්ගලයෙකුට හානියක් නොවන පරිදි ආරක්ෂා කරන ලෙසයි,\" BASL මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் விரைவான அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொது கட்டுப்பாட்டிற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியாக தனது கடமைகள் மற்றும் அதிகாரங்கள் மற்றும் கடமைகளை அவர் தொடர்ந்து நிறைவேற்ற முடியுமா என்பதை பரிசீலிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) இன்று அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "BASL இன் போசர் இன்று காலை வெளிப்பட்ட நிகழ்வுகளின் வெளிச்சத்தில் இருந்தது  அங்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்த பொதுமக்கள் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்து ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "BASL  செயற்குழு, பிரதமர், சபாநாயகர், அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை, தேசத்தின் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை உடனடியாகப் பாதுகாக்கப்படுவதை உடனடியாக உறுதிசெய்யுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது. \"அத்தகைய மாற்றத்தை உறுதி செய்வதில் எந்த தாமதமும் இருக்கக்கூடாது\" என்று BASL மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "மேலும் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள மக்களுக்கு எந்தவித பாதிப்பும் ஏற்படாமல் பார்த்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு காவல்துறை மற்றும் ஆயுதப்படையினரையும் கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"பொதுச் சொத்துக்களை - குறிப்பாக இலங்கையின் வரலாற்றுத் தலங்களான ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை பாதுகாக்குமாறும், எவருக்கும் பாதிப்பு ஏற்படாதவாறு பார்த்துக் கொள்ளுமாறும் பொதுமக்களை நாம் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம்\" என BASL பொதுமக்களிடம் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL  நிர்வாகக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}