{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/japan-halts-12-jaica-projects-in-sri-lanka-until-imf-provides-roadmap-minister-98408/",
  "time_ut": 1660121340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan halts 12 JAICA projects in Sri Lanka until IMF provides roadmap: minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan halts 12 JAICA projects in Sri Lanka until IMF provides roadmap: minister",
      "author": "Mahadiya Hamza",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Japan has halted 12 projects under Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) in Sri Lanka until the International Monetary Fund (IMF) provides a roadmap to the crisis-hit island, a top minister said.",
        "“Twelve projects funded by Japan under JICA will be suspended until the IMF establishes a roadmap on Sri Lanka’s debts and its sustainability because the country has been declared bankrupt,” Minister of Ports, Shipping and Aviation Nimal Siripala de Silva told parliament on Wednesday August 10.",
        "Sri Lanka’s relations with Japan was tested in the last two years after former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who was closer to China scrapped a JICA-funded light railway transit (LRT) project claiming it was too expensive and unilaterally cancelled a 500 million US dollars trilateral deal with India and Japan to develop the Eastern Container Terminal (ECT) of the Colombo Port.",
        "The LRT project was a 1.5 billion US dollar soft-loan project that would have solved some of the traffic issues in the Malabe corridor.",
        "Sri Lanka has recently been trying to rebuild relations with Japan who previously poured many millions of dollars in funds to the country.",
        "Sri Lanka president orders immediate termination of Japan-funded light rail project",
        "Japan firm claims damages of Rs5.8bn from Sri Lanka after LRT deal scrapped",
        "Sri Lanka is facing its worst economic crisis in the post-independent era. Many countries have pledged help but said only they can do that once Sri Lanka ensures an IMF programme after renegotiations with its creditors. (Colombo/Aug10/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "JAICA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan International Cooperation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twelve",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shipping and Aviation Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday August 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Container Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 billion US dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malabe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "many millions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug10/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල මාර්ග සිතියම ලබා දෙන තුරු ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ JAICA ව්‍යාපෘති 12 ක් නවතා දමයි: ඇමති",
      "author": "මහදිය හම්සා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) අර්බුදකාරී දිවයිනට මාර්ග සිතියමක් සපයන තෙක් ජපානය විසින් ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය (JICA) යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ව්‍යාපෘති 12 ක් නතර කර ඇති බව ඉහළ අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "\"රට බංකොලොත් වී ඇති නිසා ජාමූඅ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය සහ එහි තිරසාරභාවය පිළිබඳ මාර්ග සිතියමක් ජාමූඅ විසින් පිහිටුවන තුරු ජයිකා යටතේ ජපානයෙන් අරමුදල් සපයන ව්‍යාපෘති 12 ක් අත්හිටුවන බව\" වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා අගෝස්තු 10 බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය. .",
        "චීනයට සමීපව සිටි හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, JICA අරමුදල් සහිත සැහැල්ලු දුම්රිය සංක්‍රමණ (LRT) ව්‍යාපෘතියක් මිල අධික බව පවසමින් එය අවලංගු කර ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක ත්‍රෛපාර්ශ්වික ගිවිසුමක් ඒකපාර්ශ්විකව අවලංගු කිරීමෙන් පසු පසුගිය වසර දෙක තුළ ජපානය සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සබඳතා පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් විය. කොළඹ වරායේ නැගෙනහිර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය (ECT) සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට ඉන්දියාව සහ ජපානය.",
        "එල්ආර්ටී ව්‍යාපෘතිය මාලඹේ කොරිඩෝවේ රථවාහන ගැටලුවලට විසඳුම් ලබා දෙන ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 ක සහන ණය ව්‍යාපෘතියකි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මීට පෙර ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනින් රටට අරමුදල් සම්පාදනය කළ ජපානය සමඟ සබඳතා නැවත ගොඩනඟා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරයි.",
        "ජපානයේ අරමුදල් සහිත සැහැල්ලු දුම්රිය ව්‍යාපෘතිය වහා අවසන් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති නියෝග කරයි",
        "LRT ගනුදෙනුව අවලංගු කිරීමෙන් පසු ජපාන සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් රුපියල් බිලියන 5.8 ක අලාභයක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පශ්චාත් නිදහස් යුගයේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටී. බොහෝ රටවල් උදව් කිරීමට ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇති නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ණය හිමියන් සමඟ නැවත සාකච්ඡා කිරීමෙන් පසු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනක් සහතික කළ පසු එය කළ හැක්කේ ඔවුන්ට පමණක් බව පවසා ඇත. (කොළඹ/අගෝ.10/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජයිකා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දොළහයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 10 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර බහාලුම් පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලබේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනාවක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝ.10/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் 12 JAICA திட்டங்களை IMF வழங்கும் வரை ஜப்பான் நிறுத்துகிறது: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "மஹதியா ஹம்சா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தீவுக்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) ஒரு வரைபடத்தை வழங்கும் வரை இலங்கையில் ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு அமைப்பின் (JICA) கீழ் 12 திட்டங்களை ஜப்பான் நிறுத்தியுள்ளதாக உயர்மட்ட அமைச்சர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நாடு திவாலானதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால், இலங்கையின் கடன்கள் மற்றும் அதன் நிலைத்தன்மை குறித்து சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் ஒரு வரைபடத்தை அமைக்கும் வரை, JICA இன் கீழ் ஜப்பானால் நிதியளிக்கப்படும் 12 திட்டங்கள் இடைநிறுத்தப்படும்\" என்று துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமான போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா புதன்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 10 அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "சீனாவுடன் நெருக்கமாக இருந்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, JICA நிதியுதவியுடன் கூடிய இலகு ரயில் போக்குவரத்து (LRT) திட்டத்தை மிகவும் விலையுயர்ந்ததாகக் கூறி ஒருதலைப்பட்சமாக 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் முத்தரப்பு ஒப்பந்தத்தை ரத்து செய்ததை அடுத்து, ஜப்பானுடனான இலங்கையின் உறவு கடந்த இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளில் சோதிக்கப்பட்டது. கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தின் கிழக்கு கொள்கலன் முனையத்தை (ECT) அபிவிருத்தி செய்ய இந்தியா மற்றும் ஜப்பான்.",
        "LRT திட்டமானது 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான கடன் திட்டமாகும், இது மாலபே வழித்தடத்தில் உள்ள சில போக்குவரத்து பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்கும்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு முன்னர் பல மில்லியன் டொலர்களை நிதியாக வாரி வழங்கிய ஜப்பானுடனான உறவை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்ப இலங்கை சமீபகாலமாக முயற்சித்து வருகிறது.",
        "ஜப்பானின் நிதியுதவியுடன் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இலகு ரயில் திட்டத்தை உடனடியாக நிறுத்துமாறு இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்",
        "எல்ஆர்டி ஒப்பந்தம் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டதையடுத்து, ஜப்பான் நிறுவனம் இலங்கையிடமிருந்து 5.8 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் நஷ்டஈடு கோரியுள்ளது",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னரான காலப்பகுதியில் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது. பல நாடுகள் உதவி வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளன, ஆனால் இலங்கை தனது கடனாளிகளுடன் மறுபரிசீலனைகளுக்குப் பிறகு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் திட்டத்தை உறுதிசெய்தால் மட்டுமே அதைச் செய்ய முடியும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்10/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜெய்கா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னிரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கப்பல் மற்றும் விமான போக்குவரத்து நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 10 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கொள்கலன் முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலபே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்10/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}