{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-ceb-warns-of-likely-increase-in-power-cut-duration-over-lack-of-diesel-96772/",
  "time_ut": 1656691140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka CEB warns of likely increase in power cut duration over lack of diesel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka CEB warns of likely increase in power cut duration over lack of diesel",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s ongoing power cuts could be extended from the current daily three hours due to continuous diesel shortage for thermal power plants amid water levels in reservoirs are declining , state run utility provider, Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) said.",
        "The government is running out of diesel for electricity generation as well as for transportation purposes as it does not have adequate US dollars to import fuel.",
        "“We are running out of diesel to operate thermal power plants,” Andrew Navamani, CEB spokesman told EconomyNext.",
        "“And with the water levels dropping, it is possible that the power cut duration can increase again”",
        "However, Navamani said, no decision has been taken yet on such an increase in power cut.",
        "Even though the hydro power plants contributed for electricity generation in the country, still the majority of the power is being generated through thermal power plants, the government data showed.",
        "The last consignment under the Indian credit line arrived in Sri Lanka on June 16.",
        "The expected 500 million US dollar credit line from Indian EXIM Bank has not been finalised yet by Indian officials, Sri Lanka government officials have said.",
        "According to the CEB data, 59.7 percent of the total power needed for June 30 was generated through thermal power plants while around 34.1 percent was generated through the hydro power plants. The rest were from other sources including solar and wind power.",
        "Thermal power generation has increased by nearly 6 percent compared to a week earlier while hydro power generation has dropped around 2 percent.",
        "According to the status data issued by the CEB, several key catchment area that fed water to Randenigala, Samanala wewa, Rantambe and Bowatenna have not received any rainfall in the recent past. (Colombo/ July 01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Andrew Navamani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navamani",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500 million US dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian EXIM Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "59.7 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 34.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nearly 6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Randenigala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samanala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rantambe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bowatenna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩීසල් නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීමේ කාලය වැඩි විය හැකි බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ලංවිම අනතුරු අඟවයි",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජලාශවල ජල මට්ටම අඩුවෙමින් පවතින අතර තාප බලාගාර සඳහා අඛණ්ඩ ඩීසල් හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දැනට පවතින දෛනික පැය තුනේ විදුලි කප්පාදුව වත්මන් දෛනික පැය තුනේ සිට දීර්ඝ කළ හැකි බව රජයේ උපයෝගිතා සැපයුම්කරු, ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය (ලංවිම) පවසයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් නොමැතිකම නිසා රජයට විදුලිය නිෂ්පාදනයට මෙන්ම ප්‍රවාහන කටයුතු සඳහාද ඩීසල් හිඟ වෙමින් පවතී.",
        "“තාප බලාගාර ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා අපට ඩීසල් ඉවරයි,” ලංවිම ප්‍රකාශක Andrew Navamani EconomyNext වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ජල මට්ටම පහත වැටීමත් සමඟ විදුලිය විසන්ධි වන කාලය යළිත් වැඩි විය හැකියි",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එවැනි විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් වැඩි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙතෙක් තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැති බව නවමනී පැවසුවාය.",
        "මෙරට විදුලිබල උත්පාදනය සඳහා ජල විදුලි බලාගාර දායකත්වය ලබාදුන්නද තවමත් විදුලිය වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් නිෂ්පාදනය කරනු ලබන්නේ තාප බලාගාර හරහා බව රජයේ දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ක්‍රෙඩිට් රේඛාව යටතේ අවසන් තොගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේ ජුනි 16 වැනිදාය.",
        "ඉන්දීය EXIM බැංකුවෙන් අපේක්ෂා කරන ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක ණය මාර්ගය ඉන්දීය නිලධාරීන් විසින් තවමත් අවසන් කර නොමැති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ බලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "ලංවිම දත්ත වලට අනුව ජූනි 30 දිනට අවශ්‍ය මුළු විදුලියෙන් සියයට 59.7ක් තාප බලාගාර හරහා ජනනය කර ඇති අතර සියයට 34.1ක් පමණ ජල විදුලි බලාගාර හරහා ජනනය කර ඇත. ඉතිරිය සූර්ය බලශක්තිය සහ සුළං බලය ඇතුළු වෙනත් ප්‍රභවයන්ගෙන්.",
        "පෙර සතියකට සාපේක්ෂව තාප විදුලිය නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 6කින් පමණ ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර ජල විදුලි නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 2කින් පමණ පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ලංවිම නිකුත් කළ තත්ව දත්ත වලට අනුව රන්දෙණිගල, සමනල වැව, රන්ටැඹේ සහ බෝවතැන්න යන ප්‍රදේශවලට ජලය සපයන ප්‍රධාන ජල පෝෂක ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට පසුගිය කාලයේ වර්ෂාපතනයක් ලැබී නොමැත. (කොළඹ/ ජූලි 01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය තුනක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ඩෘ නවමානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවමානි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු EXIM බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 59.7 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 34.1 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 2 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්දෙණිගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමනල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ටැඹේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bowatenna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டீசல் பற்றாக்குறையால் மின்வெட்டு கால அளவு அதிகரிக்க வாய்ப்புள்ளதாக இலங்கை CEB எச்சரித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நீர்த்தேக்கங்களில் நீர்மட்டம் குறைந்து வருவதால், அனல் மின் நிலையங்களுக்கான தொடர்ச்சியான டீசல் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக, இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய மின்வெட்டு தினசரி மூன்று மணித்தியாலங்களில் இருந்து நீடிக்கப்படலாம் என, அரச நிறுவனமான, இலங்கை மின்சார சபை (CEB) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய போதிய அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் இல்லாததால், மின்சார உற்பத்திக்கும், போக்குவரத்துக்கும் டீசல் இல்லாமல் அரசு திணறி வருகிறது.",
        "\"அனல் மின் நிலையங்களை இயக்க டீசல் இல்லாமல் போகிறோம்\" என்று CEB செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஆண்ட்ரூ நவமணி EconomyNext இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும் நீர்மட்டம் குறைந்து வருவதால், மின்வெட்டு காலம் மீண்டும் அதிகரிக்க வாய்ப்புள்ளது.",
        "எனினும், மின்வெட்டு அதிகரிப்பது குறித்து இதுவரை எந்த முடிவும் எடுக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் நவமணி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் மின்சார உற்பத்திக்கு நீர் மின் நிலையங்கள் பங்களிப்பு செய்தாலும், அனல் மின் நிலையங்கள் மூலம் அதிகளவு மின்சாரம் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்பட்டு வருவதாக அரசாங்க தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்திய கடன் வரியின் கீழ் கடைசி சரக்கு ஜூன் 16 அன்று இலங்கைக்கு வந்தது.",
        "இந்தியன் EXIM வங்கியிடமிருந்து எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் கடன் வரி இந்திய அதிகாரிகளால் இன்னும் இறுதி செய்யப்படவில்லை என இலங்கை அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "CEB தரவுகளின்படி, ஜூன் 30 க்கு தேவையான மொத்த மின்சாரத்தில் 59.7 சதவீதம் அனல் மின் நிலையங்கள் மூலமாகவும், 34.1 சதவீதம் நீர் மின் நிலையங்கள் மூலமாகவும் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்பட்டது. மீதமுள்ளவை சூரிய சக்தி மற்றும் காற்றாலை உள்ளிட்ட பிற ஆதாரங்களில் இருந்து வந்தவை.",
        "கடந்த ஒரு வாரத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் அனல் மின் உற்பத்தி கிட்டத்தட்ட 6 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்துள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில் நீர் மின் உற்பத்தி 2 சதவீதம் குறைந்துள்ளது.",
        "மின்சார சபையினால் வெளியிடப்பட்ட நிலவரப்படி, ரந்தெனிகல, சமனல வெவ, ரன்தம்பே மற்றும் போவதென்ன ஆகிய பகுதிகளுக்கு நீர் வழங்கும் பல முக்கிய நீர்ப்பிடிப்புப் பகுதிகள் அண்மைக் காலமாக மழையைப் பெறவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ ஜூலை 01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மணி நேரங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்ட்ரூ நவமணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நவமணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் EXIM வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "59.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 34.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரந்தெனிகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமனல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரண்டாம்பே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bowatenna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}