{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/21/208-sri-lanka-bound-flights-had-stopover-at-thiruvananthapuram-int-l-airport-for-refueling-till-date/",
  "time_ut": 1661054760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "208 Sri Lanka bound flights had stopover at Thiruvananthapuram Int’l airport for refueling till date",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "208 Sri Lanka bound flights had stopover at Thiruvananthapuram Int’l airport for refueling till date",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ANI): A total of 208 Sri Lanka flights had a stopover at Kerala's Thiruvananthapuram International Airport for refuelling to date.",
        "On Saturday (20), 4 flights had stopped at Thiruvananthapuram for refuelling.",
        "With this, the total number of Sri Lankan flights had a stopover since May 27 this year is 208.  Of these, the most number of flights is SriLankan Airlines.",
        "Moreover, 130 SriLankan Airlines flights stopped at Thiruvananthapuram for refuelling till yesterday.",
        "Other airlines are Fly Dubai, Oman Air, Gulf Air, Air Arabia, Emirates and Fits Voyage flying to various destinations.",
        "The Sri Lankan flights started refuelling from Thiruvananthapuram Airport since May 27, 2022 after they faced a shortage of fuel.",
        "Notably, Sri Lanka is suffering its worst economic crisis since gaining independence in 1948, which comes on the heels of successive waves of COVID-19, threatening to undo years of development progress and severely undermining the country's ability to achieve the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).",
        "208 Sri Lanka bound flights had stopover at Thiruvananthapuram Int’l airport for refueling till date"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "208",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 27 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fly Dubai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman Air",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf Air",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fits Voyage",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 27, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sustainable Development Goals",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලා යන ගුවන් ගමන් 208ක් මේ දක්වා ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ නතර කර ඇත.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ANI): මේ දක්වා ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් ගමන් 208 ක් කේරළයේ තිරුවන්තම්පුරම් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ නතර කර ඇත.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා (20) ගුවන් යානා 4ක් ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා තිරුවානන්තපුරම් හි නතර කර තිබුණි.",
        "මේ සමඟ, මේ වසරේ මැයි 27 සිට නැවතුම් ඇති මුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් ගමන් සංඛ්‍යාව 208 කි.  මෙයින් වැඩිම ගුවන් ගමන් සංඛ්‍යාව ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයයි.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලන්කන් ගුවන් සේවයේ ගුවන් ගමන් 130ක් ඊයේ වනතුරු තිරුවානන්තපුරම් හි නතර කර ඇත.",
        "අනෙකුත් ගුවන් සමාගම් වන්නේ ෆ්ලයි ඩුබායි, ඕමාන් එයාර්, ගල්ෆ් එයාර්, එයාර් ඇරබියා, එමිරේට්ස් සහ ෆිට්ස් වොයේජ් විවිධ ගමනාන්ත වෙත පියාසර කිරීමයි.",
        "2022 මැයි 27 දින සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් ගමන් තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් ඉන්ධන සැපයීම ආරම්භ කළේ ඉන්ධන හිඟයකට මුහුණ දීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "සැලකිය යුතු කරුණක් නම්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 1948 නිදහස ලබා ගැනීමෙන් පසු එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට ගොදුරු වී ඇති අතර, එය වසර ගණනාවක සංවර්ධන ප්‍රගතිය අවලංගු කිරීමට තර්ජනය කරමින් සහ තිරසාර සංවර්ධන ඉලක්ක (SDGs) සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට රටට ඇති හැකියාව බරපතල ලෙස හෑල්ලුවට ලක් කරමින් කොවිඩ්-19 හි අනුප්‍රාප්තික රැල්ල මත පැමිණේ. )",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලා යන ගුවන් ගමන් 208ක් මේ දක්වා ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ නතර කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "208",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මැයි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි පියාසර කරන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් එයාර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ් ගුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගමනට ගැලපේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරසාර සංවර්ධන ඉලක්ක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை செல்லும் 208 விமானங்கள் இன்றுவரை எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக திருவனந்தபுரம் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ANI): கேரளாவின் திருவனந்தபுரம் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இன்றுவரை எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக மொத்தம் 208 இலங்கை விமானங்கள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை (20) எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக 4 விமானங்கள் திருவனந்தபுரத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "இதன் மூலம், இந்த ஆண்டு மே 27 முதல் நிறுத்தப்பட்ட இலங்கை விமானங்களின் மொத்த எண்ணிக்கை 208 ஆகும்.  இவற்றில், அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான விமானங்கள் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் ஆகும்.",
        "மேலும், நேற்று வரை 130 ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானங்கள் எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக திருவனந்தபுரத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "பிற விமான நிறுவனங்கள் ஃப்ளை துபாய், ஓமன் ஏர், கல்ஃப் ஏர், ஏர் அரேபியா, எமிரேட்ஸ் மற்றும் ஃபிட்ஸ் வோயேஜ் ஆகியவை பல்வேறு இடங்களுக்கு பறக்கின்றன.",
        "இலங்கை விமானங்கள் எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொண்டதை அடுத்து, மே 27, 2022 முதல் திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் நிரப்பத் தொடங்கியது.",
        "குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில், 1948 இல் சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் இலங்கை அதன் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்கிறது, இது தொடர்ச்சியான COVID-19 அலைகளின் அடிமட்டத்தில் வருகிறது, இது பல ஆண்டுகால வளர்ச்சி முன்னேற்றத்தை செயல்தவிர்க்க அச்சுறுத்துகிறது மற்றும் நிலையான அபிவிருத்தி இலக்குகளை (SDGs) அடைவதற்கான நாட்டின் திறனை கடுமையாக குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்துகிறது. )",
        "இலங்கை செல்லும் 208 விமானங்கள் இன்றுவரை எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக திருவனந்தபுரம் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருந்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "208",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஎன்ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மே 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துபாய் பறக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் ஏர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா ஏர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர் அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயணத்திற்கு ஏற்றது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 27, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையான வளர்ச்சி இலக்குகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}