{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130813",
  "time_ut": 1656998915,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மேலும் 5 தமிழக மீனவர்கள் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "5 more Tamil Nadu fishermen arrested",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Five fishermen from Tamil Nadu have been arrested by the navy on charges of fishing across the border.",
        "The five fishermen from Pudukottai district's Jegatapattinam area, who left Kodiakkarai area in a boat to catch fish, were arrested by the navy on Monday while they were fishing across the border at Karainagar beach in Jaffna.",
        "The Navy has taken steps to present the arrested fishermen in the Home Guard Magistrate's Court through the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources on Tuesday.",
        "Meanwhile, the 12 Tamil Nadu fishermen who were arrested for the crime of fishing across the border on Sunday, has been ordered to be remanded until the next 08th.",
        "17 Tamil Nadu fishermen have been arrested for crossing the border in two days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jegatapattinam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodiakkarai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karainagar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Home Guard Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 08th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවත් තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 5 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශ සීමාව හරහා මසුන් ඇල්ලීමේ චෝදනාව මත තමිල්නාඩුවේ ධීවරයින් පස් දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "කොඩියක්කරෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ සිට බෝට්ටුවකින් ධීවර කටයුතු සඳහා පිටත්ව ගිය පුදුකෝට්ටෙයි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ජගදපට්ටිනම් ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවරයින් පස්දෙනා සඳුදා දින යාපනයේ කරෙයිනගර් වෙරළ තීරයේ මායිම හරහා මසුන් අල්ලමින් සිටියදී නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ධීවරයින් අඟහරුවාදා ධීවර හා ජලජ සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හරහා ග්‍රාමාරක්ෂක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නාවික හමුදාව පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර පසුගිය ඉරිදා දේශසීමා හරහා ධීවර කටයුතුවල නිරත වීමේ වරදට අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 12 දෙනා ලබන 08 වනදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට නියෝග කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "දින දෙකක් තුළ දේශසීමා තරණය කළ තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 17 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙගතපට්ටිනම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodiakkarai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරෙයිනගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්‍රාමාරක්ෂක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර හා ජලජ සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීළඟ 08 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேலும் 5 தமிழக மீனவர்கள் கைது",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "எல்லை தாண்டி மீன் பிடித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் தமிழக மீனவர்கள் ஐந்து பேர் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "புதுக்கோட்டை மாவட்டம் ஜெகதாப்பட்டினம் பகுதியை சேர்ந்த ஐந்து மீனவர்களும் விசைப்படகொன்றில் கோடியாக்கரை பகுதியில் இருந்து மீன் பிடிக்க புறப்பட்டவர்கள் எல்லை தாண்டி யாழ்ப்பாணம் காரைநகர் கடற்பரப்பில் மீன் பிடியில் ஈடுபட்டு இருந்த வேளை கடற்படையினரால் நேற்று திங்கட்கிழமை கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட மீனவர்கள் இன்று செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கடற்தொழில் நீரியல் வளத்துறையினர் ஊடாக ஊர்காவற்துறை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் முற்படுத்த கடற்படையினர் நடவடிக்கைகளை முன்னெடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அதேவேளை நேற்று முன்தினம் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை எல்லை தாண்டி மீன் பிடியில் ஈடுபட்ட குற்றத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 12 தமிழக மீனவர்களை பருத்தித்துறை நீதவான் எதிர்வரும் 08 ஆம் திகதி வரையில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இரு தினங்களில் எல்லை தாண்டிய குற்றத்தின் கீழ் 17 தமிழக மீனவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெகதாபட்டினம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodiakkarai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரைநகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊர்க்காவல் படை மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்பிடி மற்றும் நீரியல் வளங்கள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 08 ஆம் திகதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}