{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ලංකාවට-ණය-දුන්-රටවල්-සාකච්ඡා-කරන්න-එන්න/1-619004",
  "time_ut": 1661847860,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාවට ණය දුන් රටවල් සාකච්ඡා කරන්න එන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Come to discuss the countries that have given loans to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Shunichi Suzuki, Minister of Finance of Japan, said that all lender countries are requested to meet at one table to discuss the loans given to Sri Lanka.",
        "Mr. Suzuki pointed out that it is very important to find a solution to the economic crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "Japanese Finance Minister Mr. Shunichi Suzuki said that Japan will coordinate with Sri Lanka's creditors to find a solution to the ongoing economic crisis.",
        "Mr. Suzuki said that Japan is concerned about the severe economic and social situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "Mr. Suzuki pointed out that Sri Lanka should speed up the negotiations to obtain a loan from the International Monetary Fund and countries that have given bilateral loans to Sri Lanka including China and India should gather at one table to discuss the loan issue."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාවට ණය දුන් රටවල් සාකච්ඡා කරන්න එන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දී ඇති ණය සම්බන්ධව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට එක මේසයකට රැස්වෙන ලෙස සියලුම ණය දුන් රටවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ජපාන මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ෂුනිචි සුසුකි මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඔඩු දුවන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට විසඳුමක් සෙවීම සඳහා එය ඉතා වැදගත් බව සුසුකි මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "එසේ ඔඩු දුවන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට විසඳුමක් සෙවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ජපානය සම්බන්ධීකරණ කටයුතු සිදු කරනු ඇතැයි ජපාන මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ෂුනිචි සුසුකි මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇති වී තිබෙන දරුණු ආර්ථික සහ සමාජීය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ ජපානය කණසල්ලට පත්ව ඇති බව සුසුකි මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ණය මුදලක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා සිදුකරන සාකච්ඡා කඩිනම් කළ යුතු බවත් චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද්වි පාර්ශ්වික ණය ලබා දුන් රටවල් ණය ප්‍රශ්නය පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට එක මේසයකට රැස්විය යුතු බවත් සුසුකි මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு கடன் வழங்கிய நாடுகள் குறித்து விவாதிக்க வாருங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட கடன்கள் தொடர்பில் கடன் வழங்கும் அனைத்து நாடுகளும் ஒரே மேசையில் கூடி கலந்துரையாடுமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுவதாக ஜப்பான் நிதி அமைச்சர் திரு.சுனிச்சி சுசுகி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண்பது மிகவும் முக்கியமானது என திரு.சுசுகி சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண இலங்கையின் கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் ஜப்பான் ஒருங்கிணைந்து செயல்படும் என ஜப்பானிய நிதி அமைச்சர் திரு.சுனிச்சி சுசுகி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் நிலவும் கடுமையான பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக நிலைமை குறித்து ஜப்பான் கவலை கொண்டுள்ளது என திரு.சுசுகி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் இருந்து கடனைப் பெறுவதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தையை இலங்கை துரிதப்படுத்த வேண்டும் என்றும், சீனா, இந்தியா உள்ளிட்ட இலங்கைக்கு இருதரப்புக் கடன்களை வழங்கிய நாடுகள் ஒரே மேசையில் ஒன்று கூடி கடன் விவகாரம் குறித்து விவாதிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் திரு.சுசுகி சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}