{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131160",
  "time_ut": 1657368693,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் காரசார விவாதம் : யார் ஜனாதிபதி ? யார் பிரதமர் ? - முழு விபரம் இதோ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Political debate in the party leader's meeting: Who is the president? Who is the Prime Minister? - Here are the full details",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Anurakumar Dissanayake and Sumandran participated in this meeting through virtual (Zoom).",
        "In this case, it was discussed in the party leader's meeting that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should step down together and after that the Speaker should hold the position of Acting President for a short period of time.",
        "In addition, the party leader Maithripala Sirisena has insisted in the meeting that the President and the Prime Minister should resign.",
        "Meanwhile, the party leader Maithripala Sirisena also emphasized in the meeting that if the President and Prime Minister do not step down, the country will have to face serious consequences in the coming days.",
        "Meanwhile, independent party leaders expressed strong opposition to the idea of ​​appointing Ranil Wickramasinghe as the interim president.",
        "In this case, Kota Go Home is against President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and No Deal is against Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe. If Ranil Wickremesinghe is appointed as the President, the people will destroy the Parliament, party leader Vasudeva Nanayakkara said in the meeting.",
        "Meanwhile, the Prime Minister did not agree to the resignation of the Prime Minister and the President, despite the party leader's meeting demanding his resignation. However, Raub Hakeem said that the decision has been taken to request the resignation of both the President and the Prime Minister due to the request of many people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumar Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumandran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota Go Home",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Raub Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේ දේශපාලන විවාදයක්: ජනපති කවුද? අගමැති කවුද? - මෙන්න සම්පූර්ණ විස්තරය",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, අනුරකුමාර් දිසානායක සහ සුමන්ද්‍රන් යන මහත්වරු මෙම රැස්වීමට අථත්‍ය (Zoom) හරහා සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "මෙහිදී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා එක්ව ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවත් ඉන් අනතුරුව කථානායකවරයා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධුරය කෙටි කලක් දැරීමට කටයුතු කළ යුතු බවත් පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී සාකච්ඡා වී තිබේ.",
        "ඊට අමතරව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට පක්ෂ නායක මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාද එම රැස්වීමේදී අවධාරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉවත් නොවන්නේ නම් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී රටට බරපතල ප්‍රතිවිපාකවලට මුහුණදීමට සිදුවන බව පක්ෂ නායක මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාද එම රැස්වීමේදී අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පත් කිරීමේ අදහසට ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ නායකයින් දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කළා.",
        "මෙහිදී කොටා ගෝ හෝම් පක්ෂය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට එරෙහිවත්, නෝ ඩීල් පක්ෂය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාටත් විරුද්ධ බවත්, රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කළහොත් ජනතාව විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විනාශ කරන බවත් පක්ෂ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා එම රැස්වීමේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ඉල්ලා සිටියද අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඊට එකඟ නොවීය. කෙසේ වෙතත් බොහෝ දෙනෙකුගේ ඉල්ලීම මත ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා යන දෙදෙනාගෙන්ම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලීමට මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇති බවයි රවුබ් හකීම් කියා සිටියේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර් දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා ගෙදර යන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රවුබ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் காரசார விவாதம் : யார் ஜனாதிபதி ? யார் பிரதமர் ? - முழு விபரம் இதோ",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "இக் கூட்டத்தில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, அனுரகுமார திசாநாயக்க மற்றும் சுமந்திரன் ஆகியோர் மெய்நிகர் ( சூம் ) மூலம் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் குறித்த கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் உடன் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்றும், அதன் பின்னர் குறுகிய காலத்திற்கு சபாநாயகர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவி வகிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது.",
        "அத்தோடு ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் உடன் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்று மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஜனாதிபதி ,பிரதமர் பதவி விலகாவிடின் நாட்டில் பாரதூரமான விளைவுகளை இனிவரும் நாட்களில் எதிர்கொள்ள நேரிடும் என்றும் மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் மேலும் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்போது இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை  நியமிக்கும் யோசனைக்கு சுயாதீன கட்சி தலைவர்கள் கடும் எதிர்ப்பினை வெளியிட்டனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், கோட்டா கோ ஹோம்  ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்‌ஷவிற்கு எதிரானது, நோ டீல் கம பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு எதிரானது.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்தால் மக்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தை தரை மட்டமாக்குவார்கள் என  கட்சி் தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பிரதமரையும் ஜனாதிபதியையும் ராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் கோரப்பட்ட போதிலும் , பிரதமர் இதற்கு உடன்படவில்லை. எவ்வாறாயினும் , பெருமளவானோரின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கமைய  ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் ஆகிய இருவரையுமே பதவி விலகுமாறு கோருவதற்கு தீர்மானம் எடுத்துள்ளதாக ரவுப் ஹக்கீம் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார் திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ ஹோம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}