{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131194",
  "time_ut": 1657437371,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யாழ். நவாலி சென். பீற்றர்ஸ் தேவாலயம் மீதான விமான தாக்குதலின் 27 ஆம் ஆண்டு நினைவுதினம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jaffna. Navali Sen. 27th Anniversary of Air Attack on Peter's Church",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Jaffna, Navali Sen. The 27th anniversary of the air attack on St. Peter's Church was held on Saturday evening, 09 September. A memorial service was held at Peter's Church.",
        "Following this, relatives of the deceased and members of the public paid their respects by lighting floral obelisks.",
        "On July 9, 1995, Navali Sen. 147 people were killed when three Air Force planes dropped 13 bombs in a row on displaced people who were staying at Peter's Church and Navali Sri Kathirgama Murugan Temple.",
        "Early that morning, the military carried out a military operation of advancing towards Valigamam areas with the help of missile attacks and airstrikes.",
        "Due to continuous shelling, the people who were displaced from their habitations towards Navali went to Navali and took shelter in Peter's Church and Navali Sri Kathirgama Murugan Temple.",
        "That morning, three planes suddenly arrived and dropped 13 bombs in a row on the church and temple where people were sheltering. In this bombing incident, 147 people, including children and women, were killed on the spot. More than 350 people were injured."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "27th Anniversary",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Peter's Church",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navali",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "St. Peter's Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter's Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 9, 1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navali",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "147",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter's Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navali Sri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathirgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Early that morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valigamam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter's Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navali Sri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathirgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "147",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "More than 350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාපනය. නවාලි සෙන්. පීතර දේවස්ථානයට එල්ල වූ ගුවන් ප්‍රහාරයේ 27 වැනි සංවත්සරය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය, නාවලි සෙන්. ශාන්ත පීතර දේවස්ථානයට එල්ල වූ ගුවන් ප්‍රහාරයේ 27 වැනි සංවත්සරය සැප්තැම්බර් 09 සෙනසුරාදා සවස පැවැත්විණි. පීතර දේවස්ථානයේ අනුස්මරණ දේව මෙහෙයක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව මියගිය අයගේ ඥාතීන් සහ මහජනතාව පුෂ්පෝපහාර දල්වමින් ගෞරව දැක්වූහ.",
        "1995 ජූලි 9 වැනිදා නවාලි සෙන්. පීතර දේවස්ථානයේ සහ නාවලි ශ්‍රී කතිර්ගම මුරුගන් විහාරස්ථානයේ රැඳී සිටි අවතැන් වූවන් වෙත ගුවන් හමුදාවේ ගුවන් යානා තුනක් එක දිගට බෝම්බ 13ක් හෙළීමෙන් පුද්ගලයන් 147 දෙනෙකු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "එදින අලුයම මිසයිල ප්‍රහාර සහ ගුවන් ප්‍රහාරවල ආධාරයෙන් හමුදාව වලිගාමම් ප්‍රදේශය දෙසට හමුදා මෙහෙයුමක් දියත් කරන ලදී.",
        "දිගින් දිගටම එල්ල වූ ෂෙල් වෙඩි ප්‍රහාර හේතුවෙන් වාසස්ථානවලින් නවාලි දෙසට අවතැන් වූ ජනතාව නාවලි වෙත ගොස් පීතර දේවස්ථානයේ සහ නාවලි ශ්‍රී කතිර්ගම මුරුගන් විහාරස්ථානයේ නවාතැන් ගත්හ.",
        "එදින උදෑසන හදිසියේ ගුවන් යානා තුනක් පැමිණ මිනිසුන් නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටි පල්ලියට හා පන්සලට එක දිගට බෝම්බ 13ක් හෙළන ලදී.මෙම බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් කුඩා දරුවන් සහ කාන්තාවන් ඇතුළු 147 දෙනෙකු එම ස්ථානයේදීම මිය ගියහ. 350කට වැඩි පිරිසක් තුවාල ලැබූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නවාලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "27 වැනි සංවත්සරය",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පේතෘස් පල්ලිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවාලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත පීතර දේවස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේතෘස් පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9, 1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවාලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "147",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේතෘස් පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවලි ශ්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතිර්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එදා උදේ පාන්දරම",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලිගාමම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේතෘස් පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවලි ශ්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතිර්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "147",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "350 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ். நவாலி சென். பீற்றர்ஸ் தேவாலயம் மீதான விமான தாக்குதலின் 27 ஆம் ஆண்டு நினைவுதினம்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாம், நவாலி சென். பீற்றர்ஸ் தேவாலயம் மீதான விமான தாக்குதலின் 27 ஆம் ஆண்டு நினைவுதினம் 09 ஆம் திகதி சனிக்கிழமை  மாலை சென். பீற்றர்ஸ் தேவாலயத்தில் நினைவு கூறப்பட்டது.",
        "அதனை தொடர்ந்து உயிரிழந்தவர்களின் உறவினர்கள், பொதுமக்கள் மலர் தூபி சுடரேற்றி அஞ்சலி செலுத்தினார்கள்.",
        "கடந்த 1995 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 09 திகதியன்று நவாலி சென். பீற்றர்ஸ் தேவாலயத்திலும், நவாலி ஸ்ரீ கதிர்காம முருகன் ஆலயத்திலும் இடம்பெயர்ந்து தங்கியிருந்த மக்கள் மீது விமானப்படையினரின் மூன்று விமானங்கள் தொடர்ச்சியாக 13 குண்டுகளை வீசியதில் 147 பேர் பலியாகினர்.",
        "அன்று அதிகாலை வலிகாமம் பிரதேசங்களை நோக்கி எறிகணை தாக்குதல் ,விமான தாக்குதல்களின் உதவியுடன் இராணுவத்தினர் முன்னேறிப்பாய்தல்  எனும் இராணுவ நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டனர்.",
        "தொடர் எறிகணை தாக்குதல்களால் தமது வாழ்விடங்களை விட்டு நவாலியை நோக்கி இடம்பெயர்ந்த மக்கள் நவாலி சென்ற் பீற்றர்ஸ் தேவாலயத்திலும் நவாலி ஸ்ரீ கதிர்காம முருகன் ஆலயத்திலும் தஞ்சமடைந்தனர்.",
        "அன்றைய காலை திடீரென வந்த மூன்று விமானங்கள் தொடர்ச்சியாக 13 குண்டுகளை மக்கள் தஞ்சமடைந்திருந்த தேவாலயம் மற்றும் ஆலயம் மீது வீசின.இக் குண்டு வீச்சு சம்பவத்தில் குழந்தைகள் பெண்கள் உட்பட 147 பேர் அந்த இடத்திலேயே உடல் சிதறி பலியாகியிருந்தனர். 350க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் காயமடைந்திருந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நவாலி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "27வது ஆண்டுவிழா",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பீட்டர்ஸ் சர்ச்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவாலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித பீட்டர் தேவாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர்ஸ் சர்ச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9, 1995",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவாலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "147",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர்ஸ் சர்ச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவாலி ஸ்ரீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலிகாமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர்ஸ் சர்ச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவாலி ஸ்ரீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "147",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "350க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}