{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84773/flood-warning-as-water-levels-rise-in-maha-oya",
  "time_ut": 1662396480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Flood warning as water levels rise in Maha Oya",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Flood warning as water levels rise in Maha Oya",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Irrigation urged residents in low-lying areas of Alawwa, Divulapitiya, Meerigama, Pannala, Wennappuwa, Negombo, Katana and Dankotuwa to be vigilant of floods, as water levels are rising in the Maha Oya Basin due to heavy rains.",
        "Issuing a flood warning message, the Hydrology and Disaster Management Division of the department said that considerable rainfall has occurred in some of the upstream catchment areas of Maha Oya Basin as of 9.00 p.m. today (05).",
        "By analyzing the current rainfall situation and river water levels of Hydrological Stations in Maha Oya, there is a possibility of a minor flood situation occurring in low-lying areas of Maha Oya valley situated in Alawwa, Diwulapitiya, Meerigama, Pannala, Wennappuwa, Negambo, Katana and Dankotuwa D/S Divisions, it said.",
        "Residents of these area as well as motorists traveling through those areas are requested to pay high attention in this regard.",
        "Disaster management authorities are requested to take adequate precautions in this regard, it further said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Maha Oya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Irrigation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alawwa, Divulapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meerigama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pannala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dankotuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Hydrology and Disaster Management Division of the department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Oya Basin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hydrological Stations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Oya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Oya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alawwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diwulapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meerigama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pannala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negambo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහඔයේ ජල මට්ටම ඉහළ යන බැවින් ගංවතුර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධික වර්ෂාවත් සමඟ මහඔය ද්‍රෝණියේ ජල මට්ටම ඉහළ යමින් පවතින බැවින් අලව්ව, දිවුලපිටිය, මීරිගම, පන්නල, වෙන්නප්පුව, මීගමුව, කටාන සහ දංකොටුව යන ප්‍රදේශවල පහත් බිම්වල පදිංචිකරුවන්ට ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයන් පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙස වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "ගංවතුර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජල විද්‍යා හා ආපදා කළමනාකරණ අංශය පැවසුවේ මහඔය ද්‍රෝණියේ ඉහළ ජල පෝෂක ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට රාත්‍රී 9.00 වන විට සැලකිය යුතු වර්ෂාපතනයක් ලැබී ඇති බවයි. අද (05)",
        "දැනට පවතින වර්ෂාපතන තත්ත්වය සහ මහඔය ජල විද්‍යා ස්ථානවල ගංගා ජල මට්ටම් විශ්ලේෂණය කිරීමෙන් අලව්ව, දිවුලපිටිය, මීරිගම, පන්නල, වෙන්නප්පුව, මීගමුව, යන ප්‍රදේශවල පිහිටි මහඔය නිම්නයේ පහත් බිම්වල සුළු ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇතිවීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී. කටාන සහ දංකොටුව ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශය.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන් මෙන්ම එම ප්‍රදේශ හරහා ගමන් කරන රියදුරන්ගෙන් මේ පිළිබඳව දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රමාණවත් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ආපදා කළමනාකරණ බලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවද එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහඔය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලව්ව, දිවුලපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීරිගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දන්කොටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජල විද්‍යා හා ආපදා කළමනාකරණ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහඔය ද්රෝණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජල විද්‍යා ස්ථාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහඔය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහඔය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලව්ව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවුලපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීරිගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மஹா ஓயாவில் நீர் மட்டம் உயர்வதால் வெள்ள அபாய எச்சரிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கனமழை காரணமாக மகா ஓயா பள்ளத்தாக்குகளில் நீர்மட்டம் அதிகரித்து வருவதால், அலவ்வ, திவுலப்பிட்டிய, மீரிகம, பன்னல, வென்னப்புவ, நீர்கொழும்பு, கட்டான மற்றும் தங்கொடுவ ஆகிய தாழ்நிலப் பிரதேசங்களில் வசிக்கும் மக்களை அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு நீர்ப்பாசனத் திணைக்களம் கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "வெள்ள அபாய எச்சரிக்கை செய்தியை வெளியிட்ட திணைக்களத்தின் நீரியல் மற்றும் அனர்த்த முகாமைத்துவப் பிரிவு, மஹா ஓயா பள்ளத்தாக்கின் சில மேல் நீரோடை நீர்ப்பிடிப்புப் பகுதிகளில் இரவு 9.00 மணி நிலவரப்படி கணிசமான மழை பெய்துள்ளது. இன்று (05)",
        "தற்போதைய மழைவீழ்ச்சி மற்றும் மஹா ஓயாவின் நீரியல் நிலையங்களின் ஆற்று நீர் மட்டங்களை பகுப்பாய்வு செய்வதன் மூலம், அலவ்வ, திவுலப்பிட்டிய, மீரிகம, பன்னல, வென்னப்புவ, நீர்கொழும்பு, ஆகிய இடங்களில் அமைந்துள்ள மஹா ஓயா பள்ளத்தாக்கின் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் சிறிய வெள்ள நிலைமை ஏற்படுவதற்கான சாத்தியம் உள்ளது. கட்டான மற்றும் தங்கொடுவ D/S பிரிவுகள், அது கூறியது.",
        "இப்பிரதேசங்களில் வசிப்பவர்களும், அவ்வழியாக பயணிக்கும் வாகன சாரதிகளும் இது தொடர்பில் அதிக கவனம் செலுத்துமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு பேரிடர் முகாமைத்துவ அதிகாரிகள் கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுவதாக மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஹா ஓயா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலவ்வ, திவுலப்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீரிகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கொடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திணைக்களத்தின் நீரியல் மற்றும் பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹா ஓயா படுகை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.00 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீரியல் நிலையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹா ஓயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹா ஓயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலவ்வா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திவுலப்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீரிகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெகம்போ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}