{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132470",
  "time_ut": 1659077606,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையின் கடன் நெருக்கடி தொடர்பான சமந்தா பவரி;ன் கருத்திற்கு சீனாவின் பதில் என்ன?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "What is China's response to Samantha Bavary's comment on Sri Lanka's debt crisis?",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Spokesperson of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Zhao Lijian, said that Sri Lanka-China cooperation always follows Sri Lanka-led and Sri Lankan policies.",
        "He said this while responding to a question raised by reporters about USAIT's CEO Samantha Power's comments.",
        "He mentioned that all cooperation projects have been carried out on the basis of complete scientific research and thorough evaluations and said that no political conditions have been imposed.",
        "Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Zhao Lijian said that Sri Lankan Chinese cooperation has contributed to Sri Lankan economy and provided significant benefits to Sri Lankan people.",
        "He said that Sri Lanka's foreign debt has many components and China's contribution to Sri Lanka's debt is less than that of the international capital market multilateral development banks.",
        "He also said that China is providing preferential loans with low interest rates and long term maturity to Sri Lanka which has helped to enrich Sri Lanka's infrastructure and livelihood.",
        "He further stated that after Sri Lanka announced that it would stop issuing international loan payments, Chinese financial institutions approached the Sri Lankan side to find appropriate ways to deal with China-related maturing loans and to get rid of the crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Samantha Bavary's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USAIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමන්තා බවරි කළ ප්‍රකාශයට චීනයේ ප්‍රතිචාරය කුමක්ද?",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීන විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Zhao Lijian පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා-චීන සහයෝගීතාව සෑම විටම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රමුඛ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රතිපත්ති අනුගමනය කරන බවයි.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව පැවසුවේ USAIT හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සමන්තා පවර්ගේ අදහස් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් නැගූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමිනි.",
        "සියලු සහයෝගීතා ව්‍යාපෘති සම්පූර්ණ විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ සහ ගැඹුරු ඇගයීම් මත සිදු කර ඇති බවත් දේශපාලන කොන්දේසි පනවා නොමැති බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Zhao Lijian පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා චීන සහයෝගීතාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකයට දායක වී ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ ණයවල බොහෝ කොටස් තිබෙන බවත්, ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවර්ධන බැංකුවලට වඩා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය සඳහා චීනයේ දායකත්වය අඩු බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඩු පොලී අනුපාත සහ දිගුකාලීන කල් පිරෙන වරණීය ණය ලබා දෙන බවත් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යටිතල පහසුකම් සහ ජීවනෝපාය පොහොසත් කිරීමට ඉවහල් වූ බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර ණය ලබාදීම නතර කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු චීනයට අදාළ කල්පිරුණු ණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට සහ අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට සුදුසු ක්‍රම සොයා ගැනීමට චීන මූල්‍ය ආයතන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ශ්වය අමතා කටයුතු කළ බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සමන්තා බාවාරිගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USAIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் கடன் நெருக்கடி தொடர்பான சமந்தா பவரி;ன் கருத்திற்கு சீனாவின் பதில் என்ன?",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சீனா ஒத்துழைப்பு எப்போதும் இலங்கை தலைமையிலான - இலங்கையின் கொள்கைகளையே பின்பற்றுகின்றது என சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் சாவோ லிஜியன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "யுஎஸ்எயிட்டின் தலைமை நிர்வாகி சமந்தா பவரின் கருத்து குறித்து செய்தியாளர்கள் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கையில் அவர் இதனை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அனைத்து ஒத்துழைப்பு திட்டங்களும் முழுமையான விஞ்ஞானரீதியிலான ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் முழுமையான மதிப்பீடுகளின் அடிப்படையிலேயே முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன என குறிப்பிட்டுள்ள அவர் எந்த அரசியல் நிபந்தனைகளும் விதிக்கப்படவில்லை எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை சீன ஒத்துழைப்பு இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு பங்களிப்பு செய்துள்ளது இலங்கை மக்களிற்கு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அனுகூலங்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது என சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் சாவோ லிஜியன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டுக்கடன்கள் பல கூறுகளை கொண்டது என தெரிவித்துள்ள அவர் இலங்கையின் கடன்களிற்கான சீனாவின் பங்களிப்பு சர்வதேச மூலதனச்சந்தை பல்தரப்பு அபிவிருத்தி வங்கிகளை காட்டிலும் குறைவானது எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு சீனா குறைந்த வட்டிவீதங்கள் கொண்ட நீண்ட கால முதிர்ச்சியுடனான முன்னுரிமை கடன்களையே வழங்குகின்றது இது இலங்கையின் உட்கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை வளப்படுத்த உதவியது எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச கடன்கொடுப்பனவுகளை வழங்குவதை நிறுத்துவதாக இலங்கை அறிவித்த பின்னர் சீனாவின் நிதிநிறுவனங்கள் இலங்கை தரப்பை அணுகி சீனா தொடர்பான முதிர்ச்சியடைந்த கடன்களை கையாள்வதற்கான சரியான வழிகளை கண்டறிவதற்கும் நெருக்கடிகளில் இருந்து விடுபடுவதற்குமான வழிவகைளை தெரிவித்தன எனவும் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சமந்தா பவாரியின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USAIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர் தான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}