{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/opinion/නව-අගමැති-ගැනයි/2-395656",
  "time_ut": 1658473882,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නව අගමැති ගැනයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "About the new prime minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker of Parliament Dinesh Gunawardena took oath as the new Prime Minister of Sri Lanka. The new Prime Minister's media department had released an announcement about the life details.",
        "Phillip Gunawardena, nicknamed the Lion of Boralugoda, and Kusuma Gunawardena, known as Vame Ratu Kusuma, are the parents of Abhinava Agramatya Dinesh Gunawardena. Born on March 2, 1949, Dinesh Gunawardena has been the leader of the People's United Front since 1973 after the death of Mr. Philip Gunawardena. He is also the longest living leader of a democratic political party in the world.",
        "Dinesh Gunawardena received his schooling from the Royal College, Colombo. Later, he earned associate degrees in business administration, management, and business administration, management and international transportation from the Netherlands Business University and the University of Oregon.",
        "Dinesh Gunawardena was married to Ramani Vatsala Kothalawala. Despite her sudden death in the middle of 1980, he faced life with his beloved, two children, Yadamini and Sankhapali, and his commitment to Buddhism, the country and the nation did not diminish even a little.",
        "Indika Gunawardena who was a minister, Geethanjana Gunawardena who held the position of Deputy Speaker, Deputy Minister, Prasanna Gunawardena who was the mayor of Colombo, and writer Lakmali Gunawardena are his brothers and sisters.",
        "The leader of the People's United Front, Mr. Dinesh Gunawardena, entered the Parliament for the first time in the 1983 by-election, winning a historic victory as the MP for Maharagama.",
        "Since then he has represented the Parliament, Transport, Transport and Environment, Urban Development and Water Supply, Higher Education Deputy, Urban Development and Sacred Area Development, Water Supply and Drainage, Municipalities and Western Development, Foreign Affairs and Skill Development and Employment and Labour. , also held the positions of Minister of Foreign Affairs, Education, Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government.",
        "Having held the positions of the chief organizer of the ruling party in the parliament, the leader of the parliament, and the chairman of three parliamentary special committees to amend the voting system, he has a thorough knowledge and understanding of the parliamentary system.",
        "His son, Mr. Yadamini Gunawardena, is currently a public representative representing the Parliament.",
        "In the history of Sri Lanka, the national leadership of Dinesh Gunawardena, who always stands on the progressive side in national politics, is not greedy for positions, acts directly, and moves forward with the unshakable vision of preserving Sambudu Sasuna, the nation, the united country and the common people, has a special place.",
        "In the Geneva Human Rights Conference as the Minister of Foreign Affairs dressed in national dress, it was a unique opportunity that the leadership took to the international community to announce that 'Sri Lanka will immediately officially withdraw from the co-sponsorship of the 30/1 and related resolution'.",
        "As a result of long hard work, the Dinesh Gunawardena Parliamentary Committee was also able to make ID cards mandatory for voting. He gave solutions to the problem of teacher principals that had been unresolved for 24 years when he was the Minister of Education, and 51000 graduates were confirmed in 2021 based on the recommendations of the cabinet sub-committee he chaired.",
        "Twice President of the country, LTTE. When Mr. Mahinda Rajapaksa, who led the defeat of terrorism, was defeated in 2015, the historic rally in Nugegoda, the fight led by the joint opposition in the parliament and outside, the fight against the 1987 Indo-Lanka Agreement in the middle of the great terror, the May Day that was banned at that time, in the midst of gunfire. There are many indelible notes about Dinesh Gunawardane in the political history of this country as the leader of M.E.P., which was the only party with Mrs. Sirimavo in the 1988 presidential election, as well as the way it was celebrated.",
        "Also, at a time when his camp was in great difficulty in the country, he led a joint May rally of the left including Podujana Peramuna and held a historic rally in Nugegoda on May 1st, 2021, demonstrating his past achievements as a labor leader and the love of the people.",
        "Mr. Abhinava Agramatya Dinesh Gunawardena, as a labor leader, as a national leader, is engaged in a continuous political journey for the sake of an ideal country, for the sake of the Sambuddha order, the unity of the country, the nation and the common people. Congratulations on the journey of purity, confidence, courage and people's love!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Phillip Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusuma Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vame Ratu Kusuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abhinava Agramatya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's United Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philip Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal College, Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Netherlands Business University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Oregon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramani Vatsala Kothalawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the middle of 1980",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yadamini",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sankhapali",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indika Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geethanjana Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmali Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the People's United Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urban Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sacred Area Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skill Development and Employment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Labour",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yadamini Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sambudu Sasuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the united country",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Geneva Human Rights Conference",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30/1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May Day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.E.P.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirimavo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 1st, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abhinava Agramatya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sambuddha",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව අගමැති ගැනයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අභිනව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායක දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය. නව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ජීවන තොරතුරු පිළිබඳව ඔහුගේ මාධ්‍ය අංශය විසින් නිවේදනයක් මගින් නිකුත් කොට තිබුණි.",
        "බොරළුගොඩ සිංහයා යන විරුදාවලිය ලැබූ, පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධනයන් සහ වමේ රතු කුසුම ලෙස හඳුන්වන කුසුමා ගුණවර්ධනයන්, අභිනව අග්‍රමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනගේ මා-පිය දෙපළය. 1949 මාර්තු 02 වනදා උපන්, දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනයන්,  පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ අභාවයෙන් පසු, 1973 සිට මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ නායකයාය ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී. ලොව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී දේශපාලන පක්ෂයකට වැඩි ම කාලයක් නායකත්වය දෙන, ජීවතුන් අතර සිටින නායකයාද ඔහුය.",
        "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනයන් පාසල් අධ්‍යාපනය ලැබුවේ, කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයෙනි. පසුව, ව්‍යාපාර පරිපාලනය, කළමනාකරණය ආශ්‍රිත මෙන්ම ව්‍යාපාර පරිපාලනය, කළමනාකරණය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රවාහනය පිළිබඳ උපාධි හිමිකර ගත්තේ, නෙදර්ලන්ත ව්‍යාපාරික විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙන් හා ඔරිගන් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙනි.",
        "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනයන් විවාහ වූයේ, රමණි වත්සලා කොතලාවල සමගය. 1980 මැද භාගයේ ඇය හදිසියේ මියගියද ආදරණීය, දරු දෙදෙනා, යදාමිණි හා සංඛපාලි සමග ශක්තිමත්ව ජීවිතයට මුහුණ දෙමින්, බුදු සසුන, රට, ජාතික වෙනුවෙන් වන කැපවීම ඔහු මදකින් හෝ අඩු නොකළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයකු වූ ඉන්දික ගුණවර්ධන,  නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායක,නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ධුර දැරූ ගීතාංජන ගුණවර්ධන, කොළඹ පුරපති වූ ප්‍රසන්න ගුණවර්ධන, ලේඛිකා ලක්මලි ගුණවර්ධන  ඔහුගේ සහෝදර සහෝදරියන්ය.",
        "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ නායක දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා, පළමු වරට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන්නේ 1983 අතුරු මැතිවරණයෙන්, මහරගම මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ලෙස ඓතිහාසික ජයග්‍රහණයලක් ලබමිනි.",
        "එතැන් පටන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන ඔහු, ප්‍රවාහන,  ප්‍රවාහන හා පරිසර,  නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා ජල සම්පාදන,  උසස් අධ්‍යාපන නියෝජ්‍ය,  නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා පූජනීය ප්‍රදේශ සංවර්ධන,  ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන,  මහ නගර හා බස්නාහිර සංවර්ධන,  විදේශ කටයුතු හා කුසලතා සංවර්ධන සහ රැකියා හා කම්කරු,  විදේශ කටයුතු,  අධ්‍යාපන,  රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා හා පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍ය ධුරද දැරීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායක ධුරයන්ද, ඡන්ද ක්‍රමය සංශෝධනය කිරීමේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු විශේෂ,කාරක සභා තුනක සභාපති ධුරද දැරූ ඔහුට පාර්ලිමේන්තු ක්‍රමය පිළිබඳ ඇත්තේ හසළ දැනුමක් සහ අවබෝධයකි.",
        "ඔහුගේ පුත්, යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන මහතාද, මේ වනවිට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන මහජන නියෝජිතයෙකි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉතිහාසයේ, ජාතික දේශපාලනයේ සැමවිට ම ප්‍රගතිශීලි පිලේ සිටගනිමින්,  තනතුරුවලට ගිජු නොවී, සෘජුව කටයුතු කරමින්, සම්බුදු සසුන, ජාතිය, ඒකීය රට, පොදු ජනයා සුරැකීමේ නොසැලෙන දර්ශනයෙන් යුතුව ඉදිරියට යන දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනයන්ගේ ජාතික නායකත්වයට, හිමිව ඇත්තේ සුවිශේෂි ස්ථානයකි.",
        "ජාතික ඇඳුමින් සැරසී විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් සමුළුවේදී, ' ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 30/1 හා ඊට අදාළ යෝජනාවේ සම අනුග්‍රාහකත්වයෙන් වහාම නිල වශයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව ' දැනුම් දීමද එම නායකත්වය ජාත්‍යන්තරය වෙත ගෙනගිය සුවිශේෂි අවස්ථාවක් විය.",
        "දීර්ඝ මහන්සියක ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස, ඡන්දයට හැඳුනුම්පත් අනිවාර්ය කර දීමටද දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටුවට හැකියාව ලැබිණි. වසර 24ක් තිස්සේ නොවිසඳී පැවති ගුරු විදුහල්පති ගැටළුවට ඔහු අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටියදී වි‍සඳුම් ලබාදුන් අතර, 2021 වසරේදී උපාධිධාරීන් 51000 ක් ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබුවේ ඔහු සභාපතිත්වය දැරූ කැබිනට අනුකාරක සභාවේ නිර්දේශ මතය.",
        "මෙරට දෙවරක් ජනාධිපති වූ, එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ. ත්‍රස්තවාදය පරාජය කිරීමට නායකත්වය දුන්, මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා 2015 දී පරාජය වූ අවස්ථාවේ, නුගේගොඩ ඓතිහාසික ජන රැළියට, ඒකාබද්ධ විපක්ෂයට නායකත්වය දෙමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේත් ඉන් පිටදීත් මෙහෙය වූ සටන, 1987 ඉන්දු ලංකා ගිවිසුමට එරෙහිව මහා භීෂණය මැද ගෙනගිය සටන, එකල තහනම් කළ මැයි දිනය වෙඩි ප්‍රහාර මධ්‍යයේ සැමරූ ආකාරය මෙන්ම 1988 ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී සිරිමාවෝ මැතිනිය සමග සිටි එකම පක්ෂය වූ ම.එ.පෙ., නායකයා ආදි ලෙස, මෙරට දේශපාලන  ඉතිහාසය තුළ දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනයන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් නොමැකෙන සටහන් බොහෝය.",
        "ඒ වගේම ඔහුගේ කඳවුර රට තුළ සුවිශාල අසීරුතාවකට පත්ව තිබූ අවස්ථාවක, පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඇතුළු වමේ ඒකාබද්ධ මැයි රැළියකට නායකත්වය දෙමින් පසුගිය 2021 මැයි පළමුවන දා නුගේගොඩදී ඓතිහාසික රැළියක් පැවැත්වූයේ කම්කරු නායකයෙකු ලෙස අතීතයේ සිට ලැබූ පන්නරය සහ ජනතා ආදරය මොනවට විදහා දක්වමිනි.",
        "අභිනව අග්‍රමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා, සම්බුද්ධ ශාසනයේත්, රටේ ඒකීයභාවයේත්, ජාතියේත්, පොදු ජනතාවගේත් උන්නතිය හා සුරක්ෂිතභාවය පිණිසත්, කම්කරු නායකයෙකු ලෙස, ජාතික නායකයෙකු ලෙස, පතිරූප දේශයක් උදෙසා අඛණ්ඩ දේශපාලන ගමනක නිරතව සිටින්නේය. පිරිසුදුකම, විශ්වාසය, එඩිතරකම, ජනතා ආදරය ඔස්සේ යන ඒ ගමනට සුබ පතමු !"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසුමා ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වමේ රතු කුසුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභිනව අග්‍රමාත්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 2, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්ත ව්‍යාපාරික විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔරිගන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමණි වත්සලා කොතලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980 මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යදාමිනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංඛපාලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගීතාංජන ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාලි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූජා භූමි සංවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිපුණතා සංවර්ධනය සහ රැකියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කම්කරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්බුදු සසුන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30/1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 24 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ඊ.පී.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිමාවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 1, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අභිනව අග්‍රමාත්‍ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්බුද්ධයි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய பிரதமர் பற்றி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் புதிய பிரதமராக சபாநாயகர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன பதவியேற்றார். புதிய பிரதமரின் ஊடகத்துறை வாழ்க்கை விவரங்கள் குறித்த அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்டிருந்தது.",
        "பொரலுகொட சிங்கம் என அழைக்கப்படும் பிலிப் குணவர்தன மற்றும் வமே ரது குசுமா என அழைக்கப்படும் குசுமா குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் அபினவ அக்ரமத்ய தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவின் பெற்றோர்களாவர். 1949ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் மாதம் 2ஆம் திகதி பிறந்த தினேஸ் குணவர்தன, திரு.பிலிப் குணவர்தனவின் மறைவுக்குப் பின்னர் 1973ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணியின் தலைவராக இருந்து வருகிறார். உலகிலேயே ஜனநாயக அரசியல் கட்சியின் நீண்ட காலம் வாழும் தலைவர் என்ற பெருமையையும் பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன கொழும்பு றோயல் கல்லூரியில் தனது பள்ளிப்படிப்பைப் பெற்றார். பின்னர், நெதர்லாந்து வணிக பல்கலைக்கழகம் மற்றும் ஒரேகான் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் வணிக நிர்வாகம், மேலாண்மை மற்றும் வணிக நிர்வாகம், மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சர்வதேச போக்குவரத்து ஆகியவற்றில் இணை பட்டங்களைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, ரமணி வத்சலா கொத்தலாவல என்பவரை மணந்தார். 1980 ஆம் ஆண்டின் நடுப்பகுதியில் அவர் திடீரென இறந்த போதிலும், அவர் தனது அன்பான இரண்டு குழந்தைகளான யாதாமினி மற்றும் சங்கபாலியுடன் வாழ்க்கையை எதிர்கொண்டார், மேலும் பௌத்தம், நாடு மற்றும் தேசத்தின் மீதான அவரது அர்ப்பணிப்பு கொஞ்சம் கூட குறையவில்லை.",
        "அமைச்சராக இருந்த இந்திக்க குணவர்தன, பிரதி சபாநாயகர் பதவியை வகித்த கீதாஞ்சன குணவர்தன, பிரதி அமைச்சர் பதவியை வகித்தவர், கொழும்பு மேயராக இருந்த பிரசன்ன குணவர்தன, எழுத்தாளர் லக்மாலி குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் சகோதர சகோதரிகளாவர்.",
        "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணியின் தலைவர் திரு.தினேஷ் குணவர்தன அவர்கள் 1983 இடைத்தேர்தலில் மஹரகம பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க வெற்றியைப் பெற்று முதல் தடவையாக பாராளுமன்றம் பிரவேசித்தார்.",
        "அப்போதிருந்து அவர் பாராளுமன்றம், போக்குவரத்து, போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல், நகர்ப்புற மேம்பாடு மற்றும் நீர் வழங்கல், உயர் கல்வி துணை, நகர்ப்புற அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் புனித பிரதேச அபிவிருத்தி, நீர் வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகால், நகராட்சிகள் மற்றும் மேற்கு அபிவிருத்தி, வெளியுறவு மற்றும் திறன் மேம்பாடு மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் தொழிலாளர் ., வெளிவிவகார, கல்வி, பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சர் பதவிகளையும் வகித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர், நாடாளுமன்றத் தலைவர், மூன்று நாடாளுமன்ற சிறப்புக் குழுக்களின் வாக்களிப்பு முறைமைத் திருத்தத் தலைவர் ஆகிய பதவிகளை வகித்துள்ள அவர், நாடாளுமன்ற முறைமை பற்றிய முழுமையான அறிவும் புரிதலும் கொண்டவர்.",
        "அவரது மகன் திரு.யாதாமினி குணவர்தன தற்போது பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பொது பிரதிநிதியாக உள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை வரலாற்றில், தேசிய அரசியலில் எப்போதும் முற்போக்கு பக்கம் நிற்கும் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவின் தேசியத் தலைமை பதவிகளுக்கு பேராசை கொள்ளாமல், நேரடியாகச் செயற்பட்டு, சம்புது சசுனத்தை, தேசத்தைப் பாதுகாக்கும் அசைக்க முடியாத பார்வையுடன் முன்னோக்கிச் செல்கிறது. ஒன்றுபட்ட நாடு மற்றும் சாமானியர்களுக்கு தனி இடம் உண்டு.",
        "ஜெனீவா மனித உரிமைகள் மாநாட்டில் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் தேசிய உடை அணிந்து, '30/1 இன் இணை அனுசரணையிலிருந்து இலங்கை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக உடனடியாக விலகும்' என்று சர்வதேச சமூகத்திற்கு தலைமைத்துவம் எடுத்துச் சென்றது ஒரு தனித்துவமான வாய்ப்பாகும். மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய தீர்மானம்'.",
        "நீண்டகால கடின உழைப்பின் விளைவாக, தினேஷ் குணவர்தன பாராளுமன்றக் குழுவும் வாக்களிப்பதற்கு அடையாள அட்டையை கட்டாயமாக்க முடிந்தது. தாம் கல்வி அமைச்சராக இருந்த போது 24 வருடங்களாக தீர்க்கப்படாமல் இருந்த ஆசிரியர் அதிபர்களின் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வை வழங்கியதுடன், அவர் தலைமையிலான அமைச்சரவை உபகுழுவின் பரிந்துரைகளின் அடிப்படையில் 2021 இல் 51000 பட்டதாரிகள் உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இரண்டு முறை நாட்டின் அதிபராக இருந்த விடுதலைப் புலிகள். பயங்கரவாதத்தை தோற்கடித்த திரு.மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச 2015ல் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட போது, ​​நுகேகொடையில் வரலாற்று சிறப்பு மிக்க பேரணி, பாராளுமன்றத்திலும் வெளியிலும் கூட்டு எதிரணியின் தலைமையில் போராட்டம், மத்தியில் 1987 இந்திய இலங்கை ஒப்பந்தத்திற்கு எதிரான போராட்டம். பெரும் பயங்கரவாதம், துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு மத்தியில், அப்போது தடை செய்யப்பட்ட மே தினம், திருமதி சிறிமாவோவுடன் ஒரே கட்சியாக இருந்த ம.இ.கா.வின் தலைவராக, தினேஷ் குணவர்தன பற்றி இந்த நாட்டின் அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் அழியாத குறிப்புகள் ஏராளம். 1988 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலிலும், அது கொண்டாடப்பட்ட விதத்திலும்.",
        "மேலும், நாட்டில் தனது முகாம் மிகவும் சிரமத்தில் இருந்த நேரத்தில், பொதுஜன பெரமுன உள்ளிட்ட இடதுசாரிகளின் கூட்டு மே பேரணிக்கு தலைமை தாங்கி, 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே 1 ஆம் தேதி நுகேகொடையில் வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க பேரணியை நடத்தி, தொழிலாளர் தலைவராக தனது கடந்தகால சாதனைகளை வெளிப்படுத்தினார். மக்களின் அன்பு.",
        "திரு.அபினவ அக்ரமத்ய தினேஸ் குணவர்தன அவர்கள் ஒரு தொழிலாளர் தலைவராக, தேசிய தலைவராக, ஒரு இலட்சிய நாட்டிற்காக, சம்புத்த ஒழுங்கிற்காக, நாட்டின் ஒற்றுமைக்காக, தேசத்தின் ஒற்றுமைக்காக தொடர்ச்சியான அரசியல் பயணத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளார். பொது மக்கள். தூய்மை, நம்பிக்கை, தைரியம் மற்றும் மக்கள் அன்பின் பயணம் தொடர வாழ்த்துக்கள்!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசுமா குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வமே ரது குசும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபிநவ அக்ரமத்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் கல்லூரி, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து வணிக பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரேகான் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமணி வத்சலா கொத்தலாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980 இன் நடுப்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாதாமினி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கபாலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீதாஞ்சன குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மாலி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித பகுதி வளர்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திறன் மேம்பாடு மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழிலாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாதாமினி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்புடு சசுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுபட்ட நாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30/1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.இ.பி.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிமாவோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபிநவ அக்ரமத்யா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்புத்தர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}