{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/50-இலட்சம்-ரூபாய்-பெறுமதியான-கடல்-அட்டைகள்/175-299537",
  "time_ut": 1656649129,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "50 இலட்சம் ரூபாய் பெறுமதியான கடல் அட்டைகள்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Marine cards worth Rs 50 lakh",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Forest officials yesterday recovered 480 kg of sea cards worth Rs 50 lakh stored near the Tamil Nadu-Mandapam for smuggling to Sri Lanka.",
        "Forest Department officials have received confidential information that sea cards are being stored near Mandapam from Vedalai beach area to be smuggled to Sri Lanka.",
        "After that, the forest department rushed to the area and confiscated the sea card weighing about 480 kg and is conducting an investigation.",
        "The forest department officials have said that the international value of the confiscated sea card will be 50 lakh rupees. (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Marine",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "480 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Nadu-Mandapam",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Forest Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vedalai beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 480 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 50 ක් වටිනා නාවික කාඩ්පත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ දිනයේදී වන දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නිලධාරීන් විසින් රුපියල් කෝටි 100ක් වටිනා මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 480ක් සොයා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "වේදාලෙයි වෙරළ තීරයේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රැගෙන ඒම සඳහා මණ්ඩපය අසල මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් ගබඩා කරන බවට වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන්ට රහසිගත තොරතුරක් ලැබී ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව කඩිනමින් එම ප්‍රදේශයට ගොස් මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 480ක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි.",
        "රාජසන්තක කරන ලද මුහුදු පත්‍රිකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වටිනාකම රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 50ක් බව වන දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නිලධාරීන් පවසා ඇත. (ආ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 480 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු-මණ්ඩප",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙදලෙයි වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "480 kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "50 இலட்சம் ரூபாய் பெறுமதியான கடல் அட்டைகள்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக தமிழ்நாடு - மண்டபம் அருகே பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 50 லட்சம் மதிப்பிலான 480 கிலோ கடல் அட்டைகளை வனத்துறை  அதிகாரிகள் நேற்று மீட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மண்டபம் அருகே வேதாளை கடற்கரை  பகுதியில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக கடல் அட்டைகள் பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வனத்துறை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு  இரகசிய தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளது.",
        "இதையடுத்து அப்பகுதிக்கு விரைந்து  சென்ற வனத்துறையினர் சுமார் 480 கிலோ எடை கொண்ட கடல் அட்டையை பறிமுதல் செய்து விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "மேலும் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்ட கடல் அட்டையில் சர்வதேச மதிப்பு 50 இலட்சம் ரூபாய் இருக்கும் என வனத்துறை அதிகாரிகள்  தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடல்சார்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "480 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு-மண்டபம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேதாளை கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 480 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}