{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඉන්ධන-පෝලිම-තවත්-බිල්ලක්-ගනී/1-615896",
  "time_ut": 1657003978,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිම තවත් බිල්ලක් ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The fuel queue takes another toll",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Borella police say that a person who was waiting in line at the IOC petrol station on Borella Tikal Road has died in his luxury car.",
        "Sujeewa Vikum Gunaratne (60) of Hewagama Dissanayake, who was a resident of Angoda Gothatuwa, has died.",
        "Borella Police Station Chief Inspector AJMR Samarasinghe said that information has been received that the deceased person came by car to get fuel on the 4th of the previous night.",
        "The body of the deceased has been deposited at the mortuary of the Colombo National Hospital for post-mortem examination.",
        "Investigations are being conducted on the instructions of Borella Police Station Chief Inspector AJMR Samarasinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella Tikal Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sujeewa Vikum Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hewagama Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angoda Gothatuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AJMR Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AJMR Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිම තවත් බිල්ලක් ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බොරැල්ල ටිකල් පාරේ අයි ඕ සි ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලේ පෝලිමේ සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු සිය සුඛෝපභෝගී මෝටර් රථයක් තුළ මිය ගොස් ඇතැයි බොරැල්ල පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ අංගොඩ ගොතටුව පදිංචිව සිටි හේවාගම දිසානායකගේ සුජීව විකුම් ගුණරත්න (60) නැමැත්තෙකි.",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා පෙරේදා 4   රාත්‍රී ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා  මෝටර් රථයෙන්  පැමිණි බවට තොරතුරු ලැබී ඇතැයි  බොරැල්ල පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක ඒ ජේ එම් ආර් සමරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මිය ගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ මෘත දේහය කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලේ මෘත ශරීරාගාරයේ පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය පැවැත්වීම සඳහා තැන්පත් කර ඇත.",
        "බොරැල්ල පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක ඒ ජේ එම් ර්‍ ආර් සමරසිංහ මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත පරීක්ෂණ පැවැත්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල ටිකල් පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුජීව විකුම් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේවාගම දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංගොඩ ගොතටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AJMR සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AJMR සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் வரிசை மற்றொரு எண்ணிக்கையை எடுக்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொரளை டிகல் வீதியிலுள்ள IOC எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த நபர் ஒருவர் தனது சொகுசு காரில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொரளை பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "அங்கொட கொதட்டுவ பிரதேசத்தில் வசித்து வந்த ஹேவாகம திஸாநாயக்க என்ற சுஜீவ விக்கும் குணரத்ன (வயது 60) என்பவரே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த நபர் நேற்று முன்தினம் இரவு எரிபொருள் பெறுவதற்காக காரில் வந்ததாக தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக பொரளை பொலிஸ் நிலைய பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் ஏ.ஜே.எம்.ஆர்.சமரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவரின் சடலம் பிரேத பரிசோதனைக்காக கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையின் பிரேத அறையில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொரளை பொலிஸ் நிலைய பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் ஏ.ஜே.எம்.ஆர் சமரசிங்கவின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் விசாரணைகள் இடம்பெற்று வருகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை டிகல் வீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுஜீவ விக்கும் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேவாகம திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கொட கொதடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜேஎம்ஆர் சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜேஎம்ஆர் சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}