{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Gota-to-return-during-first-week-of-September/342-243700",
  "time_ut": 1661388064,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gota to return during first week of September",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gota to return during first week of September",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is to return to Sri Lanka during the first week of next month, Daily Mirror learns .",
        "An informed source said he is likely to return either on September 2 or 3.",
        "Earlier,The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) requested President Ranil Wickremesinghe to make arrangements for the former president to return . Subsequently, the president is reported to have contacted Mr. Rajapaksa to discuss arrangements for his return to the country .",
        "He fled the country in the face of public protests on July 9 asking for his resignation from office. He left for Singapore via the Maldives. After which he had left for Thailand where he currently stays . Tight security has been provided to his Mirihana residence. (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "first week of September",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 2 or 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සැප්තැම්බර් මුල් සතියේ ගෝඨා ආපහු එනවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ලබන මස මුල් සතියේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ඔහු සැප්තැම්බර් 2 හෝ 3 යන දිනවල නැවත පැමිණීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව තතු දත් ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා නැවත පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු සලසන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) මීට පෙර ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. අනතුරුව රාජපක්ෂ මහතා යළි මෙරටට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඔහු අමතා ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ජුලි 9 වැනිදා සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා එල්ල වූ මහජන විරෝධතා හමුවේ ඔහු රටින් පලා ගියේය. ඔහු මාලදිවයින හරහා සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව ගියේය. ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔහු දැනට රැඳී සිටින තායිලන්තය බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇත. ඔහුගේ මිරිහාන නිවසට දැඩි ආරක්ෂාවක් සපයා තිබේ. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් පළමු සතිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ මුල් සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2 හෝ 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செப்டம்பர் முதல் வாரத்தில் கோத்தா திரும்புவார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச அடுத்த மாதம் முதல் வாரத்தில் இலங்கை திரும்பவுள்ளதாக டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அவர் செப்டம்பர் 2 அல்லது 3 ஆம் தேதி திரும்புவார் என்று தகவலறிந்த வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை நாடு திரும்புவதற்கான ஏற்பாடுகளை செய்யுமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்திருந்தது. அதைத் தொடர்ந்து, அவர் நாடு திரும்புவதற்கான ஏற்பாடுகள் குறித்து ஆலோசிக்க, ஜனாதிபதி திரு.ராஜபக்ஷவைத் தொடர்பு கொண்டதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஜூலை 9 அன்று பதவி விலகக் கோரி பொதுமக்கள் நடத்திய போராட்டத்தின் காரணமாக அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார். மாலத்தீவு வழியாக சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றார். அதன் பிறகு அவர் தாய்லாந்து சென்று அங்கு தற்போது தங்கியுள்ளார். அவரது மிரிஹான இல்லத்திற்கு பலத்த பாதுகாப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "செப்டம்பர் முதல் வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம் முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2 அல்லது 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}