{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Abbotsleigh-Estate-achieves-yet-another-all-time-record-price/34-738031",
  "time_ut": 1659037103,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Abbotsleigh Estate achieves yet another all-time record price",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Abbotsleigh Estate achieves yet another all-time record price",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Abbotsleigh Estate re- established an all- time record price of Rs. 1,500 per kg for a CTC High Grown PF1 under the “Florence” mark at the tea auction held on 27 July, surpassing their own record price of Rs. 1,460 per kg for the same grade obtained at the tea auction conducted last week.",
        "Abbotsleigh Estate is located in the Hatton region and comes under the purview of Hatton Plantations. This line of tea was purchased by Sun Shine Tea Ltd. and was marketed and sold by tea broker John Keells."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Abbotsleigh Estate",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Abbotsleigh Estate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "all-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abbotsleigh Estate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sun Shine Tea Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇබොට්ස්ලී වතුයාය තවත් සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිලක් අත්කර ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇබොට්ස්ලි වතුයාය රු. ජුලි 27 වන දින පැවති තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී \"ෆ්ලෝරන්ස්\" ලකුණ යටතේ CTC High Grown PF1 සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රු. පසුගිය සතියේ පවත්වන ලද තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ලබාගත් එම ශ්‍රේණිය සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් එකක් රුපියල් 1,460 කි.",
        "ඇබොට්ස්ලී වතුයාය හැටන් කලාපයේ පිහිටා ඇති අතර එය හැටන් වතුකරයේ විෂය පථයට අයත් වේ. මෙම තේ පේලිය Sun Shine Tea Ltd විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති අතර එය අලෙවි කර අලෙවි කරන ලද්දේ තේ තැරැව්කරු ජෝන් කීල්ස් විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇබොට්ස්ලී වත්ත",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇබොට්ස්ලී වත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇබොට්ස්ලී වත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන් වැවිලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sun Shine Tea Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அபோட்ஸ்லீ எஸ்டேட் மற்றொரு அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலையை எட்டியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Abbotsleigh எஸ்டேட் மீண்டும் அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையாக ரூ. ஜூலை 27 அன்று நடைபெற்ற தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் \"புளோரன்ஸ்\" குறியின் கீழ் CTC உயர் வளர்ந்த PF1 ஒரு கிலோவிற்கு 1,500 ரூபாய், அவர்களின் சொந்த சாதனை விலையான ரூ. கடந்த வாரம் நடத்தப்பட்ட தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் கிடைத்த அதே தரத்திற்கு கிலோ ரூ.1,460.",
        "அபோட்ஸ்லீ தோட்டம் ஹட்டன் பிராந்தியத்தில் அமைந்துள்ளது மற்றும் ஹட்டன் தோட்டங்களின் கீழ் வருகிறது. இந்த தேயிலை சன் ஷைன் டீ லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் தேயிலை தரகர் ஜான் கீல்ஸால் சந்தைப்படுத்தப்பட்டு விற்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அபோட்ஸ்லீ எஸ்டேட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அபோட்ஸ்லீ எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிலோ 1,500",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபோட்ஸ்லீ எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன் தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன் ஷைன் டீ லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}