{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78927",
  "time_ut": 1659900240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe  rejects Application made by  Police to issue a restraining order against the  protest planned to be held  on August 9  by several political parties and civil organisation against President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the current Government.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe  rejects Application made by  Police to issue a restraining order against the  protest planned to be held  on August 9  by several political parties and civil organisation against President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the current Government.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe yesterday (8) rejected a request made by the Police to issue a restraining order against a protest planned to be held today (9), organised by several political parties and civil organisations, against President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the current Government.",
        "While informing the court that several political parties and civil organisations have planned to hold a protest at the Viharamahadevi (Victoria) Park in Colombo today, the Cinnamon Gardens Police had requested the Colombo Magistrate’s Court to issue an order preventing the said protest from being held.",
        "However, when the request was considered yesterday, the Chief Magistrate rejected the request made by the Police, and instead ordered the Police to take the relevant steps if any person or group attending the protest should commit any act of violence.",
        "It was reported that several groups, including political parties and civil organisations, are to hold a protest in Colombo and some other areas today, in protest over President Wickremesinghe and the current Government. However, certain groups connected to the “RanilGoGama” public protest site, which demanded the resignation of Wickremesinghe, have stated that they would not engage in the said protest.",
        "Meanwhile, the Cinnamon Gardens Police reported to Amarasinghe yesterday that two more suspects are expected to be arrested in connection with the alleged incident of a group of protestors trespassing into the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation (SLRC) premises in Colombo 7, and disrupting its broadcasting activities. The Police requested the court to issue an order to present one of the said suspects before court, as he is currently in remand custody in connection with a case being heard in the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court. The Colombo Chief Magistrate then directed the Police to obtain the relevant order from the respective magistrate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Magistrate",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Application",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Gardens Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Gardens Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහ වත්මන් රජයට එරෙහිව දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ සිවිල් සංවිධාන කිහිපයක් විසින් අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති විරෝධතාවයට එරෙහිව තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙසට පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීම කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහ වත්මන් රජයට එරෙහිව දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ සිවිල් සංවිධාන කිහිපයක් එක්ව අද (9) පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති විරෝධතාවයක් පැවැත්වීම වැළැක්වීමේ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීම කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ (8) ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. .",
        "දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ සිවිල් සංවිධාන කිහිපයක් එක්ව අද කොළඹ විහාරමහාදේවී (වික්ටෝරියා) උද්‍යානයේ විරෝධතාවයක් පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව අධිකරණයට දන්වමින් කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය එම විරෝධතාව පැවැත්වීම වළක්වාලමින් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් එම ඉල්ලීම ඊයේ සළකා බැලූ අවස්ථාවේදී පොලීසිය කළ ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා ඒ වෙනුවට විරෝධතාවයට පැමිණෙන කිසියම් පුද්ගලයෙකු හෝ කණ්ඩායමක් කිසියම් ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවක් සිදුකළහොත් අදාළ පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස පොලීසියට නියෝග කළා.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහ වත්මන් රජයට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සිවිල් සංවිධාන ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම් කිහිපයක් අද කොළඹ සහ තවත් ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බව වාර්තා විය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි “රනිල්ගොගම” මහජන විරෝධතා අඩවියට සම්බන්ධ ඇතැම් පිරිස් එම විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත නොවන බව ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, කොළඹ 7, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථා පරිශ්‍රයට විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් අනවසරයෙන් ඇතුළු වී එහි විකාශන කටයුතුවලට බාධා කළ බව කියන සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවත් සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය ඊයේ අමරසිංහට වාර්තා කළේය. . කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේ විභාග වන නඩුවකට අදාළව දැනට රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිටින මෙම සැකකරුගෙන් එක් අයෙකු අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස පොලිසිය අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. අනතුරුව අදාළ නියෝගය අදාළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගෙන් ලබා ගන්නා ලෙස කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා පොලීසියට නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අයදුම්පත",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරසිංහ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் எதிராக பல அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புகளால் ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஆம் திகதி நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ள போராட்டத்திற்கு தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்குமாறு பொலிஸார் செய்த விண்ணப்பத்தை கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க நிராகரித்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் எதிராக பல அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புக்கள் இணைந்து இன்று (9) நடத்த திட்டமிட்டிருந்த போராட்டத்திற்கு தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்குமாறு பொலிஸார் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க நேற்று (8) நிராகரித்துள்ளார். .",
        "பல அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புக்கள் இணைந்து இன்று கொழும்பு விகாரமஹாதேவி (விக்டோரியா) பூங்காவில் போராட்டத்தை நடத்த திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்திருந்த நிலையில், குறித்த போராட்டத்தை நடத்துவதை தடுக்கும் உத்தரவை பிறப்பிக்குமாறு கறுவாத்தோட்டம் பொலிஸார் கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், குறித்த கோரிக்கை நேற்று பரிசீலிக்கப்பட்ட போது, ​​பொலிஸாரின் கோரிக்கையை நிராகரித்த பிரதான நீதவான், அதற்குப் பதிலாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொள்ளும் எந்தவொரு நபரோ அல்லது குழுவினரோ வன்முறைச் செயலில் ஈடுபட்டால் உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புகள் உட்பட பல குழுக்கள் இன்று கொழும்பிலும் வேறு சில பிரதேசங்களிலும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் ஒன்றை நடத்தவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. எவ்வாறாயினும், விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பதவி விலகக் கோரி “ரணில் கோகம” பொதுப் போராட்டத் தளத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சில குழுக்கள், குறித்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடப் போவதில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, கொழும்பு 7 இல் உள்ள இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபன வளாகத்திற்குள் அத்துமீறி நுழைந்து அதன் ஒலிபரப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு இடையூறு ஏற்படுத்தியதாக கூறப்படும் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் மேலும் இரு சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்படவுள்ளதாக கறுவாத்தோட்ட பொலிஸார் நேற்று அமரசிங்கவிடம் தெரிவித்தனர். . கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் நடைபெற்று வரும் வழக்கு ஒன்று தொடர்பில் தற்போது விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சந்தேக நபர்களில் ஒருவரை நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்த உத்தரவிடுமாறு பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர். அதன் பின்னர் குறித்த உத்தரவை உரிய நீதவானிடம் பெற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "விண்ணப்பம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கறுவாத்தோட்ட காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கறுவாத்தோட்ட காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}