{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Pilot-program-to-allocate-bicycle-lanes-for-users-from-today-in-Colombo/342-242020",
  "time_ut": 1659069275,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pilot program to allocate bicycle lanes for users from today in Colombo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pilot program to allocate bicycle lanes for users from today in Colombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Muncipal Council (CMC) is to launch a pilot program to allocate a separate lane for bicycle users today, as there is a considerable increase in the use of push bicycles due to the current fuel and transport issues.",
        "A senior CMC official said that the pilot program will be launched today opposite the Bank Avenue, Colombo, at 11.00 am.",
        "Separate lanes have been allocated for bicycles on the Bank Mawatha and slots have been allocated for the safe parking of bicycles, he said.",
        "The official added that in addition to Bank Avenue, and apart from the pilot program, it is also planned to allocate a cycle lane on George R. de Silva Mawatha in Kotahena as well from today. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Muncipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bank Avenue",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bank Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bank Avenue",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "George R. de Silva Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotahena",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාපැදි භාවිත කරන්නන් සඳහා මංතීරු ලබාදීමේ නියමු වැඩසටහන අද සිට කොළඹදී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින ඉන්ධන සහ ප්‍රවාහන ගැටළු හේතුවෙන් පුෂ් බයිසිකල් භාවිතයේ සැලකිය යුතු වර්ධනයක් දක්නට ලැබෙන බැවින් පාපැදි භාවිතා කරන්නන් සඳහා වෙනම මංතීරුවක් වෙන් කිරීමේ නියමු වැඩසටහනක් කොළඹ නගර සභාව විසින් අද දියත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "කොළඹ, බැංකු මාවත ඉදිරිපිටදී අද පෙරවරු 11.00ට නියමු වැඩසටහන දියත් කරන බව කොළඹ නගර සභාවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "බැංකු මාවතේ පාපැදි සඳහා වෙනම මංතීරු වෙන් කර ඇති අතර ආරක්ෂිතව පාපැදි ගාල් කිරීම සඳහා තව් වෙන් කර ඇති බවද ඒ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බැංකු මාවතට අමතරව නියමු වැඩසටහනට අමතරව කොටහේන ජෝර්ජ් ආර් ද සිල්වා මාවතේ ද අද සිට පාපැදි මංතීරුවක් වෙන් කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව එම නිලධාරියා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකු මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැංකු මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැංකු මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝර්ජ් ආර් ද සිල්වා මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටහේන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாவனையாளர்களுக்கு சைக்கிள் பாதைகளை ஒதுக்கும் முன்னோடி வேலைத்திட்டம் இன்று முதல் கொழும்பில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய எரிபொருள் மற்றும் போக்குவரத்து பிரச்சினைகளால் மிதிவண்டிகளின் பாவனையில் கணிசமான அதிகரிப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், துவிச்சக்கரவண்டி பாவனையாளர்களுக்கு தனியான பாதையை ஒதுக்கும் முன்னோடித் திட்டத்தை கொழும்பு நகரசபை (CMC) இன்று ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளது.",
        "இன்று காலை 11.00 மணிக்கு கொழும்பு வங்கி அவென்யூவுக்கு எதிரே இந்த முன்னோடித் திட்டம் தொடங்கப்படும் என்று சிஎம்சியின் மூத்த அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வங்கி மாவத்தையில் துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகளுக்கு தனியான பாதைகள் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், துவிச்சக்கர வண்டிகளை பாதுகாப்பாக நிறுத்துவதற்கு இடங்களும் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன என்றார்.",
        "வங்கி அவென்யூவிற்கு மேலதிகமாக, முன்னோடித் திட்டத்திற்கு மேலதிகமாக, கொட்டாஞ்சேனை ஜோர்ஜ் ஆர். டி சில்வா மாவத்தையிலும் இன்று முதல் சைக்கிள் பாதையை ஒதுக்குவதற்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அந்த அதிகாரி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.எம்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.எம்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி அவென்யூ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வங்கி மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வங்கி அவென்யூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோர்ஜ் ஆர். டி சில்வா மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டாஞ்சேனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}