{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83518/railway-dept-issues-notice-on-train-operations-tomorrow",
  "time_ut": 1657304400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Railway Dept issues notice on train operations tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Railway Dept issues notice on train operations tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Railways says train services to Colombo from other destinations will not operate tomorrow (July 09).",
        "The announcement came after police curfew was imposed in several police areas in the Western Province ahead of the series of mass anti-government protests expected to take place in and outskirts of Colombo tomorrow (July 09).",
        "Accordingly, Negombo, Kelaniya, Nugegoda, Mount Lavinia, Colombo North, Colombo South and Colombo Central police areas are under police curfew from 9.00 p.m. today until further notice."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Railway Dept",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mount Lavinia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo North, Colombo South and Colombo Central",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය ධාවනය පිළිබඳව දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හෙට නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අනෙකුත් ගමනාන්තවල සිට කොළඹ දක්වා දුම්රිය සේවා හෙට (ජුලි 09) ක්‍රියාත්මක නොවන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය පවසයි.",
        "හෙට (ජූලි 09) කොළඹ සහ තදාසන්න ප්‍රදේශවල පැවැත්වීමට අපේක්ෂිත රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී මහජන විරෝධතා මාලාවට පෙර බස්නාහිර පළාතේ පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීමෙන් පසුව මෙම නිවේදනය නිකුත් විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව මීගමුව, කැලණිය, නුගේගොඩ, ගල්කිස්ස, කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ සහ කොළඹ මධ්‍යම යන පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශවලට රාත්‍රී 9.00 සිට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවා ඇත. අද නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ සහ මැද කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில் இயக்கம் குறித்த அறிவிப்பை ரயில்வே துறை நாளை வெளியிடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஏனைய இடங்களிலிருந்து கொழும்புக்கான ரயில் சேவைகள் நாளை (ஜூலை 09) இயங்காது என இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாளை (ஜூலை 09) கொழும்பிலும் அதன் புறநகர்ப் பகுதிகளிலும் இடம்பெறும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் பாரிய அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டங்களை முன்னிட்டு மேல் மாகாணத்தின் பல பொலிஸ் பகுதிகளில் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டதை அடுத்து இந்த அறிவிப்பு வெளியாகியுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, நீர்கொழும்பு, களனி, நுகேகொடை, கல்கிசை, கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு மற்றும் கொழும்பு மத்திய பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளில் இரவு 9.00 மணி முதல் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. இன்று மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு மற்றும் கொழும்பு மத்திய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.00 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}