{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132416",
  "time_ut": 1659005494,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பேராசிரியர்களான சுனந்த மத்துமபண்டார, ஷெனுகா செனவிரத்ன ஜனாதிபதியின் தேசிய, சர்வதேச ஊடக ஆலோசகர்களாக நியமனம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Appointment of Professors Sunanda Mathumabandara and Shenuka Senaviratne as National and International Media Advisers to the President",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prof. Sunanda Mathumabandara and Prof. Shenuka Senaviratne have been appointed as National and International Media Advisers to the President. These appointments have been made by President's Office of the President, Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake.",
        "Professor Sunanda Mathumabandara recently assumed duties as Senior Advisor to the President (Media) and Professor Shenuka Senaviratne as Senior Advisor to the President (International Media).",
        "Professor Sunanda Mathumabandara, former Vice-Chancellor of Kelani University, has served as the Head of the Department of Economics and the Dean of the Faculty of Social Sciences.",
        "He has served as Secretary of the State Ministry of Mass Media, Director General of Government Information Department and Director General of Development and Communication of the Ministry of Economic Development.",
        "Senior Adviser (International Media) to the President, Shenuka Senaviratne, is a senior officer with extensive experience in diplomatic affairs of this country, who has also held the post of Secretary to the Ministry of External Affairs.",
        "Shenuka Senaviratne has served as Sri Lankan High Commissioner to the United Kingdom, Sri Lankan Ambassador to Thailand, and Permanent Representative to the United Nations in Geneva and New York."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mathumabandara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shenuka Senaviratne",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "National and International Media Advisers",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunanda Mathumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shenuka Senaviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National and International Media Advisers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunanda Mathumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shenuka Senaviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunanda Mathumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Economics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Faculty of Social Sciences",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the State Ministry of Mass Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Development and Communication of the Ministry of Economic Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shenuka Senaviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shenuka Senaviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ජාතික හා ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය උපදේශකවරුන් ලෙස මහාචාර්ය සුනන්ද මතුබණ්ඩාර සහ ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න පත් කිරීම.",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ජාතික සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය උපදේශකවරුන් ලෙස මහාචාර්ය සුනන්ද මතුමබණ්ඩාර සහ මහාචාර්ය ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න පත් කර තිබේ. ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා විසින් මෙම පත්කිරීම් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "මහාචාර්ය සුනන්ද මතුමබණ්ඩාර ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක (මාධ්‍ය) ලෙසත්, මහාචාර්ය ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක (ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය) ලෙසත් පසුගියදා වැඩ භාර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "කැලණි විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ හිටපු උපකුලපති මහාචාර්ය සුනන්ද මතුබණ්ඩාර මහතා ආර්ථික විද්‍යා අංශයේ ප්‍රධානියා සහ සමාජ විද්‍යා පීඨයේ පීඨාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහු ජනමාධ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්, රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් සහ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සංවර්ධන හා සන්නිවේදන අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක (ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය) ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න මහත්මිය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් ධූරය ද හොබවා ඇති මෙරට රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පුළුල් අත්දැකීම් ඇති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකි.",
        "ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස්, තායිලන්තයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති සහ ජිනීවා සහ නිව්යෝර්ක්හි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නිත්‍ය නියෝජිතවරිය ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මතුමබණ්ඩාර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය උපදේශකයින්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුනන්ද මතුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය උපදේශකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුනන්ද මතුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුනන්ද මතුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැලණි විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ විද්‍යා පීඨය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනමාධ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික සංවර්ධන අමාත්යාංශයේ සංවර්ධනය හා සන්නිවේදනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙනුකා සෙනවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேராசிரியர்களான சுனந்த மத்துமபண்டார, ஷெனுகா செனவிரத்ன ஜனாதிபதியின் தேசிய, சர்வதேச ஊடக ஆலோசகர்களாக நியமனம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "பேராசிரியர் சுனந்த மத்துமபண்டார மற்றும் பேராசிரியர் ஷெனுகா செனவிரத்ன ஆகியோர் ஜனாதிபதியின் தேசிய மற்றும் சர்வதேச ஊடக ஆலோசகர்களாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிப்புரைக்கமைய, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்கவினால் இந்த நியமனங்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பேராசிரியர் சுனந்த மத்துமபண்டார ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகராகவும் (ஊடகம்) மற்றும் பேராசிரியர் ஷெனுகா செனவிரத்ன, ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகராகவும் (சர்வதேச ஊடகம்) அண்மையில் கடமைகளைப் பொறுப்பேற்றனர்.",
        "களனிப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் முன்னாள் உபவேந்தரான பேராசிரியர் சுனந்த மத்துமபண்டார , அந்த பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் பொருளியல் விஞ்ஞான கல்விப் பிரிவின் தலைவராகவும் சமூக விஞ்ஞான பீடத்தின் பீடாதிபதியாகவும் பணியாற்றியுள்ளார்.",
        "வெகுசன ஊடக இராஜாங்க அமைச்சின் செயலாளராக பணியாற்றியுள்ள அவர், அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்கள பணிப்பாளர் நாயகமாகவும், பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தி அமைச்சின் அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் தொடர்பாடல் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகமாகவும் பதவி வகித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகர் (சர்வதேச ஊடகம்) பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள  ஷெனுகா செனவிரத்ன, இந்த நாட்டின் இராஜதந்திர விவகாரங்களில் அதிக அனுபவமுள்ள சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரியான அவர், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் பதவியையும் வகித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஷெனுகா செனவிரத்ன, ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராகவும், தாய்லாந்துக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவராகவும், ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதியாக ஜெனிவா மற்றும் நியூயோர்க்கில் பணியாற்றியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மதுமபண்டார",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஷேனுகா சேனவிரத்ன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய மற்றும் சர்வதேச ஊடக ஆலோசகர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுனந்தா மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷேனுகா சேனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மற்றும் சர்வதேச ஊடக ஆலோசகர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுனந்தா மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷேனுகா சேனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுனந்தா மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களனி பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக அறிவியல் பீடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தி அமைச்சின் அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் தொடர்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷேனுகா சேனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷேனுகா சேனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}