{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84679/day-two-of-parliamentary-debate-on-interim-budget-speech-today",
  "time_ut": 1662004080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Day two of parliamentary debate on interim budget speech today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Day two of parliamentary debate on interim budget speech today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The second consecutive day of the parliamentary debate on the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill, presented by President Ranil Wickremesinghe for the remainder of the fiscal year 2022, is scheduled for today (Sep 01) from 9.30 a.m. to 5.30 p.m.",
        "On September 02, the second reading of the interim budget speech will be debated from 9.30 a.m. to 4.30 p.m., after which the Bill is slated to be passed after the committee stage and third reading.",
        "President Wickremesinghe, in his capacity as the Minister of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policies, delivered the interim budget speech or the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill when the parliament convened at 1.00 p.m on August 30.",
        "In the interim budget proposals, President Ranil Wickremesinghe proposed to increase the Value-Added Tax (VAT) from 12% to 15% with effect from today.",
        "It is reported that President Wickremesinghe has signed the gazette notification with regard to the VAT increase.",
        "Delivering the interim budget, President Wickremesinghe also stated that the government’s aim is to create a surplus in the primary budget by the year 2025."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The second consecutive day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the fiscal year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sep 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 a.m. to",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 a.m. to",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Value-Added Tax",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12% to 15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අතුරු අයවැය කතාව පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු විවාදයේ දෙවන දිනය අද",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු විවාදයේ අඛණ්ඩ දෙවන දිනය අද (සැප් 01) පෙරවරු 9.30 සිට පස්වරු 5.30 දක්වා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් 02 වැනිදා අතුරු අයවැය කතාවේ දෙවැනි වර කියවීම පෙරවරු 9.30 සිට පස්වරු 4.30 දක්වා විවාදයට ගෙන කාරක සභා අවස්ථාව සහ තෙවැනි වර කියවීමෙන් අනතුරුව පනත් කෙටුම්පත සම්මත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "අගෝස්තු 30 වැනි දින පස්වරු 1.00 ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස් වූ අවස්ථාවේදී මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අතුරු අයවැය කතාව හෝ විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීම සිදු කළේය.",
        "අද සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි එකතු කළ අගය මත බද්ද (VAT) 12% සිට 15% දක්වා වැඩි කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අතුරු අයවැය යෝජනා මඟින් යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "වැට් බදු ඉහළ නැංවීමට අදාළ ගැසට් නිවේදනයට ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අත්සන් තබා ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "2025 වසර වන විට ප්‍රාථමික අයවැය අතිරික්තයක් ඇති කිරීම රජයේ අරමුණ බව ද ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අතුරු අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පිට පිට දෙවැනි දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 සිට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.30 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 සිට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගය එකතු කළ බද්ද",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12% සිට 15% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැට් බද්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் உரை மீதான விவாதத்தின் இரண்டாம் நாள் இன்று",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் எஞ்சிய நிதியாண்டுக்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலம் மீதான பாராளுமன்ற விவாதத்தின் தொடர்ச்சியாக இரண்டாவது நாளான இன்று (செப். 01) காலை 9.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 5.30 மணி வரை நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "செப்டம்பர் 02 ஆம் திகதி, இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு காலை 9.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4.30 மணி வரை விவாதிக்கப்படும், அதன் பின்னர் குழு நிலை மற்றும் மூன்றாம் வாசிப்பின் பின்னர் மசோதா நிறைவேற்றப்பட உள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில், ஆகஸ்ட் 30 ஆம் திகதி பிற்பகல் 1.00 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்றம் கூடியபோது இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரை அல்லது ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பை நிகழ்த்தினார்.",
        "இன்று முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் பெறுமதி சேர் வரியை (VAT) 12% இலிருந்து 15% ஆக அதிகரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட யோசனைகளில் முன்மொழிந்தார்.",
        "VAT அதிகரிப்பு தொடர்பிலான வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க கையொப்பமிட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை சமர்ப்பித்த ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, 2025 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் முதன்மை வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் உபரியை உருவாக்குவதே அரசாங்கத்தின் நோக்கமாகும் என்றும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.30 மணி முதல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 5.30 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.30 மணி முதல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.30 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட வரி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12% முதல் 15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}