{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/six-people-get-addicted-to-heroin-daily-national-authority-on-tobacco-and-alcohol/",
  "time_ut": 1656135960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Six people get addicted to heroin daily: National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Six people get addicted to heroin daily: National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); An average of six people get addicted to heroin daily in Sri Lanka, says the Chairman of the National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol, Dr. Samadhi Rajapksa.",
        "Speaking to News 1st, he said that based on a survey conducted recently, it was discovered that close to 120,000 people are addicted to heroin in Sri Lanka, while a decline in the rate of smoking among the general public has been noticed.",
        "According to Dr. Rajapksa, the rate of smoking among the general public has reduced by 6%, in comparison to last year.",
        "Moreover, the rate of consumption of Tobacco Leaves, which stood at 15% back in 2019, has now reduced to 13%. However, there is only a slight reduction in the rate of consumption and production of narcotics has been noted, he added.",
        "What’s more alarming is the increasing rate of consumption of Cannabis and other toxic drugs, such as heroin, Dr. Rajapaksa mentioned.",
        "Six people get addicted to heroin daily: National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samadhi Rajapksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "close to 120,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tobacco Leaves",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cannabis",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිනකට හය දෙනෙක් හෙරොයින් වලට ඇබ්බැහි වෙති: දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්රී ලංකාවේ දිනපතා පුද්ගලයින් හය දෙනෙකු හෙරොයින් වලට ඇබ්බැහි වන බව ශ්රී ලංකාවේ දෛනිකව හෙරොයින් වලට ඇබ්බැහි වන බව ශ්රී ලංකාවේ දුම්කොළ හා මධ්යසාර, ආචාර්ය සමාදි රාජප්ක්සා පවසයි.",
        "News 1st වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ, මෑතකදී කරන ලද සමීක්ෂණයකට අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ 120,000 කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් හෙරොයින්වලට ඇබ්බැහි වී සිටින බව අනාවරණය වූ අතර සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාව අතර දුම්පානය අනුපාතයේ අඩුවීමක් දක්නට ලැබෙන බවයි.",
        "පසුගිය වසරට සාපේක්ෂව සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාව අතර දුම්පානය කිරීමේ අනුපාතය 6% කින් අඩු වී ඇති බව වෛද්‍ය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, 2019 වසරේ 15%ක් වූ දුම්කොළ කොළ පරිභෝජන අනුපාතය මේ වන විට 13% දක්වා අඩු වී ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පරිභෝජන අනුපාතයේ සහ නිෂ්පාදනයේ සුළු අඩුවීමක් පමණක් සිදුව ඇති බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "වඩාත් භයානක කරුණ වන්නේ ගංජා සහ හෙරොයින් වැනි විෂ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය භාවිතය ඉහළ යාම බව වෛද්‍ය රාජපක්ෂ සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "දිනකට හය දෙනෙක් හෙරොයින් වලට ඇබ්බැහි වෙති: දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දිනපතා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාධි රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "120,000 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්කොළ කොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගංජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தினமும் ஆறு பேர் ஹெராயினுக்கு அடிமையாகிறார்கள்: புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையில் நாளொன்றுக்கு சராசரியாக ஆறு பேர் ஹெரோயினுக்கு அடிமையாகிறார்கள் என்று புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் தொடர்பான தேசிய அதிகாரசபையின் தலைவர் டாக்டர் சமாதி ராஜபக்ச கூறுகிறார்.",
        "News 1st உடன் பேசிய அவர், சமீபத்தில் நடத்தப்பட்ட கணக்கெடுப்பின் அடிப்படையில், இலங்கையில் சுமார் 120,000 பேர் ஹெராயின் போதைக்கு அடிமையாகி இருப்பதாக கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ளது, அதேவேளையில் பொதுமக்கள் மத்தியில் புகைபிடிக்கும் விகிதம் குறைந்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வருடத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில், பொது மக்களிடையே புகைப்பிடிக்கும் வீதம் 6% குறைந்துள்ளதாக வைத்தியர் ராஜபக்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், 2019ல் 15% ஆக இருந்த புகையிலை இலைகளின் நுகர்வு விகிதம் தற்போது 13% ஆக குறைந்துள்ளது. எவ்வாறாயினும், போதைப்பொருளின் நுகர்வு மற்றும் உற்பத்தி விகிதத்தில் சிறிதளவு குறைப்பு மட்டுமே காணப்படுவதாக அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "கஞ்சா மற்றும் ஹெராயின் போன்ற பிற நச்சுப் போதைப்பொருட்களின் நுகர்வு விகிதம் அதிகரித்து வருவது மிகவும் ஆபத்தானது என்று டாக்டர் ராஜபக்ஷ குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "தினமும் ஆறு பேர் ஹெராயினுக்கு அடிமையாகிறார்கள்: புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தினசரி",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புகையிலை மற்றும் ஆல்கஹால் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமாதி ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "120,000க்கு அருகில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புகையிலை இலைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கஞ்சா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}