{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Court-issues-order-preventing-gathering-near-S-W-R-D-statue/342-241446",
  "time_ut": 1658307200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Court issues order preventing gathering near S.W.R.D. statue",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court issues order preventing gathering near S.W.R.D. statue",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Fort Magistrate's court today issued an order preventing anyone from reaching within a 50 meter radius of the S.W.R.D. Bandaranaike statue located at the Galle face in Colombo.",
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage made this order pursuant to a request made by Fort Police that they have received information regarding the possibility of causing damages to the statue.",
        "The Fort Police sought an order preventing any party from reaching 50-meter around the S.W.R.D. Bandaranaike statue."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Fort Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.W.R.D. Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.W.R.D. Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "S.W.R.D අසල රැස් වීම වළක්වමින් අධිකරණයෙන් නියෝගයක් පිළිමය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය අද නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළේ එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී කදවුරේ සිට මීටර් 50ක අරය තුළට කිසිවෙකුට පැමිණීම වළක්වාලමින්. කොළඹ ගාලු මුවදොර පිහිටි බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා මෙම නියෝගය කළේ ප්‍රතිමාවට අලාභහානි කිරීමට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු ලැබී ඇති බවට කොටුව පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුවය.",
        "එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී අවටින් කිසිදු පාර්ශ්වයකට මීටර් 50කට පැමිණීම වළක්වන නියෝගයක් කොටුව පොලිසිය ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා විසින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී. බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී. බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி.க்கு அருகில் கூடுவதைத் தடுக்க நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவு. சிலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "S.W.R.D இன் 50 மீற்றர் சுற்றளவிற்குள் எவரும் செல்வதைத் தடுக்கும் வகையில் கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது. கொழும்பு காலி முகத்திடலில் பண்டாரநாயக்க சிலை அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சிலைக்கு சேதம் விளைவிப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக கோட்டை பொலிசார் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி.யை சுற்றி 50 மீட்டர் தூரத்திற்கு எந்த தரப்பினரும் செல்வதை தடுக்கும் உத்தரவை கோட்டை போலீசார் கோரினர். பண்டாரநாயக்கா சிலை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி. பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி. பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}