{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මීරිගම-හලුගම-කන්දේදී-පෙට්‍රල්-බවුසරයක්-පෙරලෙයි/101-616912",
  "time_ut": 1658564487,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මීරිගම හලුගම කන්දේදී පෙට්‍රල් බවුසරයක් පෙරලෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A petrol bowser overturns at Halugama Hill, Mirigama",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mirigama police say that a bowser carrying a load of petrol has met with an accident at Halugama mountain on the Mirigama Dangowita road this afternoon on the 23rd.",
        "The fuel stock was being transported from Muthurajawela to Peradeniya and the police stated that it contained 33600 liters of petrol.",
        "Preliminary investigations have revealed that the accident occurred when the bowser suddenly ran backwards at the top of Halugama hill.",
        "The police also said that the people who were traveling on the highway at that time collected the petrol that flowed after the bowser overturned."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Halugama Hill",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mirigama",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mirigama",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halugama mountain",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mirigama Dangowita",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 23rd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muthurajawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peradeniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Halugama hill",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මීරිගම හලුගම කන්දේදී පෙට්‍රල් බවුසරයක් පෙරලෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් රැගත් බවුසරයක් මීරිගම දංඕවිට මාර්ගයේ හලුගම කන්දේදී අද 23දහවල් අනතුරට පත් වී ඇතැයි මිරිගම පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මුතුරාජවෙල සිට පේරාදෙණිය බලා මෙම ඉන්ධන තොගය ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබී ඇති අතර එහි පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර්  33600 ඇතැයි පොලීසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "හලුගම කන්ද මුදුනේ දී බවුසරය  එක්වරම පිටුපසට ධාවනය වීමෙන් මෙම අනතුර සිදුවී ඇතැයි මූලික පරීක්ෂණවලදී හෙළි වී ඇත",
        "බවුසරයේ පෙරළීමෙන් පසු ගලා ගිය  පෙට්‍රල් ඒ අවස්ථාවේ මහ මග ගමන් ගනිමින් සිටි පිරිස් විසින් එකතු කරගෙන ඇති බව ද පොලිසිය පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හළුගම කන්ද",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "මීරිගම",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මීරිගම",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හළුගම කන්ද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීරිගම දංගෝවිට",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුතුරාජවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හළුගම කන්ද",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மீரிகம ஹலுகம மலையில் பெற்றோல் பவுசர் ஒன்று கவிழ்ந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மீரிகம தங்கொவிட்ட வீதியில் ஹலுகம மலையில் இன்று 23ஆம் திகதி பிற்பகல் பெற்றோல் ஏற்றிச் சென்ற பவுசர் ஒன்று விபத்துக்குள்ளாகியுள்ளதாக மீரிகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "முத்துராஜவெலயில் இருந்து பேராதனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட இந்த எரிபொருள் கையிருப்பில் 33600 லீற்றர் பெற்றோல் இருந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஹலுகம மலை உச்சியில் பௌசர் திடீரென பின்னோக்கி ஓடியதில் இந்த விபத்து ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக முதற்கட்ட விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "அப்போது நெடுஞ்சாலையில் பயணித்தவர்களே பவுசர் கவிழ்ந்ததையடுத்து பாய்ந்த பெற்றோலை சேகரித்ததாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஹலுகம மலை",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "மீரிகம",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மீரிகம",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலுகம மலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீரிகம தங்கொவிட்ட",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முத்துராஜவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹலுகம மலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}