{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බිත්තර-හතරට-ලක්ෂ-පහක-දඩයක්/101-619063",
  "time_ut": 1661933616,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බිත්තර හතරට ලක්ෂ පහක දඩයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A fine of five lakhs for four eggs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Balangoda Acting Magistrate A. to pay a fine of five lakh rupees to a business place in Balangoda town that sold eggs at a higher price than the prescribed price. Amy. S. Mrs. Menike ordered.",
        "This trading company was fined for selling 4 white eggs at a price of 260 rupees.",
        "The officials of the consumer authority said that the eggs were bought from the relevant market by a strategist and a sum of 260 rupees was charged for four eggs at 65 rupees per egg.",
        "Balangoda Acting Magistrate A.M.S. Mrs. Menike fixed the fine amount of five lakhs as follows.",
        "Officers Nasik Ahmed and Nadisha Liyanage were present for this raid which was organized by the investigation officer Mrs. Harshani Dasanayake on the instructions of Mr. Udaya Namalgama, District Head of Ratnapura Consumer Authority."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Balangoda Acting Magistrate A.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Balangoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Menike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "260",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "260",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Balangoda Acting Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Menike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nasik Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nadisha Liyanage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshani Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Namalgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "District Head",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura Consumer Authority",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිත්තර හතරට ලක්ෂ පහක දඩයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බිත්තර සදහා නියම කර ඇති මිලට වඩා වැඩි මිලකට  අලෙවි කල බලන්ගොඩ නගරයේ  ව්‍යාපාරික ස්ථානයකට රුපියල් ලක්ෂ පහක  දඩ මුදලක් ගෙවන ලෙස බලන්ගොඩ වැඩබලන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් ඒ. එමි . එස්. මැණිකේ මහත්මිය නියෝග කළාය.",
        "සුදු බිත්තර 4 ක් රැපියල් 260 ක මිලකට අලෙවි කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට වැරදි කරුවු මෙ වෙළෙඳ ආයතනයට එසේ දඩ නියම විය.ෙ",
        "උපාය දුතයකු මගින් අදාල වෙලෙදසලින් බිත්තර මිල දි ගත් බවත් එක් බිත්තරක් රැපියල් 65 බැගින් බිත්තර හතරක් සදහා රුපියල් 260 ක මුදලක් අයකර ගෙන ඇති බවද පාරිභෝගික අධිකාරියේ නිළධාරිහු පැවැසුහ.",
        "වැඩි මිලට බිත්තර විකිණීම යන චෝදනා යටතේ ඉදිරිපත් කළ නඩුව සදහා වරද පිළිගත් අදාල ආයතනය වෙත බලන්ගොඩ වැඩ බලන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් ඒ.එමි.එස්. මැණිකේ මහත්මිය විසින් එම ලක්ෂ පහක දඩ මුදල මෙලෙස නියම කළාය.",
        "රත්නපුර පාරිභෝගික අධිකාරියේ දිස්ත්‍රික් ප්‍රධානි උදය නාමල්ගම මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි විමර්ශන නිළධාරිනි හර්ශනි දසනායක මහත්මිය විසින් සංවිධානය කළ මෙම වැටලිම සදහා නසික් අහමඩ් , නදිිශ ලියනගේ යන නිළධාරිහු එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බලංගොඩ වැඩබලන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් ඒ.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැණිකේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "260",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "260",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලංගොඩ වැඩ බලන මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැණිකේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාසික් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නදීෂා ලියනගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂනී දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය නාමල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්රික් ප්රධානියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර පාරිභෝගික අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான்கு முட்டைகளுக்கு ஐந்து லட்சம் அபராதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பலாங்கொடை நகரில் நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட விலையை விட அதிக விலைக்கு முட்டைகளை விற்பனை செய்த வர்த்தக நிலையம் ஒன்றிற்கு ஐந்து இலட்சம் ரூபா தண்டப்பணம் செலுத்துமாறு பலாங்கொடை பதில் நீதவான் ஏ. ஆமி. எஸ். திருமதி மெனிகே உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "4 வெள்ளை முட்டைகளை 260 ரூபாய்க்கு விற்ற இந்த வர்த்தக நிறுவனத்துக்கு அபராதம் விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "குறித்த சந்தையிலிருந்து மூலோபாய நிபுணர் ஒருவரினால் முட்டைகள் கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும் ஒரு முட்டைக்கு 65 ரூபா வீதம் நான்கு முட்டைகளுக்கு 260 ரூபா அறவிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக நுகர்வோர் அதிகாரசபை அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பலாங்கொடை பதில் நீதவான் ஏ.எம்.எஸ். திருமதி மெனிகே ஐந்து இலட்சம் அபராதத் தொகையை பின்வருமாறு நிர்ணயித்தார்.",
        "இரத்தினபுரி நுகர்வோர் அதிகாரசபையின் மாவட்டத் தலைவர் திரு உதய நாமல்கம அவர்களின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் விசாரணை அதிகாரி திருமதி ஹர்ஷனி தசநாயக்கவினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட இந்தச் சுற்றிவளைப்புக்கு உத்தியோகத்தர்களான நாசிக் அஹமட் மற்றும் நதிஷா லியனகே ஆகியோர் பிரசன்னமாகியிருந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொடை பதில் நீதவான் ஏ.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெனிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "260",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "260",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொடை பதில் நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெனிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாசிக் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நதிஷா லியனகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷனி தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய நமல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட தலைவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி நுகர்வோர் அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}