{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පෝලිම්වල-සිටින-ජනතාවට-‘ටෝකන්’/101-615416",
  "time_ut": 1656235540,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පෝලිම්වල සිටින ජනතාවට ‘ටෝකන්’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'Tokens' for people in queues",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera stated that the people waiting in line at petrol stations are being given a 'token' with the intervention of the three forces and will be sent home after receiving fuel at the relevant petrol station.",
        "Wijesekera said that the Chief of Defense Staff, former Army Commander General Shavendra Silva had said at the recent Security Council meeting that the three forces would be deployed to obtain information from the people in the queues by giving them 'tokens'."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tokens",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෝලිම්වල සිටින ජනතාවට ‘ටෝකන්’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් අසළ මේ වන විට පෝලිම්වල රැදී ජනතාවට ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවේ මැදිහත්වීමෙන් ‘ටෝකන්’ පතක් දී නිවෙස්වලට පිටත්කර හරින බවත් අදාල ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලට ඉන්දන ලැබුණු පසු දුරකථනය හරහා දැනුවත් කර ඉන්ධන ලබාදෙන බවත් විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආරක්‍ෂක මණ්ඩලය පසුගියදා රැස්වූ අවස්ථාවේදී ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව යොදාගෙන පෝලිම්වල සිටින ජනතාවට ‘ටෝකන්’ පතක් දී විස්තර ලබාගැනීමට කටයුතු කරන්නේ යැයි ආරක්‍ෂ මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී හිටපු හමුදාපති ජනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා පැවසූ බව කී අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා ඉදිරියේදී එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව ද සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ටෝකන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வரிசையில் இருப்பவர்களுக்கான 'டோக்கன்கள்'",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் வரிசையில் நிற்கும் மக்களுக்கு ஆயுதப்படையினரின் தலையீட்டில் 'டோக்கன்' வழங்கப்பட்டு எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக் கொண்ட பின்னர் வீடுகளுக்கு அனுப்பப்படுமென மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வரிசையில் நிற்கும் மக்களிடம் 'டோக்கன்' கொடுத்து தகவல்களைப் பெறுவதற்காக முப்படையினரும் களமிறக்கப்படுவார்கள் என பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி, முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தளபதி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற பாதுகாப்புச் சபைக் கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவித்ததாக விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டோக்கன்கள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}