{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130444",
  "time_ut": 1656513515,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதிய அதிகாரிகளை சந்தித்தது பிரதான எதிரணி - பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கான நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து ஆராய்வு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Meets with top US officials and IMF officials The main opponent - research on measures for economic recovery",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Members of the main opposition, led by Sajid Premadasa, met with a group of top US officials and a group of IMF officials today (29) to discuss measures to help the country recover from the current economic crisis.",
        "The US High Level delegation, which includes Robert Cabrot, US Assistant Secretary of State for Asia, and Kelly Gaitling, US Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asian Affairs, arrived in the country on Sunday.",
        "The group stayed in Sri Lanka until the 29th and held meetings with a delegation led by President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Leader of the Opposition Sajid Premadasa, economists and representatives of international organizations to discuss ways to help Sri Lanka in the face of a major economic crisis.",
        "Accordingly, a meeting was held on Wednesday between a group of top US officials and a group comprising Sajid Premadasa, leader of the main opposition United People's Force, and party members Harsha de Silva, Kabir Haseem and Eran Wickremaratne.",
        "During the meeting, the Opposition thanked the United States for all assistance provided to Sri Lanka by the victims of the economic crisis and discussed the next steps.",
        "Meanwhile, a meeting between a group of IMF officials in Sri Lanka and members of the United People's Power took place yesterday.",
        "It is noteworthy that the economic situation of the country and the reforms that need to be carried out in anticipation of the economic recovery were discussed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Cabrot",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Gaitling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kabir Haseem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickremaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉහළ එක්සත් ජනපද නිලධාරීන් සහ IMF නිලධාරීන් හමුවෙයි ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය - ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගවේෂණය කරයි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "සජිඩ් ප්‍රේමදාසගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු අද (29) අමෙරිකාවේ ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් හමුවී පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් රට ගොඩ ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "ආසියාව පිළිබඳ ඇමෙරිකානු සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් රොබට් කැබ්‍රොට් සහ දකුණු හා මධ්‍යම ආසියානු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ ඇමෙරිකානු සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් කෙලී ගේට්ලින් ඇතුළු ඇමෙරිකානු ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිත පිරිස ඉරිදා දිවයිනට පැමිණියහ.",
        "මෙම පිරිස ලබන 29 වැනිදා දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රැඳී සිටිමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, විපක්ෂ නායක සජිඩ් ප්‍රේමදාස, ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන නියෝජිතයන් ඇතුළු දූත පිරිසක් හමුවී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය විය හැකි ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළහ. විශාල ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක්.",
        "ඒ අනුව පසුගිය බදාදා අමෙරිකාවේ ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් සහ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගයේ නායක සජිඩ් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සහ පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන් වන හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා, කබීර් හසීම් සහ ඉරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න ඇතුළු පිරිසක් අතර හමුවක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙම හමුවේදී, ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් විපතට පත් වූවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් සියලු සහය වෙනුවෙන් එක්සත් ජනපදයට ස්තුතිය පළ කළ විපක්ෂය, ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් සහ එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගයේ සාමාජිකයින් අතර හමුවක් ඊයේ සිදුවුණා.",
        "රටේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය අපේක්ෂාවෙන් සිදු කළ යුතු ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කිරීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කැබ්රොට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී ගේට්ලිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කබීර් හසීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதிய அதிகாரிகளை சந்தித்தது பிரதான எதிரணி - பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கான நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து ஆராய்வு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழுவையும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதிய அதிகாரிகள் குழுவையும் இன்று 29 ஆம் திகதி சந்தித்த சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ தலைமையிலான பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்துக் கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளனர்.",
        "அமெரிக்க திறைசேரியின் ஆசியப்பிராந்தியத்துக்கான பிரதி உதவிச்செயலாளர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரொத் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத்திணைக்களத்தின் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியப்பிராந்தியத்துக்கான பிரதி உதவிச்செயலாளர் கெலி கெய்டெலிங் ஆகியோரை உள்ளடக்கிய அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்டக்குழு கடந்த 26 ஆம் திகதி ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை நாட்டை வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "இந்தக்குழு 29 ஆம் திகதி வரையில் இலங்கையில் தங்கியிருந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, எதிர்க்கட்சித்தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ தலைமையிலான குழுவினர், பொருளியலாளர்கள், சர்வதேச அமைப்புக்களின் பிரதிநிதிகள் உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு தரப்பினருடன் சந்திப்புக்களை நிகழ்த்தியிருந்ததுடன் அவற்றின்போது பாரிய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் இலங்கைக்கு உதவக்கூடிய வழிமுறைகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடல்களை முன்னெடுத்திருந்தது.",
        "அதன்படி அமெரிக்க உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழுவிற்கும் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ மற்றும் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களான ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, கபீர் ஹாசீம், எரான் விக்ரமரத்ன ஆகியோரடங்கிய குழுவிற்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பு நேற்று புதன்கிழமை இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இச்சந்திப்பின்போது பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியினால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருப்போருக்காக இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா வழங்கிய அனைத்து உதவிகளுக்கும் நன்றி தெரிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சியினர், அடுத்தகட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் தொடர்பிலும் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "அதேவேளை இலங்கையில் இருக்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதிய அதிகாரிகள் குழுவிற்கும் ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பொன்றும் நேற்றைய தினம் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இதன்போது நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நிலைவரம் குறித்தும் பொருளாதார மீட்சியை முன்னிறுத்தி மேற்கொள்ளப்படவேண்டிய மறுசீரமைப்புக்கள் குறித்தும் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெயிட்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபீர் ஹசீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}