{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84388/slpp-requests-president-to-facilitate-gotabayas-safe-return-to-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1660838100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP requests President to facilitate Gotabaya’s safe return to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP requests President to facilitate Gotabaya’s safe return to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "During a discussion this evening, the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) has requested President Ranil Wickremesinghe to facilitate the return of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to Sri Lanka, MP Sanjeeva Edirimanna said.",
        "SLPP parliamentarians had met the President for an official discussion this evening (18) at the President’s Office.",
        "Expressing his views during this, SLPP’s national organizer and former minister Basil Rajapaksa had said that the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna will provide its fullest support to the President to build the country by resolcing the current economic crisis.",
        "In addition, he said that former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa should be allowed to return to the island safely. He stated that this is the foremost request from the SLPP to the government and the President.",
        "MPs Prasanna Ranatunga, Sagara Kariyawasam, Rohitha Abeygunawardena, Johnston Fernando, Pavithra Wanniarachchi, Namal Rajapaksa and Sanjeeva Edirimanna participated in this official discussion on behalf of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeeva Edirimanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Abeygunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnston Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pavithra Wanniarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeeva Edirimanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභයට නිරුපද්‍රිතව ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජනපතිගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද සවස පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නිල සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා අද (18) සවස ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවී ඇත.",
        "එහිදී අදහස් දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික සංවිධායක සහ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ කියා සිටියේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳා රට ගොඩනැගීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ උපරිම සහය ජනාධිපතිතුමාට ලබාදෙන බවයි.",
        "ඊට අමතරව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට නිරුපද්‍රිතව දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට ඉඩ ලබාදිය යුතු බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රජයෙන් සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් කරන ප්‍රමුඛතම ඉල්ලීම මෙය බව ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මෙම නිල සාකච්ඡාවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග, සාගර කාරියවසම්, රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන, ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, පවිත්‍රා වන්නිආරච්චි, නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ සහ සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පවිත්‍රා වන්නිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய பாதுகாப்பாக இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதி செய்து தருமாறு SLPP ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று மாலை இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் போது, ​​முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதியாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்று (18) மாலை ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியை உத்தியோகபூர்வ கலந்துரையாடலொன்றை மேற்கொண்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "இதன் போது கருத்து வெளியிட்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளரும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சருமான பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ, தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை தீர்த்து நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்ப ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தனது பூரண ஆதரவை வழங்கும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அத்துடன், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பாதுகாப்பாக நாடு திரும்ப அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன அரசாங்கத்திடமும் ஜனாதிபதியிடமும் விடுக்கும் முதன்மையான கோரிக்கை இதுவாகும் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எம்.பி.எஸ் பிரசன்னா ரனாதுங்கா, சாகரா கரியவாசம், ரோஹிதா அபேயேகுனவர்தேனா, ஜான்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ, பவித்ரா வன்னியாராச்சி, நமல் ராஜபக்ஷா மற்றும் சஞ்சீவா எடிரிமன்னா ஆகியோர் இந்த அதிகாரப்பூர்வ கலந்துரையாடலில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா போடுஜானா சார்பாக பங்கேற்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவித்ரா வன்னியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}