{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-former-leftist-leader-blames-imf-for-russias-invasion-of-ukraine-96407/",
  "time_ut": 1656060480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka former leftist leader blames IMF for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka former leftist leader blames IMF for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A former Sri Lankan leftist leader has blamed the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for causing Russia’s war on Ukraine.",
        "Former Minister and now independent MP Vasudeva Nanayakkara claimed on Friday June 24 that the IMF represents US interests and it was the organisation’s interventions in Ukraine that led to Russia’s invasion of that country.",
        "“The IMF is the tail of US foreign foreign policy. That is the truth. There is a war in Ukraine today after the IMF intervened there.",
        "“Who pressured them to join NATO? The IMF. That’s why there is a disastrous war there today. That’s the doing of the IMF,” said Nanayakkara speaking to reporters at a press conference.",
        "There is no evidence yet that the IMF had any role to play in the chain of events that led to Russian President Vladimir Putin’s decision to invade Ukraine.",
        "Despite the MP’s misgivings about the IMF’s alleged geopolitical adventurism, he is in favour of the organisation helping Sri Lanka restructure its colossal external debt, which has now bankrupted the island nation and pushed its people to desperation after years of economic mismanagement.",
        "“We can’t pay more debt. We have asked the IMF to restructure existing debt. That’s what the IMF must be requested to do. While the IMF is looking after the debt, we can purchase oil from Russia,” said Nanayakkkara.",
        "However, in November 2021, when he was still with the government of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Nanyakkara was adamant that Sri Lanka will never approach the IMF for assistance.",
        "“We won’t go to the IMF even if we die,” he famously declared in parliament that month.",
        "Much has happened since then and Sri Lanka is now going through the worst forex crisis in its history, with the country struggling to pay for essential imports including fuel, food and medicine. An IMF team is already in the island for preliminary discussions, and according to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, the government aims to reach a staff-level agreement with the organisation and also have a framework in place for debt restructuring by the end of July.",
        "The group of former government MPs that Nanayakkara represents have questioned an apparent reluctance on the part of the Sri Lankan government to reach out to Russia for help. Nanayakkara was present at a discussion the group had with the Russian ambassador to Sri Lanka on Tuesday June 21.",
        "MP Wimal Weerawansa, the de facto leader of the group, told parliament on Wednesday June 22 that Sri Lanka must not overlook “traditional ally” Russia in its efforts to overcome a worsening economic crisis, particularly with regard to ongoing IMF negotiations.",
        "Sri Lanka must not overlook Russia in favour of IMF, says MP Weerawansa",
        "Sri Lanka is in the throes of a fuel crisis triggered by the forex shortages, and Weerawansa, Nanayakkara et al have been pressuring the government to reach out to Russia. Nanayakkara said at Friday’s press conference that Sri Lanka must either negotiate a long term concessionary oil supply from the Middle East or look to Russia.",
        "Weerawansa in his speech in parliament earlier had intimated that the reason Sri Lanka was not talking to Russia was due to pressure from the West. Echoing this, Nanayakkara said: “There is no conflict there [in buying oil from Russia while talking to the IMF]. What is the conflict?  We tel l the IMF to look after our debt, and we buy oil, gas and fertilizer from Russia. There is no conflict there.”",
        "He claimed the real reason was that the IMF was an extension of US foreign policy.",
        "The government has yet to respond to the claims. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ukraine",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NATO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "November 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanyakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "that month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday June 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday June 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara et al",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියාව විසින් යුක්රේනය ආක්‍රමණය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු වාමාංශික නායකයා IMF වෙත චෝදනා කරයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - යුක්රේනයට එරෙහිව රුසියාවේ යුද්ධය ඇති කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාමාංශික නායකයෙකු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට (IMF) දොස් පවරා ඇත.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය සහ දැන් ස්වාධීන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා කියා සිටියේ IMF එක්සත් ජනපද අවශ්‍යතා නියෝජනය කරන බවත් රුසියාව එම රට ආක්‍රමණය කිරීමට හේතු වූයේ එම සංවිධානය යුක්රේනයට කරන ලද මැදිහත්වීම් බවත්ය.",
        "IMF යනු එක්සත් ජනපද විදේශ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ වලිගයයි. ඒක තමයි ඇත්ත. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල මැදිහත් වීමෙන් පසු අද යුක්රේනයේ යුද්ධයක් පවතී.",
        "“නේටෝවට බැඳෙන ලෙස ඔවුන්ට බලපෑම් කළේ කවුද? අයි.එම්.එෆ්. අද එහි විනාශකාරී යුද්ධයක් ඇත්තේ එබැවිනි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය එයයි.",
        "යුක්රේනය ආක්‍රමණය කිරීමට රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්ගේ තීරණයට තුඩු දුන් සිදුවීම් දාමය තුළ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට භූමිකාවක් ඇති බවට තවමත් සාක්ෂි නොමැත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ භූදේශපාලනික වික්‍රමාන්විතභාවය ගැන මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ සැක සංකා තිබියදීත්, ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එහි දැවැන්ත විදේශ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට උදව් කරන සංවිධානයට පක්ෂව සිටී, එය දැන් දිවයිනේ ජාතිය බංකොලොත් කර ඇති අතර වසර ගණනාවක ආර්ථික වැරදි කළමනාකරණයෙන් පසු එහි ජනතාව මංමුලා සහගත තත්ත්වයට තල්ලු කර ඇත.",
        "“අපිට තවත් ණය ගෙවන්න බැහැ. පවතින ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරන ලෙස අපි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබෙනවා. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිය යුත්තේ එයයි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ණය බලාගෙන ඉන්න අතරේ අපිට රුසියාවෙන් තෙල් ගන්න පුළුවන්.” නානායක්කාර පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, 2021 නොවැම්බරයේදී, ඔහු තවමත් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ රජය සමඟ සිටියදී, නාන්යක්කාර දැඩිව සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කිසි විටෙකත් ආධාර සඳහා IMF වෙත නොයන බවයි.",
        "\"අපි මැරුණත් අපි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට යන්නේ නැහැ\" ඔහු එම මාසයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රසිද්ධ ලෙස ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එතැන් සිට බොහෝ දේ සිදුවී ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් එහි ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර, ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ ඇතුළු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට රට අරගල කරයි. මූලික සාකච්ඡා සඳහා IMF කණ්ඩායමක් දැනටමත් දිවයිනට පැමිණ සිටින අතර, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට අනුව, එම සංවිධානය සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීමට රජය අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර ජූලි මස අවසන් වන විට ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ රාමුවක් සකස් කර ඇත.",
        "නානායක්කාර නියෝජනය කරන හිටපු ආණ්ඩුවේ මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම රුසියාවේ පිහිට පැතීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය දක්වන අකමැත්ත ගැන ප්‍රශ්න කර තිබේ. ජූනි 21 අඟහරුවාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුසියානු තානාපතිවරයා සමඟ කණ්ඩායම පැවැත්වූ සාකච්ඡාවකට නානායක්කාර පැමිණ සිටියේය.",
        "කණ්ඩායමේ තත්‍ය නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ ජූනි 22 බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයේදී, විශේෂයෙන්ම IMF සාකච්ඡා සම්බන්ධයෙන්, “සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍ර” රුසියාව නොසලකා හැරිය යුතු නැති බවයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට පක්ෂව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාව නොසලකා හැරිය යුතු බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වීරවංශ පවසයි",
        "විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයක ගිලී සිටින අතර වීරවංශ, නානායක්කාර ඇතුළු පිරිසක් රුසියාවට ළඟා වන ලෙස රජයට බලපෑම් කරමින් සිටිති. නානායක්කාර සිකුරාදා මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මැදපෙරදිගින් දිගුකාලීන සහනදායී තෙල් සැපයීමක් ගැන සාකච්ඡා කළ යුතු බවත් නැතහොත් රුසියාව දෙස බැලිය යුතු බවත්ය.",
        "වීරවංශ මීට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කළ කතාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාව සමඟ කතා නොකරන්නේ බටහිර බලපෑම් නිසා බව දන්වා සිටියේය. මෙය ප්‍රතිරාවය කරමින් නානායක්කාර මෙසේ පැවසීය: “[ජාමූඅ සමඟ කතා කරමින් රුසියාවෙන් තෙල් මිලදී ගැනීමේදී] එහි ගැටුමක් නැත. ගැටුම කුමක්ද? අපි IMF එකට කියනවා අපේ ණය ගැන බලන්න කියලා, අපි රුසියාවෙන් තෙල්, ගෑස් සහ පොහොර ගන්නවා. එතන ගැටුමක් නැහැ.”",
        "සැබෑ හේතුව ලෙස ඔහු කියා සිටියේ IMF යනු එක්සත් ජනපද විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ දිගුවක් බවයි.",
        "එම ඉල්ලීම්වලට රජය තවමත් ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වා නැත. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "යුක්රේනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නේටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanyakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 21 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 22 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නානායක්කාර සහ අල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உக்ரைன் மீதான ரஷ்யாவின் ஆக்கிரமிப்புக்கு IMF மீது இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் இடதுசாரி தலைவர் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளார்",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - உக்ரைன் மீதான ரஷ்யாவின் போருக்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) காரணம் என்று இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் இடதுசாரி தலைவர் ஒருவர் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சரும் இப்போது சுயேச்சையான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார வெள்ளியன்று ஜூன் 24 அன்று சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் அமெரிக்க நலன்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறது என்றும் உக்ரேனில் அந்த அமைப்பின் தலையீடுகளே ரஷ்யாவின் ஆக்கிரமிப்புக்கு வழிவகுத்தது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "“ஐஎம்எஃப் என்பது அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கையின் வால் ஆகும். அது தான் உண்மை. உக்ரைனில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தலையிட்டதை அடுத்து இன்று அங்கு போர் மூண்டுள்ளது.",
        "“நேட்டோவில் சேருமாறு அவர்களுக்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுத்தது யார்? ஐ.எம்.எஃப். அதனால்தான் இன்று அங்கு ஒரு அழிவுகரமான போர் நடந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறது. அதுதான் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் செயலாகும்,” என நாணயக்கார செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினின் உக்ரைனை ஆக்கிரமிப்பதற்கான முடிவிற்கு வழிவகுத்த நிகழ்வுகளின் சங்கிலியில் IMFக்கு எந்தப் பங்கும் இல்லை என்பதற்கு இதுவரை எந்த ஆதாரமும் இல்லை.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கூறப்படும் புவிசார் அரசியல் சாகசத்தைப் பற்றி எம்.பி.யின் சந்தேகங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், அவர் இலங்கையின் மிகப்பெரிய வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை மறுசீரமைக்க உதவும் அமைப்பிற்கு ஆதரவாக இருக்கிறார், இது இப்போது தீவு நாட்டை திவாலாக்கி, பல வருட பொருளாதார தவறான நிர்வாகத்திற்குப் பிறகு அதன் மக்களை விரக்திக்கு தள்ளியுள்ளது.",
        "“எங்களால் அதிக கடனை செலுத்த முடியாது. தற்போதுள்ள கடனை மறுசீரமைக்க சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் கேட்டுள்ளோம். அதைத்தான் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் கோர வேண்டும். சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் கடனைப் பார்த்துக் கொண்டிருக்கும் வேளையில், நாங்கள் ரஷ்யாவிடம் இருந்து எண்ணெய் கொள்வனவு செய்யலாம்” என்று நாணயக்கார கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நவம்பர் 2021 இல், அவர் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்தபோது, ​​இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தை உதவிக்காக ஒருபோதும் அணுகாது என்பதில் நன்யக்கார உறுதியாக இருந்தார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் இறந்தாலும் IMF க்கு செல்ல மாட்டோம்,\" என்று அவர் அந்த மாதம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரபலமாக அறிவித்தார்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் நிறைய நடந்தது மற்றும் இலங்கை இப்போது அதன் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான அந்நிய செலாவணி நெருக்கடியை சந்தித்து வருகிறது, எரிபொருள், உணவு மற்றும் மருந்து உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசிய இறக்குமதிகளுக்கு பணம் செலுத்துவதற்கு நாடு போராடுகிறது. IMF குழுவொன்று பூர்வாங்க கலந்துரையாடல்களுக்காக ஏற்கனவே தீவில் உள்ளது, மேலும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கூற்றுப்படி, அரசாங்கம் நிறுவனத்துடன் பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்பாட்டை எட்டுவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் ஜூலை இறுதிக்குள் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புக்கான ஒரு கட்டமைப்பைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாணயக்கார பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் முன்னாள் அரசாங்க எம்.பி.க்கள் குழு, உதவிக்காக ரஷ்யாவை அணுகுவதில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் வெளிப்படையான தயக்கம் காட்டுவதாக கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளது. ஜூன் 21 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை இலங்கைக்கான ரஷ்ய தூதுவருடன் குழு நடத்திய கலந்துரையாடலில் நாணயக்கார கலந்துகொண்டார்.",
        "குழுவின் உண்மையான தலைவரான எம்.பி விமல் வீரவன்ச, புதன் ஜூன் 22 அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில், \"பாரம்பரிய நட்பு நாடான\" ரஷ்யாவை, மோசமடைந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்கும் முயற்சிகளில், குறிப்பாக நடந்து வரும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் தொடர்பாக, இலங்கையை புறக்கணிக்கக் கூடாது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு ஆதரவாக ரஷ்யாவை இலங்கை புறக்கணிக்கக் கூடாது என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையால் தூண்டப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியில் இலங்கை உள்ளது, மேலும் வீரவன்ச, நாணயக்கார மற்றும் பலர் ரஷ்யாவை அணுகுமாறு அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுத்து வருகின்றனர். வெள்ளியன்று நடந்த செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில், இலங்கை மத்திய கிழக்கிலிருந்து நீண்ட கால சலுகை விலையில் எண்ணெய் வழங்குவது பற்றி பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த வேண்டும் அல்லது ரஷ்யாவை பார்க்க வேண்டும் என்று நாணயக்கார கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை ரஷ்யாவுடன் பேசாமல் இருப்பதற்கு மேற்குலகின் அழுத்தமே காரணம் என வீரவன்ச முன்னதாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் ஆற்றிய உரையில் தெரிவித்திருந்தார். இதை எதிரொலிக்கும் வகையில், நாணயக்கார கூறினார்: “[IMF உடன் பேசும் போது ரஷ்யாவிடம் இருந்து எண்ணெய் வாங்குவதில்] எந்த முரண்பாடும் இல்லை. மோதல் என்றால் என்ன? நாங்கள் எங்கள் கடனைப் பார்க்க சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் கூறுகிறோம், நாங்கள் ரஷ்யாவிலிருந்து எண்ணெய், எரிவாயு மற்றும் உரங்களை வாங்குகிறோம். அங்கு எந்த மோதலும் இல்லை.”",
        "IMF என்பது அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கையின் விரிவாக்கம் என்பதே உண்மையான காரணம் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கோரிக்கைகளுக்கு அரசாங்கம் இன்னும் பதிலளிக்கவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "உக்ரைன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanyakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 21 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 22 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாணயக்கார மற்றும் பலர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka former leftist leader blames IMF for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – A former Sri Lankan leftist leader has blamed the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for causing Russia’s war on Ukraine.",
    "Former Minister and now independent MP Vasudeva Nanayakkara claimed on Friday June 24 that the IMF represents US interests and it was the organisation’s interventions in Ukraine that led to Russia’s invasion of that country.",
    "“The IMF is the tail of US foreign foreign policy. That is the truth. There is a war in Ukraine today after the IMF intervened there.",
    "“Who pressured them to join NATO? The IMF. That’s why there is a disastrous war there today. That’s the doing of the IMF,” said Nanayakkara speaking to reporters at a press conference.",
    "There is no evidence yet that the IMF had any role to play in the chain of events that led to Russian President Vladimir Putin’s decision to invade Ukraine.",
    "Despite the MP’s misgivings about the IMF’s alleged geopolitical adventurism, he is in favour of the organisation helping Sri Lanka restructure its colossal external debt, which has now bankrupted the island nation and pushed its people to desperation after years of economic mismanagement.",
    "“We can’t pay more debt. We have asked the IMF to restructure existing debt. That’s what the IMF must be requested to do. While the IMF is looking after the debt, we can purchase oil from Russia,” said Nanayakkkara.",
    "However, in November 2021, when he was still with the government of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Nanyakkara was adamant that Sri Lanka will never approach the IMF for assistance.",
    "“We won’t go to the IMF even if we die,” he famously declared in parliament that month.",
    "Much has happened since then and Sri Lanka is now going through the worst forex crisis in its history, with the country struggling to pay for essential imports including fuel, food and medicine. An IMF team is already in the island for preliminary discussions, and according to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, the government aims to reach a staff-level agreement with the organisation and also have a framework in place for debt restructuring by the end of July.",
    "The group of former government MPs that Nanayakkara represents have questioned an apparent reluctance on the part of the Sri Lankan government to reach out to Russia for help. Nanayakkara was present at a discussion the group had with the Russian ambassador to Sri Lanka on Tuesday June 21.",
    "MP Wimal Weerawansa, the de facto leader of the group, told parliament on Wednesday June 22 that Sri Lanka must not overlook “traditional ally” Russia in its efforts to overcome a worsening economic crisis, particularly with regard to ongoing IMF negotiations.",
    "Sri Lanka must not overlook Russia in favour of IMF, says MP Weerawansa",
    "Sri Lanka is in the throes of a fuel crisis triggered by the forex shortages, and Weerawansa, Nanayakkara et al have been pressuring the government to reach out to Russia. Nanayakkara said at Friday’s press conference that Sri Lanka must either negotiate a long term concessionary oil supply from the Middle East or look to Russia.",
    "Weerawansa in his speech in parliament earlier had intimated that the reason Sri Lanka was not talking to Russia was due to pressure from the West. Echoing this, Nanayakkara said: “There is no conflict there [in buying oil from Russia while talking to the IMF]. What is the conflict?  We tel l the IMF to look after our debt, and we buy oil, gas and fertilizer from Russia. There is no conflict there.”",
    "He claimed the real reason was that the IMF was an extension of US foreign policy.",
    "The government has yet to respond to the claims. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka former leftist leader blames IMF for Russia’s invasion of Ukraine",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A former Sri Lankan leftist leader has blamed the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for causing Russia’s war on Ukraine.",
        "Former Minister and now independent MP Vasudeva Nanayakkara claimed on Friday June 24 that the IMF represents US interests and it was the organisation’s interventions in Ukraine that led to Russia’s invasion of that country.",
        "“The IMF is the tail of US foreign foreign policy. That is the truth. There is a war in Ukraine today after the IMF intervened there.",
        "“Who pressured them to join NATO? The IMF. That’s why there is a disastrous war there today. That’s the doing of the IMF,” said Nanayakkara speaking to reporters at a press conference.",
        "There is no evidence yet that the IMF had any role to play in the chain of events that led to Russian President Vladimir Putin’s decision to invade Ukraine.",
        "Despite the MP’s misgivings about the IMF’s alleged geopolitical adventurism, he is in favour of the organisation helping Sri Lanka restructure its colossal external debt, which has now bankrupted the island nation and pushed its people to desperation after years of economic mismanagement.",
        "“We can’t pay more debt. We have asked the IMF to restructure existing debt. That’s what the IMF must be requested to do. While the IMF is looking after the debt, we can purchase oil from Russia,” said Nanayakkkara.",
        "However, in November 2021, when he was still with the government of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Nanyakkara was adamant that Sri Lanka will never approach the IMF for assistance.",
        "“We won’t go to the IMF even if we die,” he famously declared in parliament that month.",
        "Much has happened since then and Sri Lanka is now going through the worst forex crisis in its history, with the country struggling to pay for essential imports including fuel, food and medicine. An IMF team is already in the island for preliminary discussions, and according to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, the government aims to reach a staff-level agreement with the organisation and also have a framework in place for debt restructuring by the end of July.",
        "The group of former government MPs that Nanayakkara represents have questioned an apparent reluctance on the part of the Sri Lankan government to reach out to Russia for help. Nanayakkara was present at a discussion the group had with the Russian ambassador to Sri Lanka on Tuesday June 21.",
        "MP Wimal Weerawansa, the de facto leader of the group, told parliament on Wednesday June 22 that Sri Lanka must not overlook “traditional ally” Russia in its efforts to overcome a worsening economic crisis, particularly with regard to ongoing IMF negotiations.",
        "Sri Lanka must not overlook Russia in favour of IMF, says MP Weerawansa",
        "Sri Lanka is in the throes of a fuel crisis triggered by the forex shortages, and Weerawansa, Nanayakkara et al have been pressuring the government to reach out to Russia. Nanayakkara said at Friday’s press conference that Sri Lanka must either negotiate a long term concessionary oil supply from the Middle East or look to Russia.",
        "Weerawansa in his speech in parliament earlier had intimated that the reason Sri Lanka was not talking to Russia was due to pressure from the West. Echoing this, Nanayakkara said: “There is no conflict there [in buying oil from Russia while talking to the IMF]. What is the conflict?  We tel l the IMF to look after our debt, and we buy oil, gas and fertilizer from Russia. There is no conflict there.”",
        "He claimed the real reason was that the IMF was an extension of US foreign policy.",
        "The government has yet to respond to the claims. (Colombo/Jun24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ukraine",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NATO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "November 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanyakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "that month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday June 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday June 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara et al",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියාව විසින් යුක්රේනය ආක්‍රමණය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු වාමාංශික නායකයා IMF වෙත චෝදනා කරයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - යුක්රේනයට එරෙහිව රුසියාවේ යුද්ධය ඇති කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාමාංශික නායකයෙකු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට (IMF) දොස් පවරා ඇත.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය සහ දැන් ස්වාධීන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා කියා සිටියේ IMF එක්සත් ජනපද අවශ්‍යතා නියෝජනය කරන බවත් රුසියාව එම රට ආක්‍රමණය කිරීමට හේතු වූයේ එම සංවිධානය යුක්රේනයට කරන ලද මැදිහත්වීම් බවත්ය.",
        "IMF යනු එක්සත් ජනපද විදේශ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ වලිගයයි. ඒක තමයි ඇත්ත. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල මැදිහත් වීමෙන් පසු අද යුක්රේනයේ යුද්ධයක් පවතී.",
        "“නේටෝවට බැඳෙන ලෙස ඔවුන්ට බලපෑම් කළේ කවුද? අයි.එම්.එෆ්. අද එහි විනාශකාරී යුද්ධයක් ඇත්තේ එබැවිනි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය එයයි.",
        "යුක්රේනය ආක්‍රමණය කිරීමට රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්ගේ තීරණයට තුඩු දුන් සිදුවීම් දාමය තුළ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට භූමිකාවක් ඇති බවට තවමත් සාක්ෂි නොමැත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ භූදේශපාලනික වික්‍රමාන්විතභාවය ගැන මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ සැක සංකා තිබියදීත්, ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එහි දැවැන්ත විදේශ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට උදව් කරන සංවිධානයට පක්ෂව සිටී, එය දැන් දිවයිනේ ජාතිය බංකොලොත් කර ඇති අතර වසර ගණනාවක ආර්ථික වැරදි කළමනාකරණයෙන් පසු එහි ජනතාව මංමුලා සහගත තත්ත්වයට තල්ලු කර ඇත.",
        "“අපිට තවත් ණය ගෙවන්න බැහැ. පවතින ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරන ලෙස අපි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබෙනවා. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිය යුත්තේ එයයි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ණය බලාගෙන ඉන්න අතරේ අපිට රුසියාවෙන් තෙල් ගන්න පුළුවන්.” නානායක්කාර පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, 2021 නොවැම්බරයේදී, ඔහු තවමත් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ රජය සමඟ සිටියදී, නාන්යක්කාර දැඩිව සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කිසි විටෙකත් ආධාර සඳහා IMF වෙත නොයන බවයි.",
        "\"අපි මැරුණත් අපි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට යන්නේ නැහැ\" ඔහු එම මාසයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රසිද්ධ ලෙස ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එතැන් සිට බොහෝ දේ සිදුවී ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් එහි ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර, ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ ඇතුළු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට රට අරගල කරයි. මූලික සාකච්ඡා සඳහා IMF කණ්ඩායමක් දැනටමත් දිවයිනට පැමිණ සිටින අතර, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට අනුව, එම සංවිධානය සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීමට රජය අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර ජූලි මස අවසන් වන විට ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ රාමුවක් සකස් කර ඇත.",
        "නානායක්කාර නියෝජනය කරන හිටපු ආණ්ඩුවේ මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම රුසියාවේ පිහිට පැතීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය දක්වන අකමැත්ත ගැන ප්‍රශ්න කර තිබේ. ජූනි 21 අඟහරුවාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුසියානු තානාපතිවරයා සමඟ කණ්ඩායම පැවැත්වූ සාකච්ඡාවකට නානායක්කාර පැමිණ සිටියේය.",
