{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/22කට-එරෙහිව-පෙත්සම්-නවයක්/1-618334",
  "time_ut": 1660815441,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "22කට එරෙහිව පෙත්සම් නවයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Nine petitions against 22",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "9 petitions have been filed before the Supreme Court today (18) stating that certain clauses of the 22nd Constitutional Amendment Bill are contrary to the Constitution and requesting an order to pass it by a special number of MPs and a referendum, including Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara.",
        "These petitions have been filed before the Supreme Court by 9 people, including Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara, General Secretary of Praideh Peramuna, lawyer Nagananda Kodithuvakku, and lawyer Nuvan Bellantudawe.",
        "The petitioners have pointed out in their petition that the Twenty-second Constitution Amendment Bill has been included in the parliamentary agenda on the 10th and some of its clauses are against the Constitution.",
        "Therefore, the petitioners request in their petitions to issue an order to pass this subject to the approval of a special majority group of members of Parliament and through a referendum."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nine",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Amendment Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Praideh Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodithuvakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuvan Bellantudawe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution Amendment Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22කට එරෙහිව පෙත්සම් නවයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "22වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ ඇතැම් වගන්ති ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට පටහැනි බව සඳහන් කරමින් එය විශේෂ මන්ත්‍රී සංඛ්‍යාවකගේ සහ ජනමත විචාරයකින් සම්මත කර ගැනීමේ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලා වෛද්‍ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර මහතා ඇතුළු නවදෙනකු ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ අද (18) පෙත්සම් 9ක් ගොනු කරනු ලැබ ඇත.",
        "වෛද්‍ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර, විනිවිද පෙරමුණේ මහ ලේකම් නීතීඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු, නීතීඥ නුවන් බෙල්ලන්තුඩාවේ යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු 9 දෙනකු මෙම පෙත්සම් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ ගොනු කරනු ලැබ තිබේ.",
        "විසිදෙවැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත ඉකුත් 10 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තු න්‍යාය පුස්තකයට ඇතුළත් කරනු ලැබ ඇති බවත් මෙහි ඇතැම් වගන්ති ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට පටහැනි බවත් පෙත්සම් කරුවෝ සිය පෙත්සම් පෙත්සමෙන් පෙන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් මෙය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විශේෂ බහුතර මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායමකගේ අනුමැතියට යටත්ව සහ ජනමත විචාරයකින් සම්මත කර ගැනීමට නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන්නැයි පෙත්සම් කරුවෝ සිය පෙතකරුවෝ සිය පෙත්සම් වලින් ඉල්ලා සිටිති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නවය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයිඩ් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවන් බෙල්ලන්තුඩාවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22க்கு எதிராக ஒன்பது மனுக்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "22ஆவது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்தின் சில சரத்துக்கள் அரசியலமைப்புக்கு முரணானவை எனவும், அதனை விசேட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறு உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்குமாறும் 9 மனுக்கள் இன்று (18) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பிரைதே பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் கலாநிதி குணதாச அமரசேகர, சட்டத்தரணி நாகாநந்த கொடித்துவக்கு, சட்டத்தரணி நுவன் பெல்லந்துடாவே உள்ளிட்ட 9 பேரினால் இந்த மனுக்கள் உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் கடந்த 10ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்ற நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலில் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், அதில் உள்ள சில சரத்துக்கள் அரசியலமைப்புக்கு முரணானது எனவும் மனுதாரர்கள் தமது மனுவில் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே, விசேட பெரும்பான்மை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு உட்பட்டு வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் இதனை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கான உத்தரவை பிறப்பிக்குமாறு மனுதாரர்கள் தமது மனுக்களில் கோரியுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்பது",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்த மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரைதே பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகானந்த கொடித்துவக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவன் பெல்லந்துடாவே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்த மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}