{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/හිරුණිකා-සී-අයි-ඩියට/101-618449",
  "time_ut": 1660989217,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හිරුණිකා සී.අයි.ඩියට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika to C.I.D",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mrs. Hirunika Premachandra has come to the Criminal Investigation Department today (20) to give a statement.",
        "According to a notice given by the Criminal Investigation Department to Mrs. Premachandra yesterday afternoon, she came to the Criminal Investigation Department this morning to give this statement.",
        "Before giving the statement, in response to a question raised by the media as to why the summons was made today, he stated that there is no mention of it in the letter he was summoned to and that he thinks it may be related to the struggle and that Ranil Rajapakse, who came to power with the help of the struggle, is the worst president ever born."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "C.I.D",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිරුණිකා සී.අයි.ඩියට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබාදීම සඳහා හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට අද (20 ) පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මියට ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ කළ දැණුම් දීමකට අනුව මෙම ප්‍රකාශය ලබාදීම සඳහා අද පෙරවරුවේ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පැමිණ ඇත.",
        "ප්‍රකාශය ලබාදීමට යාමට  පෙර අද දින කැඳවීම සිදුකර ඇත්තේ කවර කාරනයකටදැයි මාද්‍යය නැගූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිලිතුරු දෙමින් තමාට කැඳවීම ලද ලිපියේ ඒ පිලිබඳව කිසිදු සඳහනක් නොමැති බවත් තමා සිතන ආකාරයට  අරගලය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වියහැකි බවත් අරගලයේ පිහිටෙන් බලයට පැමිණි රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ මෙතෙක් බිහිවූ දරුණුතම ජනාධිපති වරයා බවත්  ප්‍රකාශ කලේය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සී.අයි.ඩී",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஹிருனிகா சி.ஐ.டி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வாக்குமூலம் வழங்குவதற்காக திருமதி ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர இன்று (20) குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்திற்கு வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தினால் நேற்று பிற்பகல் திருமதி பிரேமச்சந்திரவிற்கு வழங்கிய அறிவித்தலின் பிரகாரம், அவர் இன்று காலை குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்திற்கு இந்த வாக்குமூலத்தை வழங்குவதற்காக வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அறிக்கையை வழங்குவதற்கு முன்னர், இன்று ஏன் அழைப்பாணை விடுக்கப்பட்டது என ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கையில், தாம் வரவழைக்கப்பட்ட கடிதத்தில் அதுகுறித்து எதுவும் குறிப்பிடப்படவில்லை எனவும், அது போராட்டத்துடன் தொடர்புடையதாக இருக்கலாம் என தாம் கருதுவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். போராட்டத்தின் உதவியுடன் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த ரணில் ராஜபக்ஷ இதுவரை பிறந்ததில் மிக மோசமான ஜனாதிபதி என்றும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}