{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sri-Lanka-receives-5000-MT-rice-donation-from-China/56-736868",
  "time_ut": 1656532430,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka receives 5000 MT rice donation from China",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka receives 5000 MT rice donation from China",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The first consignment of 5,000 metric tons of rice out of 10,000 tons committed by China reached Sri Lanka on Tuesday.",
        "The consignment was officially handed over to the current Transport, Highways and Mass Media Minister and the Education Acting Minister Dr. Bandula Gunawardena, by the Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Qi Zhenhong.",
        "During a discussion held between the Chinese Government and the Chinese Embassy in Sri Lanka and the then Trade Minister Dr. Bandula Gunawardena on 8 January this year to mark the 70th anniversary of the China-Sri Lanka Rubber-Rice Agreement, the Chinese Government has announced a donation of 10,000 metric tons of rice to Sri Lanka.",
        "Minister Dr. Bandula Gunawardena appreciated the assistance provided by the Chinese Government to Sri Lanka in the face of the economic crisis.",
        "He also said that the understanding between the two countries would be further enhanced by the past cooperation and sincere friendship between the two countries.",
        "The Minister said that this stock of rice will be used for the program to provide food to school children and accordingly, by sending children to schools, the need for education as well as the need for nutrition will be met.",
        "Ambassador Qi Zhenhong said China would extend its fullest support to Sri Lanka in the current crisis situation.",
        "Ambassador stated that the vulnerable population, especially children from low-income families suffer the most in the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka and further support will be given to meet the nutritional needs of school children.",
        "He said China supports the School Meal Program of Sri Lanka to provide daily nutritious meals to 1.1 million children in 7,900 schools across Sri Lanka. China will try all-out efforts to sustain the Sri Lanka School Meal Program for at least six months, he added.",
        "The Ambassador further stated that another two shipments of rice donations will arrive respectively in the next week and the following week while more are in the pipeline.",
        "He said that the Chinese Government was honoured to make such a donation at an urgent time and in addition to the stock of rice being handed over, measures have been taken already to bring the remaining 5,000 metric tons of rice to Sri Lanka expeditiously.",
        "In addition, the Chinese Embassy is discussing with Sri Lanka Ministry of Education to provide school uniform for students across the island in the new school year, the Chinese Ambassador Qi Zhenhong announced at the hand-over ceremony."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "MT",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Transport, Highways and Mass Media",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 January this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the China-Sri Lanka Rubber-Rice Agreement",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the School Meal Program of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,900",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka School Meal Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the following week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the remaining 5,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the new school year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000ක් ලැබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනය විසින් ලබාදුන් සහල් ටොන් 10,000න් පළමු සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000ක තොගය අඟහරුවාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong මහතා විසින් මෙම තොගය වත්මන් ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග හා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සහ අධ්‍යාපන වැඩබලන අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා වෙත නිල වශයෙන් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා රබර්-සහල් ගිවිසුමට වසර 70ක් පිරීම නිමිත්තෙන් චීන රජය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය සහ එවකට වෙළෙඳ ඇමැති ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අතර මේ වසරේ ජනවාරි 8 වැනිදා පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවකදී චීන රජය නිවේදනය කර ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 10,000 ක පරිත්‍යාගයක්.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ චීන රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදෙන සහය අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අගය කළේය.",
        "දෙරට අතර පවතින අතීත සහයෝගීතාවය සහ අවංක මිත්‍රත්වය තුළින් දෙරට අතර අවබෝධය තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය වනු ඇති බව ද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පාසල් සිසුන්ට ආහාර ලබාදීමේ වැඩසටහන සඳහා මෙම සහල් තොගය යොදා ගන්නා බවත් ඒ අනුව දරුවන් පාසල් වෙත යැවීමෙන් අධ්‍යාපනයේ අවශ්‍යතාවය මෙන්ම පෝෂණයේ අවශ්‍යතාවයද සපුරාලන බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "වත්මන් අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය තුළ චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බව තානාපති Qi Zhenhong පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ජනගහනය, විශේෂයෙන්ම අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී පවුල්වල දරුවන් වැඩිපුරම පීඩාවට පත්වන බවත්, පාසල් දරුවන්ගේ පෝෂණ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා තවදුරටත් සහාය ලබාදෙන බවත් තානාපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා පාසල් 7,900 ක ළමුන් මිලියන 1.1 කට දිනපතා පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර සැපයීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහනට චීනය සහාය දක්වන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන අවම වශයෙන් මාස හයක්වත් පවත්වාගෙන යාමට චීනය උපරිම උත්සාහයක් ගන්නා බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "තවත් සහල් පරිත්‍යාග තොගයක් පිළිවෙළින් ඉදිරි සතියේදී සහ ඉදිරි සතියේදී පැමිණෙන අතර තවත් සහල් තොග ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට නියමිත බව තානාපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "කඩිනමින් මෙවැනි පරිත්‍යාගයක් කිරීමට චීන රජයට ගෞරවයක් හිමිවන බවත් භාරදෙන සහල් තොගයට අමතරව ඉතිරි සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000 කඩිනමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට දැනටමත් කටයුතු කර ඇති බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මීට අමතරව, නව පාසල් වර්ෂයේදී දිවයින පුරා සිටින සිසුන් සඳහා පාසල් නිල ඇඳුම් ලබාදීම සඳහා චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බව චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong මහතා ප්‍රදානය කිරීමේ උත්සවයේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එම්.ටී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 10,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග සහ ජන මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ජනවාරි 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා රබර්-සහල් ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 10,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,900 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතිරි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව පාසල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனாவிடம் இருந்து 5000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசியை இலங்கை பெறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 10,000 தொன் அரிசியில் 5,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் அரிசியின் முதலாவது சரக்கு செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை இலங்கையை வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong அவர்களினால் தற்போதைய போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சரும், கல்வி பதில் அமைச்சருமான கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தனவிடம் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக இந்தச் சரக்கு கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சீன அரசுக்கும் இலங்கையில் உள்ள சீனத் தூதரகத்துக்கும் அப்போதைய வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தனவுக்கும் இடையில் இந்த ஆண்டு ஜனவரி 8ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற சீன-இலங்கை இறப்பர்-அரிசி ஒப்பந்தத்தின் 70ஆவது ஆண்டு நிறைவை முன்னிட்டு நடைபெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் போது, ​​சீன அரசாங்கம் அறிவித்துள்ளது. இலங்கைக்கு 10,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் அரிசி நன்கொடை.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்து சீன அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய உதவிகளை அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன பாராட்டினார்.",
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான கடந்தகால ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் நேர்மையான நட்புறவின் மூலம் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான புரிந்துணர்வு மேலும் மேம்படுத்தப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த அரிசி இருப்பு பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு உணவு வழங்கும் வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படும் எனவும், அதற்கமைவாக குழந்தைகளை பாடசாலைகளுக்கு அனுப்புவதன் மூலம் கல்வி மற்றும் போசாக்கு தேவையும் பூர்த்தி செய்யப்படும் எனவும் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு சீனா தனது பூரண ஆதரவை வழங்கும் என தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மக்கள் குறிப்பாக குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் குடும்பங்களைச் சேர்ந்த பிள்ளைகள் அதிகம் பாதிக்கப்படுவதாகவும், பாடசாலை மாணவர்களின் போசாக்கு தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்வதற்கு மேலதிக உதவிகள் வழங்கப்படும் எனவும் தூதுவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை முழுவதிலும் உள்ள 7,900 பாடசாலைகளில் 1.1 மில்லியன் சிறார்களுக்கு தினசரி போஷாக்கான உணவை வழங்குவதற்கு இலங்கையின் பாடசாலை உணவுத் திட்டத்திற்கு சீனா ஆதரவளிப்பதாக அவர் கூறினார். இலங்கை பாடசாலை உணவுத் திட்டத்தை குறைந்தது ஆறு மாதங்களுக்கு நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கு சீனா அனைத்து முயற்சிகளையும் மேற்கொள்ளும் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்னும் இரண்டு அரிசி நன்கொடைகள் முறையே அடுத்த வாரத்திலும் அடுத்த வாரத்திலும் வந்து சேரும் என்றும், மேலும் பல பொருட்கள் தயாராக உள்ளதாகவும் தூதுவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சீன அரசாங்கம் அவசர காலத்தில் இவ்வாறான நன்கொடையை வழங்கியமைக்கு பெருமை சேர்ப்பதாகவும், கையளிக்கப்பட்ட அரிசிக்கு மேலதிகமாக எஞ்சிய 5,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் அரிசியை விரைவாக இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வருவதற்கு ஏற்கனவே நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், புதிய கல்வியாண்டில் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உள்ள மாணவர்களுக்கு பாடசாலை சீருடை வழங்குவதற்கு சீன தூதரகம் இலங்கை கல்வி அமைச்சுடன் கலந்துரையாடி வருவதாக சீன தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong கையளிப்பு விழாவில் அறிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எம்டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடகங்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜனவரி 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா-இலங்கை ரப்பர்-அரிசி ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பள்ளி உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,900",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பள்ளி உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீதமுள்ள 5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதிய பள்ளி ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}