{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Tourist-arrivals-stage-slight-recovery-in-June-thanks-to-Aussie-cricket-fans/273-240371",
  "time_ut": 1656994682,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tourist arrivals stage slight recovery in June thanks to Aussie cricket fans",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tourist arrivals stage slight recovery in June thanks to Aussie cricket fans",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "India tops as largest source market, followed by UK and Australia",
        "Tourist arrivals to Sri Lanka for the month of June totalled 32,856, recording a marginal increase when compared with the previous month.",
        "When compared with the arrival figure of 30,207 recorded in May, which is the lowest number since the impressive kick-start in January, the June arrivals indicate a slight improvement in destination Sri Lanka, despite the ongoing crisis.",
        "The data shared by the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) showed that the improvement in arrivals was due to the increased arrivals from Australia.",
        "The Sri Lanka versus Australia T20 and ODI cricket match series was held in the island nation last month, while the test match series is currently underway.",
        "India emerged as the largest tourist traffic generator for Sri Lanka in June with 6,650 arrivals from that country. The United Kingdom, with 3,199, emerged as the second largest source market. The hype created by the ongoing cricket match pulled Australia up to the third position, accounting to 2,448 tourist arrivals.",
        "The average daily arrivals for the month of June stood at 1,095. Since the beginning of the year, until the economic crisis spiralled out of control in the month of April, the island nation’s daily tourist arrivals were in the ranges of 2500 to 3000.",
        "In the month of March, which saw the highest number of arrivals (106,500) since the outbreak of the pandemic, the daily average arrival was 3,435.",
        "The cumulative analysis of the data shared by the SLTDA showed that the tourist arrivals for the first six months of the year ending in June crossed the 400,000 mark.",
        "In the January 01 to June 30, 2022 period, a total of 411,377 tourists have visited the country.",
        "Here again, India topped the list as the largest source market, bringing in 69,103 visitors. The UK ranked second, accounting for 49,996 tourists and the Russian Federation ranked as the third largest source market, accounting for 46,496 of the total tourists for the year so far.",
        "Sri Lanka aims to lure in 800,000 tourists by the end of 2022 and to generate an income of about US $ 800 million.",
        "Initially, the Tourism Ministry announced its plans to attract 2.3 million tourists and generate an income of about US $ 4.5 billion.",
        "Based on the revised tourist arrival target, Sri Lanka has realised 51 percent of its target for the year 2022."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "June",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aussie",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,207",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,650",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,448",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,095",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the beginning of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the month of March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,435",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first six months of the year ending in June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the January 01 to June 30, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411,377",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69,103",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49,996",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Russian Federation",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,496",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US $ 800 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tourism Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US $ 4.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ක්‍රිකට් ලෝලීන්ට ස්තුතිවන්ත වන්නට ජුනි මාසයේදී සංචාරක පැමිණීම් සුළු වශයෙන් යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාව විශාලතම ප්‍රභව වෙළඳපොල ලෙස ඉහළින්ම සිටින අතර පසුව එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව",
        "ජුනි මාසය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව 32,856 ක් වූ අතර එය පෙර මාසය හා සැසඳීමේ දී සුළු වර්ධනයක් වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "මැයි මාසයේ වාර්තා වූ 30,207 පැමිණීමේ සංඛ්‍යාව සමඟ සසඳන විට, එය ජනවාරි මාසයේ ආකර්ෂණීය ආරම්භයෙන් පසු අඩුම සංඛ්‍යාව වන අතර, පවතින අර්බුද මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, ජුනි මාසයේ පැමිණීම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගමනාන්තයේ සුළු දියුණුවක් පෙන්නුම් කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය (SLTDA) විසින් බෙදාගත් දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙන්නේ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ සිට පැමිණීමේ වැඩිවීම නිසා පැමිණීමේ වර්ධනයට හේතු වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව අතර T20 සහ ODI ක්‍රිකට් තරඟාවලිය පසුගිය මාසයේදී දිවයිනේ දී පැවැත්වුණු අතර ටෙස්ට් තරඟාවලිය මේ වන විට පැවැත්වෙමින් තිබේ.",
        "ජුනි මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා විශාලතම සංචාරක ගමනාගමන උත්පාදක යන්ත්රය බවට ඉන්දියාව පත්ව ඇති අතර එම රටෙන් 6,650 ක් පැමිණ ඇත. එක්සත් රාජධානිය, 3,199 සමඟ, දෙවන විශාලතම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපොළ ලෙස මතු විය. දැනට පැවැත්වෙන ක්‍රිකට් තරගය විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද ප්‍රබෝධය හේතුවෙන් සංචාරක පැමිණීම් 2,448 ක් වාර්තා කරමින් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව තෙවැනි ස්ථානය දක්වා ඉහළ නැංවීය.",
        "ජුනි මාසය සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය දෛනික පැමිණීම් 1,095 ක් විය. වසරේ ආරම්භයේ සිට, අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පාලනයෙන් තොර වූ තෙක්, දිවයිනේ දෛනික සංචාරක පැමිණීම් 2500 සිට 3000 දක්වා පරාසයක පැවතුනි.",
        "වසංගතය පැතිරීමෙන් පසු වැඩිම පැමිණීම් සංඛ්‍යාවක් (106,500) දුටු මාර්තු මාසයේදී, දෛනික සාමාන්‍ය පැමිණීම 3,435 කි.",
        "SLTDA විසින් බෙදාගත් දත්ත සමුච්චිත විශ්ලේෂණයෙන් පෙන්නුම් කළේ ජුනි මාසයෙන් අවසන් වන වසරේ පළමු මාස ​​හය සඳහා සංචාරක පැමිණීම් 400,000 සීමාව ඉක්මවා ඇති බවයි.",
        "2022 ජනවාරි 01 සිට ජූනි 30 දක්වා කාලය තුළ සංචාරකයින් 411,377ක් මෙරටට පැමිණ ඇත.",
        "මෙහිදී නැවතත්, ඉන්දියාව විශාලතම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපොළ ලෙස ලැයිස්තුවේ ඉහළින්ම සිටින අතර, අමුත්තන් 69,103ක් පැමිණ ඇත. සංචාරකයින් 49,996 ක් සඳහා එක්සත් රාජධානිය දෙවන ස්ථානයට පත්ව ඇති අතර රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව තුන්වන විශාලතම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපොළ ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇත, මේ දක්වා වසර සඳහා මුළු සංචාරකයින්ගෙන් 46,496 ක්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2022 වසර අවසන් වන විට සංචාරකයින් 800,000ක් ගෙන්වා ගැනීමටත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 800ක පමණ ආදායමක් උපයා ගැනීමටත් අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "මුලදී, සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය සංචාරකයින් මිලියන 2.3 ක් ආකර්ශනය කර ගැනීමටත් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.5 ක පමණ ආදායමක් උපයා ගැනීමටත් සිය සැලසුම් නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "සංශෝධිත සංචාරක පැමිණීමේ ඉලක්කය මත පදනම්ව, 2022 වසර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ඉලක්කයෙන් සියයට 51 ක් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඔසී",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,207 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,650 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,448 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,095 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරේ ආරම්භය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,435 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මාසයෙන් අවසන් වන වසරේ මුල් මාස හය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි 01 සිට ජූනි 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411,377 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69,103 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49,996 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,496 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 800ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.5 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 51 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆஸி. கிரிக்கெட் ரசிகர்களுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை சற்று சீரானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியா மிகப்பெரிய மூல சந்தையாக முதலிடத்தில் உள்ளது, அதைத் தொடர்ந்து இங்கிலாந்து மற்றும் ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் இலங்கைக்கான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை மொத்தம் 32,856 ஆக இருந்தது, முந்தைய மாதத்துடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது இது ஒரு சிறிய அதிகரிப்பை பதிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "மே மாதத்தில் பதிவான 30,207 வருகையின் எண்ணிக்கையுடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது, ​​இது ஜனவரியில் ஈர்க்கக்கூடிய கிக்-ஆரம்பத்திற்குப் பிறகு மிகக் குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையாகும், ஜூன் மாத வருகையானது, தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியிலும் இலக்கான இலங்கையில் சிறிது முன்னேற்றத்தைக் குறிக்கிறது.",
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபை (SLTDA) பகிர்ந்துள்ள தரவுகள், அவுஸ்திரேலியாவில் இருந்து வருகை தந்தவர்களின் வருகை அதிகரிப்பதன் காரணமாகவே வருகையில் முன்னேற்றம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகக் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை மற்றும் ஆஸ்திரேலியா இடையேயான டி20 மற்றும் ஒருநாள் கிரிக்கெட் போட்டித் தொடர் கடந்த மாதம் தீவு நாட்டில் நடைபெற்றது, அதே நேரத்தில் டெஸ்ட் போட்டி தொடர் தற்போது நடைபெற்று வருகிறது.",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு 6,650 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வருகை தந்ததன் மூலம், இலங்கைக்கான மிகப்பெரிய சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்து உற்பத்தியாளராக இந்தியா உருவெடுத்துள்ளது. யுனைடெட் கிங்டம், 3,199 உடன், இரண்டாவது பெரிய மூல சந்தையாக உருவெடுத்தது. நடப்பு கிரிக்கெட் போட்டியால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட பரபரப்பு ஆஸ்திரேலியாவை 2,448 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகையுடன் மூன்றாவது இடத்திற்கு இழுத்தது.",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்திற்கான சராசரி தினசரி வருகை 1,095 ஆக இருந்தது. ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து, ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி கட்டுப்பாட்டை மீறும் வரை, தீவு நாட்டின் தினசரி சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை 2500 முதல் 3000 வரை இருந்தது.",
        "தொற்றுநோய் வெடித்ததில் இருந்து அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான வருகைகளை (106,500) கண்ட மார்ச் மாதத்தில், தினசரி சராசரி வருகை 3,435 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "SLTDA ஆல் பகிரப்பட்ட தரவுகளின் ஒட்டுமொத்த பகுப்பாய்வு, ஜூன் மாதத்துடன் முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டின் முதல் ஆறு மாதங்களில் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை 400,000 ஐத் தாண்டியுள்ளது என்பதைக் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "ஜனவரி 01 முதல் ஜூன் 30, 2022 வரையிலான காலகட்டத்தில், மொத்தம் 411,377 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் நாட்டிற்கு வருகை தந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இங்கு மீண்டும், இந்தியா 69,103 பார்வையாளர்களைக் கொண்டு, மிகப்பெரிய மூல சந்தையாக பட்டியலில் முதலிடத்தைப் பிடித்தது. 49,996 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளைக் கொண்டு இங்கிலாந்து இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது மற்றும் ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு மூன்றாவது பெரிய மூலச் சந்தையாகத் தரவரிசையில் உள்ளது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதிக்குள் 800,000 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை ஈர்த்து சுமார் 800 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் வருமானத்தை ஈட்டுவதை இலங்கை இலக்காகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஆரம்பத்தில், சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகம் 2.3 மில்லியன் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை ஈர்த்து, சுமார் 4.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் வருமானத்தை ஈட்டுவதற்கான திட்டங்களை அறிவித்தது.",
        "திருத்தப்பட்ட சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை இலக்கின் அடிப்படையில், 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான தனது இலக்கில் 51 சதவீதத்தை இலங்கை அடைந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆஸி",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,207",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,650",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,199",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,448",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,095",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் ஆரம்பம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,435",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மாதம் முடிவடையும் ஆண்டின் முதல் ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "400,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 01 முதல் ஜூன் 30, 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411,377",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69,103",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49,996",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46,496",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 800 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 4.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}