{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/24/sri-lanka-party-leader-arrested-for-harboring-murder-suspects/",
  "time_ut": 1661323740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Party leader arrested for harboring murder suspects",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Party leader arrested for harboring murder suspects",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Saman Perera, the leader of 'Ape Jana Bala Pakshaya' or Our Power of People Party was arrested by Police in Kosgoda on Wednesday (24).",
        "The suspect was arrested on the charge of harboring suspects wanted for a murder that took place in Tangalle recently.",
        "IMF delegation in Sri Lanka for talks on economic and financial reforms"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bala Pakshaya'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Our Power of People Party",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kosgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිනීමැරුම් සැකකරුවන්ට රැකවරණය දුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂ නායකයා අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ‘අපේ ජන බල පක්ෂය’ හෙවත් අපේ ජන බලය පක්ෂයේ නායක සමන් පෙරේරා බදාදා (24) කොස්ගොඩදී පොලිස් අත්අඩංගුවට පත් විය.",
        "පසුගිය දා තංගල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුවූ මනුෂ්‍ය ඝාතනයකට අවශ්‍ය සැකකරුවන්ට රැකවරණය ලබාදීමේ චෝදනාව මත සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ආර්ථික හා මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා IMF නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බල පක්ෂය'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපේ ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොස්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொலைச் சந்தேக நபர்களுக்கு அடைக்கலம் கொடுத்ததற்காக ஸ்ரீலங்கா கட்சித் தலைவர் கைது!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அபே ஜன பல பக்ஷய அல்லது எமது மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சியின் தலைவர் சமன் பெரேரா கொஸ்கொடவில் வைத்து பொலிஸாரால் புதன்கிழமை (24) கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "தங்காலை பிரதேசத்தில் அண்மையில் இடம்பெற்ற கொலைச் சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சந்தேகநபர்களுக்கு அடைக்கலம் வழங்கிய குற்றச்சாட்டில் சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பொருளாதார மற்றும் நிதி சீர்திருத்தங்கள் தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளுக்காக IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கை வந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பால பக்ஷயா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்கள் சக்தி மக்கள் கட்சி",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொஸ்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}