{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ලක්ෂ-19ක්-වටිනා-දුම්වැටි-අල්ලයි/11-395742",
  "time_ut": 1658812403,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලක්ෂ 19ක් වටිනා දුම්වැටි අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cigarettes worth 19 lakhs are seized",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Police Special Task Force, a person was arrested in Maligawatta area with a stock of cigarettes worth over 19 lakh rupees, which were smuggled into Sri Lanka without duty.",
        "The police have taken more than 30,000 cigarettes with the suspect.",
        "The raid was carried out according to information received by the officers of the Organized Crime Unit of the Police Special Task Force.",
        "The police officers who conducted the raid said that the government pictorial warning was not written on these cigarettes. The 54-year-old suspect, a resident of Maligawatta area, has been handed over to the Maligawatta police for further investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maligawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Organized Crime Unit of the Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "54-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maligawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maligawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලක්ෂ 19ක් වටිනා දුම්වැටි අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තීරුබදු රහිතව හොර රහසේ මෙරටට ආනයනය කරන ලද  රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 19 ක ට අධික වටිනා දුම්වැටි තොගයක් සමග පුද්ගලයෙකු මාලිගාවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ දී  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය පවසයි.",
        "සැකකරු සමඟ දුම්වැටි තිස්දාහකට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් පොලිසිය භාරයට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්යය බලකා සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ මර්දන ඒකකයේ නිලධාරීන් ට ලද තොරතුරක් අනුව මෙම වැටලීම සිදුකර ඇත.",
        "මෙම දුම්වැටි වල රජයේ රූපමය අවවාදය සටහන් කර නොමැති බවත් වැටලීම සිදුකළ සිදුකළ පොලිස් නිලධාරීහු පැවසීය. මාලිගාවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු පනස් හතරක් වන එම සැකකරු වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සඳහා මාලිගාවත්ත පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "54 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "19 லட்சம் மதிப்புள்ள சிகரெட்டுகள் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்டன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடமையின்றி இலங்கைக்கு கடத்தப்பட்ட 19 இலட்சம் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான சிகரெட்டுகளுடன் ஒருவர் மாளிகாவத்தை பகுதியில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபரிடம் 30,000க்கும் அதிகமான சிகரெட்டுகளை பொலிஸார் எடுத்துச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலுக்கு அமைய இந்த சுற்றிவளைப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த சிகரெட்டுகளில் அரசு பட எச்சரிக்கை எழுதப்படவில்லை என்று ரெய்டு நடத்திய போலீஸ் அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர். மாளிகாவத்தை பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த 54 வயதான சந்தேக நபர் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக மாளிகாவத்தை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "54 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}