{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79202",
  "time_ut": 1661539680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japanese Embassy Asks Jaffna Municipal Council to  Refund  Rs 14,329,446 Given in 2019 to Purchase four reconditioned waste-collection trucks ;”greatly regrettable that the project has already been three years late over the schedule and you were unable to implement the project,” the embassy informs Mayor V. Manivannan on the cancellation of the project.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japanese Embassy Asks Jaffna Municipal Council to  Refund  Rs 14,329,446 Given in 2019 to Purchase four reconditioned waste-collection trucks ;”greatly regrettable that the project has already been three years late over the schedule and you were unable to implement the project,” the embassy informs Mayor V. Manivannan on the cancellation of the project.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Japanese embassy has requested the Jaffna Municipal Council (JMC) to refund the money spent for the import of four reconditioned waste-collection trucks after the project was delayed for more than three years.",
        "The embassy has written to the council to refund Rs 14.3 million (USD 83,432) which was given for the import of the four trucks.",
        "“It is greatly regrettable that the project has already been three years late over the schedule and you were unable to implement the project,” the embassy informed Mayor V. Manivannan on the cancellation of the project.",
        "The embassy requested the JMC to refund the total amount of Rs 14,329,446 which was given to buy the four vehicles and cover expenses related to unloading, import, customs clearance and domestic transport.",
        "In April 2019, the Society for Promotion of Japanese Diplomacy (SPJD), a non-profit arm of the Japan’s Foreign Affairs Ministry, entered into a “Recycled Equipment Acquisition Project’ agreement with the JMC to provide the four trucks donated by local councils in Japan.",
        "In the partner agreement, it was agreed to transport vehicles to Hambantota after necessary reconditioning and inspection in addition to providing training for local staff on effective usage and self-maintenance of the vehicles.",
        "It was agreed that the JMC would obtain necessary permits and approvals in advance to import the used vehicles. A JMC senior official said one of the main reasons for terminating this project was the delay to get necessary approval from the Finance Ministry.",
        "Former Mayor Emmanuel Arnold who signed the agreement in 2019 alleged that the JMC’s current administration had failed to fast-track the project as agreed by both parties and the failure to do so resulted in the eventual termination of the project.",
        "Attempts to reach Mayor Manivannan were not possible since he is on an overseas visit.",
        "The latest JMC project cancellation came in the wake of projects of the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) being suspended after the government declared a debt default in April.  Parliament was told recently that some twelve projects were halted until the International Monetary Fund established a roadmap on Sri Lanka’s debt sustainability."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japanese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "2019",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "three years late",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mayor V. Manivannan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three years late",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mayor V. Manivannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Society for Promotion of Japanese Diplomacy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Recycled Equipment Acquisition Project’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Emmanuel Arnold",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Attempts",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manivannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japan International Cooperation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය යාපනය මහ නගර සභාවට 2019 දී ලබා දුන් රුපියල් 14,329,446 ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කරන ලද අපද්‍රව්‍ය එකතු කිරීමේ ට්‍රක් රථ හතරක් මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉල්ලා සිටී; ”මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය කාලසටහනට වඩා වසර තුනක් ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති අතර ඔබට ව්‍යාපෘතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම ගැන බලවත් කණගාටුව,” තානාපති කාර්යාලය දැනුම් දෙයි. මනිවන්නන් ව්‍යාපෘතිය අවලංගු කිරීම පිළිබඳව නගරාධිපති වී.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ව්‍යාපෘතිය වසර තුනකට වැඩි කාලයක් ප්‍රමාද වීමෙන් පසු ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කරන ලද අපද්‍රව්‍ය එකතු කරන ට්‍රක් රථ හතරක් ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා වැය වූ මුදල ආපසු ගෙවන ලෙස ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලය යාපනය මහ නගර සභාවෙන් (JMC) ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "ට්‍රක් රථ හතර ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ලබා දුන් රුපියල් මිලියන 14.3 (ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් 83,432) ආපසු ගෙවන ලෙස තානාපති කාර්යාලය සභාවට ලිඛිතව දන්වා ඇත.",
        "“මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය කාලසටහනට වඩා වසර තුනක් ප්‍රමාද වී තිබීම සහ ඔබට ව්‍යාපෘතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම ගැන කණගාටුයි,” ව්‍යාපෘතිය අවලංගු කිරීම පිළිබඳව තානාපති කාර්යාලය නගරාධිපති වී. මනිවන්නන් වෙත දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "වාහන හතර මිලදී ගැනීමට සහ ගොඩබෑම, ආනයනය, රේගු නිෂ්කාශනය සහ ගෘහස්ත ප්‍රවාහනයට අදාළ වියදම් පියවා ගැනීම සඳහා ලබා දුන් මුළු මුදල රුපියල් 14,329,446 ආපසු ගෙවන ලෙස තානාපති කාර්යාලය JMC වෙතින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "2019 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී, ජපාන විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලාභ නොලබන හස්තයක් වන ජපන් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ප්‍රවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ සංගමය (SPJD), ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද ට්‍රක් රථ හතරක් ලබා දීම සඳහා JMC සමඟ “ප්‍රතිචක්‍රීකරණය කරන ලද උපකරණ අත්පත් කර ගැනීමේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය” ගිවිසුමකට එළඹියේය. ජපානය.",
        "හවුල්කාර ගිවිසුමේ දී, වාහන ඵලදායි ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීම සහ ස්වයං නඩත්තුව පිළිබඳ දේශීය කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සඳහා පුහුණුවක් ලබා දීමට අමතරව, අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය සහ පරීක්ෂාවෙන් පසු වාහන හම්බන්තොටට ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට එකඟ විය.",
        "පාවිච්චි කරන ලද වාහන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා JMC විසින් අවශ්‍ය බලපත්‍ර සහ අනුමැතිය කල්තියා ලබා ගැනීමට එකඟ විය. JMC ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකු පැවසුවේ මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය අවසන් කිරීමට එක් ප්‍රධාන හේතුවක් වන්නේ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් අවශ්‍ය අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම ප්‍රමාද වීමයි.",
        "2019 දී ගිවිසුමට අත්සන් කළ හිටපු නගරාධිපති එම්මානුවෙල් ආර්නෝල්ඩ් චෝදනා කළේ දෙපාර්ශ්වයම එකඟ වූ පරිදි ව්‍යාපෘතිය කඩිනම් කිරීමට JMC හි වත්මන් පරිපාලනය අපොහොසත් වී ඇති බවත් එසේ කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වීම අවසානයේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය අවසන් කිරීමට හේතු වූ බවත්ය.",
        "නගරාධිපති මනිවන්නන් විදේශ සංචාරයක නිරතව සිටින බැවින් ඔහු වෙත පැමිණීමට උත්සාහ කළද නොහැකි විය.",
        "නවතම JMC ව්‍යාපෘති අවලංගු කිරීම සිදුවූයේ අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී රජය ණය පැහැර හැරීමක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසු ජපානයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගීතා නියෝජිතායතනයේ (JICA) ව්‍යාපෘති අත්හිටුවීමත් සමඟය. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය තිරසාරභාවය පිළිබඳ මාර්ග සිතියමක් සකස් කරන තෙක් ව්‍යාපෘති දොළහක් පමණ නවතා දැමූ බව පසුගියදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රකාශ විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "2019",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු තුනක් ප්රමාදයි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මනිවන්නන් නගරාධිපති වී",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු තුනකට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 14.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු තුනක් ප්රමාදයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනිවන්නන් නගරාධිපති වී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019 අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ප්‍රවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රතිචක්රීකරණය කරන ලද උපකරණ අත්පත් කර ගැනීමේ ව්යාපෘතිය'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එමානුවෙල් ආර්නෝල්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උත්සාහයන්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනිවන්නන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட்ட நான்கு கழிவுகளை சேகரிக்கும் பாரவூர்திகளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்காக 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு வழங்கப்பட்ட 14,329,446 ரூபாவை யாழ் மாநகர சபைக்குத் திருப்பித் தருமாறு ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் கோரியுள்ளது;”திட்டமானது ஏற்கனவே மூன்று வருடங்கள் காலதாமதமாகி திட்டத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்த முடியாமல் போனமை மிகவும் வருந்தத்தக்கது” என்று தூதரகம் தெரிவிக்கிறது. இத்திட்டம் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டது குறித்து மேயர் வி.மணிவண்ணன்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூன்று வருடங்களுக்கும் மேலாக இத்திட்டம் தாமதப்படுத்தப்பட்டதையடுத்து, மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட்ட நான்கு கழிவுகளை சேகரிக்கும் பாரவூர்திகளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு செலவழித்த பணத்தை மீள வழங்குமாறு ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் யாழ்ப்பாண மாநகர சபையிடம் (JMC) கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "நான்கு டிரக்குகளை இறக்குமதி செய்ததற்காக கொடுக்கப்பட்ட ரூ.14.3 மில்லியன் (அமெரிக்க டாலர் 83,432) பணத்தை திருப்பித் தருமாறு தூதரகம் கவுன்சிலுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளது.",
        "திட்டம் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டது குறித்து மேயர் வி.மணிவண்ணனிடம் தூதரகம் தெரிவித்தது: “இந்த திட்டம் ஏற்கனவே மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் காலதாமதமாகி, திட்டத்தை செயல்படுத்த முடியாமல் போனது மிகவும் வருந்தத்தக்கது.",
        "நான்கு வாகனங்களை வாங்கவும், இறக்குதல், இறக்குமதி, சுங்க அனுமதி மற்றும் உள்நாட்டுப் போக்குவரத்து தொடர்பான செலவுகளை ஈடுகட்டவும் வழங்கப்பட்ட மொத்தத் தொகையான 14,329,446 ரூபாயை திருப்பித் தருமாறு தூதரகம் ஜேஎம்சியிடம் கோரியது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 2019 இல், ஜப்பானிய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் இலாப நோக்கற்ற பிரிவான ஜப்பானிய இராஜதந்திரத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான சங்கம் (SPJD), உள்ளூராட்சி மன்றங்களால் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட நான்கு டிரக்குகளை வழங்க JMC உடன் “மறுசுழற்சி செய்யப்பட்ட உபகரண கையகப்படுத்தல் திட்டம்” ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டது. ஜப்பான்.",
        "பங்குதாரர் உடன்படிக்கையில், வாகனங்களின் பயனுள்ள பயன்பாடு மற்றும் சுய பராமரிப்பு குறித்து உள்ளூர் ஊழியர்களுக்கு பயிற்சி அளிப்பதுடன், தேவையான மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் பரிசோதனையின் பின்னர் வாகனங்களை அம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு கொண்டு செல்ல ஒப்புக் கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "பயன்படுத்திய வாகனங்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு தேவையான அனுமதிகள் மற்றும் அனுமதிகளை ஜேஎம்சி முன்கூட்டியே பெறும் என்று ஒப்புக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. ஜேஎம்சி மூத்த அதிகாரி ஒருவர் கூறுகையில், இந்த திட்டம் நிறுத்தப்படுவதற்கான முக்கிய காரணங்களில் ஒன்று நிதி அமைச்சகத்திடம் இருந்து தேவையான அனுமதி பெறுவதில் தாமதம் ஆகும்.",
        "2019 இல் ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்ட முன்னாள் மேயர் இம்மானுவேல் அர்னால்ட், JMC இன் தற்போதைய நிர்வாகம் இரு தரப்பினராலும் ஒப்புக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட திட்டத்தை விரைவாகக் கண்காணிக்கத் தவறிவிட்டதாகவும், அவ்வாறு செய்யத் தவறியதன் விளைவாக திட்டம் இறுதியில் நிறுத்தப்படும் என்றும் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "மேயர் மணிவண்ணன் வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணமாக இருப்பதால் அவரைச் சந்திக்க முயன்றும் முடியவில்லை.",
        "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச கூட்டுறவு முகமையின் (JICA) திட்டங்கள் ஏப்ரலில் அரசாங்கம் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை என்று அறிவித்ததை அடுத்து, சமீபத்திய JMC திட்டம் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டது. சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் இலங்கையின் கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை குறித்த ஒரு வரைபடத்தை உருவாக்கும் வரையில் சில பன்னிரண்டு திட்டங்கள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக அண்மையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "2019",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் தாமதம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மேயர் வி.மணிவண்ணன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் தாமதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேயர் வி.மணிவண்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானிய இராஜதந்திரத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மறுசுழற்சி செய்யப்பட்ட உபகரணங்களை கையகப்படுத்தும் திட்டம்'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இம்மானுவேல் அர்னால்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முயற்சிகள்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிவண்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜேஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}