{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Excise-earns-Rs-93Mn-as-revenue-from-fines-in-first-five-months/342-240324",
  "time_ut": 1656948094,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Excise earns Rs.93Mn as revenue from fines in first five months",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Excise earns Rs.93Mn as revenue from fines in first five months",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Excise has managed to make a staggering sum of Rs.93 million as revenue to the government from fines imposed on various offences and violations of the Excise Ordinance during the first five months of this year.",
        "The department has earned this sum of revenue from fines imposed on 13, 405 detections made countrywide from January 01st to May 31st in 2022, said the departmental spokesman Commissioner Kapila Kumarasinghe.",
        "According to the statistics, 12, 313 detections have been made under the Excise Ordinance, National Act on Tobacco and Alcohol (NATA) and Poison, Opium and Dangerous Drugs Ordinance, and a sum of Rs.52, 990, 370 imposed as fines.",
        "Also, 1, 092 TCR (Technical Crime Report) cases have been detected from countrywide licensed premises and revenue of Rs.41, 572, 480 had been generated through fines.",
        "The general offences include production, transportation and sale of illicit liquor and spirits, possession and sale of Heroin, Cocaine, Ganja, illicit cigarettes and Opium.",
        "The department has arrested 10, 432 persons in connection with these detections and 1, 881 were females.",
        "About 900 Excise personnel took part in the detections representing 57 Excise Stations countrywide with five Special Operations Bureaus and the Excise Narcotic Unit. (Kurulu Koojana Kariyakarawana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Excise",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "first five months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Department of Excise",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Excise Ordinance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first five months of this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "405",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 01st to May 31st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kapila Kumarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "313",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Excise Ordinance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Act on Tobacco and Alcohol",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poison",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opium",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs.52",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "990",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "092",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TCR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "572",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "480",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Heroin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cocaine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ganja",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opium",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "432",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "881",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Excise Stations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Special Operations Bureaus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Excise Narcotic Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurulu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Koojana Kariyakarawana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළමු මාස ​​පහ තුළ සුරාබදු බදුවලින් රුපියල් මිලියන 93 ක ආදායමක් උපයයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වසරේ මුල් මාස පහ තුළ විවිධ වැරදි සහ සුරාබදු ආඥාපනත උල්ලංඝණය කිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පනවන ලද දඩ මුදල්වලින් රජයට රුපියල් මිලියන 93 ක දැවැන්ත ආදායමක් උපයා ගැනීමට සුරාබදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සමත් වී ඇත.",
        "2022 ජනවාරි 01 වැනිදා සිට මැයි 31 වැනිදා දක්වා රටපුරා හඳුනාගැනීම් 13,405ක් සඳහා පනවා ඇති දඩ මුදල්වලින් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මෙම ආදායම උපයාගෙන ඇතැයි දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ප්‍රකාශක කොමසාරිස් කපිල කුමාරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනවලට අනුව, සුරාබදු ආඥාපනත, දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික පනත (NATA) සහ විෂ, අබිං සහ අන්තරායකර ඖෂධ ආඥාපනත යටතේ හඳුනාගැනීම් 12,313 ක් සිදු කර ඇති අතර දඩ වශයෙන් රුපියල් 52, 990, 370 ක මුදලක් නියම කර ඇත.",
        "එසේම, රටපුරා බලපත්‍රලාභී පරිශ්‍රවලින් TCR (තාක්ෂණික අපරාධ වාර්තාව) 1, 092 ක් හඳුනාගෙන ඇති අතර දඩ මුදල් මගින් රුපියල් 41, 572, 480 ක ආදායමක් උපයා ඇත.",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී මත්පැන් සහ ස්ප්‍රීතු නිෂ්පාදනය, ප්‍රවාහනය සහ විකිණීම, හෙරොයින්, කොකේන්, ගංජා, නීති විරෝධී දුම්වැටි සහ අබිං ළඟ තබා ගැනීම සහ විකිණීම සාමාන්‍ය වැරදි අතර වේ.",
        "මෙම හඳුනාගැනීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 10,432 දෙනෙකු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර 1,881ක් කාන්තාවන් වේ.",
        "දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි සුරාබදු ස්ථාන 57ක් නියෝජනය කරමින් විශේෂ මෙහෙයුම් කාර්යාංශය සහ සුරාබදු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක අංශය සමඟ සුරාබදු නිලධාරීන් 900ක් පමණ මෙම හඳුනාගැනීම් සඳහා සහභාගි වූහ. (කුරුළු කූජන කාරියකරවන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සුරාබදු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පළමු මාස ​​පහ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරාබදු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරාබදු ආඥාපනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මුල් මාස පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "405",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 01 සිට මැයි 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කපිල කුමාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "313",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරාබදු ආඥාපනත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රු.52",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "990",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "092",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "TCR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "572",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "480",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙරොයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොකේන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "432",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "881",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරාබදු ස්ථාන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ මෙහෙයුම් කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරාබදු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුලු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කූජන කාරියකරවන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்களில் அபராதம் மூலம் கலால் வரி ரூ.93 மில்லியன் வருவாய் ஈட்டுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கலால் திணைக்களம் இந்த வருடத்தின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்களில் பல்வேறு குற்றங்கள் மற்றும் கலால் கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தை மீறியதற்காக விதிக்கப்பட்ட அபராதங்கள் மூலம் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு 93 மில்லியன் ரூபாவை வருமானமாக ஈட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனவரி 01 ஆம் திகதி முதல் மே 31 ஆம் திகதி வரை நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட 13, 405 கண்டறிதல்களுக்கு விதிக்கப்பட்ட அபராதத் தொகையின் மூலம் திணைக்களம் இந்தத் தொகையை ஈட்டியுள்ளதாக திணைக்களப் பேச்சாளர் ஆணையாளர் கபில குமாரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புள்ளிவிபரங்களின்படி, கலால் சட்டம், புகையிலை மற்றும் ஆல்கஹால் மீதான தேசிய சட்டம் (NATA) மற்றும் விஷம், அபின் மற்றும் ஆபத்தான மருந்துகள் கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் 12, 313 கண்டறியப்பட்டு, ரூ.52, 990, 370 அபராதம் விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், நாடு முழுவதும் உரிமம் பெற்ற வளாகங்களில் இருந்து 1, 092 TCR (தொழில்நுட்ப குற்ற அறிக்கை) வழக்குகள் கண்டறியப்பட்டு அபராதம் மூலம் ரூ.41, 572, 480 வருவாய் ஈட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொது குற்றங்களில் சட்டவிரோத மதுபானம் மற்றும் மதுபானங்களை உற்பத்தி செய்தல், போக்குவரத்து செய்தல் மற்றும் விற்பனை செய்தல், ஹெராயின், கொக்கெய்ன், கஞ்சா, சட்டவிரோத சிகரெட் மற்றும் அபின் வைத்திருத்தல் மற்றும் விற்பனை செய்தல் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "இந்த கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் தொடர்பாக 10,432 பேரை கைது செய்த திணைக்களம், 1,881 பெண்கள்.",
        "ஐந்து சிறப்பு நடவடிக்கைப் பணியகங்கள் மற்றும் கலால் போதைப்பொருள் பிரிவுடன் நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள 57 கலால் நிலையங்களைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி சுமார் 900 கலால் பணியாளர்கள் கண்டறிதல்களில் பங்கேற்றனர். (குருலு கூஜன காரியகரவன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கலால் வரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கலால் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலால் ஆணை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "405",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 01 முதல் மே 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபில குமாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "313",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலால் ஆணை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புகையிலை மற்றும் மது மீதான தேசிய சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஷம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.52",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "990",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "092",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசிஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "572",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "480",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹெராயின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோகோயின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஞ்சா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "432",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "881",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலால் நிலையங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு செயல்பாட்டு பணியகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலால் போதைப்பொருள் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருலு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூஜன காரியகரவன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}