{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/long-term-investments-in-sri-lanka-are-indias-plan-to-fix-economic-crisis/",
  "time_ut": 1658826900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Long-term investments in Sri Lanka are India’s plan to fix economic crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Long-term investments in Sri Lanka are India’s plan to fix economic crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st)/ ThePrint; Indian High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay said that after helping Sri Lanka with an unprecedented assistance of around $4 billion since January, India is now planning to invest heavily in newer sectors through both private and public firms there.",
        "The Indian High Commissioner speaking to ThePrint, Baglay said that discussions with the new government in Sri Lanka have already begun regarding which sectors the investments will be coming in.",
        "He said Indian investors, from the public as well as private sectors, will explore opportunities in certain key sectors of ports and infrastructure, renewable energy, electricity, hydrocarbons, agriculture and dairy, education and information technology, among others.",
        "He said the National Thermal Power Corporation Limited of India is looking at establishing a solar power plant in Sampur in eastern Sri Lanka near Trincomalee, under a joint collaboration with the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB).",
        "Similarly, the high commissioner said, Sri Lanka has huge potential in solar and wind energy, thus that can also be exported to India after meeting its own requirements.",
        "He said India has “made a strong case” for Sri Lanka in bilateral talks also with the US, Japan and Australia for coming forward to help the country.",
        "Apart from investments, Baglay said both sides are now also working towards expediting the conclusion of the pending Economic and Technology Co-operation Agreement (ETCA), which will “go beyond” the existing India-Sri Lanka free trade agreement that came into force in March 2000.",
        "Modi congratulates Ranil; says India will support Sri Lankan people",
        "Long-term investments in Sri Lanka are India’s plan to fix economic crisis"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around $4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "January",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ThePrint, Baglay",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Thermal Power Corporation Limited of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Baglay",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic and Technology Co-operation Agreement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETCA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගුකාලීන ආයෝජන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ සැලසුමයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st)/ ThePrint; ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ පැවසුවේ ජනවාරි මාසයේ සිට පෙර නොවූ විරූ ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 ක පමණ ආධාරයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දීමෙන් පසු ඉන්දියාව දැන් එහි පෞද්ගලික සහ රාජ්‍ය ආයතන හරහා නව ක්ෂේත්‍ර සඳහා විශාල වශයෙන් ආයෝජනය කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ThePrint වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් Baglay කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව රජය සමඟ මෙම ආයෝජන පැමිණෙන්නේ කුමන ක්ෂේත්‍ර වෙතද යන්න පිළිබඳව දැනටමත් සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ආයෝජකයින්, රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ මෙන්ම පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ ද, වරාය සහ යටිතල පහසුකම්, පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය, විදුලිය, හයිඩ්‍රොකාබන්, කෘෂිකර්මය සහ කිරි, අධ්‍යාපනය සහ තොරතුරු තාක්‍ෂණය යනාදී ප්‍රධාන අංශවල අවස්ථා ගවේෂණය කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (ලංවිම) ඒකාබද්ධ සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික තාප විදුලි සංස්ථාව සීමාසහිත ත්‍රිකුණාමලයට ආසන්නයේ නැගෙනහිර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සාම්පූර් හි සූර්ය බලාගාරයක් පිහිටුවීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එසේම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සූර්ය හා සුළං බලශක්තිය සඳහා විශාල විභවයක් ඇති බවත්, එම නිසා එය ඉන්දියාවට අපනයනය කළ හැකි බවත් මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා පැවසීය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය, ජපානය සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡාවලදී ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීමට ඉදිරිපත් වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව “ශක්තිමත් තර්කයක්” ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ආයෝජන හැරුණු විට, දැනට බලාත්මක වූ ඉන්දියා-ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් වෙළඳ ගිවිසුමෙන් ඔබ්බට යන අපේක්ෂිත ආර්ථික හා තාක්ෂණ සහයෝගීතා ගිවිසුම (ETCA) කඩිනම් කිරීම සඳහා දෙපාර්ශ්වයම දැන් කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බව Baglay පැවසීය. 2000 මාර්තු.",
        "මෝදි රනිල්ට සුබ පතයි; ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට සහාය දෙන බව පවසයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගුකාලීන ආයෝජන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ සැලසුමයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ThePrint, Baglay",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික තාප විදුලි සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාම්පූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බග්ලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික හා තාක්ෂණ සහයෝගිතා ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETCA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் நீண்டகால முதலீடுகள் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சரிசெய்வதற்கான இந்தியாவின் திட்டமாகும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st)/ ThePrint; இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே கூறுகையில், ஜனவரி முதல் இதுவரை இல்லாத வகையில் சுமார் 4 பில்லியன் டாலர் உதவியை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய பின்னர், தற்போது அங்குள்ள தனியார் மற்றும் பொது நிறுவனங்கள் மூலம் புதிய துறைகளில் அதிக முதலீடு செய்ய இந்தியா திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ThePrint உடன் பேசிய இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் Baglay, எந்தெந்த துறைகளில் முதலீடுகள் வரும் என்பது குறித்து இலங்கையின் புதிய அரசாங்கத்துடனான கலந்துரையாடல்கள் ஏற்கனவே ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பொது மற்றும் தனியார் துறைகளைச் சேர்ந்த இந்திய முதலீட்டாளர்கள் துறைமுகங்கள் மற்றும் உள்கட்டமைப்பு, புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி, மின்சாரம், ஹைட்ரோகார்பன், விவசாயம் மற்றும் பால், கல்வி மற்றும் தகவல் தொழில்நுட்பம் போன்ற சில முக்கிய துறைகளில் வாய்ப்புகளை ஆராய்வார்கள் என்றார்.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின் (CEB) கூட்டு ஒத்துழைப்பின் கீழ், திருகோணமலைக்கு அருகிலுள்ள கிழக்கில் இலங்கையின் சம்பூரில் சூரிய மின்சக்தி நிலையத்தை நிறுவுவதற்கு இந்தியாவின் தேசிய அனல் மின் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் லிமிடெட் உத்தேசித்து வருவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அதேபோன்று, இலங்கை சூரிய மற்றும் காற்றாலை ஆற்றலில் பெரும் ஆற்றலைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, எனவே அதன் சொந்த தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்த பின்னர் இந்தியாவிற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்ய முடியும் என்று உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் கூறினார்.",
        "அமெரிக்கா, ஜப்பான் மற்றும் அவுஸ்திரேலியா ஆகிய நாடுகளுடனான இருதரப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளிலும் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ முன்வருவதற்கு இந்தியா \"வலுவான கோரிக்கையை\" முன்வைத்துள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "முதலீடுகள் தவிர, நிலுவையில் உள்ள பொருளாதார மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப ஒத்துழைப்பு ஒப்பந்தத்தின் (ETCA) முடிவை விரைவுபடுத்துவதற்கு இரு தரப்பும் இப்போது செயல்பட்டு வருவதாகவும், இது நடைமுறைக்கு வந்த இந்தியா-இலங்கை தடையற்ற வர்த்தக உடன்படிக்கைக்கு அப்பால் செல்லும் என்றும் பாக்லே கூறினார். மார்ச் 2000.",
        "ரணிலுக்கு மோடி வாழ்த்து; இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியா ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று கூறினார்",
        "இலங்கையில் நீண்டகால முதலீடுகள் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சரிசெய்வதற்கான இந்தியாவின் திட்டமாகும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி பிரிண்ட், பாக்லே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேஷனல் தெர்மல் பவர் கார்ப்பரேஷன் லிமிடெட் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாக்லே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப ஒத்துழைப்பு ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETCA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}