{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/දෙවැනි-විද්‍යාගාර-මොඩුයලය-අභ්‍යවකාශගත-කිරීමට-සැරසේ/3-396851",
  "time_ut": 1662182988,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දෙවැනි විද්‍යාගාර මොඩුයලය අභ්‍යවකාශගත කිරීමට සැරසේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The second laboratory module is about to be launched",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China's second laboratory module, Mengtian, prepares for launch, the final component of China's space station.",
        "To this end, a Long March-5B Y4 carrier rocket has been transported to the Wenchang Spacecraft Launch Site in southern China's Hainan Province, where it is ready for assembly and testing, the China Manned Space Agency (CMS) announced.",
        "The lab module has been assembled and is undergoing tests after being moved to the launch site in early August."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mengtian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Wenchang Spacecraft Launch Site",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hainan Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the China Manned Space Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "early August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙවැනි විද්‍යාගාර මොඩුයලය අභ්‍යවකාශගත කිරීමට සැරසේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ අවසාන අංගය වන චීනයේ දෙවැනි විද්‍යාගාර මොඩියුලය වන මෙන්ග්ටියාන් අභ්‍යවකාශගත කිරීමට සූදානම් වෙයි.",
        "මේ වෙනුවෙන්, ලෝන්ග් මාර්ච්-5B Y4 වාහක රොකට්ටුවක් දකුණු චීනයේ හයිනාන් පළාතේ වෙන්චැන්ග් අභ්‍යවකාශ යානා දියත් කරන ස්ථානයට ප්‍රවාහනය කර ඇති අතර, එය එකලස් කිරීම සහ පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා සූදානම් බව චීන මිනිසුන් සහිත අභ්‍යවකාශ ඒජන්සිය (CMS) නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "මෙම විද්‍යාගාර මොඩියුලය එකලස් කර ඇති අතර අගෝස්තු මස මුලදී එම දියත් කිරීමේ ස්ථානයට ගෙන යාමෙන් පසු පරීක්ෂණ සිදු කරමින් පවතී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mengtian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wenchang අභ්‍යවකාශ යානා දියත් කිරීමේ අඩවිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හයිනාන් පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන මිනිසුන් සහිත අභ්‍යවකාශ ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டாவது ஆய்வக தொகுதி தொடங்கப்பட உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் இரண்டாவது ஆய்வகத் தொகுதியான மெங்டியன், சீனாவின் விண்வெளி நிலையத்தின் இறுதிக் கூறு ஏவுவதற்குத் தயாராகிறது.",
        "இதற்காக, லாங் மார்ச்-5பி ஒய்4 கேரியர் ராக்கெட், தெற்கு சீனாவின் ஹைனான் மாகாணத்தில் உள்ள வென்சாங் விண்கல ஏவுதளத்திற்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டுள்ளது, அங்கு அது அசெம்பிளி மற்றும் சோதனைக்கு தயாராக உள்ளது என்று சீன மனிதர்கள் கொண்ட விண்வெளி நிறுவனம் (சிஎம்எஸ்) அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆய்வக தொகுதி ஒன்று திரட்டப்பட்டு, ஆகஸ்ட் தொடக்கத்தில் வெளியீட்டு தளத்திற்கு மாற்றப்பட்ட பின்னர் சோதனைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mengtian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வென்சாங் விண்கல ஏவுதளம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹைனான் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா மனிதர்கள் கொண்ட விண்வெளி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CMS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}