{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Repeal-PTA-and-release-arrested-Uni-students-NPP/108-243574",
  "time_ut": 1661251749,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Repeal PTA and release arrested Uni.  students: NPP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Repeal PTA and release arrested Uni.  students: NPP",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "While urging the government to repeal the Prevention of Terrorrism Act (PTA), the National People's Power today called on the government to release the three student activists who were detained under the PTA.",
        "NPP General Secretary Tilvin Silva told a news conference that the three students including the IUSF Convener were detained under the PTA without producing in court as there was no evidence against them.",
        "He said most of the Aragalaya activists who were arrested earlier were released by the court as there were no evidence against them.",
        "\"The government is now using the PTA to detain them without producing them in court as there is no evidence against them. We urge the government to repeal the PTA and release the detained student activists,\" he said.",
        "Mr. Silva said it was surprising that President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who advocated to repeal the PTA during the Yahapalanaya Government, is now using the same Act to take revenge.",
        "\"This is an anti-democratic and anti-human Act. It should be repealed immediately,' he said. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "NPP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tilvin Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IUSF Convener",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Yahapalanaya Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අවලංගු කර අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් යුනිව නිදහස් කරන්න. සිසුන්: NPP",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PTA) අහෝසි කරන ලෙස රජයට බලකරමින් ජාතික ජන බලවේගය අද රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ රඳවාගෙන සිටින ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් තිදෙනා නිදහස් කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "එන්පීපී ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ටිල්වින් සිල්වා ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී කියා සිටියේ අවිශිබම කැඳවුම්කරු ඇතුළු සිසුන් තිදෙනාට එරෙහිව කිසිදු සාක්ෂියක් නොමැති බැවින් ඔවුන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකර ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ රඳවා ගත් බවයි.",
        "මීට පෙර අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට එරෙහිව කිසිදු සාක්ෂියක් නොමැති බැවින් ඔවුන් අධිකරණයෙන් නිදහස් කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ආණ්ඩුව දැන් ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යොදා ගනිමින් ඔවුන්ව අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකර රඳවා ගැනීමට කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින්නේ ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව කිසිදු සාක්ෂියක් නොමැති නිසායි. ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත ඉවත් කර රඳවාගෙන සිටින ශිෂ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස අපි රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමු,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "යහපාලන රජය සමයේ ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අහෝසි කරන ලෙස පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දැන් එම පනතම යොදා ගනිමින් පළිගැනීම පුදුමයට කරුණක් බවද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"මෙය ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී සහ මානව විරෝධී පනතක්. මෙය වහා ඉවත් කළ යුතුයි\" (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එන්පීපී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටිල්වින් සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම කැඳවුම්කරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயங்கரவாத தடை சட்டத்தை ரத்து செய்து, கைது செய்யப்பட்ட யூனியை விடுவிக்கவும். மாணவர்கள்: NPP",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தை (PTA) இரத்துச் செய்யுமாறு அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்தும் அதேவேளை, பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மூன்று மாணவர் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை விடுதலை செய்யுமாறு தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி இன்று அரசாங்கத்திடம் கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "NPP பொதுச் செயலாளர் டில்வின் சில்வா ஒரு செய்தி மாநாட்டில், IUSF அழைப்பாளர் உட்பட மூன்று மாணவர்களுக்கு எதிராக எந்த ஆதாரமும் இல்லாததால், நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தாமல் PTA இன் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னதாக கைது செய்யப்பட்ட அறகலயா செயற்பாட்டாளர்களில் பெரும்பாலோர் அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக எந்த ஆதாரமும் இல்லாததால் நீதிமன்றத்தால் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவர்களுக்கு எதிராக எந்த ஆதாரமும் இல்லாததால், அவர்களை நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தாமல், தற்போது பயங்கரவாத தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி, அவர்களைக் காவலில் வைக்க அரசு முயற்சிக்கிறது. பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தை ரத்து செய்து, தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மாணவர் ஆர்வலர்களை விடுவிக்குமாறு அரசை வலியுறுத்துகிறோம், என்றார்.",
        "யஹபாலனய அரசாங்கத்தின் போது பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தை இரத்துச் செய்யுமாறு வாதிட்ட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, தற்போது அதே சட்டத்தை பயன்படுத்தி பழிவாங்குவது ஆச்சரியமளிப்பதாக திரு.சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இது ஜனநாயக விரோத மற்றும் மனித விரோதச் சட்டம். இது உடனடியாக ரத்து செய்யப்பட வேண்டும்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "NPP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டில்வின் சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF கன்வீனர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலனய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}