{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/மதுபோதை-சண்டை-மலக்குழிக்குள்-சடலம்/175-299199",
  "time_ut": 1656171959,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மதுபோதை சண்டை:  மலக்குழிக்குள் சடலம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Alcohol fight: Corpse in the rectum",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Maharagama Police have arrested a man suspected of assaulting and killing a Paco motorist at a Navinna holiday hotel in Maharagama and hiding him in a latrine.",
        "The deceased was identified as A., 37, of Harantota, Ratnapura. H. He has been identified as Ravindra.",
        "Police said the incident took place following an argument between the suspect and the murdered man after drinking alcohol.",
        "The arrested suspect is a 42 year old from Katugasthota area and police are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maharagama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paco",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navinna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharagama",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ravindra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katugasthota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මත්පැන් සටන: ගුද මාර්ගයේ මළ සිරුර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහරගම නාවින්න නිවාඩු දින හෝටලයකදී පැකෝ රියදුරෙකුට පහර දී ඝාතනය කර වැසිකිළියක සඟවා තැබූ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයකු මහරගම පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ රත්නපුර හරන්තොට ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 37 හැවිරිදි ඒ. එච්. ඔහු රවීන්ද්‍ර ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, සැකකරු සහ ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයා මත්පැන් පානය කර අතර ඇති වූ බහින්බස්වීමක් දුරදිග යාමෙන් මෙම සිද්ධිය සිදුව ඇති බව ය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු කටුගස්තොට ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 42 හැවිරිදි අයෙකු වන අතර පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදුකරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහරගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැකෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවින්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවීන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුගස්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மதுபோதை சண்டை:  மலக்குழிக்குள் சடலம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மஹரகம, நாவின்ன விடுமுறை விடுதியில் பக்கோ இயந்திர சாரதி ஒருவரை தாக்கி படுகொலை  செய்து மலசல கூடக்குழிக்குள் மறைத்து வைத்தார் என்று  சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் ஒருவரை கைது செய்துள்ளதாக மஹரகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர், இரத்தினபுரி, ஹரந்தோட்டையைச் சேர்ந்த 37 வயதான ஏ. எச். ரவீந்திர என்று அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபரும் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட நபரும் மது அருந்திய பின்னர் ஏற்பட்ட வாக்குவாதத்தை அடுத்து இந்த சம்பவம் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர், கட்டுகஸ்தோட்டை பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த 42 வயதுடையவர் என்றும் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருவதாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாவின்னா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவீந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுகஸ்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}