{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/health-official-to-expedite-4th-covid-19-dose/",
  "time_ut": 1658805240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Health official to expedite 4th COVID-19 dose",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Health official to expedite 4th COVID-19 dose",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Health has decided to speed up the administration of the 4th booster dose to control the spread of the COVID-19 virus.",
        "Secretary to the Health Ministry Janaka Chandragupta said the necessary steps are being taken to initiate the 4th dose vaccination drive this week itself.",
        "He noted that PCR tests will be conducted to detect COVID-19 patients as required, adding that if patients are reported in clusters, surveillance testing will be carried out.",
        "Chandragupta added that the current health situation in the country was taken up for discussion during a meeting with President Ranil Wickremesinghe yesterday.",
        "Three-wheelers to register with police for fuel; 49CC Bikes to register with DMT for Fuel"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Health Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Chandragupta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandragupta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "4 වන COVID-19 මාත්‍රාව කඩිනම් කිරීමට සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරියා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); COVID-19 වෛරසය පැතිරීම පාලනය කිරීම සඳහා 4 වන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබාදීම කඩිනම් කිරීමට සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් ජනක චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත මහතා පැවසුවේ, 4 වන එන්නත් කිරීමේ වැඩසටහන මේ සතියේදීම ආරම්භ කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගනිමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "අවශ්‍ය පරිදි COVID-19 රෝගීන් හඳුනා ගැනීම සඳහා PCR පරීක්ෂණ සිදු කරන බව සඳහන් කළ ඔහු, පොකුරු වශයෙන් රෝගීන් වාර්තා වුවහොත් නිරීක්ෂණ පරීක්ෂණ සිදු කරන බව පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ ඊයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී රටේ වත්මන් සෞඛ්‍ය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ බව චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ත්‍රිරෝද රථ ඉන්ධන සඳහා පොලිසියේ ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමට; ඉන්ධන සඳහා DMT සමඟ ලියාපදිංචි වීමට 49CC බයික්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "4வது கோவிட்-19 டோஸை விரைவுபடுத்த சுகாதார அதிகாரி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); COVID-19 வைரஸின் பரவலைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த 4 வது பூஸ்டர் டோஸின் நிர்வாகத்தை விரைவுபடுத்த சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் முடிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த வாரத்தில் 4 ஆவது டோஸ் தடுப்பூசி இயக்கத்தை ஆரம்பிக்க தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக சுகாதார அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ஜனக சந்திரகுப்த தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தேவைக்கேற்ப கோவிட்-19 நோயாளிகளைக் கண்டறிய PCR சோதனைகள் நடத்தப்படும் என்று குறிப்பிட்ட அவர், நோயாளிகள் குழுக்களாகப் பதிவாகினால், கண்காணிப்புப் பரிசோதனை மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போது நாட்டின் தற்போதைய சுகாதார நிலைமை குறித்து கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாக சந்திரகுப்த மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருளுக்காக பொலிஸில் பதிவு செய்ய முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள்; எரிபொருளுக்காக DMT இல் பதிவு செய்ய 49CC பைக்குகள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக சந்திரகுப்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரகுப்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}