{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-opposition-leader-welcomes-dissident-ruling-party-faction-to-opposition-99299/",
  "time_ut": 1661957580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka opposition leader welcomes dissident ruling party faction to opposition",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka opposition leader welcomes dissident ruling party faction to opposition",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka opposition leader Sajith Premadasa has “warmly” welcomed a breakaway faction of the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) to the opposition.",
        "Hours after SLPP Chairman and former Foreign Minister G L Peiris announced that 13 members of his party who had already been functioning independently in parliament would now be sitting in the opposition, Premadasa tweeted his greetings to the rebel group.",
        "The @sjbsrilanka warmly welcomes the Chairman of SLPP Prof. GL Peiris & the team to the opposition.",
        "This will strengthen our resolve in our fight against an anti-democratic government. pic.twitter.com/V7Zj8yySWi",
        "The tweet contained a picture of Premadasa welcoming SLPP Matara district leader Dullas Alahapperuma, whose candidacy at the recent election in parliament for Sri Lanka’s eighth executive president was backed by Premadasa, having himself withdrawn from the race.",
        "Alahapperuma lost the election to then Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe who won by 134 votes in a 225-member assembly.",
        "President Wickremesinghe has been making repeated calls for an interim all-party government to see much needed economic reforms through, as Sri Lanka grapples with the hardships of the worst currency crisis in its central bank’s history.",
        "Though Premadasa’s main opposition the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) has officially said it is ready to support the government in its reform efforts through parliamentary committees, without joining the cabinet. However, analysts say senior SJB members have been blowing hot and cold on the matter, with some appearing eager to play a more hands-on role.",
        "SJB MP Harsha de Silva on Wednesday said while President Wickremesinghe’s proposals for economic recovery – presented through the interim budget for the rest of the year – were sound, it is hard to imagine the present SLPP-led disposition will support it given its diametrically opposed policies.",
        "MP de Silva’s remarks prompted Aviation Minister Nimal Sirpala de Silva to quip in parliament that the SJB parliamentarian, widely regarded for his economics prowess, is “aasayi bayai” or that he “wants it but too afraid to take it”. (Colombo/Aug31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G L Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP Prof. GL Peiris &",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aviation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Sirpala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ නායක විපක්‍ෂයට විරුද්ධ ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂයේ කන්ඩායම පිළිගනී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් (SLPP) කැඩී ගිය කන්ඩායමක් විපක්ෂයට \"උණුසුම්\" ලෙස පිළිගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ වන විටත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටි තම පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනෙකු දැන් විපක්ෂයේ අසුන් ගන්නා බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති සහ හිටපු විදේශ අමාත්‍ය ජී එල් පීරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පැය කිහිපයකට පසු ප්‍රේමදාස කැරලිකාර කණ්ඩායමට සිය සුබපැතුම් ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම විපක්ෂයට පැමිණ සිටින පිරිස @sjbsrilanka විසින් උණුසුම් ලෙස පිළිගනී.",
        "මෙය ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී රජයකට එරෙහි අපගේ සටනේ අපගේ අධිෂ්ඨානය ශක්තිමත් කරනු ඇත. pic.twitter.com/V7Zj8yySWi",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික් නායක ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම පිළිගන්නා ආකාරය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයේ අඩංගු වූ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අටවැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහා පසුගියදා පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේ අපේක්ෂකත්වය ප්‍රේමදාසගේ සහාය ඇතිව ඔහු තරඟයෙන් ඉවත්ව ගිය ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පිළිගන්නා ආකාරයයි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් සභාවකින් ඡන්ද 134 කින් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ එවකට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවේ අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා පරාජයට පත්විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයේ දුෂ්කරතා සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටින විට, අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ දැකීමට අන්තර්වාර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආන්ඩුවක් සඳහා ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ නැවත නැවතත් ඉල්ලීම් කරමින් සිටී.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාසගේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට සම්බන්ධ නොවී පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටු හරහා රජය ගෙන යන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට සහාය දීමට සූදානම් බව නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, විශ්ලේෂකයින් පවසන්නේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ SJB සාමාජිකයින් මෙම කාරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් උණුසුම් හා සීතල හමා ගොස් ඇති අතර ඇතැමුන් වඩාත් ප්‍රායෝගික කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කිරීමට උනන්දු වන බව පෙනේ.",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා බදාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, වසරේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා අතුරු අයවැය හරහා ඉදිරිපත් කළ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහගේ යෝජනා - හොඳ මට්ටමක පවතින අතර, වර්තමාන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ ආකල්පය එහි පරස්පර විරෝධී ප්‍රතිපත්ති අනුව එයට සහාය දෙනු ඇතැයි සිතීම දුෂ්කර බවයි. .",
        "ද සිල්වා මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශය ගුවන්සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සර්පාල ද සිල්වා මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී උපහාසයට ලක් කළේ ඔහුගේ ආර්ථික දක්‍ෂතාවය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුළුල් ලෙස සැලකෙන SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා “ආසයි බයයි” හෝ “එය අවශ්‍ය නමුත් එය ගැනීමට බයයි” කියායි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සර්පාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அதிருப்தி ஆளும் கட்சிப் பிரிவை எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு வரவேற்கிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பிரிந்து சென்ற பிரிவை எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு \"அன்புடன்\" வரவேற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "SLPP தலைவரும் முன்னாள் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சருமான GL Peiris ஏற்கனவே பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்பட்டு வந்த தமது கட்சியின் 13 உறுப்பினர்கள் தற்போது எதிர்க்கட்சியில் அமர்வார்கள் என அறிவித்த சில மணி நேரங்களிலேயே பிரேமதாச கிளர்ச்சியாளர் குழுவிற்கு தனது வாழ்த்துக்களை ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "SLPP இன் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி அணியை @sjbsrilanka அன்புடன் வரவேற்கிறது.",
        "இது ஜனநாயக விரோத அரசுக்கு எதிரான நமது போராட்டத்தில் நமது உறுதியை வலுப்படுத்தும். pic.twitter.com/V7Zj8yySWi",
        "இலங்கையின் எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாராளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் அண்மையில் வேட்பாளராகப் போட்டியிட்ட பிரேமதாசவின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்ற பிரேமதாச, SLPP மாத்தறை மாவட்டத் தலைவர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை வரவேற்கும் பிரேமதாசவின் படம் அந்த ட்வீட்டில் இருந்தது.",
        "225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட சபையில் 134 வாக்குகளால் வெற்றி பெற்ற அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் அழகப்பெரும தோல்வியடைந்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை தனது மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியின் கஷ்டங்களை எதிர்கொள்ளும் நிலையில், இடைக்கால சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு தேவையான பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்களைக் காண ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க மீண்டும் மீண்டும் அழைப்பு விடுத்து வருகிறார்.",
        "பிரேமதாசவின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) அமைச்சரவையில் இணையாமல், பாராளுமன்றக் குழுக்களின் ஊடாக அரசாங்கத்தின் சீர்திருத்த முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக தெரிவித்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், மூத்த SJB உறுப்பினர்கள் இந்த விஷயத்தில் சூடாகவும் குளிராகவும் இருப்பதாக ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர், சிலர் இன்னும் கைகளில் பங்கு வகிக்க ஆர்வமாக உள்ளனர்.",
        "பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கான ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் முன்மொழிவுகள் – இடைக்கால வரவுசெலவுத்திட்டத்தின் மூலம் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டது – நல்லதாக இருந்தபோதும், தற்போதைய SLPP தலைமையிலான மனப்பான்மை அதன் முற்றிலும் எதிர்க்கும் கொள்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவாக இருக்கும் என்று கற்பனை செய்வது கடினம் என்று SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா புதன்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டி சில்வாவின் கருத்துக்கள் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிர்பால டி சில்வாவை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கிண்டல் செய்ய தூண்டியது, SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், அவரது பொருளாதார வல்லமைக்காக பரவலாக கருதப்படுகிறார், \"அசாய் பயாய்\" அல்லது அவர் \"அதை விரும்புகிறார் ஆனால் அதை எடுக்க மிகவும் பயப்படுகிறார்\". (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ் &",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமான போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிர்பால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}