{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/protestors-storm-sri-lanka-prime-ministers-office-despite-police-resistance-97349/",
  "time_ut": 1657704000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protestors storm Sri Lanka Prime Minister’s Office despite police resistance",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protestors storm Sri Lanka Prime Minister’s Office despite police resistance",
      "author": "Neshella Perera and Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Protestors in Sri Lanka stormed the Prime Minister’s Office in Colombo, hours after President Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country and confusion over his resignation and the appointment of an acting president triggered a wave of protest.",
        "Thousands gathered onto Flower Road, Colombo, Wednesday July 13 morning met stiff resistance from police who fired teargas and water canon jets into the crowd, but the relentless protestors broke down a police barricade and made their way into the PM’s office premises by afternoon.",
        "The protestors are now occupying the PM’s office in addition to the President’s House, the PM’s official residence Temple Trees, and the Presidential Secretariat.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence was burnt down on Saturday July 09, though it unclear at present who was behind the incident. Protestors at the premier’s office, however, have blocked people from entering the premises to prevent property damage.",
        "Tens of thousands of protestors congregated in Colombo Fort that day in an attempt to force the ouster of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Rajapaksa has now fled to the Maldives, and PM Wickremesinghe has been appointed Acting President.",
        "It is possible that Wickreseminghe is both Sri Lanka’s Acting President and Prime Minister at present, according to attorney-at-law Gehan Gunatillake.",
        "Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena said the president will send in his resignation letter on Wednesday within the day and that a new president will be elected in parliament on July 20. (Colombo/Jul13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flower Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July 13 morning",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickreseminghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gehan Gunatillake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිසියේ ප්‍රතිරෝධය නොතකා විරෝධතාකරුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදී ඇත",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා සහ චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පලා ගොස් පැය කිහිපයකට පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදී ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීම පිළිබඳ ව්‍යාකූලත්වය විරෝධතා රැල්ලක් ඇති කළේය.",
        "ජුලි 13 බදාදා උදෑසන කොළඹ මල් පාරට රැස්ව සිටි දහස් ගණන් ජනතාව කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාරක ජෙට් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ පොලිසියේ දැඩි ප්‍රතිරෝධයට මුහුණ දුන් නමුත් ඉවක් බවක් නැති විරෝධතාකරුවෝ පොලිස් බාධකය බිඳ දමා දහවල් වන විට අගමැති කාර්යාල පරිශ්‍රයට පැමිණියහ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් දැන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට අමතරව අගමැති කාර්යාලය, අගමැති නිල නිවස අරලියගහ මන්දිරය සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අල්ලාගෙන සිටිති.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ජුලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා ගිනි තබා ඇතත්, සිද්ධිය පිටුපස සිටින්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න තවමත් පැහැදිලි නැත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අගමැති කාර්යාලයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් දේපල හානි වැළැක්වීම සඳහා පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළුවීම අවහිර කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා බලයෙන් පහ කිරීමට බලකරමින් දස දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් එදින කොළඹ කොටුවට රැස්ව සිටියහ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මේ වන විට මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගොස් ඇති අතර අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "නීතීඥ ගෙහාන් ගුණතිලක මහතාට අනුව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දැනට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති යන දෙකම විය හැකිය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් බදාදා දිනයේදී ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය එවන බවත් ජූලි 20 වැනි දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා බවත් කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල් පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෙහාන් ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொலிஸாரின் எதிர்ப்பையும் மீறி ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் இலங்கை பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டனர்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா மற்றும் சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய சில மணிநேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, இலங்கையில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டனர் மற்றும் அவரது ராஜினாமா மற்றும் செயல் ஜனாதிபதி நியமனம் குறித்த குழப்பம் எதிர்ப்பு அலையைத் தூண்டியது.",
        "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை காலை கொழும்பில் உள்ள மலர் வீதியில் ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோர் திரண்டிருந்த பொலிசாரின் கடுமையான எதிர்ப்பை எதிர்கொண்டனர், அவர்கள் கூட்டத்தின் மீது கண்ணீர்ப்புகை மற்றும் நீர் கேனான் ஜெட்களை வீசினர், ஆனால் இடைவிடாத எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் பொலிஸ் தடுப்புகளை உடைத்து பிற்பகலில் பிரதமர் அலுவலக வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்தனர்.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் இப்போது ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமான அலரிமாளிகை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் ஆகியவற்றிற்கு மேலதிகமாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 09 சனிக்கிழமையன்று பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் எரிக்கப்பட்டது, இந்த சம்பவத்தின் பின்னணியில் யார் இருக்கிறார்கள் என்பது தற்போது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை. எவ்வாறாயினும், முதல்வர் அலுவலகத்தில் போராட்டக்காரர்கள், சொத்து சேதத்தைத் தடுக்க மக்களை வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைய விடாமல் தடுத்தனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றுவதற்கான முயற்சியில் அன்றைய தினம் கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் குவிந்தனர்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச தற்போது மாலத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதால், பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கே தற்காலிக அதிபராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சட்டத்தரணி கெஹான் குணதிலக்கவின் கூற்றுப்படி, தற்போது விக்ரமசிங்கே இலங்கையின் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமராக இருப்பதற்கு சாத்தியம் உள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை நாளை புதன்கிழமை அனுப்பி வைப்பார் என்றும் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவார் என்றும் சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலர் சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை ஜூலை 13 காலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹான் குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}