{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131442",
  "time_ut": 1657791718,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை கலவரமாக்க ஒரு தரப்பு  முயற்சி -  வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One-sided attempt to turn people's protest into a riot - Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The people of the country are outraged by the appointment of Ranil Wickremesinghe as the acting president following the departure of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa. Commenting on the theory of democracy, the president should respect the aspirations of the people and step down.",
        "One party is trying to turn the people's protest into a riot, and the people participating in the protest should act with caution, said Vasudeva Nanayakkara, the leader of the Left Democratic Front in the Parliament.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is facing a crisis that no leader in Sri Lankan political history has ever faced.",
        "This situation would not have arisen for President Gotadabhaya Rajapaksa if he had taken appropriate action at the beginning regarding the wrong economic policy of former Finance Minister Bashil Rajapaksa.",
        "Because the former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa and President Gotabaya Rajapaksa did not take any action against Bashil Rajapaksa out of fraternal affection, the political future of the Rajapaksas has been completely destroyed and the future of the people of the country has also been affected.",
        "The main victory of the people's struggle is that the president has left the country following the people's fierce struggle.",
        "Following the appointment of Ranil Wickremesinghe as the acting president, the people have become angry and have been involved in protests.",
        "One party is trying to turn the people's protest into violence. The People's Liberation Front should be held responsible for the protest in the parliamentary constituency.",
        "As the responsible party when the country is in a state of unrest, they should cooperate to solve the crisis through the constitution rather than inciting the people.",
        "Commenting on the principle of democracy, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said that he should respect the aspirations of the people and step down from office and cooperate to advance the resolutions through the Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Left Democratic Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotadabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bashil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bashil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනතා විරෝධය කෝලාහලයක් බවට පත්කිරීමේ ඒකපාර්ශ්වික උත්සාහයක් - වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නික්ම යාමෙන් පසු වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කිරීම පිළිබඳව රටේ ජනතාව දැඩි කෝපයට පත්ව සිටිති. ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදයේ න්‍යාය ගැන අදහස් දක්වන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජනතා අභිලාෂයට ගරු කර ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් විය යුතුය.",
        "ජනතා විරෝධය කෝලාහලයක් බවට පත්කිරීමට එක් පාර්ශ්වයක් උත්සාහ කරන බවත්, විරෝධතාවට සහභාගි වන ජනතාව ප්‍රවේශමෙන් ක්‍රියා කළ යුතු බවත් වාමාංශික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පෙරමුණේ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ කිසිඳු නායකයෙකු මුහුණ නොදුන් අර්බුදයකට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මුහුණ දී සිටී.",
        "හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ වැරදි ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ආරම්භයේදීම නිසි ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගත්තේ නම් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට මේ තත්ත්වය උදා නොවනු ඇත.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහෝදර සෙනෙහසින් බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට එරෙහිව කිසිදු ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් නොගැනීම නිසා රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ දේශපාලන අනාගතය මුළුමනින්ම විනාශ වී ගොස් රටේ ජනතාවගේ අනාගතයටද බලපෑම් එල්ල වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "ජන අරගලයේ ප්‍රධාන ජයග්‍රහණය වන්නේ ජනතා උග්‍ර අරගලයෙන් පසු ජනාධිපතිවරයා රට හැර යාමයි.",
        "වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කිරීමත් සමඟ ජනතාව කෝපයට පත්වී විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරවල නිරතව සිටිති.",
        "එක පාර්ශ්වයක් මේ ජනතා විරෝධය ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයට පත් කරන්න හදනවා.පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාසයේ විරෝධතාවට මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ වගකියන්න ඕන.",
        "රට නොසන්සුන්තාවයකට පත්ව ඇති අවස්ථාවක වගකිවයුතු පාර්ශවය ලෙස ජනතාව උසිගැන්වීමට වඩා ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් අර්බුදය විසඳීමට සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කළ යුතුයි.",
        "ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදයේ මූලධර්මය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික‍්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප‍්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනතා අභිලාෂයන්ට ගරු කරමින් තමන් ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වී පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කළ යුතු බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை கலவரமாக்க ஒரு தரப்பு  முயற்சி -  வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதை தொடர்ந்து பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமையினால் நாட்டு மக்கள் ஆத்திரமடைந்துள்ளார்கள். ஜனநாயக கோட்பாடு தொடர்பில் கருத்துரைக்கும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டு மக்களின் அபிலாஷைக்கு மதிப்பளித்து பதவி விலக வேண்டும்.",
        "மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை கலவரமாக மாற்றியமைக்க ஒரு தரப்பினர் முயற்சிக்கிறார்கள், போராட்டத்தில் கலந்துக்கொள்ளும் மக்கள் அவதானத்துடன் செயற்பட வேண்டும் என இடதுசாரி ஜனநாயக முன்னணியின் தலைவர் பாராளுமன்ற இடதுசாரி ஜனநாயக முன்னணியின் தலைவர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் எத்தலைவர்களும் எதிர்கொள்ளாத நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பஷில் ராஜபக்ஷவின் தவறான பொருளாதார கொள்கை குறித்து உரிய நடவடிக்கையினை ஆரம்பத்தில் முன்னெடுத்திருந்தால் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாடபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு இந்நிலைமை தோற்றம் பெற்றிருக்காது.",
        "சகோதர பாசத்திற்காக கட்டுப்பட்டு பஷில் ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு எதிராக எவ்வித நடவடிக்கையினையும்,முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ எடுக்காத காரணத்தினால் ராஜபக்ஷர்களினது அரசியல் எதிர்காலம் முழுமையாக இல்லாதொழிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன்,நாட்டு மக்களின் எதிர்காலமும் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மக்களின் கடுமையாக போராட்டத்தை தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளமை மக்கள் போராட்டத்தின் பிரதான வெற்றியாகும்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமையினை தொடர்ந்து மக்கள் ஆத்திரமடைந்து போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுப்பட்டுள்ளார்கள்.",
        "மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை ஒரு தரப்பினர் வன்முறையாக மாற்றியமைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறார்கள்.பாராளுமன்ற சுற்றுவட்டத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற போராட்டத்திற்கு மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியினர் பொறுப்புக் கூற வேண்டும்.",
        "நாடு அமைதியற்ற நிலையில் உள்ள போது பொறுப்பாக கட்சி என்ற ரீதியில் மக்களை தூண்டி விடாமல் அரசியலமைப்பின் ஊடாக நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண அவர்கள் ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்க வேண்டும்.",
        "ஜனநாயக கோட்பாடு தொடர்பில் கருத்துரைக்கும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மக்களின் அபிலாசைகளுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து பதவி விலகி பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக தீர்மானங்களை முன்னெடுக்க ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்க வேண்டும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடது ஜனநாயக முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஷில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஷில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}