{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/26/token-system-for-fuel-delivery-from-monday-27/",
  "time_ut": 1656229260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Token system for fuel delivery from Monday (27)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Token system for fuel delivery from Monday (27)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka has decided to implement a token system dedicated for filling stations to supply fuel for motorists waiting in line to obtain Petrol & Diesel.",
        "Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera said the program will come into effect from Monday (27) and the assistance of Sri Lanka Police and Sri Lanka Army, Navy, and Air Force will be obtained to ensure the process is carried out smoothly.",
        "The Minister said the token will be awarded dedicated to filling stations, and it cannot be tampered with.",
        "Updating the press on the latest developments on delayed fuel shipments, the Minister said that four separate groups from the Ministry are working on Petrol, Diesel, Crude / Furnace Oil, and Jet Fuel imports.",
        "He said the teams are working on 130 plus proposals for fuel delivery to Sri Lanka.",
        "The Minister said the next 12 months will be a challenging period of Sri Lanka in terms of fuel delivery, adding that it may or may be not possible to completely eliminate the fuel queues.",
        "” USD 500 Million is something that Sri Lanka cannot bear at the moment. Therefore, consumption will have to be slashed to at least USD 350 Million and a system that will prioritize public transport will be introduced,” he said.",
        "Two ministers will fly to Russia on Monday (27) for discussion on fuel imports and related matters, said Minister Kanchana Wijesekera during the media briefing.",
        "The Minister said that bunker suppliers have been granted permission to deliver fuel for industries that deal in US currency established in Sri Lanka.",
        "The Minister said that overseas fuel companies based in countries that produce fuel will be invited to set up business in Sri Lanka, and CPC filling stations will be provided as the CPC alone cannot undertake the burden of importing fuel to Sri Lanka.",
        "He said the CPC will become a more service-provider based institution, to facilitate fuel imports."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Monday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol & Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petrol",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jet Fuel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next 12 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීමේ සංකේත පද්ධතිය සඳුදා (27) සිට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා පෝලිමේ රැඳී සිටින රියදුරන්ට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා පිරවුම්හල් සඳහා වෙන් වූ සංකේත ක්‍රමයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම වැඩසටහන සඳුදා (27) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත්, එම ක්‍රියාවලිය සුමටව සිදු කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද, නාවික සහ ගුවන් හමුදාවේ සහය ලබා ගන්නා බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් සඳහා මෙම ටෝකනය ප්‍රදානය කරන බවත්, එය කඩාකප්පල් කළ නොහැකි බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රමාද වූ ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් පිළිබඳ නවතම වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව පුවත්පත් යාවත්කාලීන කරමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසුවේ පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල්, බොර / උදුන් තෙල් සහ ජෙට් ඉන්ධන ආනයනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ වෙනම කණ්ඩායම් හතරක් කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා කණ්ඩායම් 130 කට වැඩි යෝජනා ක්‍රියාත්මක කරමින් සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඉදිරි මාස 12 ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අභියෝගාත්මක කාල පරිච්ඡේදයක් වනු ඇති බව පැවසූ අමාත්‍යවරයා, ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට හෝ නොහැකි වීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව පැවසීය.",
        "”ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මේ මොහොතේ දරාගත නොහැකි දෙයකි. ඒ නිසා පරිභෝජනය අවම වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 350 දක්වා කප්පාදු කිරීමට සිදුවනු ඇති අතර පොදු ප්‍රවාහනයට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දෙන ක්‍රමයක් හඳුන්වා දෙනවා.",
        "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය සහ ඒ ආශ්‍රිත කටයුතු පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු ලබන සඳුදා (27) රුසියාව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිත බව අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාපිත ඇමෙරිකානු මුදලින් ගණුදෙණු කරන කර්මාන්ත සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට බංකර් සැපයුම්කරුවන්ට අවසර ලබාදී ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන නිෂ්පාදනය කරන රටවල පිහිටි විදේශීය ඉන්ධන සමාගම්වලට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ව්‍යාපාර ආරම්භ කිරීමට ආරාධනා කරන බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමේ බර CPC ආයතනයට පමණක් දැරිය නොහැකි බැවින් CPC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් ලබාදෙන බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය පහසු කිරීම සඳහා CPC වඩාත් සේවා සපයන ආයතනයක් බවට පත් කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සඳුදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙට් ඉන්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்திற்கான டோக்கன் முறை திங்கட்கிழமை (27) முதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசலைப் பெற வரிசையில் காத்திருக்கும் வாகன ஓட்டிகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்வதற்காக எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையங்களுக்கு அர்ப்பணிக்கப்பட்ட டோக்கன் முறையை நடைமுறைப்படுத்த இலங்கை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த வேலைத்திட்டம் திங்கட்கிழமை (27) முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் எனவும், இந்த செயற்பாடுகள் சுமூகமாக நடைபெறுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக இலங்கை பொலிஸ் மற்றும் இலங்கை இராணுவம், கடற்படை மற்றும் விமானப்படை ஆகியவற்றின் உதவிகள் பெறப்படும் எனவும் மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த டோக்கன் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் என்றும், அதை சீர்குலைக்க முடியாது என்றும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "தாமதமான எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி குறித்த சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்கள் குறித்து செய்தியாளர்களுக்குப் புதுப்பித்த அமைச்சர், பெட்ரோல், டீசல், கச்சா / உலை எண்ணெய் மற்றும் ஜெட் எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதியில் அமைச்சகத்தின் நான்கு தனித்தனி குழுக்கள் பணியாற்றி வருவதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை விநியோகிப்பதற்கான 130 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட முன்மொழிவுகளில் குழுக்கள் பணியாற்றி வருவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் தொடர்பில் எதிர்வரும் 12 மாதங்கள் இலங்கைக்கு சவாலான காலகட்டமாக இருக்கும் எனத் தெரிவித்த அமைச்சர், எரிபொருள் வரிசைகளை முற்றாக நீக்குவது சாத்தியப்படாமலும் போகலாம் என்றும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "” 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் என்பது இலங்கையால் தற்போது தாங்க முடியாத ஒன்று. எனவே, நுகர்வு குறைந்தபட்சம் 350 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக குறைக்கப்பட வேண்டும், மேலும் பொதுப் போக்குவரத்திற்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கும் முறை அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்படும்,” என்றார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் அது தொடர்பான விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக இரண்டு அமைச்சர்கள் எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை (27) ரஷ்யாவிற்கு செல்லவுள்ளனர் என அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட அமெரிக்க நாணயத்தில் வர்த்தகம் செய்யும் தொழிற்சாலைகளுக்கு எரிபொருளை விநியோகிக்க பதுங்கு குழி விநியோகஸ்தர்களுக்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் உற்பத்தி செய்யும் நாடுகளில் உள்ள வெளிநாட்டு எரிபொருள் நிறுவனங்களை இலங்கையில் வர்த்தகம் செய்ய அழைக்கப்படும் என்றும், இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்யும் சுமையை CPC மட்டும் ஏற்க முடியாது என்பதால் CPC நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் வழங்கப்படும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதியை எளிதாக்கும் வகையில், CPC மேலும் சேவை வழங்கும் நிறுவனமாக மாறும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் & டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான எரிப்பொருள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 12 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}