{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-schedules-power-cuts-of-2-hours-20-mins-from-aug-30-sept-02-99149/",
  "time_ut": 1661777760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka schedules power cuts of 2 hours 20 mins from Aug 30 – Sept 02",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka schedules power cuts of 2 hours 20 mins from Aug 30 – Sept 02",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Power cuts of 2 hours and 20 minutes would be imposed on around Sri Lanka from August 30 to September 02, 2022 Public Utilities Commission Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said.",
        "Groups ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW will have one hour cuts during the daytime and 1 hour and 20 minutes of power cut during the night.",
        "Sri Lanka’s had power cuts increased to 3 hours from 0 hour in August after 300 MegaWatt coal plant went down.",
        "Related Sri Lanka may reduce power cuts after coal plant repair",
        "The CEB has said due to lack of fuel power, cuts cannot be reduced to one hour. (Colombo/Aug30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2 hours",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2 hours and 20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30 to September 02, 2022 Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Groups ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "daytime and 1 hour and 20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "0 hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MegaWatt",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අගෝස්තු 30 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 02 දක්වා පැය 2 විනාඩි 20 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සැලසුම් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - 2022 අගෝස්තු 30 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 02 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා පැය 2 යි විනාඩි 20 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් පනවන බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කණ්ඩායම් ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW දිවා කාලයේ දී පැයක් සහ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ දී පැය 1 යි විනාඩි 20 ක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "මෙගාවොට් 300ක ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරයක් කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු අගෝස්තු මාසයේ පැය 0 සිට පැය 3 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලි කප්පාදුව වැඩි විය.",
        "අදාළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරය අලුත්වැඩියා කිරීමෙන් පසු විදුලි කප්පාදුව අඩු කළ හැකිය",
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය පවසන්නේ ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් විදුලි කප්පාදුව පැයකට අඩු කළ නොහැකි බවයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැය 2",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය 2 යි විනාඩි 20 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 30 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 02 දක්වා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කණ්ඩායම් ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවා කාලය සහ පැය 1 විනාඩි 20 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 3",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 0 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙගාවොට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 02 வரை 2 மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடங்களுக்கு இலங்கையில் மின்வெட்டு",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ஆகஸ்ட் 30 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 02, 2022 வரை இலங்கை முழுவதும் 2 மணிநேரம் 20 நிமிடங்களுக்கு மின்வெட்டு அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் ஜானக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "குழுக்கள் ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW பகல் நேரத்தில் ஒரு மணிநேரம் மற்றும் இரவில் 1 மணிநேரம் 20 நிமிடங்கள் மின்வெட்டு இருக்கும்.",
        "300 மெகாவாட் நிலக்கரி ஆலை செயலிழந்த பின்னர் இலங்கையில் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 0 மணி நேரமாக இருந்த மின்வெட்டு 3 மணி நேரமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "தொடர்புடைய இலங்கை நிலக்கரி ஆலை பழுதுபார்க்கப்பட்ட பிறகு மின்வெட்டுகளை குறைக்கலாம்",
        "எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக மின்வெட்டை ஒரு மணித்தியாலமாக குறைக்க முடியாது என இலங்கை மின்சார சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2 மணி நேரம்",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2 மணி 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 02, 2022 பொதுப் பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழுக்கள் ABCDEFGHIJKLPQRSTUVW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பகல் நேரம் மற்றும் 1 மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "0 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}