{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මන්ත්‍රී-අමරකීර්ති-ඝාතනයට-තවත්-8-ක්-සොයයි/1-617260",
  "time_ut": 1659105323,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මන්ත්‍රී අමරකීර්ති ඝාතනයට තවත් 8 ක් සොයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "8 more are wanted for MP Amarakirthi's murder",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The CCTV footage of the killing of the Member of Parliament Mr. Amarakirthi Athukorala and three persons including his security police sergeant in Nittambuwa town on May 9th. The police are seeking public assistance to arrest 8 more persons identified through the footage.",
        "The police are publishing the photographs of the eight persons and asking the public to provide information about them to the Homicide and Organized Crime Investigation Division on 0112514217 (Director) or 0718592868 (Assistant Director).",
        "Regarding this incident, 35 suspects have been arrested and most of them have been arrested on CCTV. The police media division further says that they have been identified through the footage."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Amarakirthi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarakirthi Athukorala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nittambuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Organized Crime Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0718592868",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්ත්‍රී අමරකීර්ති ඝාතනයට තවත් 8 ක් සොයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරළ මහතා සහ ඔහුගේ ආරක්‍ෂක පොලිස් සැරයන්වරයකු ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනකු නිට්ටඹුව නගරයේදී පසුගිය මැයි මස 9 වැනිදා ඝාතනය කිරීමේ සිද්ධියේ සී.සී.ටී.වී. දර්ශන ඔස්සේ හදුනාගත් තවත් පුද්ගලයන් 8 ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පොලිසිය මහජන සහය පතයි.",
        "පොලිසිය එම පුද්ගලයන් අට දෙනාගේ ඡායාරූප ප්‍රසිද්ධ කරමින් ඔවුන් පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු මනුෂ්‍ය ඝාතන හා සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ විමර්ෂන කොට්ඨාෂයේ 0112514217 (අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ) හෝ 0718592868 (සහකාර අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ) දුරකථනවලට ලබාදෙන ලබාදෙන ලෙස ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්තනගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට කරුණු ඉදිරිපත්කර සැකකරුවන් 35 ක් මේ වන විට අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බවත් ඔවුන්ගෙන් බහුතරයක් සී.සී.ටී.වී. දර්ශන ඔස්සේ හදුනාගත් බවත් පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය කොට්ඨාසය වැඩි දුරටත් පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අමරකීර්ති",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිට්ටඹුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0718592868",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அமரகீர்த்தி கொலை வழக்கில் மேலும் 8 பேர் தேடப்பட்டு வருகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி நிட்டம்புவ நகரில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு. அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரள மற்றும் அவரது பாதுகாப்பு பொலிஸ் சார்ஜன்ட் உட்பட மூவர் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட சம்பவத்தின் CCTV காட்சிகள். இந்த காட்சிகள் மூலம் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட மேலும் 8 பேரை கைது செய்ய பொதுமக்களின் உதவியை போலீசார் நாடியுள்ளனர்.",
        "8 பேரின் புகைப்படங்களை வெளியிட்டு, அவர்களைப் பற்றிய தகவல்களை 0112514217 (இயக்குனர்) அல்லது 0718592868 (உதவிப் பணிப்பாளர்) என்ற தொலைபேசி இலக்கங்களுக்குத் தெரிவிக்குமாறு பொதுமக்களிடம் பொலிஸார் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் தொடர்பாக 35 சந்தேக நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன் அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலானோர் சிசிடிவியில் பதிவாகியுள்ளனர். காட்சிகள் மூலம் அவர்கள் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமரகீர்த்தி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிட்டம்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0718592868",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}