{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/14/british-mp-calls-for-international-arrest-warrant-against-gotabaya-rajapaksa/",
  "time_ut": 1657792140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "British MP Calls For International Arrest Warrant Against Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "British MP Calls For International Arrest Warrant Against Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "New Delhi: Sir Ed Davey, the chief of the Liberal Democrats, has demanded that a global arrest warrant ought to be issued in opposition to Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and his “cronies”.",
        "“The horrible state of affairs in Sri Lanka has been caused by the corruption of the Rajapaksa Authorities, tax cuts, skyrocketing defence expenditure and draconian police powers,” he was quoted by the media.",
        "Talking within the Home of Commons, Davey instructed that the UK works with worldwide companions for a full financial and political resolution to “assist the democrats in Sri Lanka,” which incorporates the issuance of an arrest warrant.",
        "British MP Calls For International Arrest Warrant Against Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
        "Russia “Responsible” For Ongoing Crisis In Sri Lanka: Ukraine’s Zelensky",
        "Army empowered to use force to protect lives & state property",
        "Two soldiers rendered unconscious in brutal attack in Battaramulla protest – Army"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "British",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ed Davey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liberal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democrats",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rajapaksa Authorities",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Home of Commons",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Davey",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "democrats",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Responsible",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zelensky",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මන්ත්‍රී ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට එරෙහිව ජාත්‍යන්තර වරෙන්තුවක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවදිල්ලිය: ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ ඔහුගේ “ගෝලබාලයන්ට” එරෙහිව ගෝලීය අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුවක් නිකුත් කළ යුතු බව ලිබරල් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධානී ශ්‍රීමත් එඩ් ඩේවි ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බිහිසුණු තත්ත්වයට හේතු වී ඇත්තේ රාජපක්ෂ බලධාරීන්ගේ දූෂණය, බදු කප්පාදුව, අහස උසට නැඟෙන ආරක්‍ෂක වියදම් සහ කුරිරු පොලිස් බලතල නිසා,” ඔහු මාධ්‍ය විසින් උපුටා දක්වන ලදී.",
        "හොම් ඔෆ් කොමන්ස් තුළ කතා කරමින්, ඩේවි, අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුවක් නිකුත් කිරීම ඇතුළත් “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදීන්ට සහාය වීම” සඳහා පූර්ණ මූල්‍ය හා දේශපාලන යෝජනාවක් සඳහා ලෝක ව්‍යාප්ත සහචරයන් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන ලෙසට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මන්ත්‍රී ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට එරෙහිව ජාත්‍යන්තර වරෙන්තුවක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින අර්බුද සම්බන්ධයෙන් රුසියාව \"වගකීම\": යුක්රේනයේ සෙලෙන්ස්කි",
        "ජීවිත සහ රාජ්‍ය දේපළ ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා බලය යෙදවීමට හමුදාවට බලය ලැබී ඇත",
        "බත්තරමුල්ල විරෝධතාවයේ දී ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රහාරයකින් හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනෙක් සිහිසුන් වෙති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩ් ඩේවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදීන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ බලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදීන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගකිව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලෙන්ස්කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு எதிராக சர்வதேச கைது வாரண்ட் வழங்குமாறு பிரித்தானிய எம்.பி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதுடெல்லி: இலங்கை அதிபர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் அவரது கூட்டாளிகளுக்கு எதிராக உலகளாவிய கைது வாரண்ட் பிறப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று லிபரல் டெமாக்ராட் கட்சியின் தலைவர் சர் எட் டேவி கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "\"ராஜபக்சே அதிகாரிகளின் ஊழல், வரி குறைப்பு, உயரும் பாதுகாப்பு செலவுகள் மற்றும் கொடூரமான போலீஸ் அதிகாரங்கள் ஆகியவற்றால் இலங்கையில் பயங்கரமான நிலைமை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது\" என்று அவர் ஊடகங்களால் மேற்கோள் காட்டினார்.",
        "ஹோம் ஆஃப் காமன்ஸில் பேசிய டேவி, \"இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஜனநாயகவாதிகளுக்கு உதவுவதற்கு\" ஒரு முழுமையான நிதி மற்றும் அரசியல் தீர்மானத்திற்காக உலகளாவிய தோழர்களுடன் இணைந்து இங்கிலாந்து பணியாற்ற வேண்டும் என்று அறிவுறுத்தினார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு எதிராக சர்வதேச கைது வாரண்ட் வழங்குமாறு பிரித்தானிய எம்.பி",
        "இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடிக்கு ரஷ்யா \"பொறுப்பு\": உக்ரைனின் ஜெலென்ஸ்கி",
        "உயிர்கள் மற்றும் அரச சொத்துக்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கு இராணுவத்தைப் பயன்படுத்த அதிகாரம் பெற்றுள்ளது",
        "பத்தரமுல்ல ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கொடூர தாக்குதலில் இராணுவத்தினர் இருவர் மயக்கமடைந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட் டேவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகவாதிகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ச அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமன்ஸ் இல்லம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகவாதிகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொறுப்பு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெலென்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}