{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84646/another-petition-against-sanath-nishantha-over-contempt-of-court",
  "time_ut": 1661864700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Another petition against Sanath Nishantha over contempt of court",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another petition against Sanath Nishantha over contempt of court",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Another petition has been filed before the Court of Appeal requesting the court to punish SLPP Puttlam District Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha on charges of contempt of court.",
        "Attorney-at-law Vijith Kumara has filed the petition naming MP Nishantha as the respondent of the petition.",
        "On Monday (Aug 29), Attorney-at-Law Priyalal Sirisena filed a petition against MP Nishantha seeking punishment for contempt of court, while the Attorney General, the Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) and MP Sanath Nishantha were named as respondents in the petition.",
        "MP Nishantha was named as a suspect in the case filed by the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) before the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court in connection with the incident of attacking the GotaGoGama protest site at Galle Face Green on May 09. He has been released on bail after being remanded in custody by the Colombo Fort Magistrate with regard to the incident.",
        "He emphasized in the petition that the respondent Sanath Nishantha, who spoke to the media at a media conference held at the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) party headquarters on August 23, had expressed critical views on the manner in which the magistrates acted in granting bail to the suspects involved in the ‘Aragalaya’ protest movement.",
        "The attorney had added that the MP has damaged the honour and the image of the judiciary."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Aragalaya’",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සනත් නිශාන්තට එරෙහිව තවත් පෙත්සමක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්තට දඬුවම් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා තවත් පෙත්සමක් අභියාචනාධිකරණය හමුවේ ගොනු කර තිබේ.",
        "නිශාන්ත මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරු ලෙස නම් කරමින් නීතීඥ විජිත් කුමාර මහතා විසින් මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කර ඇත.",
        "සඳුදා (අගෝස්තු 29) නීතීඥ ප්‍රියලාල් සිරිසේන මන්ත්‍රී නිශාන්තට එරෙහිව අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දඬුවම් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කළ අතර එහි වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස නීතිපතිවරයා, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත නම් කර ඇත. පෙත්සම.",
        "පසුගිය මැයි 09 වැනිදා ගාලුමුවදොර ගෝඨාගොගම විරෝධතා ස්ථානයට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය හමුවේ ගොනුකළ නඩුවේ සැකකරුවෙකු ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නිශාන්ත නම් කර තිබේ. සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා විසින් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 23 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකදී මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දැක්වූ වගඋත්තරකාර සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා, මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරුන් ලබා දීමට කටයුතු කළ ආකාරය පිළිබඳව විවේචනාත්මක අදහස් පළ කළ බව ඔහු පෙත්සමෙන් අවධාරණය කළේය. අරගලය විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවන්ට ඇප.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අධිකරණයේ ගෞරවයට හා ප්‍රතිරූපයට හානි කර ඇති බව නීතිඥවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලුමුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'අරගලය'",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாக சனத் நிஷாந்தவுக்கு எதிராக மேலும் ஒரு மனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் புத்தளம் மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவை தண்டிக்குமாறு கோரி மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றில் மற்றுமொரு மனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனுவின் பிரதிவாதியாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நிஷாந்தவை பெயரிட்டு சட்டத்தரணி விஜித் குமார இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 29) நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றத்திற்காக எம்.பி நிஷாந்தவுக்கு எதிராக சட்டத்தரணி பிரியலால் சிறிசேன மனு தாக்கல் செய்த நிலையில், சட்டமா அதிபர், இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த ஆகியோர் பிரதிவாதிகளாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர். மனு.",
        "மே 09ஆம் திகதி காலிமுகத்திடலில் உள்ள கோட்டகோகம போராட்டத் தளத்தை தாக்கிய சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தினால் (CID) கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கில் சந்தேக நபராக நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நிஷாந்த குறிப்பிடப்பட்டிருந்தார். சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவானால் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தில் ஆகஸ்ட் 23ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த பிரதிவாதி சனத் நிஷாந்த, நீதவான்கள் வழங்கிய விதம் தொடர்பில் விமர்சனக் கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்டதாக அவர் மனுவில் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார். அரகலய போராட்ட இயக்கத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட சந்தேக நபர்களுக்கு பிணை.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நீதித்துறையின் கெளரவத்தையும் நற்பெயரையும் சேதப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக சட்டத்தரணி மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'அரகலயா'",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}