{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/සජිත්-අනුප්‍රාප්තික-ජනපති-කරන-යෝජනාව-සජබය-ඒකමතිකව-ස්ථිර-කරයි/11-395343",
  "time_ut": 1657556150,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත් අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනපති කරන යෝජනාව සජබය ඒකමතිකව ස්ථිර කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajabaya unanimously approves the proposal made by Sajith as the successor president",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The members of Samagi Jana Balawega unanimously passed resolutions to nominate Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the leader of the opposition, for the post of the next president.",
        "In this regard, the resolution was brought by the General Secretary of the party Mr. Ranjith Maddumabandara and it was confirmed by the president of the party Mr. Field Marshal Sarath Fonseka.",
        "The MP group meeting of Samagi Jana Balawega and Samagi Jana Sanandha is currently being held at the office of the opposition leader in Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Field",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනපති කරන යෝජනාව සජබය ඒකමතිකව ස්ථිර කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාව අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා යෝජනා කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම ඒකමතිකව යෝජනා ස්තීර කර ගත්තේය.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳව යෝජනාව පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් රංජිත්  මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා විසින් ගෙන ආ අතර පක්ෂයේ සභාපති ෆීල්ඩ්මාර්ෂල් සරත් ෆොන්සේකා මහතා විසින් එය ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබීය.එම යෝජනා ස්ථිරත්වය සමස්ත මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම විසින් ඒකමතිකව සම්මත කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ සහ සමගි ජන සන්ධානයේ මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම් රැස්වීම මේ වන විට කොළඹ විපක්ෂනායක කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්ෂේත්රය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வாரிசு ஜனாதிபதியாக சஜித் முன்வைத்த பிரேரணைக்கு சஜபய ஏகமனதாக ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை நியமிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேக உறுப்பினர்கள் ஏகமனதாக தீர்மானங்களை நிறைவேற்றினர்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் திரு.ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டாரவினால் தீர்மானம் கொண்டு வரப்பட்டதுடன், அதனை கட்சியின் தலைவர் பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் சரத் பொன்சேகா உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேக மற்றும் சமகி ஜன சனந்த ஆகிய கட்சிகளின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குழு கூட்டம் தற்போது கொழும்பில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்று வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}