{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කුඩු-කිලෝ-02ක්-සමග-කාන්තාවක්-මාට්ටූ/11-396895",
  "time_ut": 1662365554,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කුඩු කිලෝ 02ක් සමග කාන්තාවක් මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A woman was killed with 02 kilos of drug",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Anuradhapura headquarters police said that a woman was arrested today (5th) along with more than 2 kilos of heroin worth more than five crore rupees, which is the largest haul of heroin drugs ever seized by the Anuradhapura police.",
        "Police say that the person arrested was a 26-year-old Dravidian woman who was residing in a line room in Elugolla Watta area of ​​Rangala Police Domain, Kandy.",
        "According to a statement given by the suspect who was a resident of Kottawa area who was engaged in cloth trade near Anuradhapura Hospital, who was arrested yesterday (4th) at Bhatia Mawatha, Anuradhapura, with 630 grams of heroin, the police said that the suspect was arrested along with this heroin.",
        "According to the information of the suspect, a group of officers from the anti-corruption division of the Anuradhapura headquarters police went to the Rangala area of ​​Kandy and arrested the suspect along with two kilos and 10 grams of heroin, and it was revealed that she was the sister-in-law of the first suspect who was arrested yesterday (4th) in Anuradhapura. .",
        "Police say that the suspect's 28-year-old husband was also killed in a shooting by a group of drug dealers in Theldeniya area of ​​Kandy last April.",
        "The police say that the statements made by the suspect have been recorded that after the death of her husband, the first suspect, who is her brother-in-law, brought one kilo of this heroin drug stock, which was hidden in the line room, to Anuradhapura.",
        "The arrested suspect was to be produced before the Anuradhapura Magistrate Court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "02",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravidian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elugolla Watta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bhatia Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "630",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rangala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theldeniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුඩු කිලෝ 02ක් සමග කාන්තාවක් මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අනුරාධපුර පොලිසිය මගින් මෙතෙක්  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් විශාලම හෙරොයින් මත්කුඩු තොගය වන රුපියල් කෝටි පහකට වැඩි හෙරොයින් මත්කුඩු කිලෝ 2  කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් සමග  කාන්තාවක් අද ( 5දා) අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව අනුරාධපුර මූලස්ථාන පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ, මහනුවර රංගල පොලිස් වසමේ එළුගොල්ල  වත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ ලයින් කාමරයක පදිංචිව සිටි 26 හැවිරිදි ද්‍රවිඩ  ජාතික කාන්තාවක් බව පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "අනුරාධපුර විජයපුර, භාතිය මාවතේදී ඊයේ (4දා)  හෙරොයින් මත්කුඩු ග්‍රෑම් 630 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් සමග අත්අඩංගුවට ගත්, අනුරාධපුර රෝහල ආසන්නයේ රෙදි වෙළෙඳාමේ නිරතව සිටි කොට්ටාව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි සැකකරු ලබා දුන් ප්‍රකාශයකට අනුව මෙම හෙරොයින් මත්කුඩු තොගය සමග සැකකාරිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලීසිය පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සැකකරුගේ තොරතුරු වලට අනුව අනුරාධපුර මූලස්ථාන පොලිසියේ දූෂණ මර්දන අංශයේ නිලධාරීහු පිරිසක්  මහනුවර රංගල ප්‍රදේශයට ගොස්, හෙරොයින්  මත් කුඩු කිලෝ දෙකයි ග්‍රෑම් 10ක ප්‍රමාණයක් සමග මෙම සැකකාරිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවත්, ඇය ඊයේ (4දා) අනුරාධපුරයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පළමු සැකකරුගේ නෑනා බවට අනාවරණය වූ බවද පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එම සැකකාරියගේ 28 හැවිරිදි වියේ පසුවූ සැමියා ද පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් මස මහනුවර තෙල්දෙණිය ප්‍රදේශයේදී මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම් කරුවන් පිරිසක් සිදු කළ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇති බවද පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "තම සැමියා ජීවත්ව සිටියදී රැගෙන විත්, ලයින් කාමරය තුළ සඟවා තිබූ මෙම හෙරොයින් මත්කුඩු තොගයෙන් කිලෝ එකක ප්‍රමාණයක් සැමියා මිය යෑමෙන් අනතුරුව මස්සිනා වන පළමු සැකකරු අනුරාධපුරයට රැගෙන ආ බවද  සැකකාරිය සිදු කළ ප්‍රකාශ වල සටහන් බව පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකාරිය අනුරාධපුර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "02",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 ට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එළුගොල්ල වත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාතිය මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "630",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 10 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙල්දෙණිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "02 கிலோ போதைப்பொருளுடன் பெண் ஒருவர் கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அநுராதபுரம் பொலிஸாரினால் இதுவரை கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட அதிகளவான ஹெரோயின் போதைப்பொருளான ஐந்து கோடி ரூபாவிற்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான 2 கிலோவிற்கும் அதிகமான ஹெரோயினுடன் பெண் ஒருவர் இன்று (5ம் திகதி) கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக அனுராதபுரம் தலைமையக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர் கண்டி, ரங்கல பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட எழுகொல்ல வத்த பகுதியில் உள்ள லைன் அறையில் வசித்த 26 வயதான திராவிடப் பெண் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "630 கிராம் ஹெரோயினுடன் அனுராதபுரம் பாட்டியா மாவத்தையில் வைத்து நேற்று (4ஆம் திகதி) கைது செய்யப்பட்ட அனுராதபுரம் வைத்தியசாலைக்கு அருகில் துணி வியாபாரத்தில் ஈடுபட்டு வந்த கொட்டாவ பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சந்தேகநபர் வழங்கிய வாக்குமூலத்தின் பிரகாரம் சந்தேகநபர் இந்த ஹெரோயினுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபரின் தகவலுக்கு அமைய அனுராதபுரம் தலைமையக பொலிஸ் பிரிவின் ஊழல் ஒழிப்பு பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று கண்டி ரங்கல பகுதிக்கு சென்று சந்தேக நபரை இரண்டு கிலோ 10 கிராம் ஹெரோயினுடன் கைது செய்த போது தெரியவந்துள்ளது. அநுராதபுரத்தில் நேற்று (4ஆம் திகதி) கைது செய்யப்பட்ட முதலாவது சந்தேக நபரின் மைத்துனர் அவர்.",
        "கடந்த ஏப்ரல் மாதம் கண்டி தெல்தெனிய பிரதேசத்தில் போதைப்பொருள் வியாபாரிகள் குழுவினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் சந்தேகநபரின் 28 வயதான கணவரும் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "கணவரின் மரணத்தின் பின்னர் லைன் அறையில் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த ஒரு கிலோ ஹெரோயின் போதைப்பொருளை அவரது மைத்துனரான முதலாவது சந்தேக நபர் கொண்டு வந்ததாக சந்தேகநபரின் வாக்குமூலங்கள் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர். , அனுராதபுரத்திற்கு.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர் அனுராதபுரம் நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "02",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்துக்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிடம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எழுகொல்ல வத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாட்டியா மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "630",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரங்கலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெல்தெனிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}