{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/மலையகம்/மயானத்தில்-அடக்கம்-செய்ய-அனுமதி/76-302620",
  "time_ut": 1660898466,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மயானத்தில் அடக்கம் செய்ய அனுமதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Burial is allowed in the cemetery",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A resolution has been unanimously passed in the Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha to continue to use the burial ground which has been used for the burial of the dead by the people of Vanaraja area - Darawala Colony under the Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha.",
        "The monthly meeting of the Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha was held yesterday (18) under the chairmanship of the Chairman of the Council, Mr. Ravi Kuddavelu, at Dinsin Mandapam.",
        "During this, Samarvil Local Member M. Ramachandran presented a special motion regarding Hatton-Tikoya Municipal Council's refusal to allow the bodies of the dead to be buried in the public cemetery, which has been used by the people of Darawala Kolani under Vanaraja District for burying their dead.",
        "It is saddening that Hatton – Dikoya Municipal Council Chairman and Dikoya District Municipal Council member could not give permission to bury the body of Kathirvel who died yesterday (17) evening in the public cemetery where the people were burying the deceased in Darawala Colony under the jurisdiction of Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha.",
        "The Norwood Parish Council should provide appropriate redress to Annarath's family who have been affected by this inhuman act.",
        "The victims told me that while arrangements have been made for cremation of the body of the deceased today (18) at 03 in the evening, it is now 11.30 a.m. Till this time Hatton-Tikoya Municipal Council has refused permission to cut a burial pit in the burial ground and there are only three and a half hours left.",
        "Burial land can be transferred to the local council or city council and cannot be owned. On behalf of the Norwood Parish Council, I express my strong condemnation of this action by the Hutton-Tikoya City Council and express my condolences to the affected family.",
        "He said that the said graveyard is an area under the jurisdiction of Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha, so Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha is allowing the use of the cemetery which has been used by the people of Darawala Colony until now and today I am giving permission to bury Anna's body in the same graveyard.",
        "After this was supported by all the members who participated in the meeting, the resolution was passed that the people of Darawala Colony under Vanaraja will continue to use the same burial ground."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ravi Kuddavelu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinsin Mandapam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samarvil Local",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Ramachandran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton-Tikoya Municipal Council's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darawala Kolani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hatton – Dikoya Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dikoya District Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Norwood Parish Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03 in the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.30 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton-Tikoya Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three and a half hours",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Norwood Parish Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hutton-Tikoya City Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darawala Colony",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Darawala Colony",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vanaraja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සුසාන භූමියේ මිහිදන් කිරීමට අවසර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවට අයත් වනරාජ ප්‍රදේශය - දරවල ජනපදයේ ජනතාව විසින් මළවුන්ගේ දේහයන් මිහිදන් කිරීම සඳහා භාවිත කර ඇති සොහොන් බිම තවදුරටත් භාවිත කිරීමට නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේදී යෝජනාවක් ඒකමතිකව සම්මත වී තිබේ.",
        "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ මාසික රැස්වීම ඊයේ (18) සභාවේ සභාපති රවී කුඩ්ඩවේලු මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ඩින්සින් මණ්ඩපයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මේ අතර වනරාජා දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට අයත් දරවල කොලනි ප්‍රදේශයේ ජනතාව මිහිදන් කිරීමට භාවිත කරන පොදු සුසාන භූමියේ මියගිය අයගේ සිරුරු මිහිදන් කිරීමට හැටන් - තික්ඔය නගර සභාව අවසර නොදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමර්විල් ප්‍රාදේශීය මන්ත්‍රී එම්.රාමචන්ද්‍රන් මහතා විශේෂ යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය. ඔවුන්ගේ මළවුන්.",
        "හැටන් - දික්ඔය නගර සභා බල ප්‍රදේශයට අයත් දරවල ජනපදයේ ජනතාව මිහිදන් කරමින් සිටි පොදු සුසාන භූමියේ ඊයේ (17) සවස මියගිය කතිර්වේල්ගේ දේහය මිහිදන් කිරීමට හැටන් - දික්ඔය නගර සභාවේ සභාපති දික්ඔය දිස්ත්‍රික් නගර සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට අවසර ලබා දීමට නොහැකි වීම කණගාටුවට කරුණක්. නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ.",
        "මෙම අමානුෂික ක්‍රියාවෙන් විපතට පත් අන්නාරත්ගේ පවුලට නොර්වුඩ් පළාත් සභාව විසින් නිසි පිළියමක් සලසා දිය යුතුය.",
        "මියගිය අයගේ දේහය අද (18) සවස 03 ට ආදාහනය කිරීමට කටයුතු සූදානම් කර තිබියදී මේ වන විට පෙරවරු 11.30 පමණ වන අතර මේ වනතුරු හැටන් - තික්ඔය නගර සභාව මිහිදන් වළක් කැපීමට අවසර ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති බව විපතට පත්වූවන් මා සමග ප්‍රකාශ කළා. සොහොන් බිම සහ ඉතිරිව ඇත්තේ පැය තුනහමාරක් පමණි.",
        "සුසාන භූමිය ප්රාදේශීය සභාවට හෝ නගර සභාවට පැවරිය හැකි අතර එය අයිති කර ගත නොහැක. නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව වෙනුවෙන් හුටන්-ටික්ඔය නගර සභාවේ මෙම ක්‍රියාව දැඩි පිළිකුලෙන් යුතුව හෙළා දකින අතර විපතට පත් පවුලට මාගේ ශෝකය ප්‍රකාශ කරමි.",
        "ඉහත කී සොහොන් බිම නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා බල ප්‍රදේශයට අයත් ප්‍රදේශයක් බැවින් දරවල ජනපදයේ ජනතාව මෙතෙක් භාවිත කළ සුසාන භූමිය නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශිය සභාව විසින් භාවිත කිරීමට ඉඩ ලබා දෙන බවත් ඇනාගේ දේහය මිහිදන් කිරීමට අද මම අවසර දෙන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. එකම සොහොන් පිටියේ.",
        "මෙයට සහභාගි වූ සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සහයෝගය ලැබුණු පසු වනරාජා යටතේ ඇති දරවල ජනපදයේ ජනතාව තවදුරටත් එම සොහොන් බිම භාවිත කරන බවට යෝජනාව සම්මත විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවී කුඩ්ඩවේලු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින්සින් මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමර්විල් දේශීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් රාමචන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්-ටික්ඔය නගර සභාවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරවල කොලනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැටන් – දික්ඔය නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දික්ඔය දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොර්වුඩ් පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 03 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.30 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්-ටික්ඔය නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය තුනහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුටන්-ටික්ඔය නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරවල ජනපදය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇනා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දරවල ජනපදය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மயானத்தில் அடக்கம் செய்ய அனுமதி",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபைக்கு உட்பட்ட வனராஜா வட்டாரம் – தரவளை கொலனி வாழ் மக்கள், இறந்தவர்களை நல்லடக்கம் செய்வதற்காக இதுவரை காலமும் பயன்படுத்திய மயான பூமியை தொடர்ந்து பயன்படுத்த நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபையில் ஏகமானதாக தீர்மானம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நோர்வூட் பிரதேசசபையின் மாதாந்த சபையமர்வு    டின்சின் மண்டபத்தில் சபைத்தலைவர்  ரவி குழந்தைவேலு தலைமையில் நேற்று (18) இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இதன் போது சமர்வில் வட்டார உறுப்பினர் மு.இராமச்சந்திரன், வனராஜா வட்டாரத்திற்கு உட்பட்ட தரவளை கொலனி மக்கள் இறந்தவர்களை நல்லடக்கம் செய்வதற்காக இதுவரை காலமும் பயன்படுத்தி வந்த பொது மயான பூமியில்  இறப்பவர்களின் உடலை நல்லடக்கம் செய்ய ஹட்டன் – டிக்கோயா நகரசபை அனுமதி மறுத்துள்ளமை தொடர்பில், விசேட பிரேரணையை முன் வைத்து உரையாற்றினார்.",
        "நோர்வூட் பிரதேசசபை அதிகார எல்லைக்கு உட்பட்ட  வனராஜா வட்டாரத்திற்கு உட்பட்ட தரவளை கொலனியில் வாழ் மக்கள் அங்கு உயிரிழந்தவர்களை நல்லடக்கம் செய்து வந்த பொது மயானத்தில், நேற்று (17)   மாலை மரணமான கதிர்வேல்  என்பவரின் உடலை நல்லடக்கம் செய்ய ஹட்டன் – டிக்கோயா நகரசபை தலைவர் மற்றும் டிக்கோயா வட்டார நகரசபை உறுப்பினரும்  அனுமதி  வழங்க முடியாதென  மறுத்துள்ளமை வேதனையளிக்கிறது.",
        "இந்த மனிதாபிமானம் அற்ற செயலால் பாதிப்படைந்துள்ள அன்னாரது குடும்பத்திற்கு நோர்வூட் பிரதேசசபை உரிய தீர்வினை பெற்றுக்கொடுக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "மரணமானவரின் உடல் இன்று (18) மாலை 03 மணிக்கு நல்லடக்கம் செய்ய ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில் இப்போது நேரம் காலை 11. 30 இந் நேரம் வரை  மயான பூமியில் புதை குழி வெட்டுவதற்கு  ஹட்டன் – டிக்கோயா நகரசபை  நல்லடக்கம்  செய்ய  அனுமதி மறுத்துள்ளதாகவும் இன்னும் மூன்றரை மணித்தியாலங்களே   உள்ளதென என்னிடம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர் என்றார்.",
        "மயான பூமியை பிரதேசசபை அல்லது நகரசபை பரமாரிப்புகளை செய்யலாமே தவிர சொந்தம் கொண்டாட முடியாது.   ஹட்டன் – டிக்கோயா நகரசபையின் இந்த நடவடிக்கைக்கு எனது வன்மையான கண்டனத்தை தெரிவித்துக்கொள்வதோடு பாதிக்கப்பட்ட குடும்பத்திற்கு நோர்வூட் பிரதேசசபையின் சார்பாக   எனது வருத்ததை தெரிவித்துக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "குறித்த மயான பூமி நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபை எல்லைக்கு உட்பட்ட பகுதி ஆகவே  இதுவரை காலமும் தரவளை கொலனி வாழ் மக்கள் பயன்படுத்திய மயானத்தை தொடர்ந்து பயன்படுத்த நோர்வூட் பிரதேசசபை அனுமதியளிக்கிறது என்பதோடு இன்றைய தினமும் அதே மயான பூமியில் அன்னாரது உடலை நல்லடக்கம் செய்ய அனுமதியளிக்கிறேன்  என்றார் .",
        "இதனை சபையமர்வில் கலந்து கொண்ட அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களும்  ஆதரித்ததையடுத்து  வனராஜா வட்டாரத்திற்கு உட்பட்ட தரவளை கொலனி வாழ் மக்கள் இனியும் தொடர்ந்து அவர்கள் பயன்படுத்திய அதே மயான பூமியை பயன்படுத்த ஏகமானதாக தீர்மானம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டடது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவி குட்டவேலு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தின்சின் மண்டபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமர்வில் உள்ளூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ராமச்சந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்-டிக்கோயா மாநகர சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரவல கொலனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன் – டிக்கோயா நகரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிக்கோயா மாவட்ட மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரவாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் திருச்சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 03",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 11.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்-டிக்கோயா மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றரை மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பாரிஷ் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்-டிக்கோயா நகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரவாலா காலனி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அண்ணா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தரவாலா காலனி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}