{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/චීන-තානාපති-හා-විදෙස්-ඇමති-අතර-හමුවක්/11-395839",
  "time_ut": 1659022249,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීන තානාපති හා විදෙස් ඇමති අතර හමුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A meeting between the Chinese ambassador and the foreign minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A meeting has been held between the Minister of Foreign Affairs Mr. Ali Sabri and the Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Mr. Chi Shenhong. The meeting was held at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.",
        "At the beginning, Ambassador Shenhong congratulated the Foreign Minister on his new appointment and also handed over the congratulatory message of the State Councilor and Foreign Minister of China Mr. Wang.",
        "The Minister of Foreign Affairs stated that Sri Lanka and China are traditional friends with long-term bilateral and economic relations. Both sides expressed great satisfaction over the strong bilateral relations, including the existing relations between governments and people-to-people.",
        "Senior officials of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and officials of the Chinese Embassy also participated in the meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Councilor",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන තානාපති හා විදෙස් ඇමති අතර හමුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මහතා හා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති චී ෂෙන්හොන්ග් මහතා අතර හමුවක් පවත්වා තිබේ. විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී මෙම හමුව පැවැත්විණ.",
        "ආරම්භයේදීම, විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ නව පත්වීම පිළිබඳව සුබ පැතුම් එක් කළ තානාපති ෂෙන්හොන්ග් මහතා රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රණ සභික සහ චීනයේ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය වැංග් මහතාගේ සුබපැතුම් පණිවුඩය ද භාර දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ චීනය දීර්ඝ කාලීන ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහ ආර්ථික සබඳතා සහිත සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍ර රටවල් වන බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. රජයන් අතර සහ ජනතාවන් අතර පවත්නා සම්බන්ධතා ඇතුළු ශක්තිමත් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා පිළිබඳව දෙපාර්ශ්වයම ඉමහත් තෘප්තිය පළ කළහ.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් සහ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ නිලධාරීන් ද මෙම හමුව සඳහා සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මන්ත්රණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனத் தூதுவருக்கும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சருக்கும் இடையில் சந்திப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் திரு அலி சப்ரி மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர் திரு சி ஷென்ஹோங் ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் சந்திப்பொன்று இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது. வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சில் இந்த சந்திப்பு இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "தொடக்கத்தில், தூதுவர் ஷென்ஹாங், வெளியுறவு அமைச்சரின் புதிய நியமனத்திற்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்ததோடு, சீன அரச கவுன்சிலரும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சருமான திரு.வாங்கின் வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியையும் கையளித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையும் சீனாவும் நீண்டகால இருதரப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார உறவுகளை கொண்ட பாரம்பரிய நண்பர்கள் என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அரசாங்கங்கள் மற்றும் மக்களிடையே தற்போதுள்ள உறவுகள் உட்பட வலுவான இருதரப்பு உறவுகள் குறித்து இரு தரப்பினரும் மிகுந்த திருப்தியை வெளிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் உயர் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் சீன தூதரக அதிகாரிகளும் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில கவுன்சிலர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}