{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/sri-lanka-navy-seizes-indian-trawler-during-weekend/",
  "time_ut": 1661741280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Navy seizes Indian trawler during weekend",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Navy seizes Indian trawler during weekend",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy on the night of 27th August 2022 conducted a special operation to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in the island's waters.",
        "The operation led to the seizure of an Indian trawler with 06 Indian fishermen while poaching in Sri Lanka’s waters off Talaimannar, via the International Maritime Boundary Line (IMBL).",
        "The Navy continues to carry out regular patrols in the island's waters to prevent illegal fishing practices by foreign fishermen, intending to curb its impact on the local fishing community as well as the damage it causes to the marine environment of the country.",
        "In this special operation mounted by the North Central Naval Command to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in Sri Lanka’s waters, via the IMBL, the apprehension was made by the Fast Attack Craft attached to the Northern Naval Command on 27th August.",
        "In this operation, the Navy seized an Indian poaching trawler remaining off Talaimannar, with 06 Indian fishermen and their fishing gears.",
        "The Indian trawler and 06 Indian fishermen held by the Navy are in naval custody in Talaimannar as of now and they will be handed over to the Fisheries Inspector of Mannar for onward legal action.",
        "In a similar operation conducted on 22nd August, the Navy held an Indian poaching trawler with 10 Indian fishers off Mullaitivu and produced them for legal proceedings.",
        "Meanwhile, the Sri Lanka Navy continues to carry out regular operations to protect the country’s fishery resources and the livelihood of the local fishing community."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "weekend",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of 27th August 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Maritime Boundary Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fisheries Inspector of Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සති අන්තයේදී ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදා භාරයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 අගෝස්තු 27 වන දින රාත්‍රියේ දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ දඩයම් කරන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීමේ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමක් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර සීමා රේඛාව (IMBL) හරහා තලෙයිමන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු තීරයේ දඩයම් කරමින් සිටියදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට මෙම මෙහෙයුම හේතු විය.",
        "දේශීය ධීවර ප්‍රජාවට සිදුවන බලපෑම මෙන්ම එමගින් මෙරට සාගර පරිසරයට සිදුවන හානිය මැඩලීමේ අරමුණින් විදේශීය ධීවරයින්ගේ නීතිවිරෝධී ධීවර කටයුතු වැළැක්වීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ නිරන්තර මුර සංචාර අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරයි.",
        "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ දඩයම් කරන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීම සඳහා IMBL හරහා ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ මෙම විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමේදී අගෝස්තු 27 වන දින උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව විසින් මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ධීවර ආම්පන්න සමඟ තලෙයිමන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව භාරයේ සිටින ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව සහ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු මේ වන විට තලෙයිමන්නාරම නාවික හමුදා භාරයේ පසුවන අතර ඔවුන් ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා මන්නාරම ධීවර පරීක්ෂක වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 22 වැනි දින සිදු කරන ලද මෙවන් මෙහෙයුමකදී නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 10 දෙනෙකු සමඟ මුලතිව් ඔබ්බෙන් ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් රඳවාගෙන නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව රටේ ධීවර සම්පත සහ දේශීය ධීවර ප්‍රජාවගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා නිරන්තර මෙහෙයුම් අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "සති අන්තය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 27 රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර මායිම් රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම ධීවර පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வார இறுதியில் இந்திய இழுவை படகை இலங்கை கடற்படை கைப்பற்றியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 27 ஆம் தேதி இரவு தீவுக் கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டியடிக்க சிறப்பு நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டனர்.",
        "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு (IMBL) ஊடாக தலைமன்னார் கடற்பரப்பில் இலங்கையின் கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடிய 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் இந்திய இழுவை படகு கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு மீனவர்களின் சட்டவிரோத மீன்பிடி நடைமுறைகளைத் தடுப்பதற்காக, உள்நாட்டு மீனவ சமூகத்தின் மீதான அதன் தாக்கத்தையும், அது நாட்டின் கடல் சூழலுக்கு ஏற்படும் பாதிப்பையும் தடுக்கும் நோக்கில், கடற்படையினர் தீவுக் கடற்பரப்பில் தொடர்ந்து ரோந்துப் பணிகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டுவதற்காக வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இந்த விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​ஐஎம்பிஎல் ஊடாக, வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட விரைவுத் தாக்குதல் கப்பலினால் கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் 27ஆம் திகதி அச்சம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில், 06 இந்திய மீனவர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களது மீன்பிடி சாதனங்களுடன் தலைமன்னார் கடற்பரப்பில் எஞ்சியிருந்த இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட இந்திய இழுவை படகு மற்றும் 06 இந்திய மீனவர்கள் தற்போது தலைமன்னாரில் கடற்படை காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், அவர்கள் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக மன்னார் கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 22 ஆம் திகதி மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இதேபோன்ற நடவடிக்கையில், கடற்படையினர் 10 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் முல்லைத்தீவில் இருந்து இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் இழுவை படகை பிடித்து சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஆஜர்படுத்தினர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் நாட்டின் மீன்பிடி வளங்களையும் உள்ளூர் மீனவ மக்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தையும் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான வழக்கமான நடவடிக்கைகளை தொடர்ந்து மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "வார இறுதி",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 27, 2022 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}