{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-state-litro-gas-acquires-100000mt-of-lp-gas-using-world-bank-funds-96700/",
  "time_ut": 1656576720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s state Litro Gas acquires 100,000MT of LP gas using World Bank funds",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s state Litro Gas acquires 100,000MT of LP gas using World Bank funds",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run Litro Gas Lanka Ltd has procured 100,000 metric tons of liquid petroleum (LP) gas worth 90 million US dollars, 70 million of which was funded by the World Bank.",
        "The prime minister’s office said Thursday June 30 afternoon that the remaining 20 million dollars was from Litro.",
        "Sri Lanka, going through its worst forex crisis since Independence, has seen long queues for LP gas which is primarily used for cooking at both domestic and industrial levels. Angry consumers were seen lining up outside gas vendors for days.",
        "“This consignment will be enough to supply the country for four months. Seventy percent of the consignment will be provided to domestic consumers. An estimated 5 million 12.5kg cylinders, 1 million 5kg cylinders and 1 million 2.5kg cylinders will be obtained from this. The remaining 30% will be provided for commercial use,” the prime minster’s office said.",
        "An initial consignment of 33,000 tons of LP gas procured by Litro at a cost of 20 million dollars will reach Sri Lanka by the first week of July and distribution will commence immediately, the statement said. (Colombo/Jun30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Litro Gas",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100,000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "World Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the remaining 20 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seventy percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "An estimated 5 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම ලෝක බැංකු අරමුදල් යොදා ගනිමින් එල්පී ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් ලබා ගනී.",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන Litro Gas Lanka Ltd විසින් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 ක් වටිනා ද්‍රව පෙට්‍රෝලියම් (LP) ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000 ක් ලබාගෙන ඇති අතර ඉන් මිලියන 70 ක් ලෝක බැංකුව විසින් අරමුදල් සපයන ලදී.",
        "ඉතිරි ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ලිට්‍රෝ වෙතින් බව අගමැති කාර්යාලය ජුනි 30 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සවස ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටින අතර, ගෘහස්ත සහ කාර්මික මට්ටම් දෙකෙහිම ආහාර පිසීම සඳහා මූලික වශයෙන් භාවිතා කරන LP ගෑස් සඳහා දිගු පෝලිම් දක්නට ලැබේ. කෝපයට පත් පාරිභෝගිකයින් දින ගණනාවක් ගෑස් වෙළෙන්දන් පිටත පෙළ ගැසී සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "“මෙම තොගය මාස හතරකට රටට සැපයීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් වනු ඇත. භාණ්ඩ තොගයෙන් සියයට හැත්තෑවක් ගෘහස්ථ පාරිභෝගිකයන් වෙත ලබා දෙනු ඇත. මෙයින් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 5 ක්, කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 1 ක් සහ කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 2.5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 1 ක් ලබා ගැනීමට ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇත. ඉතිරි 30% වාණිජමය භාවිතය සඳහා ලබා දෙනු ඇත, ”අගමැති කාර්යාලය පැවසීය.",
        "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක වියදමින් ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම විසින් ලබා ගන්නා ලද LP ගෑස් ටොන් 33,000 ක මූලික තොගයක් ජූලි මස මුල් සතිය වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන අතර බෙදා හැරීම වහාම ආරම්භ කරන බව එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ. (කොළඹ/ජුනි30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100,000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 30 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතිරි ඩොලර් මිලියන 20",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිව් මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට හැත්තෑවක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5ක් යැයි ගණන් බලා ඇත",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 33,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம் உலக வங்கி நிதியைப் பயன்படுத்தி 100,000MT LP எரிவாயுவைப் பெறுகிறது.",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான Litro Gas Lanka Ltd ஆனது 90 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான 100,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் திரவ பெட்ரோலியம் (LP) எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்துள்ளது, இதில் 70 மில்லியன் உலக வங்கியின் நிதியுதவி.",
        "மீதமுள்ள 20 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள் லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்ததாக ஜூன் 30 வியாழக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்தது.",
        "இலங்கை, சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் மிக மோசமான அந்நிய செலாவணி நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது, உள்நாட்டு மற்றும் தொழில்துறை மட்டங்களில் சமையலுக்குப் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் LP எரிவாயுவுக்கான நீண்ட வரிசைகளைக் கண்டுள்ளது. கோபமடைந்த நுகர்வோர் பல நாட்களாக எரிவாயு விற்பனையாளர்களுக்கு வெளியே வரிசையில் நிற்பதைக் காண முடிந்தது.",
        "“இந்த சரக்கு நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கு நாட்டிற்கு வழங்க போதுமானதாக இருக்கும். 70 சதவீத சரக்கு உள்நாட்டு நுகர்வோருக்கு வழங்கப்படும். இதன் மூலம் 5 மில்லியன் 12.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள், 1 மில்லியன் 5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் மற்றும் 1 மில்லியன் 2.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் பெறப்படும். மீதமுள்ள 30% வணிக பயன்பாட்டிற்கு வழங்கப்படும், ”என்று பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "லிட்ரோவினால் 20 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் செலவில் கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்ட 33,000 தொன் எல்பி எரிவாயு ஆரம்ப சரக்கு ஜூலை முதல் வாரத்தில் இலங்கையை வந்தடையும் எனவும் விநியோகம் உடனடியாக ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் எனவும் அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100,000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "உலக வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீதமுள்ள 20 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எழுபது சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன் என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}