{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/unicef-rotary-partner-to-provide-essential-aid-to-sri-lankan-families-98921/",
  "time_ut": 1661257980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UNICEF, Rotary partner to provide essential aid to Sri Lankan families",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNICEF, Rotary partner to provide essential aid to Sri Lankan families",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The United Nations International Children’s Emergency Fund (UNICEF) and Rotary International have partnered to provide lifesaving medicines, clean drinking water, education materials, and other critical supplies to children and families in Sri Lanka, a UNICEF statement said.",
        "“The partnership will capitalise on Rotary International’s global network along with the alumni of Sri Lanka’s leading schools to raise funds from the Sri Lankan community living overseas,” the statement, released on Tuesday August 23, said.",
        "A fundraising page has been developed to generate the funds required, and once the adequate fund has been generated, the statement said, UNICEF will acquire essential medicines, medical equipment, water purifiers, and school stationery to support vulnerable communities facing shortages across the island.",
        "Sri Lanka is experiencing its worst economic meltdown since Independence, which has resulted in severe shortages of essentials turning over to skyrocketing cost of living.",
        "The UNICEF Sri Lanka Appeal calls for 25.3 million US dollars, out of which 26.58 percent will be spent on social protection, 24.8% on education and 23% on nutrition.",
        "“Sri Lanka is among the top ten countries with the highest number of malnourished children and the numbers are expected to rise further,” the statement said.",
        "Sri Lanka has the second-highest rate of acute malnutrition among children under five in South Asia.",
        "In June 2022, Spokesperson for UNICEF Sri Lanka Bismarck Swangin told the media that he has worked with Somalia, Yemen and Sudan and said, that this is a crisis like none other.",
        "The partnership was launched on Monday August 22 in Colombo by UNICEF Regional Director for South Asia George Laryea-Adjei and UNICEF Sri Lanka Representative Christian Skoog together with Zone Director of Rotary International A S Venkatesh and Sri Lanka Rotary District Governor Pubudu de Zoysa. (Colombo/Aug23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rotary",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Nations International Children’s Emergency Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rotary International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rotary International’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25.3 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.58 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "24.8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "under five",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson for UNICEF Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bismarck Swangin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Somalia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yemen",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday August 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "George Laryea-Adjei",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Christian Skoog",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rotary International A S Venkatesh and",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rotary",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubudu de Zoysa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පවුල් සඳහා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීම සඳහා UNICEF, Rotary සහකරු",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර ළමා හදිසි අරමුදල (UNICEF) සහ Rotary International එක්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ළමුන් සහ පවුල් සඳහා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක ඖෂධ, පිරිසිදු පානීය ජලය, අධ්‍යාපන ද්‍රව්‍ය සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සැපයුම් සැපයීමට හවුල් වී ඇති බව යුනිසෙෆ් නිවේදනයක් පවසයි.",
        "\"මෙම හවුල්කාරිත්වය විදේශයන්හි වෙසෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ප්‍රජාවෙන් අරමුදල් රැස් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ පාසල්වල ආදි සිසුන් සමඟ රොටරි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් හි ගෝලීය ජාලය ප්‍රාග්ධනය කරනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් අගෝස්තු 23 අඟහරුවාදා නිකුත් කරන ලද නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "අවශ්‍ය අරමුදල් උත්පාදනය කිරීම සඳහා අරමුදල් රැස්කිරීමේ පිටුවක් සකස් කර ඇති අතර, ප්‍රමාණවත් අරමුදලක් උත්පාදනය වූ පසු, දිවයින පුරා හිඟයකට මුහුණ දෙන අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා යුනිසෙෆ් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ, වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ, ජල පිරිපහදු යන්ත්‍ර සහ පාසල් ලිපි ද්‍රව්‍ය ලබා ගන්නා බව නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීම අත්විඳිමින් සිටින අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍යවල උග්‍ර හිඟය ජීවන වියදම අහස උසට නැඟී ඇත.",
        "යුනිසෙෆ් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභියාචනය ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 25.3ක් ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර එයින් සියයට 26.58ක් සමාජ ආරක්ෂණය සඳහා ද 24.8%ක් අධ්‍යාපනයටද 23%ක් පෝෂණය සඳහාද වැය කෙරේ.",
        "\"වැඩිම මන්දපෝෂණයෙන් පෙළෙන දරුවන් සිටින රටවල් දහය අතරට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළත් වන අතර එම සංඛ්‍යාව තවදුරටත් ඉහළ යනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ\" යනුවෙන් එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "දකුණු ආසියාවේ අවුරුදු පහට අඩු ළමුන් අතර උග්‍ර මන්දපෝෂණයේ දෙවැනි ඉහළම අනුපාතය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සතුය.",
        "2022 ජුනි මාසයේදී යුනිසෙෆ් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රකාශක Bismarck Swangin මාධ්‍ය වෙත පැවසුවේ තමා සෝමාලියාව, යේමනය සහ සුඩානය සමඟ වැඩ කර ඇති බවත්, මෙය අන් කිසිවකට නැති අර්බුදයක් බවත්ය.",
        "මෙම හවුල්කාරිත්වය අගෝස්තු 22 සඳුදා කොළඹදී දියත් කරන ලද්දේ යුනිසෙෆ් දකුණු ආසියාව සඳහා කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජෝර්ජ් ලැරියා-අඩ්ජේ සහ යුනිසෙෆ් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිත ක්‍රිස්ටියන් ස්කූග් විසින් රොටරි ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ කලාප අධ්‍යක්ෂ ඒ එස් වෙන්කටේෂ් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රොටරි දිස්ත්‍රික් ආණ්ඩුකාර පුබුදු ද සොයිසා විසිනි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රොටරි",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර ළමා හදිසි අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොටරි ජාත්‍යන්තරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොටරි ජාත්‍යන්තරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 23 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 25.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 26.58 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "24.8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ යටතේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනිසෙෆ් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිස්මාර්ක් ස්වංගින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝමාලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යේමනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුඩානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝර්ජ් ලැරියා-ඇඩ්ජේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටියන් ස්කූග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොටරි ජාත්‍යන්තර ඒ එස් වෙන්කටේෂ් සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොටරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුබුදු ද සොයිසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை குடும்பங்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய உதவிகளை வழங்க UNICEF, Rotary பங்காளி",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சர்வதேச சிறுவர் அவசர நிதியம் (UNICEF) மற்றும் Rotary International ஆகியவை இலங்கையில் உள்ள குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் குடும்பங்களுக்கு உயிர்காக்கும் மருந்துகள், சுத்தமான குடிநீர், கல்விப் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் பிற முக்கியமான பொருட்களை வழங்க கூட்டு சேர்ந்துள்ளன என்று UNICEF அறிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"வெளிநாட்டில் வாழும் இலங்கை சமூகத்திடம் இருந்து நிதி திரட்டுவதற்காக இலங்கையின் முன்னணி பள்ளிகளின் பழைய மாணவர்களுடன் இணைந்து ரோட்டரி இன்டர்நேஷனலின் உலகளாவிய வலையமைப்பை இந்த கூட்டாண்மை பயன்படுத்திக் கொள்ளும்\" என்று ஆகஸ்ட் 23 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "தேவையான நிதியை உருவாக்க ஒரு நிதி திரட்டும் பக்கம் உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் போதுமான நிதி உருவாக்கப்பட்டவுடன், UNICEF அத்தியாவசிய மருந்துகள், மருத்துவ உபகரணங்கள், தண்ணீர் சுத்திகரிப்பாளர்கள் மற்றும் பள்ளி எழுதுபொருட்களை வாங்கும், நாடு முழுவதும் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய சமூகங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும்.",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியை அனுபவித்து வருகின்றது, இதன் விளைவாக அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் கடுமையான தட்டுப்பாடு அதிகரித்து வாழ்க்கைச் செலவுக்கு மாறியுள்ளது.",
        "UNICEF Sri Lanka மேன்முறையீடு 25.3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை கோருகிறது, இதில் 26.58 சதவீதம் சமூக பாதுகாப்புக்காகவும், 24.8% கல்விக்காகவும், 23% ஊட்டச்சத்துக்காகவும் செலவிடப்படும்.",
        "\"அதிக ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாடுள்ள குழந்தைகளைக் கொண்ட முதல் பத்து நாடுகளில் இலங்கையும் உள்ளது, மேலும் இந்த எண்ணிக்கை மேலும் உயரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தெற்காசியாவில் ஐந்து வயதிற்குட்பட்ட குழந்தைகளிடையே கடுமையான ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாட்டின் விகிதத்தில் இலங்கை இரண்டாவது இடத்தில் உள்ளது.",
        "ஜூன் 2022 இல், UNICEF ஸ்ரீலங்காவின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் பிஸ்மார்க் ஸ்வாங்கின் ஊடகங்களுக்கு அவர் சோமாலியா, யேமன் மற்றும் சூடானுடன் பணியாற்றியதாகவும், இது வேறு எதிலும் இல்லாத நெருக்கடி என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 22 திங்கட்கிழமை கொழும்பில் யுனிசெஃப் தெற்காசியாவிற்கான பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் ஜோர்ஜ் லரியா-அட்ஜெய் மற்றும் யுனிசெஃப் இலங்கை பிரதிநிதி கிறிஸ்டியன் ஸ்கூக் ஆகியோர் இணைந்து ரோட்டரி இன்டர்நேஷனல் மண்டல இயக்குனர் ஏ எஸ் வெங்கடேஷ் மற்றும் இலங்கை ரோட்டரி மாவட்ட ஆளுநர் புபுது டி சொய்சா ஆகியோரால் இந்த கூட்டாண்மை தொடங்கப்பட்டது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரோட்டரி",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் சர்வதேச குழந்தைகள் அவசர நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோட்டரி இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோட்டரி இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25.3 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "26.58 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "24.8%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "23%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து கீழ்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனிசெஃப் இலங்கையின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஸ்மார்க் ஸ்வாங்கின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோமாலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூடான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்ஜ் லாரியா-அட்ஜீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டியன் ஸ்கூக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோட்டரி இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஏ எஸ் வெங்கடேஷ் மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோட்டரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புபுது டி சொய்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}