{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131751",
  "time_ut": 1658203069,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மழை, பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் - வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rain, strong winds likely - Department of Meteorology",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology has said that rain will occur several times in the Upper, Sabaragamuwa and North-West provinces and Nuwara Eliya, Kandy, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Uva, Eastern and North Central Provinces and Mullaitivu District will experience rain or thundershowers at many places during afternoon or night.",
        "Strong winds of 40-50 km per hour may occur in the southern province from time to time.",
        "The general public is advised to take adequate precautions during thunderstorms to minimize possible damage due to temporary strong winds and lightning strikes.",
        "Scattered showers will occur over coastal areas from Puttalam through Colombo and Galle to Matara.",
        "Wind will blow from South-West direction with wind speed of 30-40 kmph. The wind speed may increase to 50-60 kmph in coastal areas from Colombo through Galle to Ambantota.",
        "The offshore seas from Colombo through Galle to Ambantota will be rough from time to time. Other seas surrounding the country are temperate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Department of Meteorology",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-West",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central Provinces",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50 km per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South-West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වැසි, තද සුළං ඇති විය හැක - කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉහළ, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් නුවරඑළිය, මහනුවර, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ඌව, නැගෙනහිර සහ උතුරු මැද පළාත්වලත් මුලතිව් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේත් බොහෝ ස්ථානවල අපරභාගයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "දකුණු පළාතේ විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 40-50 දක්වා තද සුළං ඇති විය හැක.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවට දැනුම් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ සහ ගාල්ල හරහා මාතර දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල තැනින් තැන වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "සුළඟේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී. 30-40 දක්වාත් සමඟ නිරිත දෙසින් සුළඟ හමයි. කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල හරහා අඹන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-60 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල හරහා අඹන්තොට දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට රළු වේ. රට වටා ඇති අනෙකුත් මුහුද සෞම්‍ය වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද පළාත්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව් දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර 40-50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිරිත-බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மழை, பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் - வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் நுவரெலியா, கண்டி, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊவா, கிழக்கு மற்றும் வடமத்திய மாகாணங்களிலும் முல்லைத்தீவு மாவட்டத்திலும் பல இடங்களில் பிற்பகல் அல்லது இரவு வேளையில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "தென் மாகாணத்தில் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 40-50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைப்பதற்கு போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொது மக்கள் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும் காலி ஊடாக மாத்தறை வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் பரவலாக மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "காற்று தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும், காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. கொழும்பிலிருந்து காலி ஊடாக அம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-60 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து காலி ஊடாக அம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கரையோரத்திற்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகள் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும். நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புகள் மிதமானதாக இருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய மாகாணங்கள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 40-50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50-60 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}