{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-seeks-to-meet-creditors-armed-with-imf-deal-99342/",
  "time_ut": 1662020460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka seeks to meet creditors armed with IMF deal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka seeks to meet creditors armed with IMF deal",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will meet creditors over the next few weeks to update them on the economic development and a reform package agreed with the International Monetary Fund, the Finance Ministry said.",
        "Sri Lanka and the IMF has announced a staff level program for 2.9 billion US dollar extended fund facility.",
        "“This agreement is a testimony to our commitment to carry out the necessary reforms to offer a better life to our fellow citizens,” President Ranil Wickremesinghe said.",
        "“It paves the way for the provision of financial support from the IMF and other development partners that should help us to address current external imbalances.”",
        "Creditors could contact financial advisors at lk.investors@lazard.com and legal advisors at srilanka@cliffordchance.com",
        "Sri Lanka has been “working with legal and financial advisors on the debt restructuring strategy.",
        "A presentation will be made to creditors to update them on the most recent economic developmetns and main areas of the reform package. (Colomo/Sept02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.9 billion US dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "lk.investors@lazard.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colomo/Sept02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ගනුදෙනුවෙන් සන්නද්ධ ණය හිමියන් හමුවීමට උත්සාහ කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ එකඟ වූ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පැකේජයක් පිළිබඳව යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය තුළ ණය හිමියන් හමුවනු ඇති බව මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල විසින් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9ක දිගු අරමුදල් පහසුකම් සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ වැඩසටහනක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "\"මෙම ගිවිසුම අපගේ සහෝදර පුරවැසියන්ට යහපත් ජීවිතයක් ලබා දීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදු කිරීමට අපගේ කැපවීමට සාක්ෂියක්\" යැයි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"වර්තමාන බාහිර අසමතුලිතතා විසඳීමට අපට උපකාර කළ යුතු IMF සහ අනෙකුත් සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන්ගෙන් මූල්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීමට එය මග පාදයි.\"",
        "ණය හිමියන්ට lk.investors@lazard.com හි මූල්‍ය උපදේශකයින් හා srilanka@cliffordchance.com හි නීති උපදේශකයින් සම්බන්ධ කර ගත හැකිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ උපායමාර්ගය සම්බන්ධයෙන් නීතිමය සහ මූල්‍ය උපදේශකයන් සමඟ කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී.",
        "ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පැකේජයේ වඩාත්ම මෑතකාලීන ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනයන් සහ ප්‍රධාන ක්ෂේත්‍ර පිළිබඳව යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම සඳහා ණය හිමියන්ට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමක් කරනු ලැබේ. (කොළඹ/සැප්තැම්බර්02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "lk.investors@lazard.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොලමෝ/සැප්තැම්බර්02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF உடன்படிக்கையுடன் ஆயுதம் ஏந்திய கடனாளிகளை சந்திக்க இலங்கை முயல்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் இணக்கம் காணப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தப் பொதி தொடர்பில் இலங்கை அடுத்த சில வாரங்களில் கடன் வழங்குநர்களை சந்திக்கும் என நிதி அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதிக்கான பணியாளர் மட்டத் திட்டத்தை அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த உடன்படிக்கை எமது சக குடிமக்களுக்கு சிறந்த வாழ்க்கையை வழங்குவதற்கு தேவையான சீர்திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கான எமது அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கான சாட்சியமாகும் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இது IMF மற்றும் பிற மேம்பாட்டு பங்காளிகளிடமிருந்து நிதி உதவியை வழங்குவதற்கு வழி வகுக்கிறது, இது தற்போதைய வெளிப்புற ஏற்றத்தாழ்வுகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்ய எங்களுக்கு உதவும்.\"",
        "கடன் வழங்குபவர்கள் நிதி ஆலோசகர்களை lk.investors@lazard.com மற்றும் சட்ட ஆலோசகர்களை srilanka@cliffordchance.com என்ற முகவரியில் தொடர்பு கொள்ளலாம்.",
        "இலங்கை “கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு மூலோபாயத்தில் சட்ட மற்றும் நிதி ஆலோசகர்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றி வருகிறது.",
        "மிக சமீபத்திய பொருளாதார மேம்பாடுகள் மற்றும் சீர்திருத்தப் பொதியின் முக்கிய பகுதிகள் குறித்து கடன் வழங்குநர்களுக்கு ஒரு விளக்கக்காட்சி வழங்கப்படும். (கொலோமோ/செப்டம்பர்02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "lk.investors@lazard.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொலோமோ/செப்டம்பர்02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}