{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/05/14th-death-in-fuel-queue-reported/",
  "time_ut": 1657012440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "14th death in fuel queue reported",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "14th death in fuel queue reported",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The 14th death in connection with fuel queues was reported today in Borella, ​​Colombo.",
        "A 60-year-old man who was waiting in a queue to obtain fuel from an LIOC filling station in Borella, and was found dead in his car.",
        "According to others who were present at the fuel queue, the deceased had joined the fuel queue in the morning, and had passed away after two hours of waiting in the queue.",
        "The deceased was identified as a 60-year-old man named M.D.S.D. Gunaratne, whom our correspondent reported to be a resident of Angoda, Gothatuwa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "14th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "14th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.D.S.D. Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gothatuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ 14 වන මරණය වාර්තා වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් ආශ්‍රිතව සිදුවූ 14 වන මරණය අද කොළඹ බොරැල්ල ප්‍රදේශයෙන් වාර්තා විය.",
        "බොරැල්ල LIOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලකින් ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට පෝලිමක සිටි 60 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු සිය මෝටර් රථය තුළ මියගොස් සිටියදී සොයා ගැනුණා.",
        "ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ සිටි අනෙක් අය පවසන පරිදි මියගිය පුද්ගලයා උදෑසන ඉන්ධන පෝලිමට එක්වී පැය දෙකක් පෝලිමේ රැඳී සිටීමෙන් පසු මියගොස් ඇත.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ 60 හැවිරිදි එම්.ඩී.එස්.ඩී. ගුණරත්න, ගොතටුව අංගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු බවට අප වාර්තාකරු වාර්තා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "14 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය දෙකක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ඩී.එස්.ඩී. ගුණරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොතටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் 14வது மரணம் பதிவாகியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பு பொரளையில் எரிபொருள் வரிசைகள் தொடர்பில் 14வது மரணம் இன்று பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "பொரளையில் உள்ள LIOC எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையத்தில் எரிபொருள் பெற வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த 60 வயதுடைய நபர் ஒருவர் காரில் சடலமாக மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் இருந்த ஏனையவர்களின் கூற்றுப்படி, இறந்தவர் காலையில் எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் சேர்ந்தார், இரண்டு மணி நேரம் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த பிறகு இறந்தார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் 60 வயதுடைய எம்.டி.எஸ்.டி. குணரத்ன, அங்கொட, கொத்தடுவையில் வசிப்பவர் என எமது செய்தியாளர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "14வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.டி.எஸ்.டி. குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோதடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}