{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83514/parts-of-western-province-under-police-curfew",
  "time_ut": 1657291500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parts of Western Province under police curfew",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parts of Western Province under police curfew",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Police curfew will be imposed in several police areas of the Western Province with effect from 9.00 p.m. today (July 08), Inspector-General of Police C.D. Wickramaratne announced.",
        "Thereby, the curfew orders will be effective in the following police areas until further notice:"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Western Province",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police C.D. Wickramaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බස්නාහිර පළාතේ සමහර ප්‍රදේශ පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය යටතේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "9.00 සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි බස්නාහිර පළාතේ පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවනු ලැබේ. අද (ජූලි 08) පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී. වික්‍රමරත්න නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු පහත සඳහන් පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශවල ඇඳිරි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් සී.ඩී. වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேல் மாகாணத்தின் சில பகுதிகள் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தின் பல பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளில் இரவு 9.00 மணி முதல் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளது. இன்று (ஜூலை 08), இன்ஸ்பெக்டர்-ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ் சி.டி. விக்ரமரத்ன அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன் மூலம், ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு அடுத்த அறிவிப்பு வரும் வரை பின்வரும் காவல் பகுதிகளில் அமலில் இருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலீஸ் சி.டி. விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}