{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Fmr-Japan-PM-Shinzo-Abe-shot-in-chest-and-taken-to-hospital-attacker-in-custody/108-240571",
  "time_ut": 1657250164,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fmr Japan PM Shinzo Abe shot in chest and taken to hospital, attacker in custody",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fmr Japan PM Shinzo Abe shot in chest and taken to hospital, attacker in custody",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe has been reportedly shot by an unidentified gunman. Abe was giving a speech in the city of Nara, in western Japan, when the incident happened.",
        "An NHK reporter on site heard something that sounded like a gunshot, and saw Abe bleeding. Nara is the capital of Japan’s Nara Prefecture, in South-central Honshu",
        "The reporter claimed to have heard 'consecutive bangs', after which Abe was seen in blood. While some reports claimed he was shot in the chest, some said his neck was bleeding. (economictimes)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honshu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපාන අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේ පපුවට වෙඩි තබා රෝහල් ගත කර ප්‍රහාරකයා අත්අඩංගුවේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ හිටපු අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේට නාඳුනන තුවක්කුකරුවෙකු විසින් වෙඩි තබා ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ. අබේ බටහිර ජපානයේ නාරා නගරයේ දේශනයක් පවත්වමින් සිටියදී මෙම සිද්ධිය සිදු විය.",
        "වෙබ් අඩවියේ NHK වාර්තාකරුවෙකුට වෙඩි හඬක් වැනි යමක් ඇසුණු අතර, අබේ ලේ ගලනු දුටුවේය. නාරා යනු දකුණු-මධ්‍යම හොන්ෂු හි ජපානයේ නාරා ප්‍රාන්තයේ අගනුවරයි",
        "වාර්තාකරු කියා සිටියේ 'අඛණ්ඩ පිපිරුම්' ඇසුණු බවත්, ඉන් පසුව අබේ රුධිරයෙන් සිටින බවත්ය. ඔහුගේ පපු ප්‍රදේශයට වෙඩි වැදුණු බව ඇතැම් වාර්තාවල සඳහන් වන අතර ඇතැමුන් පැවසුවේ ඔහුගේ බෙල්ලෙන් ලේ ගලන බවයි. (ආර්ථික වේලාවන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්එච්කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honshu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே மார்பில் சுடப்பட்டு மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டார், தாக்குதல் நடத்தியவர் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானின் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே இனந்தெரியாத துப்பாக்கிதாரி ஒருவரால் சுட்டுக்கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. மேற்கு ஜப்பானில் உள்ள நாரா நகரில் அபே உரையாற்றிக் கொண்டிருந்த போது, ​​சம்பவம் நடந்தது.",
        "தளத்தில் NHK நிருபர் ஒருவர் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு போன்ற சத்தம் கேட்டது, மேலும் அபே இரத்தப்போக்கைக் கண்டார். நாரா என்பது ஜப்பானின் தென்-மத்திய ஹோன்ஷுவில் உள்ள நாரா மாகாணத்தின் தலைநகரம் ஆகும்",
        "'தொடர்ச்சியான பேங்க்ஸ்' கேட்டதாக அந்த நிருபர் கூறினார், அதன் பிறகு அபே ரத்தத்தில் காணப்பட்டார். சில அறிக்கைகள் அவர் மார்பில் சுடப்பட்டதாகக் கூறினாலும், சிலர் அவரது கழுத்தில் இரத்தப்போக்கு இருப்பதாகக் கூறினர். (பொருளாதார நேரம்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honshu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}