{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Some-SJB-MPs-in-favour-of-all-party-govt-with-RW/108-241818",
  "time_ut": 1658830059,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Some SJB MPs in favour of all party govt with RW",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Some SJB MPs in favour of all party govt with RW",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Whilst Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) parliamentary group has unanimously decided to vote against the Emergency Bill tomorrow, there seemed to be different opinions about an all party government as some MPs representing the party opine that the party should play a role in an all party government without accepting ministerial portfolios.",
        "SJB Gampaha District MP Harshana Rajakauna who spoke to media after the party’s working committee and parliamentary group meeting, said his party would support a multi-party government without accepting ministerial portfolios.",
        "“We are of the opinion that SJB should play a role in the government without accepting any ministerial portfolios. We have also requested the government to appoint MP Harsha de Silva as the Chairman of Public Finance Committee. Also we believe that SJB should play a role in committees,” Mr. Rajakaruna said.",
        "MP Rajitha Senaratne said SJB will not play a role in an all party government which the ruling party envisages. “What the ruling party and President Ranil Wickremesinghe intend doing is to woo MPs to their camp by offering ministries and money. Therefore we don’t intend to be a party of such a government,” he said.",
        "He alleged that monetary rewards have been given to MPs to get them to vote for Mr.  Wickremesinghe when electing a new President.",
        "However MPs Thursha Indunil Amarasena, Mujibur Rahman, Harshana Rajakaruna and Tissa Attanayake confirmed that SJB will vote against Emergency today.",
        "“We will see whether any SJB MPs would vote in favour of Emergency and confirmed the claim made by Minister Harin Fernando that some SJBer have voted against the decision of their party on July 20.,” MP Amarasena said. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Rajakauna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajakaruna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursha Indunil Amarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujibur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Rajakaruna",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Attanayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJBer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමහර SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරු RW සමග සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවට පක්ෂ වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම හෙට හදිසි පනත් කෙටුම්පතට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය දීමට ඒකමතිකව තීරණය කර ඇති අතර, සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් තුළ පක්ෂය භූමිකාවක් ඉටු කළ යුතු බවට එම පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරන ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අදහස් පළ කිරීම නිසා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිළිබඳව විවිධ මත පළ වී ඇති බව පෙනෙන්නට තිබේ. ඇමතිකම් බාර ගන්නේ නැතිව.",
        "පක්ෂයේ කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම් රැස්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දැක්වූ SJB ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂණ රාජකෞන කියා සිටියේ අමාත්‍ය ධුර භාර නොගෙන බහු පක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවකට තම පක්ෂය සහය දෙන බවයි.",
        "“ඇමති ධුර භාර නොගෙන SJB ආණ්ඩුවේ කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළ යුතුයි කියන මතයේ අපි ඉන්නවා. රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා පත් කරන ලෙසත් අපි රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබෙනවා. ඒ වගේම අපි විශ්වාස කරනවා SJB කමිටු තුළ කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළ යුතුයි කියලා,\" රාජකරුණා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය අපේක්ෂා කරන සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් තුළ SJB භූමිකාවක් ඉටු නොකරන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රාජිත සේනාරත්න මහතා පැවසීය. “ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂය සහ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමා කරන්න බලාපොරොත්තු වෙන්නේ ඇමැතිකම්, මුදල් දීලා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තමන්ගේ කඳවුරට ළංකර ගැනීමයි. ඒ නිසා අපි එවැනි ආණ්ඩුවක පක්‍ෂයක් වීමට අදහස් කරන්නේ නැහැ,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේදී වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඡන්දය ලබා දීම සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට මුදල් ත්‍යාග ලබා දී ඇති බවට ඔහු චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් SJB හදිසි නීතියට එරෙහිව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන Thursha Indunil Amarasena, Mujibur Rahman, Harshana Rajakaruna සහ තිස්ස අත්තනායක තහවුරු කළා.",
        "\"අපි බලමු SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරු කවුරුහරි හදිසි නීතියට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය දෙනවාද කියලා. සමහර එස්.ජේ.බර්ලා ජූලි 20 වැනිදා තම පක්ෂයේ තීරණයට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බවට හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු අමාත්‍යවරයා කළ ප්‍රකාශය තහවුරු කළා,\" අමරසේන මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ රාජකුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකරුණා ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තර්ෂා ඉඳුනිල් අමරසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJBer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "RW உடன் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஆதரவாக சில SJB எம்பிக்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா (SJB) நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு நாளை அவசரச் சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்க ஏகமனதாக முடிவு செய்த நிலையில், அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சியில் கட்சி பங்கு வகிக்க வேண்டும் என்று அக்கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் சில எம்.பி.க்கள் கருத்து தெரிவித்ததால், அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சி குறித்து பல்வேறு கருத்துகள் எழுந்துள்ளன. அமைச்சர் பதவிகளை ஏற்காமல்.",
        "கட்சியின் செயற்குழு மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தின் பின்னர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த SJB கம்பஹா மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷன ராஜகௌன, அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை ஏற்காமல் பல கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு தமது கட்சி ஆதரவளிக்கும் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“SJB எந்த அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளையும் ஏற்காமல் அரசாங்கத்தில் பங்கு வகிக்க வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் கருதுகிறோம். பொது நிதிக்குழுவின் தலைவராக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வாவை நியமிக்குமாறு அரசாங்கத்திடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளோம். மேலும் SJB குழுக்களில் ஒரு பங்கை வகிக்க வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்,” என்று திரு. ராஜகருணா கூறினார்.",
        "ஆளும் கட்சி எதிர்பார்க்கும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் SJB பங்கு வகிக்காது என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ராஜித சேனாரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். “ஆளும் கட்சியும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் செய்ய விரும்புவது அமைச்சுக்களையும் பணத்தையும் வழங்கி எம்.பி.க்களை தங்கள் முகாமுக்கு இழுக்க வேண்டும். எனவே நாங்கள் அத்தகைய அரசாங்கத்தின் கட்சியாக இருக்க விரும்பவில்லை, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் போது திரு.  விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு வாக்களிக்குமாறு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு பண வெகுமதிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் இன்று அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக SJB வாக்களிக்கும் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான துர்ஷ இந்துனில் அமரசேன, முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான், ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா மற்றும் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க ஆகியோர் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "“SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் யாராவது அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவாக வாக்களிப்பார்களா என்பதை நாங்கள் பார்ப்போம் மற்றும் சில SJB க்கள் ஜூலை 20 அன்று தங்கள் கட்சியின் தீர்மானத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களித்ததாக அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோவின் கூற்றை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்” என்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அமரசேன கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன ராஜகௌன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "துர்ஷா இந்துனில் அமரசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJBer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}