{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130994",
  "time_ut": 1657208831,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபயவை பதவி நீக்கி சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்போம் - ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி சூளுரை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We will oust President Gotabaya and form an all-party government - United People's Shakti Slurai",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United People's Power will give full support to the protest against the government on Saturday.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa should be removed from office and an all-party government should be formed. JVP rejected our invitation to an all-party government. Member of Parliament Nalin Bandara said that refusal is a problematic issue.",
        "He stated this at a press conference held on Thursday (6) at the office of the Leader of the Opposition in Colombo, while further mentioning that,",
        "Police use tear gas on protesting farmers, similar to bombings in Ukraine.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa gets scared when he hears the name Hirunika. We are not carrying out demonstrations for political purposes. Political stability cannot be established without the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Therefore, he should be removed from office and an all-party government should be formed. For this we have called all the parties in the Parliament.",
        "However, JVP Rejected the invitation. We really don't understand what their agenda is. We will extend full support to the demonstration to be carried out on the 9th.",
        "On the 9th, Gotabaya Rajapaksa should be forced to resign. After that, an all-party government acceptable to all should be formed.",
        "Dhammika Perera has been appointed for Bashil Rajapaksa who withdrew from politics due to public protests. Initially, when the popular protests intensified, the Rajapaksa family protected itself by setting up an iron guard called Ranil.",
        "Now that opposition to Ranil has intensified, Bashil is planning to appoint someone else to replace him.",
        "They are afraid to give us a chance because of the fear that if the Sajith Premadasa-led government is formed, a case will surely be filed against the Rajapaksas.",
        "JVP Rejecting the call for an all-party government is problematic. Anurakumara Dissanayake has said that he is ready to accept the post of Prime Minister.",
        "How can he form a government with only 3 MPs? He should realize that the cooperation of other parties is also necessary for that.",
        "A good foundation has now been laid for the formation of an all-party government. He said senior members including United People's Power, Tamil National Federation, members of Parliament who are independent from the government, members who are in the government but do not like the Rajapaksa family, COB committee member Saritha Herath and Sambika Ranawaka are ready to cooperate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "United People's Shakti Slurai",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bashil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bashil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only 3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saritha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sambika Ranawaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අපි ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය එළවා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවනවා - එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති ස්ලූරායි",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෙනසුරාදා රජයට එරෙහි විරෝධතාවයට එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගය පූර්ණ සහය ලබාදෙනවා.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා එම ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් කර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි. සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා අපි කළ ආරාධනය ජවිපෙ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළා. ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම ගැටලු සහගත ප්‍රශ්නයක් බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නලින් බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කොළඹ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (6) පැවති ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළ අතර එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු මෙසේද පැවසීය.",
        "යුක්රේනයේ බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරවලට සමානව උද්ඝෝෂණ කරන ගොවීන්ට පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කරයි.",
        "හිරුණිකා කියන නම ඇහුවම ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මැතිතුමා බය වෙනවා. අපි පෙළපාලි කරන්නේ දේශපාලන අරමුණු වෙනුවෙන් නෙවෙයි. ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් තොරව දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ඇති කළ නොහැක.",
        "ඒ නිසා එතුමා තනතුරෙන් ඉවත් කර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි. මේ සඳහා අපි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලුම පක්ෂ කැඳවා තිබෙනවා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජ.වි.පෙ ආරාධනාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළා. ඇත්තටම එයාලගේ න්‍යාය පත්‍රය මොකක්ද කියලා අපිට තේරෙන්නේ නැහැ. ලබන 9 වැනිදා සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත පෙළපාලියට අපි පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබා දෙනවා.",
        "9 වැනිදා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බල කළ යුතුයි. ඉන් පසුව සැමට පිළිගත හැකි සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි.",
        "ජනතා විරෝධය හේතුවෙන් දේශපාලනයෙන් ඉවත් වූ බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ වෙනුවෙන් ධම්මික පෙරේරා පත් කර තිබෙනවා. මුලදී ජනතා විරෝධය උග්‍ර වූ විට රාජපක්ෂ පවුල රැක ගත්තේ රනිල් නමැති යකඩ මුර පොලක් ද දමාගෙනය.",
        "දැන් රනිල්ට එරෙහි විරෝධය උග්‍ර වී ඇති හෙයින් ඔහු වෙනුවට වෙනත් අයෙකු පත් කිරීමට බෂීල් සැරසෙයි.",
        "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවුවහොත් නිසැකවම රාජපක්ෂලාට එරෙහිව නඩු පවරනු ඇතැයි යන බිය නිසා ඔවුන් අපට අවස්ථාවක් ලබා දීමට බිය වෙති.",
        "ජ.වි.පෙ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා වූ ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම ගැටලු සහගතය. අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරය භාර ගැනීමට සූදානම් බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 3 දෙනෙකුගෙන් පමණක් ඔහු ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන්නේ කෙසේද? ඒ සඳහා අනෙකුත් පක්‍ෂවල සහයෝගයද අවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු තේරුම් ගත යුතුයි.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට දැන් හොඳ අඩිතාලමක් වැටී තිබෙනවා. එක්සත් ජනතා බලය, දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය, ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ස්වාධීනව සිටින පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, ආණ්ඩුවේ සිටින නමුත් රාජපක්ෂ පවුලට අකමැති මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, COB කමිටු සාමාජික සරිතා හේරත්, සම්බික රණවක ඇතුළු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට සූදානම් බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති ස්ලූරායි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3 පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරිතා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්බික රණවක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபயவை பதவி நீக்கி சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்போம் - ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி சூளுரை",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக நாளை சனிக்கிழமை முன்னெடுக்கப்படவுள்ள ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்திற்கு ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி முழுமையான ஆதரவை வழங்கும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவியிலிருந்து விலகச் செய்து அனைவரும் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும். சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எம்மால் விடுக்கப்பட்ட அழைப்பினை ஜே.வி.பி. மறுத்துள்ளமை பிரச்சினைக்குரிய விடயமாகும் என்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நளின் பண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பிலுள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் வியாழக்கிழமை (6) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் இதனைத் தெரிவித்த அவர் மேலும் குறிப்பிடுகையில்,",
        "உக்ரேன் மீது குண்டு தாக்குதல்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுவதைப் போன்று ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள விவசாயிகள் மீது பொலிஸார் கண்ணீர்ப்புகை பிரயோகத்தை மேற்கொள்கின்றனர்.",
        "ஹிருணிகா என்ற பெயரைக் கேட்டதும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு பயம் ஏற்படுகிறது. அரசியல் நோக்கத்திற்காக நாம் ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களை முன்னெடுக்கவில்லை. கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகாமல் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை ஏற்படுத்த முடியாது.",
        "எனவே அவரை பதவியிலிருந்து நீக்கி சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும். இதற்காக நாம் பாராளுமன்றத்திலுள்ள சகல கட்சிகளுக்கும் அழைப்பு விடுத்திருக்கின்றோம்.",
        "எனினும் ஜே.வி.பி. அந்த அழைப்பினை நிராகரித்துள்ளது. உண்மையில் அவர்களது நிகழ்ச்சி நிரல் என்பது எமக்கு புரியவில்லை. 9 ஆம் திகதி முன்னெடுக்கப்படவுள்ள ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்திற்கு முழுமையான ஆதரவை வழங்குவோம்.",
        "9 ஆம் திகதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவியிலிருந்து விலகச் செய்ய வேண்டும். அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து அனைவரும் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளக் கூடிய சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "மக்கள் எதிர்ப்புக்களால் அரசியலிலிருந்து பின்வாங்கிய பஷில் ராஜபக்ஷவிற்காகவே தம்மிக பெரேரா நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். ஆரம்பத்தில் மக்கள் எதிர்ப்புக்கள் தீவிரமடைந்த போது ரணில் என்ற இரும்பு காவலரணை அமைத்து ராஜபக்ஷ குடும்பம் தன்னை பாதுகாத்துக் கொண்டது.",
        "தற்போது ரணில் மீதான எதிர்ப்புக்களும் வலுப்பெற்றுள்ளமையால் , அவருக்கு பதில் வேறு ஒருவரை நியமிப்பதற்கு பஷில் திட்டம் தீட்டிக் கொண்டிருக்கிறார்.",
        "சஜித் பிரேமதாச தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட்டால் , நிச்சயம் ராஜபக்ஷாக்களுக்கு எதிராக வழக்கு தொடரப்படும் என்ற அச்சத்தினாலேயே அவர்கள் எமக்கு வாய்ப்பளிக்க அஞ்சுகின்றனர்.",
        "ஜே.வி.பி. சர்வகட்சி அரசமைப்பதற்கான அழைப்பினை நிராகரிக்கின்றமையானது பிரச்சினைக்குரிய விடயமாகும். அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க பிரதமர் பதவியை ஏற்பதற்கு தயாராக உள்ளதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் உள்ளடங்களாக 3 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை மாத்திரம் வைத்துக் கொண்டு எவ்வாறு அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க முடியும்? அதற்கு ஏனைய கட்சிகளின் ஒத்துழைப்பும் அவசியமாகும் என்பதை அவர் உணர வேண்டும்.",
        "தற்போது சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான சிறந்த அடித்தளம் இடப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி , தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு , அரசாங்கத்திலிருந்து விலகி சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் , அரசாங்கத்திற்குள்ளிருக்கும் ஆனால் ராஜபக்ஷ குடும்பத்தை விரும்பாத உறுப்பினர்கள் , கோப் குழு உறுப்பினர் சரித ஹேரத் மற்றும் சம்பிக ரணவக்க உள்ளிட்ட சிரேஷ்ட உறுப்பினர்கள் இதற்கு ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்க தயாராக உள்ளனர் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி ஸ்லூரை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஷில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஷில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}