{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83327/ntmi-to-remain-closed-on-fridays-and-saturdays",
  "time_ut": 1656510720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NTMI to remain closed on Fridays and Saturdays",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NTMI to remain closed on Fridays and Saturdays",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The National Transport Medical Institute (NTMI) says its services are not provided on Fridays and Saturdays until further notice.",
        "According to its director Dr. Savindra Gamage, the NTMI will limit services from the 01st of July.",
        "However, the general public can schedule an appointment by contacting the hotline 1225, visiting the institute’s official website (www.ntmi.lk) or via e-channeling from Monday to Thursday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Fridays",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Saturdays",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Transport Medical Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Savindra Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 01st of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1225",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday to Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "NTMI සිකුරාදා සහ සෙනසුරාදා දිනවල වසා තබනු ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ප්‍රවාහන වෛද්‍ය ආයතනය (NTMI) පවසන්නේ නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු සිකුරාදා සහ සෙනසුරාදා දිනවල එහි සේවාවන් ලබා නොදෙන බවයි.",
        "එහි අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෛද්‍ය සවින්ද්‍ර ගමගේ මහතාට අනුව ජූලි 01 වැනි දින සිට NTMI සේවා සීමා කරනු ඇත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවට 1225 ක්ෂණික ඇමතුම් අංකය ඇමතීමෙන්, ආයතනයේ නිල වෙබ් අඩවියට (www.ntmi.lk) පිවිසීමෙන් හෝ සඳුදා සිට බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා දක්වා විද්‍යුත් නාලිකා හරහා හමුවීමක් උපලේඛනගත කළ හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිකුරාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රවාහන වෛද්‍ය ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවින්ද්‍ර ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 01 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1225",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා සිට බ්රහස්පතින්දා දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "NTMI வெள்ளி மற்றும் சனிக்கிழமைகளில் மூடப்பட்டிருக்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேஷனல் டிரான்ஸ்போர்ட் மெடிக்கல் இன்ஸ்டிட்யூட் (NTMI) அதன் சேவைகள் வெள்ளி மற்றும் சனிக்கிழமைகளில் மறு அறிவிப்பு வரும் வரை வழங்கப்படாது என்று கூறுகிறது.",
        "அதன் பணிப்பாளர் கலாநிதி சவீந்திர கமகே கருத்துப்படி, NTMI ஆனது ஜூலை 01 ஆம் தேதி முதல் சேவைகளை மட்டுப்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பொது மக்கள் 1225 என்ற ஹாட்லைனைத் தொடர்புகொள்வதன் மூலமோ, நிறுவனத்தின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ வலைத்தளத்திற்கு (www.ntmi.lk) சென்று அல்லது திங்கள் முதல் வியாழன் வரை இ-சேனலிங் மூலம் சந்திப்பைத் திட்டமிடலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமைகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சனிக்கிழமைகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து மருத்துவ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.எம்.ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவீந்திர கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.எம்.ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 01 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1225",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கள் முதல் வியாழன் வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}