{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/india-demolishes-twin-towers-for-violations/",
  "time_ut": 1661756940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India demolishes Twin Towers for violations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India demolishes Twin Towers for violations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "On Sunday (28) afternoon, two skyscrapers near India's capital Delhi were demolished in a carefully planned explosion.",
        "It was the biggest such operation in India so far and generated so much interest that it was telecast live on TV channels.",
        "It took 12 seconds to raze Supertech twin towers in Noida to the ground on Sunday, said Jet Demolitions Managing Director Joe Brinkmann.",
        "Thousands of people who lived in the neighborhood had to evacuate hours before the blast, which was powered by around 3,700kg of explosives.",
        "And the work isn't over yet – the next step is clearing thousands of tonnes of debris generated by the demolition.",
        "Conservationists said some birds may have even died in the demolition.",
        "While the Noida Supertech twin towers' demolition largely remained successful, a boundary wall of a nearby residential society suffered damage while windowpanes of several apartments developed cracks.",
        "Realty firm Supertech Ltd has incurred a loss of about ₹500 crore, including construction and interest costs, because of the demolition of its twin towers in Noida, the company's Chairman R K Arora said.",
        "Doctors have said people living nearby Supertech twin towers, especially those suffering from respiratory diseases, should take extra care and avoid the area for a few days if possible.",
        "Over 1,000 people killed by Pakistan monsoon rains and floods"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Twin Towers",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Noida",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Brinkmann",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 3,700kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands of tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supertech Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about ₹500",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Noida",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R K Arora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් සඳහා ඉන්දියාව ද්විත්ව කුළුණු කඩා දමයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉරිදා (28) පස්වරුවේ ඉන්දියාවේ දිල්ලි අගනුවර ආසන්නයේ පිහිටි අහස ගොඩනැගිලි දෙකක් ඉතා සූක්ෂ්ම ලෙස සැලසුම් කළ පිපිරීමකින් කඩා බිඳ දමන ලදී.",
        "එය මෙතෙක් ඉන්දියාවේ සිදු වූ දැවැන්තම මෙහෙයුම වූ අතර එය රූපවාහිනී නාලිකාවල සජීවීව විකාශය කිරීමට තරම් උනන්දුවක් ඇති කළේය.",
        "ඉරිදා නොයිඩා හි Supertech ද්විත්ව කුළුණු බිම හෙළීමට තත්පර 12 ක් ගත වූ බව Jet Demolitions කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජෝ බ්‍රින්ක්මන් පැවසීය.",
        "කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 3,700ක පමණ පුපුරණ ද්‍රව්‍යවලින් බල ගැන්වූ පිපිරීමට පැය කිහිපයකට පෙර අවට ජීවත් වූ දහස් ගණනකට ඉවත් කිරීමට සිදු විය.",
        "තවද කාර්යය තවම අවසන් නැත - ඊළඟ පියවර වන්නේ කඩා දැමීමෙන් ජනනය වූ ටොන් දහස් ගණනක් සුන්බුන් ඉවත් කිරීමයි.",
        "සමහර කුරුල්ලන් කඩා දැමීමේදී මිය යන්නට ඇති බව සංරක්‍ෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "නොයිඩා සුපර්ටෙක් ද්විත්ව කුළුණු කඩා දැමීම බොහෝ දුරට සාර්ථක වූ අතර, මහල් නිවාස කිහිපයක ජනෙල් වීදුරු ඉරිතැලීම් ඇති වූ අතර අසල පිහිටි නේවාසික සමාජයක මායිම් බිත්තියකට හානි සිදුවිය.",
        "රියල්ටි සමාගමක් වන Supertech Ltd නොයිඩා හි එහි ද්විත්ව කුළුණු කඩා දැමීම නිසා ඉදිකිරීම් සහ පොලී වියදම් ඇතුළුව රුපියල් කෝටි 500 ක පමණ පාඩුවක් ලබා ඇති බව සමාගමේ සභාපති ආර් කේ අරෝරා පැවසීය.",
        "සුපර්ටෙක් නිවුන් කුළුණු අසල වෙසෙන පුද්ගලයින්, විශේෂයෙන් ශ්වසන රෝගවලින් පෙළෙන පුද්ගලයින් වැඩි සැලකිල්ලක් දැක්විය යුතු අතර හැකි නම් දින කිහිපයක් එම ප්‍රදේශයෙන් වළකින ලෙස වෛද්‍යවරු පවසා ඇත.",
        "පකිස්ථානයේ මෝසම් වැසි සහ ගංවතුර හේතුවෙන් 1000කට අධික පිරිසක් මිය ගියහ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවුන් කුළුණු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තත්පර 12 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොයිඩා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝ බ්රින්ක්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,700kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුපර්ටෙක් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 500 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොයිඩා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් කේ අරෝරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விதிமீறல்களுக்காக இந்தியா இரட்டை கோபுரங்களை இடித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (28) பிற்பகல், இந்தியாவின் தலைநகர் டெல்லிக்கு அருகிலுள்ள இரண்டு வானளாவிய கட்டிடங்கள் கவனமாக திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வெடிப்பில் இடிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இது இந்தியாவில் இதுவரை நடந்த மிகப்பெரிய நடவடிக்கையாகும், மேலும் இது டிவி சேனல்களில் நேரடியாக ஒளிபரப்பப்படும் அளவுக்கு ஆர்வத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது.",
        "நொய்டாவில் உள்ள சூப்பர்டெக் இரட்டைக் கோபுரங்களை ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தரைமட்டமாக்க 12 வினாடிகள் ஆனது என்று ஜெட் டெமாலிஷன்ஸ் நிர்வாக இயக்குநர் ஜோ பிரிங்க்மேன் கூறினார்.",
        "சுமார் 3,700 கிலோ வெடிமருந்துகளால் இயங்கும் குண்டுவெடிப்புக்கு சில மணிநேரங்களுக்கு முன்பு அக்கம் பக்கத்தில் வசித்த ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் வெளியேற வேண்டியிருந்தது.",
        "வேலை இன்னும் முடிவடையவில்லை - அடுத்த கட்டமாக இடிக்கப்பட்ட ஆயிரக்கணக்கான டன் குப்பைகளை அகற்றுவது.",
        "இடிக்கப்பட்டதில் சில பறவைகள் இறந்திருக்கலாம் என்று பாதுகாவலர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நொய்டா சூப்பர்டெக் இரட்டைக் கோபுரங்கள் இடிப்பு வெற்றிகரமாக இருந்தபோதிலும், பல அடுக்குமாடி குடியிருப்புகளின் ஜன்னல் கண்ணாடிகளில் விரிசல் ஏற்பட்ட போது, ​​அருகிலுள்ள குடியிருப்பு சமுதாயத்தின் எல்லைச் சுவர் சேதமடைந்தது.",
        "ரியாலிட்டி நிறுவனமான சூப்பர்டெக் லிமிடெட் நொய்டாவில் அதன் இரட்டை கோபுரங்களை இடித்ததால் கட்டுமானம் மற்றும் வட்டி செலவுகள் உட்பட சுமார் ₹500 கோடி இழப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் ஆர் கே அரோரா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சூப்பர்டெக் இரட்டை கோபுரங்களுக்கு அருகில் வசிப்பவர்கள், குறிப்பாக சுவாச நோய்களால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் கூடுதல் கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் மற்றும் முடிந்தால் சில நாட்களுக்கு அந்தப் பகுதியைத் தவிர்க்க வேண்டும் என்று மருத்துவர்கள் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாகிஸ்தானில் பெய்த மழை மற்றும் வெள்ளத்தால் 1,000க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரட்டை கோபுரங்கள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 வினாடிகள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொய்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோ பிரிங்க்மேன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3,700 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர்டெக் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ₹500",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொய்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர் கே அரோரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}