{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/19/army-chief-pays-his-first-formal-courtesy-call-on-new-president/",
  "time_ut": 1660920000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Army Chief Pays His First Formal Courtesy Call on New President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Army Chief Pays His First Formal Courtesy Call on New President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Attaching due recognition and prominence to military formalities, Lieutenant General Vikum Liyanage, Commander of the Army this morning (19) made his first formal courtesy call on President Ranil Wickremasinghe who is also the Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces at the President's Office.",
        "During the courtesy visit, Lieutenant General Vikum Liyanage extended his best wishes to the country’s 8th Executive President and assured his organization’s best cooperation all the time for the performance of national commitments as per provisions in the Constitution in consultation with the Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces.",
        "Towards the end of the brief interaction, Lieutenant General Vikum Liyanage presented a replica of a ‘Punkalasa’ that symbolizes prosperity as a memento to the new President.",
        "Army Chief Pays His First Formal Courtesy Call on New President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikum Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vikum Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vikum Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුධ හමුදාපති නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත සිය ප්‍රථම නිල ආචාරය සිදු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); යුධ හමුදා විධිවිධානවලට නිසි පිළිගැනීමක් සහ ප්‍රමුඛත්වයක් ලබාදෙමින්, යුද්ධ හමුදාධිපති ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලියනගේ මහතා අද (19) පෙරවරුවේ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවේ ප්‍රධානී ද වන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවිය. .",
        "මෙම සුහද සංචාරයේදී ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලියනගේ මහතා රටේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත සිය සුභාශිංසන පළ කළ අතර, සේනාධිනායකතුමා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රතිපාදනවලට අනුව ජාතික කැපවීම් ඉටු කිරීම සඳහා තම සංවිධානයේ උපරිම සහයෝගය සැමවිටම ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය. සන්නද්ධ හමුදා.",
        "කෙටි සංවාදය අවසානයේ ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලියනගේ විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත සමෘද්ධිය සංකේතවත් කරන ‘පුංකලස’ අනුරුවක් පිළිගැන්වීය.",
        "යුධ හමුදාපති නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත සිය ප්‍රථම නිල ආචාරය සිදු කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை இராணுவத் தளபதி தனது முதல் முறையான மரியாதைக்குரிய சந்திப்பைச் செய்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இராணுவ சம்பிரதாயங்களுக்கு உரிய அங்கீகாரத்தையும் முக்கியத்துவத்தையும் வழங்கி, இராணுவத் தளபதி லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் விக்கும் லியனகே இன்று (19) முற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் முப்படைகளின் தலைமைத் தளபதியுமான ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தனது முதல் முறையான மரியாதையை மேற்கொண்டார். .",
        "மரியாதை நிமித்தமான விஜயத்தின் போது, ​​லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் விகும் லியனகே, நாட்டின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தனது வாழ்த்துக்களை தெரிவித்ததுடன், இராணுவத் தளபதியுடன் கலந்தாலோசித்து அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளின்படி தேசிய அர்ப்பணிப்புகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு தனது அமைப்பின் சிறந்த ஒத்துழைப்பை எப்போதும் உறுதியளித்தார். ஆயுதப்படைகள்.",
        "சுருக்கமான உரையாடலின் முடிவில், லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் விக்கும் லியனகே, புதிய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நினைவுச் சின்னமாக செழுமையைக் குறிக்கும் 'புங்கலாச' பிரதி ஒன்றை வழங்கினார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை இராணுவத் தளபதி தனது முதல் முறையான மரியாதைக்குரிய சந்திப்பைச் செய்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}