{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/08/shinzo-abe-shot-former-japan-pm-seen-holding-chest-as-he-collapsed/",
  "time_ut": 1657254720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Shinzo Abe shot: Former Japan PM seen holding chest as he collapsed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Shinzo Abe shot: Former Japan PM seen holding chest as he collapsed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Shinzo Abe, Japan’s longest-serving Prime Minister, was shot at during an election campaign in western Japan’s Nara city and is reportedly in heart failure, said a Reuters report quoting the NHK public television on Friday (8).",
        "The Nara fire department said that Abe was in cardiopulmonary arrest before he was taken to the hospital.",
        "It said that the broadcaster aired footage showing Abe collapsed on the street, with several security guards running toward him.",
        "In the video, Abe is seen holding his chest as he collapsed and his shirt is seen smeared with blood. The report said that the 67-year-old Abe was rushed to a hospital.",
        "A male suspect has been captured by the police, reported Japanese media. He appears to have shot at the Prime Minister from behind with a shotgun.",
        "Shots were heard and a white puff of smoke was seen as Abe made a campaign stump speech outside a train station, NHK said.",
        "NHK World Japan ‘s TV footage of Shinzo Abe being shot pic.twitter.com/niucWs9Xyu",
        "Shinzo Abe shot: Former Japan PM seen holding chest as he collapsed"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nara city",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ෂින්සෝ අබේට වෙඩි තැබීම: ජපානයේ හිටපු අගමැති ඔහු ඇද වැටෙන විට පපුව අල්ලාගෙන සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ දීර්ඝතම කාලයක් අගමැති ධුරය දැරූ ෂින්සෝ අබේ බටහිර ජපානයේ නාරා නගරයේ මැතිවරණ ප්‍රචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයක් අතරතුර වෙඩි තබා ඇති අතර ඔහු හෘදයාබාධයකින් පෙළෙන බව සිකුරාදා (8) NHK මහජන රූපවාහිනිය උපුටා දක්වමින් රොයිටර් වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "නාරා ගිනි නිවන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පැවසුවේ, අබේ රෝහලට ගෙන යාමට පෙර හෘද පෙනහළු අඩාල වී සිටි බවයි.",
        "එහි සඳහන් වූයේ අබේ පාරේ වැටී සිටින ආකාරය දැක්වෙන දර්ශන විකාශනය විකාශනය කළ බවත්, ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඔහු දෙසට දිව යන බවත්ය.",
        "වීඩියෝවේ, අබේ ඇද වැටෙන විට ඔහුගේ පපුව අල්ලාගෙන සිටින අතර ඔහුගේ කමිසය ලේ වලින් තැවරී ඇත. 67 හැවිරිදි අබේ වහාම රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "පිරිමි සැකකරුවෙකු පොලිසිය විසින් අල්ලාගෙන ඇති බව ජපාන මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරයි. ඔහු තුවක්කුවකින් පිටුපසින් සිට අගමැතිවරයාට වෙඩි තබා ඇති බව පෙනේ.",
        "අබේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානයකින් පිටත මැතිවරණ ප්‍රචාරක කඳේ කතාවක් කරන විට වෙඩි හඬ ඇසුණු අතර සුදු පැහැති දුමාරයක් දිස් වූ බව එන්එච්කේ පැවසීය.",
        "NHK World ජපානයේ ෂින්සෝ අබේට වෙඩි තබන ලද රූපවාහිනී දර්ශන pic.twitter.com/niucWs9Xyu",
        "ෂින්සෝ අබේට වෙඩි තැබීම: ජපානයේ හිටපු අගමැති ඔහු ඇද වැටෙන විට පපුව අල්ලාගෙන සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරා නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්එච්කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්එච්කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஷின்சோ அபே துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டார்: முன்னாள் ஜப்பான் பிரதமர் அவர் சரிந்தபோது மார்பைப் பிடித்துக் கொண்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானின் நீண்ட காலம் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த ஷின்சோ அபே, மேற்கு ஜப்பானின் நாரா நகரில் தேர்தல் பிரச்சாரத்தின் போது சுடப்பட்டு இதய செயலிழந்ததாக கூறப்படுகிறது என்று வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (8) NHK பொது தொலைக்காட்சியை மேற்கோள்காட்டி ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாரா தீயணைப்புத் துறை, அபே மருத்துவமனைக்குக் கொண்டு செல்லப்படுவதற்கு முன்பு இருதய நுரையீரல் அடைப்பில் இருந்ததாகக் கூறியது.",
        "அபே தெருவில் சரிந்து விழுந்ததைக் காட்டும் காட்சிகளை ஒளிபரப்பாளர் ஒளிபரப்பியதாகவும், பல பாதுகாப்புக் காவலர்கள் அவரை நோக்கி ஓடுவதாகவும் அது கூறியது.",
        "வீடியோவில், அபே சரிந்தபோது அவரது மார்பைப் பிடித்துக் கொண்டிருப்பதைக் காணலாம் மற்றும் அவரது சட்டை இரத்தத்தால் பூசப்பட்டதாகக் காணப்படுகிறது. 67 வயதான அபே மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டதாக அந்த அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் ஒருவர் பொலிஸாரால் பிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜப்பானிய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. அவர் துப்பாக்கியால் பிரதமரை பின்னால் இருந்து சுட்டதாக தெரிகிறது.",
        "அபே ஒரு ரயில் நிலையத்திற்கு வெளியே பிரச்சார ஸ்டம்ப் உரையை நிகழ்த்தியபோது துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சத்தம் கேட்டது மற்றும் வெண்மையான புகை மூட்டம் காணப்பட்டது என்று NHK தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஷின்சோ அபே சுடப்படும் NHK வேர்ல்ட் ஜப்பானின் தொலைக்காட்சி காட்சிகள் pic.twitter.com/niucWs9Xyu",
        "ஷின்சோ அபே துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டார்: முன்னாள் ஜப்பான் பிரதமர் அவர் சரிந்தபோது மார்பைப் பிடித்துக் கொண்டார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரா நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}