{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131197",
  "time_ut": 1657448517,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யானை தாக்கியதில் விவசாயி உயிரிழப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Farmer killed in elephant attack",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "A farmer who was on field guard was killed yesterday evening (09) after being attacked by a wild elephant in Kandiyanaru village of Vaunadivu police division of Batticaloa district, the police said.",
        "Karunakaran (57 years old), a father of four from Unnichai area, was killed in the accident.",
        "On the day of the incident, while he was tending to his violin in Kandianar area from his home, a wild elephant suddenly entered the violin and attacked the person.",
        "During the initial investigation of the police, it was revealed that the farmer who was guarding the field in Ayal, who was seriously injured, died after being taken to the Thandiyadi hospital.",
        "According to the order of the Batticaloa court judge, Vaunadivu District Sudden Death Investigation Officer Thampipillai Tavakumar, who went to Samba, visited the body and ordered the police to hand over the body to the relatives after the post-mortem."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandiyanaru",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vaunadivu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa district",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "57 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Unnichai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandianar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ayal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thandiyadi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vaunadivu District Sudden Death Investigation Officer Thampipillai Tavakumar",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samba",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වන අලි ප්‍රහාරයකින් ගොවියෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "මඩකලපුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ වවුනදිව් පොලිස් වසමේ කණ්ඩියනාරු ගම්මානයේදී වන අලි ප්‍රහාරයකට ලක්ව ඊයේ (09) සවස ක්ෂේත්‍ර මුර සේවයේ යෙදී සිටි ගොවියෙකු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇති බව පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "අනතුරින් මිය ගොස් ඇත්තේ උන්නිචායි ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි කරුණාකරන් (අවු. 57) සිව්දරු පියෙකි.",
        "සිද්ධිය වූ දිනයේ ඔහු සිය නිවසේ සිට කන්දියනාර් ප්‍රදේශයේ වයලීනය වාදනය කරමින් සිටියදී එක්වරම වයලීනයට ඇතුළු වූ වන අලියෙකු එම පුද්ගලයාට පහර දී තිබෙනවා.",
        "බරපතළ තුවාල ලැබූ අයල්හි කුඹුරු මුර කරමින් සිටි ගොවියා තාණ්ඩියාඩි රෝහලට රැගෙන යාමෙන් පසු මියගොස් ඇති බව පොලිසිය කළ මූලික විමර්ශනයේදී අනාවරණය විය.",
        "මඩකලපුව අධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරයාගේ නියෝගයට අනුව සම්බා ප්‍රදේශයට ගිය වවුනදිව් දිසා හදිසි මරණ විමර්ශන නිලධාරී තම්පිපිල්ලේ තවකුමාර් මහතා දේහය බැලීමට ගොස් පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණයෙන් පසු දේහය ඥාතීන්ට භාර දෙන ලෙස පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandiyanaru",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනදිව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 57 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උන්නිච්චයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්දියනාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අයල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තණ්ඩියාඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනදිව් දිසා හදිසි මරණ විමර්ශන නිලධාරී තම්පිපිල්ලේ තවකුමාර්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්බා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யானை தாக்கியதில் விவசாயி உயிரிழப்பு",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "மட்டக்களப்பு மாவட்டத்தின் வவுணதீவு பொலிஸ் பிரிவிலுள்ள கண்டியனாறு கிராமத்தில் காட்டு யானை தாக்கியதில் வயல் காவலில் இருந்த விவசாயி ஒருவர் நேற்று  (09) மாலை பலியாகியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "உன்னிச்சை பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த நான்கு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையான (57 வயதுடைய) கருணாகரன் என்பவரே இவ்விபத்தில் பலியானவராவார்.",
        "சம்பவ தினத்தன்று தனது வீட்டிலிருந்து கண்டியனாறு பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள தனது வயலினை பராமரித்து காவலில் இருந்த போது திடீரென வயலினுள் நுழைந்த காட்டு யானை குறித்த நபரினை தாக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்போது படுகாயமடைந்த நிலையில் அயலில் உள்ள வயல் காவலில் இருந்த விவசாயிகளால்  மீட்டெடுத்து தாண்டியடி வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு சென்றபோது சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸாரின் ஆரம்பக்கட்ட விசாரணைகளின் போது தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "மட்டக்களப்பு நீதிமன்ற நீதிவான் அவர்களின் உத்தரவிற்கமைவாக சம்ப இடத்திற்கு சென்ற வவுணதீவு பிரதேச திடீர் மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி தம்பிப்பிள்ளை தவக்குமார் சடலத்தினை பார்வையிட்டதுடன், பிரேத பிரிசோதனையின் பின்னர் சடலத்தினை உறவினர்களிடம் ஒப்படைககும் படி பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandiyanaru",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுணதீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "57 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உன்னிச்சை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டியனார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அயல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாண்டியடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுணதீவு மாவட்ட திடீர் மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி தம்பிப்பிள்ளை தவகுமார்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}