{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83503/kanchana-wants-cope-inquiry-into-pucsl-chiefs-allegations-on-fuel-prices",
  "time_ut": 1657259460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kanchana wants COPE inquiry into PUCSL chief’s allegations on fuel prices",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kanchana wants COPE inquiry into PUCSL chief’s allegations on fuel prices",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara today (July 08) urged the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) to inquire into the allegations levelled by the Chairman of Public Utilities Commission (PUCSL) with regard to the fuel prices and procurement process.",
        "In a tweet, the lawmaker asked the committee’s chairman Prof. Charitha Herath to summon the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) officials and him before the COPE to look into the allegations.",
        "Minister Wijesekara stressed that an inquiry should be conducted to determine whether the PUCSL chairman has misled the COPE and the members of public through his claims.",
        "PUCSL chairman, in a personal statement made at a recent COPE meeting, claimed that petrol and diesel can be sold for around Rs. 250 in Sri Lanka.",
        "The COPE had convened a meeting on July 06, under the chairmanship of Prof. Charita Herath to examine the Auditor General’s report for the years 2018 and 2019 and current performance of the electricity sector regulator.",
        "According to the PUCSL chairman, this was revealed in the statistics on the import prices of petroleum and the taxes levied by the government.",
        "He pointed out that petrol and diesel can be provided in Sri Lanka for Rs. 200 less than the current price. also said the government has collected a tax of Rs. 280 for one litre of diesel imported on July 01."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years 2018 and",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන මිල සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ ප්‍රධානියාගේ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෝප් පරීක්ෂණයක් අවශ්‍ය බව කාංචනාට අවශ්‍යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන මිල සහ ප්‍රසම්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (PUCSL) සභාපතිවරයා විසින් එල්ල කරන ලද චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කරන ලෙස විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා අද (ජූලි 08) පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවට (COPE) ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් නීති සම්පාදකවරයා කමිටුවේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය චරිත හේරත්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ මෙම චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බැලීම සඳහා ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ (CPC) නිලධාරීන් සහ ඔහු කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවන ලෙසයි.",
        "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා සිය ප්‍රකාශයන් හරහා කෝප් කමිටුව සහ මහජනතාව නොමඟ යවා ඇත්ද යන්න පිළිබඳව පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්විය යුතු බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "PUCSL සභාපති පසුගියදා කෝප් කමිටු රැස්වීමකදී පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් රු. ලංකාවේ 250යි.",
        "2018 සහ 2019 වසර සඳහා විගණකාධිපතිවරයාගේ වාර්තාව සහ විදුලිබල අංශයේ නියාමකයාගේ වත්මන් කාර්ය සාධනය පරීක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා කෝප් කමිටුව ජුලි 06 වැනි දින මහාචාර්ය චරිතා හේරත්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රැස්වීමක් කැඳවා තිබුණි.",
        "PUCSL සභාපතිවරයාට අනුව ඛනිජ තෙල් ආනයනික මිල ගණන් සහ රජය අය කරන බදු පිළිබඳ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනවලින් මේ බව අනාවරණය විය.",
        "ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ රු. දැනට පවතින මිලට වඩා 200ක් අඩුයි. රජය රු. ජූලි 01 වැනිදා ආනයනය කළ ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 280කි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්ති කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපතිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2018 සහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் விலை தொடர்பான PUCSL தலைவரின் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் குறித்து காஞ்சனா கோப் விசாரணையை விரும்புகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள் விலை மற்றும் கொள்முதல் செயல்முறை தொடர்பாக பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (PUCSL) தலைவர் முன்வைத்துள்ள குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் குறித்து விசாரிக்குமாறு மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர இன்று (ஜூலை 08) பொது நிறுவனங்கள் மீதான குழுவிடம் (கோப்) வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஒரு ட்வீட்டில், சட்டமியற்றுபவர் குழுவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத்திடம், இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் (CPC) அதிகாரிகளையும் அவரையும் கோப் விசாரணைக்கு அழைக்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "PUCSL தலைவர் தனது கூற்றுக்கள் மூலம் கோப் குழுவையும் பொதுமக்களையும் தவறாக வழிநடத்தியுள்ளாரா என்பதை கண்டறிய விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "PUCSL தலைவர், சமீபத்தில் நடந்த கோப் கூட்டத்தில் தனிப்பட்ட அறிக்கையில், பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசலை சுமார் ரூபாய்க்கு விற்கலாம் என்று கூறினார். இலங்கையில் 250.",
        "2018 மற்றும் 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டுகளுக்கான கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகத்தின் அறிக்கை மற்றும் மின்சாரத் துறை கட்டுப்பாட்டாளரின் தற்போதைய செயற்பாடுகளை ஆராய்வதற்காக, ஜூலை 06 ஆம் திகதி, பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத் தலைமையில், கோப் கூட்டம் கூட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "பெட்ரோலியத்தின் இறக்குமதி விலை மற்றும் அரசாங்கம் விதிக்கும் வரிகள் குறித்த புள்ளி விவரங்களில் இது தெரியவந்துள்ளதாக PUCSL தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் பெற்றோல் மற்றும் டீசலை ரூபாவிற்கு வழங்க முடியும் என அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார். தற்போதைய விலையை விட 200 ரூபாய் குறைவு. மேலும் அரசு வரியாக ரூ. ஜூலை 01 அன்று இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு லிட்டர் டீசல் 280 ரூபாய்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பவர் & எனர்ஜி காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள் 2018 மற்றும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}