{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-basl-urges-police-army-chiefs-to-ensure-freedom-of-expression-after-arrest-disruptions-96719/",
  "time_ut": 1656593820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka BASL urges police, army chiefs to ensure freedom of expression after arrest, disruptions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka BASL urges police, army chiefs to ensure freedom of expression after arrest, disruptions",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s Bar Association (BASL) expressing its displeasure over the actions of police and army wrote to the both Inspector General of Police (IGP) and army chief asked to ensure that the fundamental rights of the people.",
        "A Video shared in social media showed a man in army uniform surrounded by another two in uniform was trying to snatch the placards from the protesters in Galle Fort where Sri Lanka cricket team is playing its first test against Australia. The protesters demanded President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to resign.",
        "“We reminded the Army Commander and the IGP of the wisdom of the judgement of the SC in the Janagosha Case,” BASL chief Pieris tweeted referring to a 1993 case in which the court held that the fundamental right of the petitioner under the constitution was infringed, and awarded him compensation in the sum of Rs. 50,000 payable by the State.",
        "“It is prudent for the authorities including the Army Commander and the IGP to remember these words from the Jana Ghosha Case: “Stifling the peaceful expression of legitimate dissent today can only result, inexorably, in the catastrophic explosion of violence some other day,” Pieris said.",
        "The anti-government protestors had brought placards, boards and signs demanding the President to step down near the Galle International Cricket stadium and had displayed banners at Fort which overlooked the stadium. The placards were removed promptly and political analysts cited the move was to prevent a bad international publicity for President Rajapaksa.",
        "“We call upon you to ensure that the fundamental rights of the people such as the freedom of expression including the freedom of speech and publication and the freedom of peaceful assembly which are aspects of the sovereignty of the people are respected and protected,” the BASL said in its statement to the police and army chief.",
        "“It has also been drawn to our attention that the particular area of the ramparts of the Galle Fort are public areas and hence that there is no lawful reason to disperse protestors. We continue to remind you of the importance of allowing people to exercise their freedom of speech and expression including their right to dissent.”",
        "The BASL has repeatedly noted infringement of fundamental rights by police and military since the youth-led anti-government protests started. The latest one is the fifth statement issued by the BASL urging Sri Lankan authorities and armed forces to allow citizens to express their economic grief and difficulties, as it is a fundamental human right.",
        "“The suppression of the people’s right to protest and dissent is not the answer to the present situation in the country where the people are facing untold hardships due to shortages of fuel and other essentials,” the BASL further said.",
        "“We are also concerned of reports that Sri Lanka Army personnel had also been involved in removing the protestors. Such involvement by Army personnel is not in accordance with the law.”",
        "According to Police, six individuals had been arrested on Wednesday (29) for staging a protest outside the official residence of the President when the protest was carried out by group named United National Self-Employed Businessmen’s Association. (Colombo/June 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "some other day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Galle International Cricket",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Galle Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Self-Employed Businessmen’s Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම්, බාධා කිරීම් වලින් පසු අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස සහතික කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා BASL පොලිසියෙන්, හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) පොලිසියේ සහ හමුදාවේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය පිළිබඳව සිය අප්‍රසාදය පළකරමින් ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් තහවුරු කරන ලෙස පොලිස්පතිවරයාට (IGP) සහ හමුදා ප්‍රධානියාට ලිඛිතව දන්වා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් කණ්ඩායම ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහිව පළමු ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තරගයට ක්‍රීඩා කරන ගාලු කොටුවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් විරෝධතා පුවරු උදුරා ගැනීමට නිල ඇඳුමින් සැරසුණු තවත් දෙදෙනෙකු වටකරගත් හමුදා නිල ඇඳුමින් සැරසී සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු උත්සාහ කරන අයුරු සමාජ මාධ්‍ය තුළ හුවමාරු වූ වීඩියෝවක දැක්වෙනවා. විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙසයි.",
        "\"ජනඝෝෂ නඩුවේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ තීන්දුවේ ප්‍රඥාව අපි යුධ හමුදාපතිවරයාට සහ පොලිස්පතිතුමාට මතක් කළා\" යනුවෙන් BASL ප්‍රධානී පීරිස් ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ 1993 දී පෙත්සම්කරුගේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව යටතේ ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම උල්ලංඝණය වන බවට අධිකරණය තීන්දු කළ නඩුවක් ගැන සඳහන් කරමිනි. , සහ ඔහුට රුපියල් මිලියනයක වන්දි මුදලක් පිරිනමන ලදී. 50,000 රජය විසින් ගෙවිය යුතුය.",
        "\"යුද හමුදාපතිවරයා සහ පොලිස්පතිවරයා ඇතුළු බලධාරීන්ට ජන ඝෝෂා නඩුවේ මෙම වදන් මතක තබා ගැනීම විචක්ෂණශීලී ය: \"අද නීත්‍යානුකූල විරුද්ධත්වය සාමකාමීව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම මැඩපැවැත්වීමෙන් සිදුවිය හැක්කේ, අනිවාර්‍යෙන්ම, වෙනත් දවසක ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයේ ව්‍යසනකාරී පිපිරීමක් පමණි.\" පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂකයින් ගාල්ල ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාංගනය අසලට ජනාධිපතිවරයාට බැසීමට බල කරන පුවරු, පුවරු සහ පුවරු රැගෙන ආ අතර, ක්‍රීඩාංගනය නොපෙනෙන ලෙස කොටුවේ බැනර් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කර තිබුණි. එම පුවරු කඩිනමින් ඉවත් කරන ලද අතර දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයින් සඳහන් කළේ රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් නරක ප්‍රචාරයක් ඇතිවීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා මෙම පියවර ගත් බවයි.",
        "\"ජනතාවගේ පරමාධිපත්‍යයේ අංගයන් වන භාෂණයේ සහ ප්‍රකාශනයේ නිදහස සහ සාමකාමීව රැස්වීමේ නිදහස ඇතුළු අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස වැනි ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්වලට ගරු කිරීම සහ ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහතික කරන ලෙස අපි ඔබෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමු\". යැයි පොලිසියට හා හමුදාපතිට කළ ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "“ගාලු කොටුවේ බලකොටුවල නිශ්චිත ප්‍රදේශය පොදු ස්ථාන බවත්, එබැවින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසුරුවා හැරීමට නීත්‍යානුකූල හේතුවක් නොමැති බවත් අපගේ අවධානයට යොමු කර ඇත. මිනිසුන්ට විරුද්ධ වීමට ඇති අයිතිය ඇතුළුව ඔවුන්ගේ භාෂණයේ සහ ප්‍රකාශනයේ නිදහස භාවිතා කිරීමට ඉඩ දීමේ වැදගත්කම අපි ඔබට දිගටම මතක් කර දෙන්නෙමු.",
        "තරුනයින් විසින් මෙහෙයවන ලද ආන්ඩු විරෝධී විරෝධතා ආරම්භ වූ දා සිට පොලිසිය සහ හමුදාව විසින් මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම BASL යලි යලිත් සටහන් කර ඇත. නවතම එක වන්නේ මූලික මානව අයිතිවාසිකමක් වන බැවින් පුරවැසියන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ආර්ථික දුක සහ දුෂ්කරතා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ඉඩ දෙන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන්ට සහ සන්නද්ධ හමුදාවන්ට බල කරමින් BASL විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද පස්වැනි ප්‍රකාශයයි.",
        "\"ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ජනතාව කිව නොහැකි දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ දී සිටින රටේ වර්තමාන තත්ත්වයට විරෝධය දැක්වීමට සහ විරුද්ධ වීමට ජනතාවට ඇති අයිතිය යටපත් කිරීම පිළිතුර නොවේ,\" BASL වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "“විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාවේ නිලධාරීන් ද සම්බන්ධ වී ඇති බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා පිළිබඳව ද අපි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිමු. හමුදා සාමාජිකයන්ගේ එවැනි මැදිහත්වීම් නීතියට අනුකූල නොවේ. ”",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික ස්වයං රැකියාලාභී ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය නම් කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් පසුගිය බදාදා (29) පස්වරුවේ ජනාධිපති නිල නිවස ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වූ අවස්ථාවේදී පුද්ගලයින් 6 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු කොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස් ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙනත් දිනක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස් ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික ස්වයං රැකියා ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கைது, இடையூறுகளுக்குப் பிறகு கருத்துச் சுதந்திரத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறு இலங்கை BASL பொலிஸ், இராணுவத் தளபதிகளை வலியுறுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) பொலிஸ் மற்றும் இராணுவத்தின் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து தனது அதிருப்தியை வெளியிட்டு, மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறு பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் (IGP) மற்றும் இராணுவத் தளபதி ஆகிய இருவருக்கும் கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளது.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிரான இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் அணி தனது முதல் டெஸ்ட் போட்டியில் விளையாடும் காலி கோட்டையில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களிடம் இருந்து இராணுவ சீருடையில் இருந்த ஒருவர், சீருடையில் இருந்த மேலும் இருவரால் சூழப்பட்ட பலகைகளை பறிக்க முற்பட்ட வீடியோ சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பகிரப்பட்டது. ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி விலகுமாறு வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "\"ஜனகோஷா வழக்கில் உச்சநீதிமன்றத்தின் தீர்ப்பின் ஞானத்தை நாங்கள் இராணுவத் தளபதி மற்றும் ஐஜிபி ஆகியோருக்கு நினைவூட்டினோம்,\" என்று BASL தலைவர் பீரிஸ் 1993 ஆம் ஆண்டு வழக்கை குறிப்பிட்டு ட்வீட் செய்தார், அதில் அரசியலமைப்பின் கீழ் மனுதாரரின் அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறப்பட்டுள்ளது என்று நீதிமன்றம் கூறியது. , மற்றும் அவருக்கு இழப்பீடாக ரூ. 50,000 அரசு செலுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "\"இராணுவத் தளபதி மற்றும் ஐஜிபி உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகள் ஜன கோஷா வழக்கின் இந்த வார்த்தைகளை நினைவில் கொள்வது விவேகமானது: \"இன்று நியாயமான எதிர்ப்பின் அமைதியான வெளிப்பாட்டை முடக்குவது, தவிர்க்கமுடியாமல், வேறொரு நாளில் பேரழிவுகரமான வன்முறை வெடிப்பில் மட்டுமே விளையும்.\" பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் காலி சர்வதேச கிரிக்கட் மைதானத்திற்கு அருகில் ஜனாதிபதியை பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி பதாகைகள், பலகைகள் மற்றும் பலகைகளை கொண்டு வந்திருந்ததுடன், மைதானத்தை புறக்கணிக்கும் வகையில் கோட்டையில் பதாகைகளை காட்சிப்படுத்தியிருந்தனர். பதாகைகள் உடனடியாக அகற்றப்பட்டன மற்றும் அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்கள் இந்த நடவடிக்கை ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு மோசமான சர்வதேச விளம்பரத்தைத் தடுக்கும் என்று மேற்கோள் காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "\"மக்களின் இறையாண்மையின் அம்சங்களான பேச்சு மற்றும் வெளியிடும் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் அமைதியான முறையில் ஒன்றுகூடும் சுதந்திரம் உள்ளிட்ட கருத்துச் சுதந்திரம் போன்ற மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மதிக்கப்படுவதையும் பாதுகாக்கப்படுவதையும் உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறு நாங்கள் உங்களை அழைக்கிறோம்\" என்று BASL பொலிஸ் மற்றும் இராணுவத் தளபதிக்கு தனது அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“காலி கோட்டையின் அரண்களின் குறிப்பிட்ட பகுதி பொது இடங்கள் என்றும், எனவே போராட்டக்காரர்களை கலைப்பதற்கு சட்டபூர்வமான காரணம் எதுவும் இல்லை என்பதும் எங்கள் கவனத்திற்கு ஈர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. மக்கள் தங்கள் கருத்துச் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் கருத்துச் சுதந்திரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்த அனுமதிப்பதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை நாங்கள் உங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து நினைவூட்டுகிறோம்.",
        "இளைஞர்கள் தலைமையிலான அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டங்கள் தொடங்கியதில் இருந்து, காவல்துறை மற்றும் இராணுவத்தால் அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மீறப்படுவதை BASL மீண்டும் மீண்டும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது. அடிப்படை மனித உரிமை என்பதால், குடிமக்கள் தங்கள் பொருளாதார துயரங்களையும் சிரமங்களையும் வெளிப்படுத்த அனுமதிக்குமாறு இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளையும் ஆயுதப் படைகளையும் வலியுறுத்தி BASL வெளியிட்ட ஐந்தாவது அறிக்கை சமீபத்தியது.",
        "\"எரிபொருள் மற்றும் இதர அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்கள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக மக்கள் சொல்லொணா இன்னல்களை எதிர்நோக்கும் நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமைக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவிப்பதற்கான மக்களின் உரிமையை நசுக்குவது தீர்வாகாது\" என BASL மேலும் கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "“போராட்டக்காரர்களை அகற்றுவதில் இலங்கை இராணுவத்தினரும் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர் என்ற செய்திகள் குறித்தும் நாங்கள் கவலையடைகிறோம். இராணுவத்தினரின் இத்தகைய ஈடுபாடு சட்டத்திற்கு உட்பட்டது அல்ல.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்திற்கு முன்பாக ஐக்கிய தேசிய சுயதொழில் வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம் என்ற அமைப்பினால் நேற்று புதன்கிழமை (29) ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட ஆறு பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேறு சில நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி சர்வதேச கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய சுயதொழில் வணிகர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}