{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84748/controversial-godman-accused-of-rape-seeks-asylum-in-sri-lanka-report",
  "time_ut": 1662313440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Controversial ‘godman’ accused of rape seeks asylum in Sri Lanka - report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Controversial ‘godman’ accused of rape seeks asylum in Sri Lanka - report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Self-proclaimed spiritual leader and accused of rape, Nithyananda is reportedly seeking political asylum in Sri Lanka, according to India Today.",
        "Citing a deterioration in his health, the fugitive godman penned a letter to the president of the island nation on August 7 and flagged an ‘urgent’ need for medical attention. The letter mentioned the scarcity of medical infrastructure in the Sovereign State of Shrikailasa, an island established and named by the spiritual leader.",
        "A top source in the Sri Lankan government confirmed to India Today that the letter mentioned that Nithyananda was critically ill and in dire need of treatment. India Today accessed the letter written to the president of Sri Lanka, Ranil Wickremesinghe, in August 2022.",
        "Written by Nithyaprematma Ananda Swami, who claims to be the minister of foreign affairs of Shrikailasa, the letter requested the president as follows -",
        "“The Supreme Pontiff of Hinduism (SPH) His Divine Holiness Sri Nithyananda Paramashivam is in need of urgent medical care for a serious medical condition. After exhausting the medical facilities currently available in Kailasa, the doctors are still unable to diagnose the underlying medical condition. The SPH is presently in the Sovereign Land of Shrikailasa, which does not have the required medical infrastructure that is most urgently needed at this time.”",
        "This letter stated that Nityananda was critically unwell and required treatment, hence his followers are not only seeking political asylum but medical help from Sri Lanka.",
        "In the letter, the Shrikailasa minister said, “Keeping the health of Nithyananda in mind, we request Your Excellency to grant irrevocable political asylum immediately to SPH so he can be airlifted via air ambulance and receive medical treatment in safety in the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka. In addition, given that SPH’s life is in danger from the forces of persecution, we believe that the best way to guarantee his safety is for SPH to travel from and to Shrikailasa as a Head of State.”",
        "The self-proclaimed minister requested the island nation to initiate diplomatic ties with his so-called country. Demanding a safe passage for Nithyananda, his minister said that Shrikailasa would bear the expenses of the medical treatment and the equipment too.",
        "“Shrikailasa will purchase and bring any medical equipment required to treat SPH and will take care of all the medical expenses incurred in Sri Lanka. And as an expression of our gratitude, we will leave behind that medical equipment worth millions of dollars for the benefit of the people of your nation,” the fugitive godman’s minister’s letter read.",
        "The letter even mentioned Nithyananda’s offer to invest in Sri Lanka, ‘once irrevocable political asylum is granted’ to the fugitive self-styled godman.",
        "It may be recalled that Nithyananda fled from India in November 2018 after Gujarat police arrested two of his disciples on charges of kidnapping. He was accused of using the faces of children to attract donations. Rape charges were also registered against Nithyananda in Karnataka. Subsequently, the self-styled godman left the country.",
        "The rape charges against Nithyananda were filed in 2010 based on a complaint by his former driver Lenin. He was arrested and later released on bail.",
        "Nithyananda hails from Tamil Nadu and his real name is said to be Rajasekharan."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sovereign State of Shrikailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ananda Swami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shrikailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Pontiff of Hinduism",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sovereign Land of Shrikailasa",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nityananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shrikailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shrikailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shrikailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shrikailasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gujarat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karnataka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lenin",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nithyananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajasekharan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්ත්‍රී දූෂණ චෝදනා එල්ල වූ ආන්දෝලනාත්මක ‘දේව මිනිසා’ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සරණාගතභාවය පතා යයි - වාර්තාවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ස්වයං ප්‍රකාශිත අධ්‍යාත්මික නායකයෙකු සහ ස්ත්‍රී දූෂණ චෝදනාවට ලක්ව සිටින නිත්‍යානන්ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන රැකවරණ පතා සිටින බව ඉන්දියා ටුඩේ වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "ඔහුගේ සෞඛ්‍යයේ පිරිහීම උපුටා දක්වමින් පලාගිය දේව මිනිසා අගෝස්තු 7 වන දින දිවයිනේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලිපියක් ලියා වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා 'හදිසි' අවශ්‍යතාවයක් සලකුණු කළේය. අධ්‍යාත්මික නායකයා විසින් පිහිටුවන ලද සහ නම් කරන ලද දූපතක් වන ශ්‍රීකයිලාස ස්වෛරී රාජ්‍යයේ වෛද්‍ය යටිතල පහසුකම්වල හිඟකම ලිපියේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "නිත්‍යානන්ද අසාධ්‍ය තත්ත්වයේ පසුවන බවත් ඔහුට ප්‍රතිකාර අවශ්‍ය බවත් එම ලිපියේ සඳහන් වූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ මූලාශ්‍රයක් ඉන්දියා ටුඩේ වෙත තහවුරු කළේය. ඉන්ඩියා ටුඩේ 2022 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත ලියන ලද ලිපිය වෙත ප්‍රවේශ විය.",
        "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා යැයි කියාගන්නා නිත්‍යප්‍රේමත්මා ආනන්ද ස්වාමි විසින් ලියන ලද ලිපියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත්තේ මෙසේය.",
        "“හින්දු ආගමේ උත්තරීතර පාප් වහන්සේ (SPH) අති උතුම් ශ්‍රී නිත්‍යානන්ද පරමශිවම් තුමාට බරපතළ රෝගී තත්ත්වයක් සඳහා හදිසි වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර අවශ්‍ය වේ. කෛලාසයේ දැනට පවතින වෛද්‍ය පහසුකම් අවසන් කිරීමෙන් පසුව, වෛද්‍යවරුන්ට තවමත් යටින් පවතින රෝගී තත්ත්වය හඳුනා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී තිබේ. SPH දැනට ශ්‍රීකයිලාස ස්වෛරී දේශයේ පවතින අතර, මේ අවස්ථාවේ ඉතා කඩිනමින් අවශ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය යටිතල පහසුකම් නොමැත.",
        "නිත්‍යානන්ද අසාධ්‍ය තත්ත්වයෙන් පසුවන බවත් ප්‍රතිකාර අවශ්‍ය බවත්, එබැවින් ඔහුගේ අනුගාමිකයින් දේශපාලන රැකවරණ පතනවා පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් වෛද්‍ය ආධාර පතන බවත් මෙම ලිපියේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "එම ලිපියේ ශ්‍රීකයිලාස අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ, “නිත්‍යානන්දගේ සෞඛ්‍යය මතකයේ තබා ගනිමින්, SPH වෙත ආපසු හැරවිය නොහැකි දේශපාලන රැකවරණ ලබා දෙන ලෙස අපි ඔබතුමාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමු, එවිට ඔහුට ගුවන් ගිලන් රථයක් හරහා ගුවන් ගත කර ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ ආරක්ෂිතව වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා ගත හැකිය. ශ්රී ලංකාව. ඊට අමතරව, හිංසාකාරී බලවේගයන්ගෙන් SPH ගේ ජීවිතය අනතුරේ පවතින බැවින්, ඔහුගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහතික කිරීමට ඇති හොඳම ක්‍රමය SPH විසින් රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙකු ලෙස ශ්‍රීකයිලාස වෙත ගමන් කිරීම බව අපි විශ්වාස කරමු.",
        "තමාගේ ඊනියා රට සමඟ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස ස්වයං ප්‍රකාශිත අමාත්‍යවරයා දිවයින ජාතියෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. නිත්‍යානන්දට ආරක්ෂිත මාර්ගයක් ඉල්ලා සිටි ඔහුගේ අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසුවේ වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර සහ උපකරණවල වියදම් ද ශ්‍රීකයිලාසා විසින් දරනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "SPH ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ඕනෑම වෛද්‍ය උපකරණයක් ශ්‍රීකයිලාසා විසින් මිලදී ගෙන රැගෙන එන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිදු වන සියලුම වෛද්‍ය වියදම් බලා ගනී. අපගේ කෘතවේදීත්වයේ ප්‍රකාශයක් ලෙස, අපි ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනක් වටිනා එම වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ ඔබේ ජාතියේ ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා ඉතිරි කරමු, ”පලාගිය දේවතාවාගේ ඇමතිවරයාගේ ලිපිය කියවීය.",
        "නිත්‍යානන්ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ආයෝජනය කිරීමට ඉදිරිපත් වූ අතර, පලාගිය ස්වයං ප්‍රකාශිත දේවතාවාට ‘ආපසු හැරිය නොහැකි දේශපාලන රැකවරණ ලබා දුන් පසු’ එම ලිපියේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "2018 නොවැම්බරයේදී නිත්‍යානන්ද ඉන්දියාවෙන් පලා ගියේ ගුජරාට් පොලිසිය පැහැරගැනීමේ චෝදනාව මත ඔහුගේ ගෝලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් පසුව බව මතක තබා ගත හැකිය. පරිත්‍යාග ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීම සඳහා දරුවන්ගේ මුහුණු භාවිතා කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහුට චෝදනා එල්ල විය. නිත්‍යානන්දට එරෙහිව කර්නාටක ප්‍රාන්තයේ ස්ත්‍රී දූෂණ චෝදනා ද වාර්තා විය. ඉන්පසුව, ස්වයං-ආකාරයේ දේවතාවා රට හැර ගියේය.",
        "නිත්‍යානන්දට එරෙහිව ස්ත්‍රී දූෂණ චෝදනා ගොනු කරනු ලැබුවේ 2010 වසරේදී ඔහුගේ හිටපු රියැදුරු ලෙනින් විසින් කරන ලද පැමිණිල්ලකට අනුවය. ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන පසුව ඇප මත මුදා හැරිණි.",
        "නිත්‍යානන්ද තමිල්නාඩුවේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු වන අතර ඔහුගේ සැබෑ නම රාජසේකරන් බව පැවසේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස ස්වෛරී රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද ස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු ආගමේ උත්තරීතර පාප්තුමා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෛලාසය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාසයේ ස්වෛරී දේශය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීකයිලාස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුජරාට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කර්නාටක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙනින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජසේකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலாத்கார குற்றச்சாட்டில் சிக்கிய சர்ச்சைக்குரிய ‘தெய்வ மனிதன்’ இலங்கையில் புகலிடம் கோருகிறார் – அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுயமாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட ஆன்மீகத் தலைவர் மற்றும் கற்பழிப்பு குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கு உள்ளான நித்யானந்தா, இலங்கையில் அரசியல் தஞ்சம் கோரி வருவதாக இந்தியா டுடே செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அவரது உடல்நிலை மோசமடைந்ததை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, தப்பியோடிய கடவுள் ஆகஸ்ட் 7 அன்று தீவு நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஒரு கடிதம் எழுதி, மருத்துவ கவனிப்புக்கான 'அவசர' தேவையைக் கொடியிட்டார். ஆன்மீகத் தலைவரால் நிறுவப்பட்ட மற்றும் பெயரிடப்பட்ட தீவான ஸ்ரீகைலாசத்தின் இறையாண்மை மாநிலத்தின் மருத்துவ உள்கட்டமைப்பு பற்றாக்குறையை கடிதம் குறிப்பிடுகிறது.",
        "நித்யானந்தா உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருப்பதாகவும், அவருக்கு தீவிர சிகிச்சை தேவைப்படுவதாகவும் அந்தக் கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் உயர்மட்ட வட்டாரம் ஒன்று இந்தியா டுடேவிடம் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது. ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 இல் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தை இந்தியா டுடே அணுகியது.",
        "ஸ்ரீகைலாச வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் என்று கூறிக்கொள்ளும் நித்யபிரேமாத்மா ஆனந்த ஸ்வாமி எழுதிய கடிதத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் பின்வருமாறு கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“இந்து மதத்தின் உயர்மதத் தலைவர் (SPH) அவரது தெய்வீகப் புனிதர் ஸ்ரீ நித்யானந்த பரமசிவம் அவர்கள் தீவிரமான மருத்துவ நிலைக்காக அவசர மருத்துவ சிகிச்சை தேவைப்படுகிறார். தற்போது கைலாசாவில் உள்ள மருத்துவ வசதிகள் தீர்ந்துவிட்ட பிறகும், அடிப்படை மருத்துவ நிலையை மருத்துவர்களால் கண்டறிய முடியவில்லை. SPH தற்போது ஸ்ரீகைலாசாவின் இறையாண்மை நிலத்தில் உள்ளது, இந்த நேரத்தில் மிக அவசரமாக தேவைப்படும் மருத்துவ உள்கட்டமைப்பு இல்லை.",
        "நித்யானந்தா உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருப்பதாகவும், அவருக்கு சிகிச்சை தேவைப்படுவதாகவும், அதனால் அவரைப் பின்பற்றுபவர்கள் அரசியல் தஞ்சம் கோரி இலங்கையிடம் இருந்து மருத்துவ உதவியை நாடுகின்றனர் என்றும் இந்தக் கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அந்த கடிதத்தில், ஸ்ரீகைலாசா அமைச்சர், “நித்யானந்தாவின் உடல்நிலையை மனதில் கொண்டு, SPH க்கு உடனடியாக மீளமுடியாத அரசியல் புகலிடத்தை வழங்குமாறு உன்னதமானவர்களை கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம், இதனால் அவர் ஏர் ஆம்புலன்ஸ் மூலம் விமானம் மூலம் அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டு ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசில் பாதுகாப்பாக மருத்துவ சிகிச்சை பெற முடியும். இலங்கை. கூடுதலாக, துன்புறுத்தல் சக்திகளால் SPH இன் உயிருக்கு ஆபத்து இருப்பதால், SPH ஒரு மாநிலத் தலைவராக இருந்து ஸ்ரீகைலாசாவிற்கு பயணம் செய்வதே அவரது பாதுகாப்பிற்கு உத்தரவாதம் அளிக்க சிறந்த வழி என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்.",
        "தன்னைப் பிரகடனப்படுத்திய அமைச்சர், தனது நாடு என்று அழைக்கப்படும் நாட்டுடன் இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளைத் தொடங்குமாறு தீவு தேசத்தைக் கோரினார். நித்யானந்தாவுக்கு பாதுகாப்பான வழியைக் கோரிய அவரது அமைச்சர், மருத்துவ சிகிச்சை மற்றும் உபகரணங்களுக்கான செலவையும் ஸ்ரீகைலாசா ஏற்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீகைலாசா SPH சிகிச்சைக்கு தேவையான மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களை வாங்கி கொண்டு வருவதோடு, இலங்கையில் ஏற்படும் அனைத்து மருத்துவ செலவுகளையும் கவனித்துக்கொள்வார். எங்கள் நன்றியின் வெளிப்பாடாக, மில்லியன் கணக்கான டாலர்கள் மதிப்புள்ள அந்த மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களை உங்கள் தேசத்தின் மக்களின் நலனுக்காக விட்டுவிடுவோம், ”என்று தப்பியோடிய கடவுளின் மந்திரியின் கடிதம் வாசிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அந்த கடிதத்தில் இலங்கையில் முதலீடு செய்ய நித்யானந்தாவின் முன்மொழிவு குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, 'ஒருமுறை திரும்பப்பெற முடியாத அரசியல் தஞ்சம் வழங்கப்பட்டால்' தப்பியோடிய சுயபாணிக் கடவுள்.",
        "கடந்த 2018ஆம் ஆண்டு நவம்பரில் நித்யானந்தா தனது சீடர்கள் இருவரைக் கடத்தல் குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் குஜராத் போலீஸார் கைது செய்ததையடுத்து, அவர் இந்தியாவிலிருந்து தப்பிச் சென்றார் என்பது நினைவிருக்கலாம். நன்கொடைகளை ஈர்ப்பதற்காக குழந்தைகளின் முகங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தியதாக அவர் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டார். கர்நாடகாவில் நித்யானந்தா மீது கற்பழிப்பு வழக்கும் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டது. அதைத் தொடர்ந்து, சுயபாணியாத கடவுள் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்.",
        "நித்யானந்தா மீதான பாலியல் பலாத்கார குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் அவரது முன்னாள் டிரைவர் லெனின் புகாரின் அடிப்படையில் 2010 இல் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டது. அவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு பின்னர் ஜாமீனில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "நித்யானந்தா தமிழ்நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்தவர், அவரது உண்மையான பெயர் ராஜசேகரன் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசத்தின் இறையாண்மை அரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த சுவாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து மதத்தின் உயர்மதத் தலைவர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "கைலாசம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசத்தின் இறையாண்மை நிலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீகைலாசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஜராத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கர்நாடகா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெனின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நித்யானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜசேகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}