{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/mill-owners-lament-low-price-for-crops/",
  "time_ut": 1661751840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Mill owners lament low price for crops",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Mill owners lament low price for crops",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Small and Medium Scale Mill Owners Association say that they are not receiving a reasonable price for the paddy harvest.",
        "The Chairman of Sri Lanka Small and Medium Scale Paddy Owners Association U.K. Semasinghe said that mill owners are facing many difficulties due to this situation.",
        "The limited harvest during this season has cut down production, maily due to the fuel and fertilizer shortage,"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mill",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Small",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Small",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.K. Semasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝල් හිමියන් භෝග සඳහා අඩු මිලක් ගැන දුක් වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වී අස්වැන්න සඳහා සාධාරණ මිලක් නොලැබෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ මෝල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ වී හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති යූ.කේ සේමසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේ මෙම තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් මෝල් හිමියන් දුෂ්කරතා රැසකට මුහුණ පා සිටින බවයි.",
        "මෙම කන්නයේ සීමිත අස්වැන්න, ඉන්ධන සහ පොහොර හිඟය හේතුවෙන් තැපැල් නිෂ්පාදනය අඩු කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මෝල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කුඩා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කුඩා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූ.කේ.සේමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மில் உரிமையாளர்கள் பயிர்களுக்கு குறைந்த விலையில் புலம்புகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நெல் அறுவடைக்கு நியாயமான விலை கிடைக்கவில்லை என இலங்கை சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர ஆலை உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிலைமையினால் ஆலை உரிமையாளர்கள் பல சிரமங்களை எதிர்நோக்கி வருவதாக இலங்கை சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர நெல் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் யூ.கே.சேமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த பருவத்தில் மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அறுவடை, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் உரத் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக உற்பத்தியைக் குறைத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆலை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சிறியது",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சிறியது",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.கே.சேமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த பருவத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}