{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මූල්‍ය-අරමුදල-විදුලි-බිල-සංශෝධනය-ඇතුළු-තොරතුරු-ඉල්ලයි/101-618813",
  "time_ut": 1661520440,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මූල්‍ය අරමුදල විදුලි බිල සංශෝධනය ඇතුළු තොරතුරු ඉල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Financial Fund requests information including revision of electricity bill",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Another round of talks between President Ranil Wickremesinghe and the International Monetary Fund was held at the President's Office this afternoon (26) with the aim of finding solutions to the ongoing financial crisis.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe joined the discussion through Zoom technology and the two sides exchanged views positively, the President's Office says.",
        "In accordance with the request made by the representatives of the International Monetary Fund to provide additional information necessary for these discussions regarding the revision of the electricity bill and the Excise Act, it was also agreed to provide the information by next Monday.",
        "Financial advisers and legal advisers of the International Monetary Fund also joined the discussion today and it was decided to hold another round of discussions next Wednesday (31).",
        "Head of the International Monetary Fund's Discussion Board Peter Breuer, Deputy Head Osairo Kosaiko, Permanent Representative of the International Monetary Fund Mr. Tobagans and Chief of Staff to the President and Senior Advisor to the President on National Security Sagala Ratnayake, President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake, Central Bank Governor Dr. Mr. Nandalal Weerasinghe and senior officials of the Central Bank including the Treasury Secretary participated in the discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Financial Fund",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zoom",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Excise Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osairo Kosaiko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tobagans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Security Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මූල්‍ය අරමුදල විදුලි බිල සංශෝධනය ඇතුළු තොරතුරු ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීමේ අරමුණින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල අතර පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡා වටයේ තවත් සාකච්ඡාවක් ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී අද (26) පස්වරුවේ පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා Zoom තාක්ෂණය ඔස්සේ සාකච්ඡාවට එක් වූ අතර දෙපාර්ශ්වය ධනාත්මකව අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගත් බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය කියයි.",
        "විදුලිබිල සංශෝධනය, සුරාබදු පනත ඇතුළු භාණ්ඩාගාරය ආශ්‍රයෙන් මෙම සාකච්ඡා සඳහා අවශ්‍ය අතිරේක තොරතුරු ලබාදෙන ලෙස ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයන් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමට අනුව එම තොරතුරු ලබන සඳුදා වන විට ලබාදීමට ද මෙහිදී එකඟතාව පළ කෙරිණි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය උපදේශකවරුන් සහ නීති උපදේශකවරුන් ද අද සාකච්ඡාවට එක්ව සිටි අතර තවත් සාකච්ඡා වටයක් ලබන බදාදා (31) පැවැත්වීමට තීරණය විය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානි පීටර් බ්‍රිවර් (Peter Breuer) නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධානි ඔසයිරෝ කොසයිකෝ, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මෙරට නිත්‍ය නියෝජිත ටුබැගන්ස් යන මහත්වරු සහ ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී හා ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක, මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ යන මහත්වරු සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් ඇතුළු මහ බැංකුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීහු සාකච්ඡාවට එක්ව සිටියහ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මූල්ය අරමුදල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශාලනය කරන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරාබදු පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osairo Kosaiko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොබගන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மின் கட்டணம் திருத்தம் உள்ளிட்ட தகவல்களை நிதி நிதி கோருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது நிலவும் நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் நோக்கில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கும் இடையிலான மற்றுமொரு சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தை இன்று (26) பிற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "ஜூம் தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் ஊடாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்டதுடன் இருதரப்பும் சாதகமான கருத்துக்களை பரிமாறிக் கொண்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மின் கட்டண திருத்தம் மற்றும் கலால் சட்டம் தொடர்பான இந்த கலந்துரையாடல்களுக்கு தேவையான மேலதிக தகவல்களை வழங்குமாறு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு இணங்க, எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமைக்குள் தகவல்களை வழங்குவதற்கும் இணக்கம் காணப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி ஆலோசகர்கள் மற்றும் சட்ட ஆலோசகர்களும் இன்று கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்டதுடன், எதிர்வரும் புதன்கிழமை (31) மற்றுமொரு சுற்று கலந்துரையாடலை நடத்துவதற்கு தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கலந்துரையாடல் சபையின் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், பிரதித் தலைவர் ஒசைரோ கொசைகோ, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதி திரு. டொபாகன்ஸ் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமை அதிகாரியும் தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகருமான சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏகநாயக்க, மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி திரு.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க மற்றும் திறைசேரி செயலாளர் உட்பட மத்திய வங்கியின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிதி நிதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரிதாக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலால் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osairo Kosaiko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோபகன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}