{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78557",
  "time_ut": 1657791900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa  Sends Resignation Letter by E-mail to Speaker from Singapore; official announcement on July 15 after verifying authenticity of emailed document",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa  Sends Resignation Letter by E-mail to Speaker from Singapore; official announcement on July 15 after verifying authenticity of emailed document",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Thursday sent his resignation letter by email from Singapore, the Parliamentary Speaker’s office said, deferring an official announcement to Friday in order to verify the “authenticity and legality” of the document.",
        "The development came a day after Mr. Gotabaya, who rose to power in 2019 on a thumping election win, fled the country and sought refuge on two other islands, as mass anti-government protests rapidly escalated last weekend. Early on Wednesday, he was flown to the Maldives by a Sri Lankan military aircraft. He reached Singapore on Thursday evening, the country’s Foreign Ministry confirmed.",
        "Mr. Gotabaya was allowed entry into Singapore “on a private visit”, the city-state’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs said. “He has not asked for asylum and neither has he been granted any asylum,” the Ministry said.",
        "Parliament will not be convened on Friday as was announced, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena’s office said, owing to the delay in the receipt of the President’s resignation letter.",
        "Once accepted, Mr. Gotabaya’s resignation would signal a resounding victory to the citizen’s protests spanning months, demanding “Gota go home”, taking responsibility for the country’s worst economic downturn since Independence in 1948. The powerful leader was forced to flee and quit, after enraged protesters stormed his office and home on Saturday, as a deepening crisis left citizens scrambling for essentials, amid acute shortages and hyperinflation.",
        "For nearly 100 days, demonstrators have camped out in a tent city adjacent to the Presidential Secretariat, located along Colombo’s seafront Galle Face. They braved extreme weather, crippling fuel scarcity, and violence unleashed by ruling party supporters on May 9.",
        "Mr. Gotabaya will be the last of the Rajapaksas to resign from office, following his brothers, including former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, who stepped down earlier in the wake of raging opposition to the ruling clan.",
        "The unprecedented resistance to the Rajapaksas, Sri Lanka’s most formidable political brand for over 15 years, has decisively eliminated the first family from political prominence for the near future. Now, demonstrators continue calling for the resignation of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was appointed Acting President on Wednesday.",
        "Meanwhile, Maldivian Speaker and ex-President Mohamed Nasheed announced Mr. Gotabaya’s resignation on Twitter, minutes before the Sri Lankan Speaker announced receiving the letter. Maldivian media earlier reported that Mr. Nasheed had received Mr. Gotabaya at the airport and held talks before his departure, even as protesters in Male asked its government not to “safeguard criminals”.",
        "“President GR has resigned. I hope Sri Lanka can now move forward. I believe the President would not have resigned if he were still in Sri Lanka, and fearful of losing his life. I commend the thoughtful actions of the Govt of Maldives. My best wishes to the people of Sri Lanka,” Mr. Nasheed said in a tweet.",
        "Sri Lanka’s political opposition slammed the delay in the President’s resignation. “If it is indeed true, I am amazed at the irony of what has happened,” said Opposition lawmaker and Sri Lanka Muslim Congress Leader Rauff Hakeem. “Someone who came to power on a platform of national security has fled the country for his own security, fearing his own people. This fate would not have befallen him if he had had the foresight to quit at the right time. He has disgraced himself, and brought disgrace upon the whole nation,” he told The Hindu.",
        "Further, it was “distressing” that Mr. Gotabaya handed the reins to “another person despised by the people,” Mr. Hakeem said, referring to Mr. Wickremesinghe. “He is oblivious to ground realities… he too will be disgraced in the immediate future.”",
        "Colombo legislator and Tamil Progressive Alliance Leader Mano Ganesan said the Speaker must “immediately act” on the President’s letter and set off the constitutional process to elect a new President. “The Speaker repeatedly told us [party leaders] over the last five days that he was yet to receive the President’s letter. Now that it has come, he should verify it and produce it at the party leaders’ meeting tomorrow [July 15], so that we can take the next steps swiftly,” he told The Hindu."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gota",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nearly 100 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 15 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauff Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last five days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට කථානායකවරයාට ඊමේල් මගින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය යවයි; විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් යැවූ ලේඛනයේ සත්‍යතාව තහවුරු කිරීමෙන් පසු ජූලි 15 වැනිදා නිල නිවේදනය",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය යවා ඇති බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක කාර්යාලය පැවසුවේ, ලේඛනයේ “සත්‍යතාව සහ නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය” තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා නිල නිවේදනය සිකුරාදාට කල් දමමිනි.",
        "පසුගිය සති අන්තයේ රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී මහජන විරෝධතා වේගයෙන් උත්සන්න වීමත් සමඟ 2019 දී අතිවිශිෂ්ට මැතිවරණ ජයග්‍රහණයකින් බලයට පත් වූ ගෝඨාභය මහතා රටින් පලා ගොස් තවත් දූපත් දෙකක රැකවරණය පතා දිනකට පසුව මෙම වර්ධනය සිදුවිය. බදාදා අලුයම ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට ගෙන යන ලදී. ඔහු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සවස සිංගප්පූරුවට ළඟා වූ බව එරට විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය මහතාට \"පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක් සඳහා\" සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දී ඇති බව නගර රාජ්‍ය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි. \"ඔහු සරණාගතභාවය ඉල්ලා නැති අතර ඔහුට කිසිදු සරණාගතභාවයක් ලබා දී නැත,\" අමාත්‍යාංශය පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ලැබීම ප්‍රමාද වීම හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි සිකුරාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොකැඳවන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධනගේ කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "1948 නිදහසින් පසු රට මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අවපාතයේ වගකීම භාර ගනිමින් “ගෝඨා ගෙදර යන්න” බල කරමින් මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති පුරවැසි විරෝධතාවල විශිෂ්ට ජයග්‍රහණයක් ගෝඨාභය මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සංඥා කරනු ඇත. උග‍්‍ර හිඟය සහ අධි උද්ධමනය මධ්‍යයේ, ගැඹුරු වන අර්බුදයක් හේතුවෙන් පුරවැසියන් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය දෑ සඳහා පොරබදමින් සිටියදී කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවෝ සෙනසුරාදා ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලයට සහ නිවසට කඩා වැදුණහ.",
        "දින 100 කට ආසන්න කාලයක් විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ මුහුදු තීරයේ ගාලු මුවදොර පිහිටි ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට යාබද කූඩාරම් නගරයක කඳවුරු බැඳගෙන සිටිති. ඔවුන් ආන්තික කාලගුණය, අබලන් වූ ඉන්ධන හිඟය සහ මැයි 9 දා පාලක පක්ෂ ආධාරකරුවන් විසින් මුදා හරින ලද ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයට එරෙහිව නිර්භීතව කටයුතු කළහ.",
        "හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ ඇතුළු ඔහුගේ සහෝදරයන්, පාලක වංශයට එරෙහිව ඇති වූ දැඩි විරෝධය හේතුවෙන් කලින් ඉවත් වූ රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන අවසාන රාජපක්ෂලා වන්නේ ගෝඨාභය මහතාය.",
        "වසර 15කට වැඩි කාලයක් තිස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලවත්ම දේශපාලන සන්නාමය වූ රාජපක්ෂලාට පෙර නොවූ විරූ ප්‍රතිරෝධය, නුදුරු අනාගතය සඳහා පළමු පවුල දේශපාලන ප්‍රමුඛස්ථානයෙන් තීරණාත්මක ලෙස ඉවත් කර ඇත. දැන්, බදාදා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කරන ලද අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට විරෝධතාකරුවන් දිගින් දිගටම ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "මේ අතර, මාලදිවයින් කථානායක සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා කථානායකවරයාට ලිපිය ලැබුණු බව නිවේදනය කිරීමට මිනිත්තු කිහිපයකට පෙර ගෝඨාභය මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ට්විටර් හරහා නිවේදනය කළේය. \"අපරාධකරුවන් ආරක්‍ෂා නොකරන ලෙස\" මාලේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් සිය රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියදී පවා නෂීඩ් මහතා ගෝඨාභය මහතා ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී පිළිගෙන ඔහු පිටත්ව යාමට පෙර සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූ බව මාලදිවයින් මාධ්‍ය මීට පෙර වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "“ජනාධිපති ජී.ආර්. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැන් ඉදිරියට යා හැකි යැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. මම විශ්වාස කරනවා ජනාධිපතිතුමා තවමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටියා නම්, ජීවිතය නැති වේ යැයි බියෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වන්නේ නැහැ. මාලදිවයින් රජයේ කල්පනාකාරී ක්‍රියා කලාපය මම අගය කරමි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසී ජනතාවට මගේ සුභ පැතුම්” නෂීඩ් මහතා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ප්‍රමාදය පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන විපක්ෂය දැඩි ලෙස විවේචනය කළේය. \"එය ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම සත්‍ය නම්, සිදුවී ඇති දෙයෙහි උත්ප්‍රාසය ගැන මම පුදුම වෙමි,\" විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රී සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක රවුෆ් හකීම් පැවසීය. “ජාතික ආරක්‍ෂාව පිළිබඳ වේදිකාවක් මත බලයට පැමිණි අයෙක් තම ආරක්‍ෂාව වෙනුවෙන් රටින් පැන ගොස් ඇත්තේ තමන්ගේම ජනතාවට බියෙනි. අවශ්‍ය වේලාවට ඉවත් වීමට දූරදර්ශීව කටයුතු කළේ නම් ඔහුට මේ ඉරණම අත් නොවනු ඇත. ඔහු තමාව අපකීර්තියට පත් කර ගෙන මුළු ජාතියටම අපකීර්තියක් ගෙන ඇත, ”ඔහු හින්දු වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, ගෝඨාභය මහතා \"ජනතාව විසින් පිළිකුල් කරන ලද තවත් අයෙකුට\" බලය පැවරීම \"විවේකජනක\" බව හකීම් මහතා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ගැන සඳහන් කරමින් පැවසීය. \"ඔහු භූගත යථාර්ථයන් නොසලකා හරියි ... ඔහු ද නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී අපකීර්තියට පත් වනු ඇත.\"",
        "කොළඹ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය සහ දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නායක මනෝ ගනේෂන් පැවසුවේ කථානායකවරයා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ලිපියට “වහාම ක්‍රියා කළ යුතු” අතර නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බවයි. “පසුගිය දින පහ තුළ කථානායකවරයා අපට [පක්ෂ නායකයින්ට] නැවත නැවතත් පැවසුවේ තමාට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ලිපිය තවමත් ලැබී නොමැති බවයි. දැන් එය පැමිණ ඇති බැවින්, ඔහු එය සත්‍යාපනය කර හෙට (ජූලි 15) පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමට ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතුය, එවිට අපට ඊළඟ පියවර කඩිනමින් ගත හැකිය, ”ඔහු ද හින්දු වෙත පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සතිඅන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 100 කට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 15 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හකීම් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து சபாநாயகருக்கு மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை அனுப்பினார்; மின்னஞ்சல் ஆவணத்தின் நம்பகத்தன்மையை சரிபார்த்த பிறகு ஜூலை 15 அன்று அதிகாரப்பூர்வ அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வியாழக்கிழமை தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் அனுப்பியதாக நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் கூறியது, ஆவணத்தின் \"நம்பகத்தன்மை மற்றும் சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையை\" சரிபார்க்கும் பொருட்டு அதிகாரப்பூர்வ அறிவிப்பை வெள்ளிக்கிழமைக்கு ஒத்திவைத்தது.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு அமோக தேர்தல் வெற்றியின் மூலம் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த திரு. கோட்டாபய நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி வேறு இரண்டு தீவுகளில் தஞ்சம் புகுந்ததற்கு ஒரு நாள் கழித்து, கடந்த வார இறுதியில் வெகுஜன அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டங்கள் வேகமாக அதிகரித்ததால் இந்த வளர்ச்சி ஏற்பட்டது. புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை அவர் இலங்கை இராணுவ விமானம் மூலம் மாலைதீவுக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டார். அவர் வியாழக்கிழமை மாலை சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றடைந்ததாக அந்நாட்டு வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் உறுதி செய்துள்ளது.",
        "திரு. கோட்டாபய சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் \"தனிப்பட்ட விஜயத்தில்\" நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார் என்று நகர-மாநில வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. \"அவர் புகலிடம் கேட்கவில்லை மற்றும் அவருக்கு எந்த புகலிடமும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை\" என்று அமைச்சகம் கூறியது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமா கடிதம் கிடைக்கப்பெறுவதில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதால், அறிவிக்கப்பட்டபடி வெள்ளிக்கிழமையன்று பாராளுமன்றம் கூட்டப்படாது என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவின் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "திரு. கோட்டாபயவின் ராஜினாமா ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டதும், 1948 இல் சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிறகு நாட்டின் மோசமான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சிக்கு பொறுப்பேற்று, \"கோட்டா வீட்டிற்குச் செல்லுங்கள்\" என்று கோரி பல மாதங்களாக நீடித்து வரும் குடிமகன்களின் போராட்டங்களுக்கு ஒரு மகத்தான வெற்றியைக் குறிக்கும். கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் பணவீக்கத்திற்கு மத்தியில், தீவிரமான நெருக்கடி குடிமக்களை அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்காக துரத்தியதால், ஆத்திரமடைந்த எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் சனிக்கிழமை அவரது அலுவலகம் மற்றும் வீட்டை முற்றுகையிட்டனர்.",
        "ஏறக்குறைய 100 நாட்களாக, கொழும்பின் கடற்பரப்பில் காலி முகத்திடலில் அமைந்துள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தை அண்டிய ஒரு கூடார நகரத்தில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் முகாமிட்டுள்ளனர். மே 9 அன்று ஆளும் கட்சி ஆதரவாளர்களால் கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்ட தீவிர வானிலை, முடங்கிய எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் வன்முறை ஆகியவற்றை அவர்கள் தைரியமாக எதிர்கொண்டனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச உட்பட அவரது சகோதரர்களைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஆளும் குலத்திற்கு எதிரான கடுமையான எதிர்ப்பை அடுத்து பதவியில் இருந்து விலகிய ராஜபக்சக்களில் கடைசியாக பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தவர் திரு. கோட்டாபய.",
        "15 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக இலங்கையின் மிகவும் வலிமையான அரசியல் முத்திரையான ராஜபக்சேக்களுக்கு முன்னோடியில்லாத எதிர்ப்பு, எதிர்காலத்தில் அரசியல் முக்கியத்துவத்திலிருந்து முதல் குடும்பத்தை தீர்க்கமாக அகற்றியுள்ளது. இப்போது, ​​புதன்கிழமையன்று பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை இராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தொடர்ந்து வலியுறுத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், மாலத்தீவு சபாநாயகரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மொஹமட் நஷீட், கோட்டாபயவின் ராஜினாமாவை ட்விட்டரில் அறிவித்தார், இலங்கை சபாநாயகர் கடிதத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கு சில நிமிடங்களுக்கு முன்பு. மாலேயில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் \"குற்றவாளிகளைப் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டாம்\" என்று அதன் அரசாங்கத்தைக் கேட்டுக் கொண்டபோதும், திரு. நஷீத் திரு கோத்தபயாவை விமான நிலையத்தில் வரவேற்று அவர் புறப்படுவதற்கு முன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தினார் என்று மாலத்தீவு ஊடகங்கள் முன்னதாக தெரிவித்தன.",
        "“ஜனாதிபதி ஜி.ஆர். இலங்கை இப்போது முன்னேற முடியும் என்று நம்புகிறேன். ஜனாதிபதி இலங்கையில் இருந்திருந்தால், தனது உயிரை இழக்க நேரிடும் என்ற அச்சத்தில் அவர் பதவி விலகியிருக்க மாட்டார் என நான் நம்புகிறேன். மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்கத்தின் சிந்தனைமிக்க நடவடிக்கைகளை நான் பாராட்டுகிறேன். இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எனது நல்வாழ்த்துக்கள்” என்று திரு. நஷீத் தனது ட்வீட்டில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் ராஜினாமா தாமதம் குறித்து இலங்கையின் அரசியல் எதிர்கட்சிகள் கண்டனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. \"இது உண்மையாக இருந்தால், நடந்தவற்றில் நான் ஆச்சரியப்படுகிறேன்\" என்று எதிர்க்கட்சி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ் தலைவருமான ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் கூறினார். “தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு என்ற மேடையில் பதவிக்கு வந்த ஒருவர், தனது சொந்த மக்களுக்கு பயந்து, தனது சொந்த பாதுகாப்பிற்காக நாட்டை விட்டு ஓடிவிட்டார். சரியான நேரத்தில் விலக வேண்டும் என்ற முன்யோசனை அவருக்கு இருந்திருந்தால் இந்த கதி அவருக்கு ஏற்பட்டிருக்காது. அவர் தன்னை இழிவுபடுத்தி, ஒட்டுமொத்த தேசத்தின் மீதும் அவப்பெயரை ஏற்படுத்தினார்,” என்று அவர் தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "மேலும், திரு. கோட்டாபய, \"மக்களால் இகழ்ந்த மற்றொரு நபருக்கு\" ஆட்சியை வழங்கியது \"வேதனைக்குரியது\" என்று திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவைக் குறிப்பிட்டு திரு. ஹக்கீம் கூறினார். \"அவர் அடிப்படை உண்மைகளை மறந்துவிடுகிறார் ... அவரும் உடனடி எதிர்காலத்தில் அவமானப்படுவார்.\"",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் கடிதத்தின் மீது சபாநாயகர் \"உடனடியாக\" செயற்பட்டு புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான அரசியலமைப்புச் செயற்பாடுகளை ஆரம்பிக்க வேண்டும் என கொழும்பு சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணியின் தலைவருமான மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஜனாதிபதியின் கடிதம் தமக்கு இன்னும் கிடைக்கவில்லை என சபாநாயகர் கடந்த ஐந்து நாட்களாக எங்களிடம் (கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம்) பலமுறை கூறினார். இப்போது அது வந்துவிட்டதால், அதை அவர் சரிபார்த்து, நாளை (ஜூலை 15) கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்ய வேண்டும், எனவே அடுத்த நடவடிக்கைகளை விரைவாக எடுக்க முடியும், ”என்று அவர் தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வார இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 100 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}