{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/founder-chairman-nippon-donation-foundation-hoping-to-invest-in-multiple-projects-in-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1659100080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Founder Chairman, Nippon Donation Foundation, hoping to invest in multiple projects in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Founder Chairman, Nippon Donation Foundation, hoping to invest in multiple projects in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka is one of the countries in the Asian region that has endless potential to do business. Therefore, it is a very good place to invest in and I hope to invest in multiple projects in the future in the country, Founder Chairman, Nippon Donation Foundation Yuma Muranushi said.",
        "“It is imperative that we do as much as we can to assist this island nation and its people in their recovery from the challenges brought about by the current economic situation, Muranushi said at a function held at the Shangri La Hotel on Thursday where he handed over a donation of dry item packs to Sri Lanka’s cricketing personality Roshan Mahanama to be distributed among needy persons in the country through his charitable organization.",
        "‘I have taken the initiative to promote Japanese investments in the country in the future and some Japanese still think that the war between the government of Sri Lanka and LTTE is still on here, which is considered to be one of the peaceful countries in the region despite the current financial crisis, Muranushi said.",
        "MuranushI added: ‘I had previously donated Rs 10 million worth of medicine to the National Hospital and am hoping to donate some more in the future because Sri Lankans are now going through major hardships due to the ongoing economic crisis.",
        "‘The Nippon Donation Foundation has been active over the past 30 years around the world and continues its efforts to uplift sectors in developing nations, such as, health, education and entrepreneurship.’",
        "National Director, Nippon Donation Foundation, Dr Ruwan Perera said that he is personally working towards attracting Japanese investors into the country. ‘I am especially working on obtaining scholarships for Sri Lankan students and undergraduates, Perera added.",
        "Perera is currently the chairman of a conglomerate in Sri Lanka holding over US $ 100 million worth of interest in the country. “My latest investment was US $ 25 million to build the first airport transit in Sri Lanka, he explained.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nippon Donation Foundation",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nippon Donation Foundation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Shangri La Hotel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Roshan Mahanama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Nippon Donation Foundation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 30 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nippon Donation Foundation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 100 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 25 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජනය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන Nippon Donation Foundation හි නිර්මාතෘ සභාපති",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසියානු කලාපයේ ව්‍යාපාර කිරීමට අසීමිත හැකියාවක් ඇති රටකි. එබැවින් එය ආයෝජනය කිරීමට ඉතා හොඳ ස්ථානයක් බවත් ඉදිරියේදී රට තුළ විවිධ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජනය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත් Nippon Donation Foundation හි නිර්මාතෘ සභාපති Yuma Muranushi මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“වර්තමාන ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය විසින් ගෙන එන ලද අභියෝගවලින් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා මෙම දූපත් ජාතියට සහ එහි ජනතාවට අපට හැකි පමණින් උපකාර කිරීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය බව මුරනුෂි බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ෂැංග්‍රිලා හෝටලයේ පැවති උත්සවයකදී පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩක රොෂාන් මහානාම මහතාට තම පුණ්‍යායතනය හරහා රටේ අසරණ වූවන් අතර බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා වියළි භාණ්ඩ ඇසුරුම් පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්.",
        "'ඉදිරියේදී මෙරට ජපන් ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට මා මූලිකත්වය ගෙන ඇති අතර ඇතැම් ජපන් ජාතිකයන් තවමත් සිතන්නේ කලාපයේ සාමකාමී රටක් ලෙස සැලකෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ. අතර යුද්ධය තවමත් පවතින බවයි. වත්මන් මූල්ය අර්බුදය තිබියදීත්, මුරනුෂි පැවසීය.",
        "MuranushI තවදුරටත් මෙසේ පැවසීය: ‘මම මීට පෙර රුපියල් මිලියන 10 ක ඖෂධයක් ජාතික රෝහලට පරිත්‍යාග කර ඇති අතර, පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් දැන් විශාල දුෂ්කරතාවලට මුහුණ දෙන නිසා ඉදිරියේදී තවත් ඖෂධ කිහිපයක් පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා.",
        "‘නිපොන් පරිත්‍යාග පදනම පසුගිය වසර 30 පුරා ලොව පුරා ක්‍රියාකාරී වී ඇති අතර සෞඛ්‍ය, අධ්‍යාපනය සහ ව්‍යවසායකත්වය වැනි සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල ක්ෂේත්‍ර නංවාලීම සඳහා එහි ප්‍රයත්නයන් දිගටම කරගෙන යයි.",
        "ජපාන ආයෝජකයින් මෙරටට ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට තමන් පෞද්ගලිකව කටයුතු කරන බව නිපොන් ඩොනේෂන් පදනමේ ජාතික අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෛද්‍ය රුවන් පෙරේරා මහතා පැවසීය. ‘මම විශේෂයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන් සහ උපාධි අපේක්ෂකයින් සඳහා ශිෂ්‍යත්ව ලබා ගැනීමට කටයුතු කරමින් සිටිනවා, පෙරේරා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "පෙරේරා මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 100කට අධික පොලී මුදලක් තබාගෙන සිටින සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයක සභාපතිවරයා වේ. “මගේ අලුත්ම ආයෝජනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම ගුවන් තොටුපළ සංක්‍රමණය ඉදිකිරීම සඳහා ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක් බව ඔහු පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිපොන් පරිත්‍යාග පදනම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිපොන් පරිත්‍යාග පදනම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂැංග්‍රි ලා හෝටලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොෂාන් මහානාම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිපොන් පරිත්‍යාග පදනම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 30 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිපොන් පරිත්‍යාග පදනම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 100 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளையின் ஸ்தாபகத் தலைவர், இலங்கையில் பல திட்டங்களில் முதலீடு செய்ய எதிர்பார்க்கிறார்",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆசிய பிராந்தியத்தில் வர்த்தகம் செய்வதற்கு முடிவற்ற ஆற்றலைக் கொண்ட நாடுகளில் இலங்கையும் ஒன்று. எனவே, இது முதலீடு செய்வதற்கு மிகவும் நல்ல இடமாகும், மேலும் நாட்டில் எதிர்காலத்தில் பல திட்டங்களில் முதலீடு செய்ய நம்புகிறேன் என்று நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளையின் நிறுவனர் தலைவர் யூமா முரனுஷி கூறினார்.",
        "\"தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சூழ்நிலையால் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள சவால்களில் இருந்து மீண்டு வருவதற்கு இந்த தீவு நாட்டிற்கும் அதன் மக்களுக்கும் நம்மால் இயன்ற உதவிகளை செய்வது மிகவும் அவசியம்\" என்று வியாழக்கிழமை ஷங்கிரி லா ஹோட்டலில் நடைபெற்ற விழாவில் முரனுஷி கூறினார். இலங்கையின் கிரிக்கெட் வீரரான ரொஷான் மஹாநாமவிற்கு உலர் பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குவதற்காக தனது தொண்டு நிறுவனத்தினூடாக நாட்டில் உள்ள தேவையற்ற நபர்களுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படவுள்ளார்.",
        "'எதிர்காலத்தில் நாட்டில் ஜப்பானிய முதலீடுகளை ஊக்குவிக்க நான் முன்முயற்சி எடுத்துள்ளேன், மேலும் சில ஜப்பானியர்கள் இன்னும் இலங்கை அரசுக்கும் விடுதலைப் புலிகளுக்கும் இடையே போர் நடந்து வருவதாக நினைக்கிறார்கள், இது பிராந்தியத்தில் அமைதியான நாடுகளில் ஒன்றாக கருதப்படுகிறது. தற்போதைய நிதி நெருக்கடி இருந்தபோதிலும், முரனுஷி கூறினார்.",
        "முரனுஷ் மேலும் கூறியதாவது: 'நான் முன்னர் தேசிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு ரூபாய் 10 மில்லியன் பெறுமதியான மருந்துகளை நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியிருந்தேன், மேலும் எதிர்காலத்தில் இன்னும் சிலவற்றை நன்கொடையாக வழங்க எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன்.",
        "'நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளை கடந்த 30 ஆண்டுகளாக உலகம் முழுவதும் செயல்பட்டு வருகிறது, மேலும் வளரும் நாடுகளில் சுகாதாரம், கல்வி மற்றும் தொழில்முனைவு போன்ற துறைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான அதன் முயற்சிகளைத் தொடர்கிறது.'",
        "ஜப்பானிய முதலீட்டாளர்களை நாட்டிற்குள் ஈர்க்கும் நோக்கில் தான் தனிப்பட்ட முறையில் செயற்பட்டு வருவதாக நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளையின் தேசிய பணிப்பாளர் டாக்டர் ருவன் பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார். இலங்கை மாணவர்கள் மற்றும் இளங்கலை பட்டதாரிகளுக்கான புலமைப்பரிசில்களை பெற்றுக்கொள்வதில் நான் குறிப்பாக உழைத்து வருகிறேன், பெரேரா மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "பெரேரா தற்போது இலங்கையில் 100 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் பெறுமதியான வட்டியை வைத்திருக்கும் கூட்டு நிறுவனமொன்றின் தலைவராக உள்ளார். \"இலங்கையில் முதல் விமான நிலைய போக்குவரத்தை உருவாக்க எனது சமீபத்திய முதலீடு 25 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்\" என்று அவர் விளக்கினார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷங்கிரி லா ஹோட்டல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரொஷான் மஹாநாம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muranushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 30 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 100 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}