{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/sri-lanka-promotes-lankaremit/",
  "time_ut": 1661575560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka promotes LankaRemit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka promotes LankaRemit",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); To popularize the LankaRemit National Remittance Mobile Application among migrant workers, the Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) and the Sri Lanka Bureau of Foreign Employment (SLBFE) held a ceremony on Friday (26) at SLBFE to demonstrate its features.",
        "LankaRemit provides Sri Lankan expatriates with access to a fast, secure, and more convenient remittance channel to send money to Sri Lanka.",
        "CBSL in collaboration with LankaClear (Private) Limited (LCPL) implemented the “LankaRemit” mobile application with the launching of the first phase in February 2022.",
        "CBSL is in the process of creating awareness of “LankaRemit” locally and internationally with the support of stakeholders such as the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Ministry of Labour and Foreign Employment, and the SLBFE.",
        "LankaRemit enables users to make fund transfers to beneficiaries in Sri Lanka and to make utility bill payments using Electronic Fund Transfer Cards issued overseas.",
        "LankaRemit also offers several value-added services to its users such as the ability to locate nearby money transfer operators and find relevant details of such locations.",
        "Further, after the remittance is made via money transfer operators abroad, the user can track each remittance made to beneficiaries in Sri Lanka via the App using a tracking number.",
        "If there are any future benefit schemes introduced for the remitters by the Sri Lankan government or respective authorities, such benefit schemes would also be available in the LankaRemit App.",
        "The LankaRemit mobile application is available to download in the Google Play Store, the Apple App Store, and the Huawei AppGallery for any person remitting money to Sri Lanka from any country.",
        "Remittance service providers connected to LankaRemit are continuing to increase and it is expected that more service providers from the financial services industry including global money transfer operators and global FinTechs will join the App shortly to facilitate remittances to Sri Lanka.",
        "The features and benefits of LankaRemit were demonstrated to migrant workers who were preparing to commence work abroad.",
        "It is expected that this event would increase awareness and adoption of the LankaRemit App among Sri Lankan expatriates and encourage the use of formal remittance channels when sending remittances to the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the LankaRemit National Remittance Mobile Application",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Bureau of Foreign Employment (SLBFE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLBFE",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaClear",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Labour and Foreign Employment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLBFE",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Electronic Fund Transfer Cards",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "App",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the LankaRemit App",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Apple App Store",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Huawei AppGallery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FinTechs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "App",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the LankaRemit App",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව LankaRemit ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සංක්‍රමණික සේවකයන් අතර LankaRemit ජාතික ප්‍රේෂණ ජංගම යෙදුම ප්‍රචලිත කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව (CBSL) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය (SLBFE) සිකුරාදා (26) දින SLBFE හි එහි විශේෂාංග ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමේ උත්සවයක් පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "LankaRemit ශ්‍රී ලාංකික විදේශිකයන්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මුදල් යැවීම සඳහා වේගවත්, ආරක්ෂිත සහ වඩාත් පහසු ප්‍රේෂණ නාලිකාවකට ප්‍රවේශය ලබා දෙයි.",
        "CBSL විසින් LankaClear (Private) Limited (LCPL) සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් “LankaRemit” ජංගම යෙදුම 2022 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේ දියත් කිරීමත් සමඟ ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලදී.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය, කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ SLBFE වැනි පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ගේ සහයෝගය ඇතිව “LankaRemit” පිළිබඳව දේශීයව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තරව දැනුවත් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක CBSL කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී.",
        "LankaRemit මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිලාභීන් වෙත අරමුදල් මාරු කිරීමට සහ විදේශයන්හි නිකුත් කරන ලද ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික අරමුදල් හුවමාරු කාඩ්පත් භාවිතයෙන් උපයෝගිතා බිල්පත් ගෙවීමට පරිශීලකයින්ට හැකියාව ලැබේ.",
        "LankaRemit විසින් අවට මුදල් හුවමාරු ක්‍රියාකරුවන් සොයා ගැනීමට සහ එම ස්ථාන පිළිබඳ අදාළ තොරතුරු සොයා ගැනීමට ඇති හැකියාව වැනි අගය එකතු කළ සේවාවන් කිහිපයක් ද එහි පරිශීලකයින්ට පිරිනමයි.",
        "තවද, විදේශයන්හි මුදල් හුවමාරු ක්‍රියාකරුවන් හරහා ප්‍රේෂණ සිදු කළ පසු, පරිශීලකයාට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිලාභීන් වෙත කරන සෑම ප්‍රේෂණයක්ම ලුහුබැඳීමේ අංකයක් භාවිතයෙන් යෙදුම හරහා නිරීක්ෂණය කළ හැකිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය හෝ අදාළ බලධාරීන් විසින් ප්‍රේෂණ කරන්නන් සඳහා අනාගත ප්‍රතිලාභ යෝජනා ක්‍රම හඳුන්වා දෙන්නේ නම්, එවැනි ප්‍රතිලාභ යෝජනා ක්‍රම LankaRemit යෙදුමෙන් ද ලබා ගත හැකිය.",
        "LankaRemit ජංගම යෙදුම Google Play Store, Apple App Store සහ Huawei AppGallery වෙතින් ඕනෑම රටක සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මුදල් ප්‍රේෂණය කරන ඕනෑම අයෙකුට බාගත හැකිය.",
        "LankaRemit හා සම්බන්ධ ප්‍රේෂණ සේවා සපයන්නන් අඛණ්ඩව ඉහළ යමින් පවතින අතර ගෝලීය මුදල් හුවමාරු ක්‍රියාකරුවන් සහ ගෝලීය FinTechs ඇතුළු මූල්‍ය සේවා ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ තවත් සේවා සපයන්නන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රේෂණ පහසු කිරීම සඳහා නුදුරේදීම ඇප් එකට සම්බන්ධ වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "LankaRemit හි විශේෂාංග සහ ප්‍රතිලාභ විදේශ රැකියා ආරම්භ කිරීමට සූදානම් වන සංක්‍රමණික ශ්‍රමිකයින් වෙත ප්‍රදර්ශනය කෙරිණි.",
        "මෙම උත්සවය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික විදේශිකයන් අතර LankaRemit යෙදුම පිළිබඳ දැනුවත්භාවය සහ අනුගතවීම වැඩි කිරීමට සහ රට වෙත ප්‍රේෂණ යැවීමේදී විධිමත් ප්‍රේෂණ නාලිකා භාවිතය දිරිමත් කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit ජාතික ප්‍රේෂණ ජංගම යෙදුම",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය (SLBFE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLBFE",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaClear",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLBFE",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලෙක්ට්රොනික අරමුදල් හුවමාරු කාඩ්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෙදුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit යෙදුම",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apple App Store",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei AppGallery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FinTechs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෙදුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit යෙදුම",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை LankaRemit ஐ ஊக்குவிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்கள் மத்தியில் LankaRemit தேசிய பணம் அனுப்பும் மொபைல் அப்ளிகேஷனை பிரபலப்படுத்த, இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி (CBSL) மற்றும் இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம் (SLBFE) இணைந்து வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) SLBFE இல் அதன் அம்சங்களை வெளிப்படுத்தும் விழாவை நடத்தியது.",
        "லங்காரெமிட் இலங்கைக்கு பணம் அனுப்புவதற்கு விரைவான, பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் மிகவும் வசதியான பணம் அனுப்பும் சேனலுக்கான அணுகலை இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டவர்களுக்கு வழங்குகிறது.",
        "CBSL ஆனது LankaClear (Private) Limited (LCPL) உடன் இணைந்து “LankaRemit” மொபைல் செயலியை 2022 பெப்ரவரியில் முதல் கட்டமாக அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு, தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சு மற்றும் SLBFE போன்ற பங்குதாரர்களின் ஆதரவுடன் உள்நாட்டிலும் சர்வதேச அளவிலும் “LankaRemit” பற்றிய விழிப்புணர்வை உருவாக்கும் பணியில் CBSL ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள பயனாளிகளுக்கு நிதிப் பரிமாற்றங்களைச் செய்வதற்கும், வெளிநாடுகளில் வழங்கப்பட்ட இலத்திரனியல் நிதி பரிமாற்ற அட்டைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி பயன்பாட்டு பில் கொடுப்பனவுகளைச் செய்வதற்கும் லங்காரெமிட் பயனர்களுக்கு உதவுகிறது.",
        "லங்காரெமிட் அதன் பயனர்களுக்கு அருகிலுள்ள பணப் பரிமாற்ற ஆபரேட்டர்களைக் கண்டறியும் திறன் மற்றும் அத்தகைய இடங்களின் தொடர்புடைய விவரங்களைக் கண்டறியும் திறன் போன்ற பல மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட சேவைகளையும் வழங்குகிறது.",
        "மேலும், வெளிநாட்டில் உள்ள பணப் பரிமாற்ற ஆபரேட்டர்கள் மூலம் பணம் அனுப்பப்பட்ட பிறகு, பயனர் கண்காணிப்பு எண்ணைப் பயன்படுத்தி ஆப் மூலம் இலங்கையில் உள்ள பயனாளிகளுக்கு அனுப்பப்படும் ஒவ்வொரு பணத்தையும் கண்காணிக்க முடியும்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் அல்லது சம்பந்தப்பட்ட அதிகாரிகளால் பணம் அனுப்புபவர்களுக்கு எதிர்காலத்தில் ஏதேனும் நன்மை திட்டங்கள் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டால், அத்தகைய நன்மை திட்டங்கள் LankaRemit செயலியிலும் கிடைக்கும்.",
        "எந்தவொரு நாட்டிலிருந்தும் இலங்கைக்கு பணம் அனுப்பும் எந்தவொரு நபருக்கும் Google Play Store, Apple App Store மற்றும் Huawei AppGallery ஆகியவற்றில் பதிவிறக்கம் செய்ய LankaRemit மொபைல் பயன்பாடு கிடைக்கிறது.",
        "லங்காரெமிட்டுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட பணம் அனுப்பும் சேவை வழங்குநர்கள் தொடர்ந்து அதிகரித்து வருகின்றனர், மேலும் இலங்கைக்கு பணம் அனுப்புவதற்கு வசதியாக, உலகளாவிய பணப் பரிமாற்ற ஆபரேட்டர்கள் மற்றும் உலகளாவிய ஃபின்டெக்கள் உட்பட நிதிச் சேவைத் துறையைச் சேர்ந்த மேலும் பல சேவை வழங்குநர்கள் விரைவில் செயலியில் இணைவார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "லங்காரெமிட்டின் சிறப்பம்சங்கள் மற்றும் நன்மைகள் வெளிநாட்டில் பணியைத் தொடங்கத் தயாராகி வரும் புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வு இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டவர்களிடையே லங்காரெமிட் செயலி பற்றிய விழிப்புணர்வையும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளலையும் அதிகரிக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்காரெமிட் நேஷனல் ரெமிட்டன்ஸ் மொபைல் அப்ளிகேஷன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம் (SLBFE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLBFE",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா கிளியர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLBFE",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்னணு நிதி பரிமாற்ற அட்டைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit ஆப்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிள் ஆப் ஸ்டோர்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei AppGallery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்டெக்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LankaRemit ஆப்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}