{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78564",
  "time_ut": 1657792980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Presiden Gotabaya  Rajapaksa  emails  his resignation letter via the Sri Lanka High Commission in Singapore  to Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.Speaker will formally announce that Rajapaksa has vacated the post of President to the public after verifying the authenticity of the letter;Speaker’s office  Consults Attorney General in this connection",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Presiden Gotabaya  Rajapaksa  emails  his resignation letter via the Sri Lanka High Commission in Singapore  to Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.Speaker will formally announce that Rajapaksa has vacated the post of President to the public after verifying the authenticity of the letter;Speaker’s office  Consults Attorney General in this connection",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who was forced out of office by waves of public protests, sent in his registration letter from Singapore yesterday bringing to an end nearly three years of rudderless and chaotic rule.",
        "The President, who fled the country on Wednesday, emailed his resignation letter via the Sri Lanka High Commission in Singapore last night to Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.  Rajapaksa did so after arriving in Singapore via a Saudi Air flight from the Maldives where he spent a day after being flown in by an Air Force military plane in the early hours of Wednesday.",
        "Rajapaksa was allowed to enter Singapore on the basis of a private visit and has not been granted asylum, the city-State said, after the leader arrived from the Maldives.",
        "“It is confirmed that Rajapaksa has been allowed entry into Singapore on a private visit,” Singapore’s Foreign Ministry said in a statement. “He has not asked for asylum and neither has he been granted any asylum. Singapore generally does not grant requests for asylum.” There was speculation that Rajapaksa is planning to travel to another country from Singapore.",
        "Speaker Abeywardena said last night he will formally announce that Rajapaksa has vacated the post of President to the public today in keeping with the relevant constitutional provisions after verifying the authenticity of the letter, the Speaker’s office said last night. The Attorney General (AG) was consulted last night by the Speaker’s office in this connection,” the Daily FT learns. Originally Rajapaksa said he will tender his resignation on Wednesday 13 July.",
        "The President was forced out of office just two years and eight months into his five-year term, making him the first President to resign from his post. It is a humiliating exit for a man who was elected by a landslide in the Presidential poll held in November 2019 on the back of the promise of efficient and clean administration.",
        "The office of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, who is the Acting President, could not confirm if he will take oath today as interim President pending the vote in Parliament to select a successor to Rajapaksa.",
        "A spokesperson for the office said they are waiting to get confirmation regarding the resignation letter.",
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) announced yesterday that it will not field a candidate to contest for the Presidency when the Parliament meets to elect a new President.",
        "The party said that it was bowing to the public demand for a change in a SLPP-led administration and has hence taken this decision.",
        "Party leaders had earlier agreed to hold the election to elect a new President for 20 July but this may be delayed as an earlier decision for Parliament to meet today has been postponed. The House will now meet on Tuesday as scheduled when the Speaker will inform the House that a vacancy has occurred in the post of President and fix a date to call for nomination.",
        "In a related development representatives of several parties including the SJB, SLFP, the independent group within the SLPP, TNA that met yesterday decided to inform the Speaker that they will nominate Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa for the post of Prime Minister of the all-party Government that is being mooted to overcome the economic crises facing the country. The JVP did not attend the meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Presiden Gotabaya  ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "an end nearly three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Air",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early hours of Wednesday",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday 13 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "just two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිංගප්පූරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය හරහා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් යවයි. මෙම සම්බන්ධතාවය",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහජන විරෝධතා රැල්ල හේතුවෙන් බලයෙන් පහ කළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වසර තුනකට ආසන්න සුක්කානම සහ අවුල් සහගත පාලනය අවසන් කරමින් ඊයේ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට සිය ලියාපදිංචි ලිපිය එවා ඇත.",
        "බදාදා රටින් පලා ගිය ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ සිංගප්පූරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය හරහා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් යොමු කළේය. රාජපක්ෂ එසේ කළේ මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සෞදි එයාර් ගුවන් යානයකින් සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණ බදාදා අලුයම ගුවන් හමුදාවේ හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් පියාසර කිරීමෙන් පසු දිනක් ගත කිරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "පුද්ගලික සංචාරයක් මත රාජපක්ෂට සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දී ඇති අතර ඔහුට සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නොමැති බව නායකයා මාලදිවයිනේ සිට පැමිණි පසු නගර රාජ්‍යය පැවසීය.",
        "\"පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක් සඳහා රාජපක්ෂට සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දී ඇති බව තහවුරු වේ\" යනුවෙන් සිංගප්පූරු විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. “ඔහු සරණාගතභාවය ඉල්ලා නැත, ඔහුට සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නැත. සිංගප්පූරුව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සරණාගත ඉල්ලීම් ලබා දෙන්නේ නැත. රාජපක්ෂ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට වෙනත් රටකට යාමට සැරසෙන බවට මත පළ විය.",
        "එම ලිපියේ සත්‍යතාව තහවුරු කිරීමෙන් පසු අදාළ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ප්‍රතිපාදනවලට අනුකූලව රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වූ බව මහජනතාවට නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරන බව කථානායක අබේවර්ධන ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව කථානායක කාර්යාලය ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කථානායක කාර්යාලය විසින් ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ නීතිපතිවරයාගෙන් (AG) අදහස් විමසා ඇත, ”ඩේලි එෆ්ටී වාර්තා කරයි. රාජපක්ෂ මුලින් කියා සිටියේ ජූලි 13 බදාදා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ලබාදෙන බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඔහුගේ පස් අවුරුදු ධුර කාලය තුළ වසර දෙකයි මාස අටක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට සිදු වූ අතර, ඔහු සිය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වූ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත් විය. 2019 නොවැම්බරයේ පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී කාර්යක්‍ෂම හා පිරිසිදු පාලනයක් පිළිබඳ පොරොන්දුව මත වැඩි ඡන්දයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ මිනිසෙකුට එය නින්දා සහගත පිටවීමකි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද දිනයේදී අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙන්නේද යන්න තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී ඇත්තේ රාජපක්ෂගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයෙකු තෝරාගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද විමසීම පැවැත්වෙන තෙක්ය.",
        "එම කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු පැවසුවේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා රැඳී සිටින බවයි.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වන අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) ජනාධිපති ධූරයට තරඟ කිරීම සඳහා අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ඉදිරිපත් නොකරන බව ඊයේ නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ පාලනයක් වෙනස් කිරීම සඳහා වූ මහජන ඉල්ලීමට හිස නමන බවත්, එබැවින් මෙම තීරණය ගත් බවත් එම පක්ෂය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා වන මැතිවරණය ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට පක්ෂ නායකයින් මීට පෙර එකඟ වී තිබුණත් අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වීමට කලින් ගත් තීරණය කල් දමා තිබීම නිසා එය ප්‍රමාද විය හැකියි. ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් ඇති වූ බව කථානායකවරයා විසින් සභාවට දන්වා නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීමට දිනයක් නියම කරන විට නියමිත පරිදි අඟහරුවාදා සභාව රැස්වේ.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ අගමැති ධූරය සඳහා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා නම් කරන බව කථානායකවරයාට දැනුම් දීමට ඊයේ රැස්වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ, දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම වන SJB, SLFP ඇතුළු පක්ෂ කිහිපයක සංවර්ධන නියෝජිතයන් තීරණය කළේය. රට මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික අර්බුදවලින් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා යෝජනා කරනවා. ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ එම රැස්වීමට පැමිණ සිටියේ නැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනකට ආසන්න අවසානයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි එයාර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා හිමිදිරියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යන්තම් අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස අටක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස් අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் ஊடாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவிற்கு மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் அனுப்பியுள்ளார். இந்த இணைப்பு",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொதுமக்களின் எதிர்ப்பு அலைகளால் பதவியில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, சுமார் மூன்று வருட கால சுக்காத குழப்பமான ஆட்சியை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டு வரும் வகையில் சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து நேற்று தனது பதிவு கடிதத்தை அனுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "புதன்கிழமை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய ஜனாதிபதி, நேற்றிரவு சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் ஊடாக தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு மின்னஞ்சலில் அனுப்பியுள்ளார். மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து சவுதி ஏர் விமானம் மூலம் சிங்கப்பூர் வந்த ராஜபக்ச, புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலையில் விமானப்படையின் ராணுவ விமானம் மூலம் ஒரு நாள் தங்கியிருந்தார்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச தனிப்பட்ட விஜயத்தின் அடிப்படையில் சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார் மற்றும் புகலிடம் வழங்கப்படவில்லை, தலைவர் மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து வந்த பின்னர் நகர-மாநிலம் கூறியது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில், “ராஜபக்சே தனிப்பட்ட பயணமாக சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார் என்பது உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. \"அவர் புகலிடம் கேட்கவில்லை, அவருக்கு எந்த புகலிடமும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை. சிங்கப்பூர் பொதுவாக புகலிடக் கோரிக்கைகளை வழங்குவதில்லை. சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து ராஜபக்சே வேறு நாட்டுக்கு செல்ல திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக ஊகங்கள் எழுந்தன.",
        "கடிதத்தின் நம்பகத்தன்மையை சரிபார்த்ததன் பின்னர் உரிய அரசியலமைப்பு விதிகளுக்கு அமைவாக ராஜபக்ச ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை இன்று பொதுமக்களுக்கு வழங்கியுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன நேற்றிரவு உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் நேற்று இரவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இது தொடர்பாக அட்டர்னி ஜெனரல் (ஏஜி) நேற்று இரவு சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் மூலம் ஆலோசனை நடத்தப்பட்டது” என்று டெய்லி எப்டி செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. முதலில் ராஜபக்சே ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை தனது ராஜினாமாவை வழங்குவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தனது ஐந்தாண்டு பதவிக்காலத்திற்கு இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள் மற்றும் எட்டு மாதங்கள் மட்டுமே பதவியில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்டார். 2019 நவம்பரில் நடைபெற்ற ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் திறமையான மற்றும் தூய்மையான நிர்வாகம் என்ற வாக்குறுதியின் அடிப்படையில் பெரும் வாக்கு வித்தியாசத்தில் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட ஒருவருக்கு இது அவமானகரமான வெளியேற்றம்.",
        "ராஜபக்சவின் வாரிசை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு நிலுவையில் உள்ள நிலையில், இடைக்கால அதிபராக இன்று பதவியேற்பாரா என்பதை, தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக இருக்கும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கேவின் அலுவலகம் உறுதி செய்யவில்லை.",
        "ராஜினாமா கடிதம் தொடர்பான உறுதிப்படுத்தலைப் பெற காத்திருப்பதாக அலுவலகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றம் கூடும் போது ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதற்கு தாம் வேட்பாளரை நிறுத்தப் போவதில்லை என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) நேற்று அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலான நிர்வாகத்தை மாற்ற வேண்டும் என்ற பொதுமக்களின் கோரிக்கைக்கு தலைவணங்குவதாகவும், எனவே இந்த முடிவை எடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் அக்கட்சி தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான தேர்தலை ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி நடத்துவதற்கு கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் முன்னதாக இணக்கம் தெரிவித்திருந்தனர் ஆனால் இன்று பாராளுமன்றம் கூடவதற்கான முன்னைய தீர்மானம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால் இது தாமதமாகலாம். இப்போது திட்டமிட்டபடி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கூடும், தலைவர் பதவியில் காலியிடம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் சபைக்கு அறிவித்து, வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான தேதியை நிர்ணயிப்பார்.",
        "நேற்று கூடிய SJB, SLFP, SLPP, TNA உள்ளடங்கிய சுயேச்சைக் குழு உட்பட பல கட்சிகளின் பிரதிநிதிகள், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கவுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகரிடம் தெரிவிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர். நாடு எதிர்நோக்கும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகளை சமாளிக்கும் நோக்கில் இது முன்னெடுக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் ஜே.வி.பி."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட மூன்று வருடங்கள் முடிவடைகிறது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி ஏர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}