{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Parliament-talks-on-prevailing-crisis-on-6-July/56-736902",
  "time_ut": 1656633295,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament talks on prevailing crisis on 6 July",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament talks on prevailing crisis on 6 July",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition motion to be debated; PM’s question time also scheduled for 30 minutes on same day",
        "An adjournment debate moved by the Opposition on the prevailing situation in the country will be debated in Parliament on 6  July, the Committee on Parliamentary Business which met yesterday",
        "The House will meet for three days next week with Prime Minister’s question time also scheduled for 30 minutes on 6 July.",
        "During yesterday’s meeting presided by Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, the members present discussed holding committee meetings online on days when the Parliament is not in session due to the prevailing fuel shortage.",
        "The Business Committee also decided to allocate the whole day on 4 July for 50 Questions for Oral Answers which have been delayed due to various reasons in the past few months.",
        "On 5 July, Parliament will debate Regulations under the Foreign Exchange Act No. 12 of 2017, two Orders under the Sri Lanka Export Development Act No. 40 of 1979 published under the Gazette Extraordinary No. 2270/20 and 2280/32, a Resolution under the Custom ordinance and a resolution under Section 8 of the Appropriation Act No. 7 of 2020.",
        "Six Orders under Special Commodity Levy Act No. 48 of 2007 and Two Regulations under the Imports and Exports Control Act No. 01 of 1969 are also scheduled to be approved following debate on the same day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "6 July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "30 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Opposition on the prevailing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6  July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Business Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Regulations",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Exchange Act No",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Export Development Act No",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 of 1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2270/20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2280/32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Custom",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 8 of the Appropriation Act No",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 of 2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 6 වැනිදා සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ යෝජනාව විවාදයට අගමැතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රශ්න කාලයද එදිනම විනාඩි 30කට නියමිතයි",
        "ඊයේ රැස්වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව, රටේ පවතින තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව විපක්ෂය විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද කල් තැබීමේ විවාදයක් ජූලි 6  දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී විවාදයට ගැනීමට නියමිතය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ප්‍රශ්නාවලිය ද ජූලි 6 වැනි දින විනාඩි 30 ට නියමිතව ඇති අතර ලබන සතියේ දින තුනක් සභාව රැස්වේ.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ඊයේ පැවැති රැස්වීමේදී, පවතින ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නොපැවැත්වෙන දිනවල අන්තර්ජාලය ඔස්සේ කමිටු රැස්වීම් පැවැත්වීම පිළිබඳව පැමිණ සිටි මන්ත්‍රීවරු සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ විවිධ හේතූන් මත ප්‍රමාද වූ වාචික පිළිතුරු සඳහා ප්‍රශ්න 50 ක් සඳහා ජූලි 4 වැනි දින මුළු දවසම වෙන් කිරීමට ද ව්‍යාපාරික කමිටුව තීරණය කළේය.",
        "ජූලි 5 වැනි දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් 2017 අංක 12 දරන විදේශ විනිමය පනත යටතේ රෙගුලාසි, 1979 අංක 40 දරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන සංවර්ධන පනත යටතේ නියමයන් දෙකක් විවාදයට ගනු ඇත. රේගු ආඥාපනත යටතේ සහ 2020 අංක 7 දරන විසර්ජන පනතේ 8 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ යෝජනාවක්.",
        "2007 අංක 48 දරන විශේෂ වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ බද්ද යටතේ නියෝග හයක් සහ 1969 අංක 01 දරන ආනයන හා අපනයන පාලන පනත යටතේ නියෝග දෙකක් ද එදිනම විවාදයෙන් අනතුරුව අනුමත කිරීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "6 ජූලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 30 ක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පවතින මත විපක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6  ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සතියේ දින තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 30 ක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යාපාරික කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙගුලාසි",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ විනිමය පනත අංක",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන සංවර්ධන පනත අංක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1979 40",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2270/20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2280/32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභිරුචි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංක විසර්ජන පනතේ 8 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007 48",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடிகள் குறித்து ஜூலை 6ஆம் தேதி பேசுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி பிரேரணை விவாதம்; பிரதமரின் கேள்வி நேரமும் அதே நாளில் 30 நிமிடங்களுக்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் சூழ்நிலை குறித்து எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் முன்வைத்த ஒத்திவைப்பு விவாதம் ஜூலை 6  அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் விவாதிக்கப்படும் என்று நேற்று கூடிய நாடாளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழு",
        "சபை அடுத்த வாரம் மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு கூடும், பிரதமரின் கேள்வி நேரமும் ஜூலை 6 ஆம் தேதி 30 நிமிடங்களுக்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் நேற்றைய தினம் இடம்பெற்ற கூட்டத்தின் போது, ​​தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக பாராளுமன்றம் கூடாத நாட்களில் குழு கூட்டங்களை இணையவழியில் நடத்துவது குறித்து அங்கிருந்த உறுப்பினர்கள் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக பல்வேறு காரணங்களால் தாமதமாகி வரும் 50 கேள்விகளுக்கு வாய்மொழி பதில்களுக்கான முழு நாளையும் ஜூலை 4 ஆம் தேதி ஒதுக்க வணிகக் குழு முடிவு செய்தது.",
        "ஜூலை 5 ஆம் தேதி, 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 12 ஆம் இலக்க அந்நியச் செலாவணிச் சட்டத்தின் கீழான ஒழுங்குமுறைகள், 2270/20 மற்றும் 2280/32 ஆகிய வர்த்தமானியின் கீழ் வெளியிடப்பட்ட 1979 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 40 ஆம் இலக்க இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி அபிவிருத்திச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இரண்டு ஆணைகள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் விவாதிக்கப்படும். சுங்கச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் மற்றும் 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 7 ஆம் இலக்க ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 8 இன் கீழ் ஒரு தீர்மானம்.",
        "2007 இன் சிறப்புப் பண்ட வரிச் சட்டம் எண். 48ன் கீழ் உள்ள ஆறு ஆணைகளும், 1969 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 01. இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதிக் கட்டுப்பாட்டுச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இரண்டு ஒழுங்குமுறைகளும் அன்றைய விவாதத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "6 ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "30 நிமிடம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நடைமுறையில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6  ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம் மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நிமிடம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வணிகக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒழுங்குமுறைகள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்நிய செலாவணி சட்டம் எண்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி அபிவிருத்திச் சட்டம் இல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 இன் 1979",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2270/20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2280/32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிப்பயன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 8 எண்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007 இன் 48",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}