{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/business/ශ්‍රී-ලංකා-බැඳුම්කර-හිමියෙකු-ඇමෙරිකාවේදී-නඩු-පවරලා/7-394679",
  "time_ut": 1655872055,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කර හිමියෙකු ඇමෙරිකාවේදී නඩු පවරලා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A Sri Lankan bond holder has filed a lawsuit in America",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Sri Lankan bondholder has filed a lawsuit in the United States demanding payment of his money plus interest after Sri Lanka defaulted on its debt for the first time in its history, struggling to stave off economic collapse.",
        "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd., which owns more than $250 million in Sri Lanka's 5.875% international sovereign bonds due July 25, filed a lawsuit Tuesday in New York federal court demanding full payment of principal and interest, Bloomberg reports.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted in May after a 30-day grace period expired for missed interest payments on two of its sovereign bonds. It was Sri Lanka's first sovereign debt default since independence from Britain in 1948.",
        "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd claimed in the suit that the default was orchestrated by the ruling Rajapakse family and the highest level of government officials. It also accused Sri Lanka of disposing of bonds held by domestic banks and other interested parties in an announced debt restructuring."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "America",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than $250 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.875%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bloomberg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කර හිමියෙකු ඇමෙරිකාවේදී නඩු පවරලා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීම වළක්වා ගැනීමට සඳහා ප්‍රබල අරගලයක යෙදෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉතිහාසයේ ප්‍රථම වතාවට සිය ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හැරීමෙන් පසුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කර හිමියෙකු විසින් එක්සත් ජනපදයේදී තම මුදල් සහ පොලියද ගෙවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා නඩු පවරා තිබේ.",
        "ජූලි 25 වැනි දිනට කල් පිරීමට නියමිත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 5.875% ජාත්‍යන්තර ස්වෛරී බැඳුම්කරවලින් ඇ.ඩො.මිලියන 250කට වඩා වැඩි මුදලක් හිමි Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd විසින් මූලික මුදල හා පොලිය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ගෙවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා නිව්යෝක් ෆෙඩරල් අධිකරණයේදී අඟහරුවාදා නඩුව ගොනුකර ඇති බව බ්ලූම්බර්ග් වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, එහි ස්වෛරී බැඳුම්කර දෙකක් සඳහා මග හැරුණු පොලී ගෙවීම් සඳහා දින 30ක සහන කාලය ඉකුත්වීමෙන් පසු මැයි මාසයේදී ණය පැහැර හැරීමට ලක් විය. එය 1948 දී බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයෙන් නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් සිදු කරන ලද පළමු වැනි ස්වෛරී ණය පැහැර හැරීමයි.",
        "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd විසින් එම නඩුවේදී කියා සිටියේ, පැහැර හැරීම පාලක රාජපක්ෂ පවුල ඇතුළු ආණ්ඩුවේ ඉහළම මට්ටමේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් සංවිධානය කළ එකක් බවය. එමෙන්ම, ප්‍රකාශිත ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමකින් දේශීය බැංකු සහ අනෙකුත් උනන්දුවක් දක්වන පාර්ශ්ව විසින් තබා ඇති බැඳුම්කර බැහැර කරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට චෝදනා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 250 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.875%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්ලූම්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பிணைமுறி வைத்திருப்பவர் ஒருவர் அமெரிக்காவில் வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை தனது வரலாற்றில் முதல் தடவையாக கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தத் தவறியதன் பின்னர், பொருளாதாரச் சரிவைத் தடுக்கப் போராடி, தனது பணத்தையும் வட்டியையும் செலுத்துமாறு கோரி இலங்கைப் பத்திரதாரர் ஒருவர் அமெரிக்காவில் வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 25 ஆம் திகதி இலங்கையின் 5.875% சர்வதேச இறையாண்மை பத்திரங்களில் $250 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான சொத்துக்களை வைத்திருக்கும் Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd., அசல் மற்றும் வட்டியை முழுமையாக செலுத்துமாறு கோரி நியூயோர்க் பெடரல் நீதிமன்றத்தில் செவ்வாய்கிழமை வழக்குத் தொடுத்துள்ளது, Bloomberg தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் இரண்டு இறையாண்மைப் பத்திரங்களுக்குத் தவறிய வட்டிக் கொடுப்பனவுகளுக்கு 30 நாள் கால அவகாசம் காலாவதியான பின்னர் மே மாதம் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை. 1948 இல் பிரித்தானியாவிடமிருந்து சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் இலங்கையின் முதல் இறையாண்மைக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாத நிலை இதுவாகும்.",
        "ஆளும் இராஜபக்ஷ குடும்பம் மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தின் உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகளினால் இட்டுக்கட்டப்பட்டது என்று Hamilton Reserve Bank Ltd இந்த வழக்கில் கூறியுள்ளது. அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் உள்நாட்டு வங்கிகள் மற்றும் பிற ஆர்வமுள்ள தரப்பினர் வைத்திருக்கும் பத்திரங்களை இலங்கை அகற்றுவதாகவும் அது குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன் ரிசர்வ் வங்கி லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$250 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.875%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ளூம்பெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹாமில்டன் ரிசர்வ் வங்கி லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}