{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84639/special-unit-to-be-set-up-for-restructuring-state-owned-enterprises",
  "time_ut": 1661853780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Special unit to be set up for restructuring state-owned enterprises",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Special unit to be set up for restructuring state-owned enterprises",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The government has decided to establish a “State-Owned Enterprise Restructuring Unit” with the aim of facilitating the restructuring of government-owned business entities.",
        "Presenting the Interim Budget 2022 in the parliament, President Ranil Wickremesinghe further proposed to allocate Rs. 200 million to implement this proposal.",
        "He mentioned that the decision was taken as some of the state-owned enterprises have been making losses on a continuous basis due to issues of structural nature existed for some time.",
        "As these losses cannot be met endlessly by the General Treasury, attention is paid to find an alternative mechanism to make them effective, the President added.",
        "Speaking further on the matter, he noted that major fiscal risks arise from a few key state-owned enterprises (SOEs), particularly in the transportation (SriLankan Airlines) and energy sector (Ceylon Electricity Board and the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation).",
        "These entities face significant losses, negative equity (SriLankan Airlines and CPC) and large volumes of debt that is predominantly owed to the state banks, creating significant sector risk, he explained.",
        "He proposed to re-activate the Statement of Corporate Intent (SCI) process for key 50 SOEs, excluding CEB, CPC and Sri Lankan Airlines, as they are under different efforts to restructure, to closely monitor the set targets.",
        "“These difficult but necessary measures pertaining to SOEs will no doubt be challenging to address, but failing to do so would create catastrophic risks, particularly for financial sector stability, and will entail even higher taxation burdens on the public in the future,” the President added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the General Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SCI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය සතු ව්‍යවසාය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා විශේෂ ඒකකයක් පිහිටුවීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජය සතු ව්‍යාපාරික ආයතන ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීමේ අරමුණින් “රාජ්‍ය සතු ව්‍යවසාය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ඒකකයක්” පිහිටුවීමට රජය තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "2022 අතුරු අයවැය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් යෝජනා කළේ රු. මෙම යෝජනාව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට මිලියන 200ක්.",
        "කලක සිට පවතින ව්‍යුහාත්මක ගැටලු හේතුවෙන් ඇතැම් රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසාය අඛණ්ඩව පාඩු ලබන බැවින් මෙම තීරණය ගත් බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම පාඩුව මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයට නිමක් නැතිව පියවා ගත නොහැකි බැවින් ඒවා ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා විකල්ප යාන්ත්‍රණයක් සොයා ගැනීමට අවධානය යොමු කරන බවද ජනාධිපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේ ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් (SOEs) කිහිපයකින්, විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රවාහන (ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය) සහ බලශක්ති අංශයේ (ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය සහ ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව) ප්‍රධාන මූල්‍ය අවදානම් මතුවන බවයි.",
        "මෙම ආයතන සැලකිය යුතු පාඩු, සෘණ කොටස් (ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම සහ CPC) සහ රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවලට ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ගෙවිය යුතු විශාල ණය ප්‍රමාණයකට මුහුණ දෙන අතර, සැලකිය යුතු අංශ අවදානමක් නිර්මාණය කරන බව ඔහු පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "CEB, CPC සහ Sri Lankan Airlines හැර, ප්‍රධාන 50 SOEs සඳහා ආයතනික අභිප්‍රාය ප්‍රකාශය (SCI) ක්‍රියාවලිය නැවත සක්‍රිය කිරීමට ඔහු යෝජනා කළේය, ඒවා ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට විවිධ ප්‍රයත්නයන් යටතේ පවතින බැවින්, නියමිත ඉලක්ක සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීමට.",
        "\"SOEs සම්බන්ධ මෙම දුෂ්කර නමුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම අභියෝගාත්මක වනු ඇති බවට සැකයක් නැත, නමුත් එසේ කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වීම ව්‍යසනකාරී අවදානම් ඇති කරයි, විශේෂයෙන් මූල්‍ය අංශයේ ස්ථාවරත්වය සඳහා වන අතර, අනාගතයේදී මහජනතාව මත ඊටත් වඩා ඉහළ බදු බරක් පැටවෙනු ඇත,\" ජනාධිපතිතුමා එකතු කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SCI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களை மறுசீரமைக்க சிறப்பு பிரிவு அமைக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்குச் சொந்தமான வணிக நிறுவனங்களின் மறுசீரமைப்பை எளிதாக்கும் நோக்கத்துடன் \"அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவன மறுசீரமைப்பு அலகு\" ஒன்றை நிறுவ அரசாங்கம் முடிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "2022ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பித்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 2022ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான நிதியொதுக்கீட்டிற்கு மேலும் ரூ. இந்த திட்டத்தை செயல்படுத்த 200 மில்லியன்.",
        "சில அரச நிறுவனங்கள் சில காலமாக நிலவும் கட்டமைப்பு பிரச்சினைகளால் தொடர்ச்சியாக நட்டத்தை சந்தித்து வருவதால் இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த இழப்புக்களை பொது திறைசேரியால் முடிவில்லாமல் பூர்த்தி செய்ய முடியாது என்பதால், அவற்றை பலனளிக்கக்கூடிய மாற்று பொறிமுறையை கண்டுபிடிப்பதில் கவனம் செலுத்தப்படுவதாக ஜனாதிபதி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் மேலும் பேசிய அவர், சில முக்கிய அரச நிறுவனங்களினால் (SOEs), குறிப்பாக போக்குவரத்து (ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்) மற்றும் எரிசக்தி துறையில் (இலங்கை மின்சார சபை மற்றும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம்) பெரும் நிதி அபாயங்கள் ஏற்படுவதாக குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இந்த நிறுவனங்கள் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க இழப்புகள், எதிர்மறை சமபங்கு (ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் மற்றும் CPC) மற்றும் அரச வங்கிகளுக்கு முக்கியமாக செலுத்த வேண்டிய பெரிய அளவிலான கடன்களை எதிர்கொள்கின்றன, இது குறிப்பிடத்தக்க துறை அபாயத்தை உருவாக்குகிறது என்று அவர் விளக்கினார்.",
        "CEB, CPC மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் தவிர்த்து, முக்கிய 50 SOE களுக்கான கூட்டு நோக்கத்தின் அறிக்கை (SCI) செயல்முறையை மீண்டும் செயல்படுத்த அவர் முன்மொழிந்தார்.",
        "\"SOEகள் தொடர்பான இந்த கடினமான ஆனால் அவசியமான நடவடிக்கைகள் சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமின்றி சவாலாக இருக்கும். சேர்க்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்சிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}