{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/30/mobile-phone-vendors-affected-due-to-import-restrictions/",
  "time_ut": 1661858340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Mobile phone vendors affected due to import restrictions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Mobile phone vendors affected due to import restrictions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lanka Mobile Phone Importers and Sellers Association says that the mobile phone sales sector has been severely affected under the current import restrictions.",
        "The president of the association, Samith Senarath, stated the recently imposed 'temporary suspensions' on over 300 items have severely impaired the market.",
        "According to him, mobile phone batteries will not be allowed to be imported from 23rd of August, and the prices of the batteries have increased to Rs. 1,500 from Rs. 450.",
        "Bangladesh will never face a situation like Sri Lanka: PM Sheikh Hasina"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Mobile Phone Importers and Sellers Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samith Senarath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23rd of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Sheikh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආනයන සීමා කිරීම් හේතුවෙන් ජංගම දුරකථන වෙළෙන්දන් පීඩාවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); දැනට පවතින ආනයන සීමා කිරීම් යටතේ ජංගම දුරකථන අලෙවි ක්ෂේත්‍රයට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වී ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජංගම දුරකථන ආනයනකරුවන්ගේ සහ විකුණුම්කරුවන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "එම සංගමයේ සභාපති සමිත් සෙනරත් මහතා සඳහන් කළේ, භාණ්ඩ 300කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් සඳහා පසුගියදා පැනවූ 'තාවකාලික අත්හිටුවීම්' හේතුවෙන් වෙළඳපල දැඩි ලෙස අඩාල වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව අගෝස්තු 23 වැනිදා සිට ජංගම දුරකථන බැටරි ආනයනය කිරීමට ඉඩ නොදෙන බවත්, එම බැටරිවල මිල රු. 1,500 සිට රු. 450",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි තත්ත්වයකට බංග්ලාදේශයට කිසිදා මුහුණ නොදෙන බව අගමැතිනි ෂෙයික් හසීනා පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජංගම දුරකථන ආනයනකරුවන්ගේ සහ විකුණුම්කරුවන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමිත් සෙනරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 23 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති ෂීක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இறக்குமதி கட்டுப்பாடுகளால் மொபைல் போன் விற்பனையாளர்கள் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தற்போதைய இறக்குமதி கட்டுப்பாடுகளின் கீழ் கையடக்க தொலைபேசி விற்பனைத் துறை கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கையடக்க தொலைபேசி இறக்குமதியாளர்கள் மற்றும் விற்பனையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் சமித் செனரத் கூறுகையில், 300க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பொருட்களுக்கு சமீபத்தில் விதிக்கப்பட்ட 'தற்காலிக இடைநிறுத்தம்' சந்தையை கடுமையாக பாதித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 23ஆம் தேதி முதல் கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசி பேட்டரிகளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய அனுமதிக்கப்பட மாட்டாது என்றும், பேட்டரிகளின் விலை ரூ. 1,500 முதல் ரூ. 450.",
        "இலங்கையைப் போன்ற ஒரு சூழ்நிலையை வங்கதேசம் சந்திக்காது: பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கையடக்க தொலைபேசி இறக்குமதியாளர்கள் மற்றும் விற்பனையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமித் செனரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "300க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM ஷேக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}