{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78274",
  "time_ut": 1656358860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to purchase four shipments of fuel from India for Cash  instead of on credit; Deal Expected to materialise in One week  will result in  Initial shipment Followed by Petrol Shipments  When Required.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to purchase four shipments of fuel from India for Cash  instead of on credit; Deal Expected to materialise in One week  will result in  Initial shipment Followed by Petrol Shipments  When Required.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "In a step close to integration with India in energy security, Sri Lanka has sought to purchase four shipments of fuel – 40,000 tonnes each- from India on cash payment terms, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "India is a bulk purchaser of fuel from the global market with attractive discounts. There is a proposal in the road map worked out by the Sri Lankan envoy to New Delhi Milinda Moragoda for the development of bilateral relations to tie up with India to buy fuel from the world market together, to benefit from the same discounted rates.",
        "Foreign Affairs Minister Prof. G.L. Peiris also proposed the idea during a meeting in recent times.",
        "According to well informed sources, Sri Lanka has now sought to purchase four shipments of fuel from India instead of on credit. Initially, a shipment of diesel will be dispatched. Afterwards, petrol will be sent depending on the requirements. However, it will take at least one more week for the purchase to materialise.",
        "Already, Sri Lanka has bought US $ 700 million Indian credits to import fuel. The latest proposal for cash payment transaction comes in the wake of the government seeking another credit line of US $ 500 million.",
        "Daily Mirror learns that the next credit line is also in the process. Sri Lanka currently faces uncertainty over the next shipment of fuel"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Deal Expected",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "One week",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Petrol Shipments",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 700 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් හතරක් ණයට වෙනුවට මුදලට මිලදී ගැනීමට; සතියකින් ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන ගනුදෙනුවේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මූලික නැව්ගත කිරීම් පසුව අවශ්‍ය විට පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් සිදුවේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "බලශක්ති සුරක්ෂිතතාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව සමඟ ඒකාබද්ධ වීමේ පියවරක් ලෙස, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් හතරක් - ටොන් 40,000 බැගින්- ඉන්දියාවෙන් මුදල් ගෙවීමේ කොන්දේසි මත මිලදී ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කර ඇති බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ඉන්දියාව ගෝලීය වෙළෙඳපොළෙන් ආකර්ශනීය වට්ටම් සහිතව ඉන්ධන තොග වශයෙන් මිලදී ගන්නෙකු වේ. නවදිල්ලියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිත මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ මහතා විසින් සකස් කරන ලද මාර්ග සිතියමේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා වර්ධනය කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව සමඟ එක්ව ලෝක වෙළෙඳපොළෙන් ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා එම වට්ටම් මිලට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා ගැනීමේ යෝජනාවක් තිබේ.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතා ද මෑත කාලයේ පැවති රැස්වීමකදී මෙම අදහස ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "හොඳින් දන්නා මූලාශ්‍රවලට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් ණයට ගැනීම වෙනුවට ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉන්ධන තොග හතරක් මිලදී ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කර ඇත. මුලදී, ඩීසල් තොගයක් යවනු ලැබේ. ඊට පස්සේ අවශ්‍යතා අනුව පෙට්‍රල් එවනවා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මිලදී ගැනීම ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට අවම වශයෙන් තවත් සතියක්වත් ගතවනු ඇත.",
        "දැනටමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 700ක ඉන්දියානු ණය ලබාගෙන ඇත. මුදල් ගෙවීමේ ගනුදෙනුව සඳහා නවතම යෝජනාව පැමිණෙන්නේ රජය තවත් ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක ණය මාර්ගයක් අපේක්ෂාවෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත දැනගන්නට ලැබෙන්නේ මීළඟ ණය මාර්ගයද ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් පවතින බවයි. මීළඟ ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වන විට අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයකට මුහුණ දී සිටී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගනුදෙනුව අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සතියක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීම්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් එකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 700 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து நான்கு ஏற்றுமதி எரிபொருளை கடனுக்குப் பதிலாக பணமாக வாங்குவதற்கு இலங்கை; ஒரு வாரத்தில் நடைமுறைக்கு வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் ஒப்பந்தம், தேவைப்படும் போது பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியைத் தொடர்ந்து ஆரம்ப ஏற்றுமதிக்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிசக்தி பாதுகாப்பில் இந்தியாவுடன் ஒருங்கிணைக்கப்படுவதற்கான ஒரு படிநிலையில், இலங்கையானது நான்கு ஏற்றுமதி எரிபொருளை - இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 40,000 டன்கள்- ரொக்கக் கொடுப்பனவு அடிப்படையில் கொள்வனவு செய்ய முற்பட்டுள்ளது என்று டெய்லி மிரர் அறியிறது.",
        "கவர்ச்சிகரமான தள்ளுபடியுடன் உலக சந்தையில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை மொத்தமாக வாங்கும் நாடாக இந்தியா உள்ளது. அதே தள்ளுபடி விலையில் பலனடைவதற்கும், உலக சந்தையில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை ஒன்றாகக் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கும், இந்தியாவுடன் இணைந்து இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் புதுடில்லிக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் மிலிந்த மொரகொடவினால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட சாலை வரைபடத்தில் முன்மொழிவு உள்ளது.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸும் அண்மைய காலங்களில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போது இந்த யோசனையை முன்வைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நன்கு அறியப்பட்ட ஆதாரங்களின்படி, இலங்கை இப்போது கடனுக்குப் பதிலாக இந்தியாவிலிருந்து நான்கு ஏற்றுமதி எரிபொருளைக் கொள்வனவு செய்ய முயன்றுள்ளது. முதற்கட்டமாக, டீசல் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்படும். அதன்பிறகு, தேவைக்கேற்ப பெட்ரோல் அனுப்பப்படும். இருப்பினும், கொள்முதல் நடைமுறைக்கு வர குறைந்தது ஒரு வாரமாவது ஆகும்.",
        "ஏற்கனவே, எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக இலங்கை 700 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை இந்திய கடன்களை வாங்கியுள்ளது. ரொக்கப் பரிவர்த்தனைக்கான சமீபத்திய முன்மொழிவு, அரசாங்கம் மற்றொரு 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் கடனைத் தேடுவதை அடுத்து வந்துள்ளது.",
        "டெய்லி மிரர் அடுத்த கடன் வரிசையும் செயல்பாட்டில் உள்ளது என்பதை அறிந்து கொள்கிறது. இலங்கை தற்போது எரிபொருள் அடுத்த ஏற்றுமதி தொடர்பில் நிச்சயமற்ற நிலையை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒப்பந்தம் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்த பட்சம் ஓன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 700 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}