{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/President-Wickremesinghe-cannot-be-discharged-from-the-proceedings-of-Easter-Sunday-attack-petitions-Cardinal/108-242270",
  "time_ut": 1659437565,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Wickremesinghe cannot be discharged from the proceedings of Easter Sunday attack petitions- Cardinal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Wickremesinghe cannot be discharged from the proceedings of Easter Sunday attack petitions- Cardinal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The application made by President Ranil Wickremesinghe that he be discharged from the proceedings in connection with the twelve Fundamental Rights petitions filed over Easter Sunday attacks should be dismissed by Supreme Court, Colombo Archbishop Malcolm Cardinal Ranjith said.",
        "Tendering written submissions before Supreme Court, Colombo Archbishop today maintained that President Ranil Wickremesinghe cannot be necessarily discharged from these proceedings.",
        "President Ranil Wicremesinghe had been made a party to a Fundamental Rights petition filed by Bar Association of Sri Lanka as the 8th Respondent, for the various acts or omissions which resulted in the violation of Fundamental Rights whilst he had been serving in his capacity as the Prime Minister who functioned at the stage at which the Easter Attacks had taken place on the 21st April 2019.",
        "Archbishop of Colombo, who represents the most aggrieved party of the victims of the Easter Sunday attacks had been named as the 57th respondent.",
        "In his written submissions, the Colombo Archbishop stated that the jurisdiction granted by Article 126 was introduced for the first time through the 19th Amendment and such jurisdiction has been thereafter preserved by the Legislature under the 20th Amendment as well.",
        "Therefore by the said Article 35 (1), the Supreme Court can exercise its fundamental rights jurisdiction to scrutinize the acts and omissions of the President. Colombo Archbishop further submitted that discharging the President Wickremesinghe from these proceedings would accordingly directly contravene with the Articles 7 and 8 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.",
        "Colombo Archbishop was represented by Shammil Perera PC. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Easter Sunday",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "twelve",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter Sunday",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wicremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Easter Attacks",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st April 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Archbishop",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 126",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Article 35",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Universal Declaration of Human Rights",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shammil Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයේ පෙත්සම් විභාගයෙන් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ නිදහස් කළ නොහැකියි - කාදිනල් හිමිපාණන්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් දොළහට අදාළ නඩු විභාගයෙන් තමා නිදහස් කරන ලෙසට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කළ ඉල්ලීම ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කළ යුතු බව කොළඹ අගරදගුරු අතිඋතුම් මැල්කම් කාදිනල් රංජිත් හිමිපාණන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ ලිඛිත දේශන ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් කොළඹ අගරදගුරු හිමිපාණන් අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මෙම නඩු කටයුතුවලින් අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම නිදහස් කළ නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියදී මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩවීමට හේතු වූ විවිධ ක්‍රියා හෝ අතපසුවීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය විසින් 8 වැනි වගඋත්තරකරු ලෙස ගොනු කර තිබූ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමක පාර්ශවකරුවෙකු බවට පත් කර තිබුණි. 2019 අප්‍රේල් 21 පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය සිදුවූ වේදිකාවේ කටයුතු කළ අමාත්‍ය.",
        "57 වැනි වගඋත්තරකරු ලෙස පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයෙන් විපතට පත් වූවන්ගේ වඩාත් අගතියට පත් පාර්ශ්වය නියෝජනය කරන කොළඹ අගරදගුරු හිමිපාණන් නම් කර ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ අගරදගුරුතුමා සිය ලිඛිත දේශනවල සඳහන් කළේ 126 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් ලබා දී ඇති අධිකරණ බලය 19 වැනි සංශෝධනය හරහා ප්‍රථම වරට හඳුන්වා දුන් බවත් ඉන් අනතුරුව 20 වැනි සංශෝධනය යටතේද එවැනි අධිකරණ බලය ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය විසින් ආරක්ෂා කර ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "එබැවින් එකී 35 (1) වගන්තිය මගින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ක්‍රියාවන් සහ අතපසුවීම් විමර්ශනය කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට සිය මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අධිකරණ බලය ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ හැකිය. ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මෙම ක්‍රියාදාමයෙන් නිදහස් කිරීම ඒ අනුව මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ විශ්ව ප්‍රකාශනයේ 7 සහ 8 වගන්තිවලට සෘජුවම පටහැනි බව කොළඹ අගරදගුරු හිමිපාණන් වැඩිදුරටත් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "කොළඹ අගරදගුරුතුමා වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෂම්මිල් පෙරේරා මහතා සහභාගි විය. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොළොස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 අප්‍රේල් 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අගරදගුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "126 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ විශ්ව ප්‍රකාශනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂම්මිල් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல் மனுக்கள் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவை விடுவிக்க முடியாது - கர்தினால்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள 12 அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுக்கள் தொடர்பிலான விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து தன்னை விடுவிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க விடுத்துள்ள விண்ணப்பத்தை உயர் நீதிமன்றம் நிராகரிக்க வேண்டும் என கொழும்பு பேராயர் மல்கம் கர்தினால் ரஞ்சித் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை கட்டாயமாக விடுவிக்க முடியாது என, உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் எழுத்துமூல சமர்ப்பணங்களை சமர்ப்பித்த கொழும்பு பேராயர், இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்தபோது, ​​அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை மீறும் பல்வேறு செயல்கள் அல்லது தவறுகளுக்காக, இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தினால் 8வது பிரதிவாதியாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுவில் அவர் தரப்பு ஆக்கப்பட்டிருந்தார். 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 21 ஆம் திகதி ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்கள் இடம்பெற்ற மேடையில் செயற்பட்ட அமைச்சர்.",
        "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதலில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களில் மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தரப்பினரை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கொழும்பு பேராயர் 57வது பிரதிவாதியாக பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு பேராயர் தனது எழுத்துப்பூர்வ சமர்ப்பிப்புகளில், 126 வது சரத்தின் மூலம் வழங்கப்பட்ட அதிகார வரம்பு 19 வது திருத்தத்தின் மூலம் முதன்முறையாக அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது என்றும் அத்தகைய அதிகார வரம்பு 20 வது திருத்தத்தின் கீழும் சட்டமன்றத்தால் பாதுகாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "எனவே, கூறப்பட்ட பிரிவு 35 (1)ன்படி, குடியரசுத் தலைவரின் செயல்கள் மற்றும் புறக்கணிப்புகளை ஆராய உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் தனது அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் அதிகார வரம்பைப் பயன்படுத்த முடியும். இந்த நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவை விடுவிப்பது மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான உலகளாவிய பிரகடனத்தின் 7 மற்றும் 8 ஆவது சரத்துக்களுக்கு நேரடியாக முரணானது என கொழும்பு பேராயர் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு பேராயர் ஷம்மில் பெரேரா பி.சி. (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னிரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஏப்ரல் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பேராயர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 126",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 35",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகளின் உலகளாவிய பிரகடனம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷம்மில் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}