{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83596/srilankan-employees-withdraw-from-silk-route-lounge-terminal-operations",
  "time_ut": 1657606620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SriLankan employees withdraw from Silk Route Lounge terminal operations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SriLankan employees withdraw from Silk Route Lounge terminal operations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "SriLankan Nidahas Sewaka Sangamaya (SLNSS) has decided to walk away from operations at the CIP operations at Silk Route Lounge of the Bandaranaike International Airport in Katunayake.",
        "Their trade union action is effective from 12 noon today (July 12) until further notice.",
        "The union said it decided to withdraw services after taking into account the attempts of high-ranking officials, who are responsible for the ongoing crisis, to leave the country.",
        "The president of the union Janaka Vijayapathiratne said SriLankan employees will have to face public outrage if services are provided to such public figures.",
        "Meanwhile, the Immigration & Emigration Department’s officers attached to the Silk Route Lounge, which provides dedicated services to the VIPs at the airport, have also withdrawn their services.",
        "Early this morning, former Minister Basil Rajapaksa attempted to leave the country, however, he was forced to turn back after the Immigration & Emigration Officers’ Association members at the BIA declined to serve him at the VIP departure lounge.",
        "The chairman of the association told Reuters that the immigration & emigration officers are under tremendous pressure to not allow top-level figures to leave the country, given the prevailing crisis situation.",
        "“We are concerned for our security. So, until this issue is resolved, the immigration officials working at the VIP lounge decided to withdraw their services,” he said further."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SriLankan",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Silk Route Lounge",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Nidahas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sewaka Sangamaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNSS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Silk Route Lounge",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janaka Vijayapathiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Immigration & Emigration Department’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Silk Route Lounge",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration & Emigration Officers’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Silk Route Lounge පර්යන්ත මෙහෙයුම් වලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකන් සේවකයින් ඉවත් වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කටුනායක බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ සේද මාර්ග විවේකාගාරයේ CIP මෙහෙයුම්වල මෙහෙයුම්වලින් ඉවත් වීමට ශ්‍රීලංකන් නිදහස් සේවක සංගමය (SLNSS) තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ වෘත්තීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය අද (ජුලි 12) මධ්‍යහන 12 සිට නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයට වගකිව යුතු ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් රට හැර යාමට දරන උත්සාහය සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන සේවා ඉවත් කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කළ බව එම සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "එම සංගමයේ සභාපති ජනක විජයපතිරත්න කියා සිටියේ මෙවැනි ප්‍රසිද්ධ පුද්ගලයින්ට සේවා ලබා දෙන්නේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකන් සේවකයින්ට මහජන කෝපයට ලක්වීමට සිදුවන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ප්‍රභූවරුන් සඳහා කැපවූ සේවා සපයන සේද මාර්ග විවේකාගාරයට අනුයුක්ත ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් ද සිය සේවාවන් ඉවත් කර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අද අලුයම හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පිටවීමට උත්සාහ කළද, BIA හි ආගමන හා විගමන නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමයේ සාමාජිකයින් ඔහුට ප්‍රභූ පිටත්වීමේ විවේකාගාරයේ සේවය කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම නිසා ඔහුට ආපසු යාමට සිදු විය.",
        "පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය හමුවේ ඉහළ පෙළේ පුද්ගලයන්ට රට හැර යාමට ඉඩ නොදෙන ලෙස ආගමන හා විගමන නිලධාරීන් දැඩි පීඩනයකට ලක්ව සිටින බව සංගමයේ සභාපතිවරයා රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි අපේ ආරක්ෂාව ගැන සැලකිලිමත් වෙනවා. ඒ නිසා මේ ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳෙන තුරු ප්‍රභූ විවේකාගාරයේ සේවය කරන ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් ඔවුන්ගේ සේවය ඉවත් කර ගැනීමට තීරණය කළා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සේද මාර්ග විවේකාගාරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් නිදහස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේවක සංගමය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNSS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේද මාර්ග විවේකාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජානක විජයපතිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේද මාර්ග විවේකාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சில்க் ரூட் லவுஞ்ச் முனைய நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஊழியர்கள் விலகுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்டுநாயக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் சில்க் ரூட் லவுஞ்சில் உள்ள CIP நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து விலக ஸ்ரீலங்கன் நிதாஹஸ் சேவக சங்கமய (SLNSS) தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "அவர்களது தொழிற்சங்க நடவடிக்கை இன்று (ஜூலை 12) நண்பகல் 12 மணி முதல் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை அமுலில் இருக்கும்.",
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமான உயர் அதிகாரிகள் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற முயற்சித்ததை கருத்தில் கொண்டு சேவைகளை திரும்பப் பெற முடிவு செய்ததாக தொழிற்சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இவ்வாறான பொது நபர்களுக்கு சேவைகள் வழங்கப்படுமாயின் இலங்கை ஊழியர்கள் பொதுமக்களின் சீற்றத்தை எதிர்கொள்ள நேரிடும் என சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ஜனக விஜயபதிரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், விமான நிலையத்தில் உள்ள விஐபிகளுக்கு அர்ப்பணிக்கப்பட்ட சேவைகளை வழங்கும் சில்க் ரூட் லவுஞ்சில் இணைக்கப்பட்ட குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் அதிகாரிகளும் தங்கள் சேவைகளை திரும்பப் பெற்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று அதிகாலை, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற முயன்றார், எனினும், BIA இல் உள்ள குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு அதிகாரிகள் சங்க உறுப்பினர்கள் VIP புறப்படும் ஓய்வறையில் அவருக்கு சேவை செய்ய மறுத்ததை அடுத்து, அவர் திரும்பிச் செல்ல வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "தற்போது நிலவும் நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில், உயர்மட்ட பிரமுகர்கள் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற அனுமதிக்கக் கூடாது என குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு அதிகாரிகள் பாரிய அழுத்தத்தில் உள்ளதாக சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“எங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு குறித்து நாங்கள் கவலைப்படுகிறோம். எனவே, இந்த பிரச்சினை தீர்க்கப்படும் வரை, விஐபி ஓய்வறையில் பணிபுரியும் குடியேற்ற அதிகாரிகள் தங்கள் சேவைகளை திரும்பப் பெற முடிவு செய்தனர், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சில்க் ரூட் லவுஞ்ச்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Nidahas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேவக சங்கமய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்.எஸ்.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில்க் ரூட் லவுஞ்ச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நண்பகல் 12",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனக விஜயபதிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில்க் ரூட் லவுஞ்ச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}