{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/slt-mobitel-continues-nationwide-tree-planting-programs/",
  "time_ut": 1656073680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLT-MOBITEL continues nationwide tree planting programs",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLT-MOBITEL continues nationwide tree planting programs",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "As part of its countless Environmental Social Governance (ESG) programs, SLT-MOBITEL carried out tree planting initiatives in Anuradhapura and Colombo recently. Themed ‘Let’s Nourish the Country with Clean Air and Fertilizer’, SLT-MOBITEL embarked on the nationwide tree planting initiative with a pledge to improve air quality, reduce greenhouse gases and promote healthier soil for natural humidity control.",
        "The event launched in Colombo coincided with the 31st Anniversary of the Jathika Namal Uyana International Ecological Organization. H.M. Faizal Deen, Managing Director, Sat Co Lanka Technology (Pvt) Ltd. was the partner and donor of Meetrees at the event.",
        "Strengthening the initiative further, SLT-MOBITEL concluded yet another Mee Tree planting event at the Sri Maha Bodhi premises in Anuradhapura. Communities living in the Anuradhapura area received Meetrees from SLT-MOBITEL officials.",
        "SLT-MOBITEL selected the ‘Mee’ tree for the program considering its contribution to pest control, ability to be used in the production of organic manure, ability to purify the air and its use as a natural medicine. A significant feature of the tree planting program is the use of modern technology with the ‘THURU’ mobile application to monitor the progress of the project.",
        "SLT-MOBITEL firmly believes that this initiative contributes positively towards the protection of the environment and highlights the organisation’s expansion of its Environmental Social Governance (ESG) responsibilities, as it moves forward into a more connected, secure, and sustainable future.",
        "Seylan Cards to ease insurance payments with easy payment plans",
        "Luminex officially enters the stock market with a listing on CSE",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Environmental Social Governance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fertilizer’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 31st Anniversary",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.M. Faizal Deen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sat Co Lanka Technology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Maha Bodhi",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Environmental Social Governance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seylan Cards",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Luminex",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SLT-MOBITEL රටපුරා රුක් රෝපණ වැඩසටහන් දිගටම කරගෙන යයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "එහි අසංඛ්‍යාත පාරිසරික සමාජ පාලනය (ESG) වැඩසටහන්වල කොටසක් ලෙස, SLT-MOBITEL විසින් පසුගියදා අනුරාධපුරයේ සහ කොළඹදී රුක් රෝපණ වැඩසටහන් සිදු කරන ලදී. ‘පිරිසිදු වාතයෙන් සහ පොහොරවලින් රට පෝෂණය කරමු’ යන තේමාව යටතේ SLT-MOBITEL විසින් වාතයේ ගුණාත්මක බව ඉහළ නැංවීම, හරිතාගාර වායු අඩු කිරීම සහ ස්වභාවික ආර්ද්‍රතා පාලනය සඳහා සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න පසක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඥාවක් ඇතිව රටපුරා රුක් රෝපණ වැඩසටහනක් දියත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ජාතික නාමල් උයන ජාත්‍යන්තර පරිසර සංවිධානයේ 31 වැනි සංවත්සරයට සමගාමීව මෙම උත්සවය කොළඹදී ආරම්භ කෙරිණි. එච්.එම්. මෙම උත්සවයේ Meetrees හි හවුල්කරු සහ පරිත්‍යාගශීලියා ලෙස Sat Co Lanka Technology (Pvt) Ltd හි කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ෆයිසාල් ඩීන් මහතා කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "මෙම වැඩසටහන තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කරමින් SLT-MOBITEL විසින් තවත් මී රුක් රෝපණ වැඩසටහනක් අනුරාධපුර ශ්‍රී මහා බෝධි පරිශ්‍රයේ දී අවසන් කරන ලදී. අනුරාධපුර ප්‍රදේශයේ වෙසෙන ප්‍රජාවන්ට SLT-MOBITEL නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් Meetrees ලැබුණි.",
        "SLT-MOBITEL විසින් පළිබෝධ පාලනයට දක්වන දායකත්වය, කාබනික පොහොර නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා යොදා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව, වාතය පිරිසිදු කිරීමේ හැකියාව සහ ස්වභාවික ඖෂධයක් ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීම යන කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් මෙම වැඩසටහන සඳහා ‘Mee’ ගස තෝරා ගන්නා ලදී. රුක් රෝපණ වැඩසටහනේ කැපී පෙනෙන ලක්ෂණයක් වන්නේ ව්‍යාපෘතියේ ප්‍රගතිය නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා ‘THURU’ ජංගම යෙදුම සමඟ නවීන තාක්ෂණය භාවිතා කිරීමයි.",
        "SLT-MOBITEL මෙම මුලපිරීම පරිසරය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා ධනාත්මක ලෙස දායක වන බව තරයේ විශ්වාස කරන අතර එය වඩාත් සම්බන්ධිත, ආරක්ෂිත සහ තිරසාර අනාගතයක් කරා ඉදිරියට යන විට සංවිධානයේ පාරිසරික සමාජ පාලන (ESG) වගකීම් පුළුල් කිරීම ඉස්මතු කරයි.",
        "සෙලාන් කාඩ්පත් පහසු ගෙවීමේ සැලසුම් සමඟ රක්ෂණ ගෙවීම් පහසු කිරීමට",
        "ලුමිනෙක්ස් නිල වශයෙන් කොටස් වෙලඳපොලට ඇතුල් වන්නේ CSE හි ලැයිස්තුගත කරමිනි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාරිසරික සමාජ පාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොර'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 වන සංවත්සරය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එම්. ෆයිසාල් ඩීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැට් කෝ ලංකා ටෙක්නොලොජි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී මහා බෝධිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාරිසරික සමාජ පාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් කාඩ්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලුමිනෙක්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLT-MOBITEL நாடு தழுவிய மரம் நடும் திட்டங்களைத் தொடர்கிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "அதன் எண்ணற்ற சுற்றுச்சூழல் சமூக ஆளுகை (ESG) வேலைத்திட்டங்களின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, SLT-MOBITEL ஆனது அண்மையில் அனுராதபுரம் மற்றும் கொழும்பில் மரம் நடும் முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டது. ‘சுத்தமான காற்று மற்றும் உரம் மூலம் நாட்டை வளர்ப்போம்’ என்ற கருப்பொருளில், SLT-MOBITEL, காற்றின் தரத்தை மேம்படுத்தவும், பசுமை இல்ல வாயுக்களை குறைக்கவும் மற்றும் இயற்கையான ஈரப்பதத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த ஆரோக்கியமான மண்ணை மேம்படுத்தவும் உறுதிமொழியுடன் நாடு தழுவிய மரம் நடும் முயற்சியைத் தொடங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஜாதிக நாமல் உயன சர்வதேச சூழலியல் அமைப்பின் 31வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை ஒட்டி கொழும்பில் இந்த நிகழ்வு ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டது. எச்.எம். Sat Co Lanka Technology (Pvt) Ltd. இன் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் பைசல் டீன் நிகழ்வில் Meetrees இன் பங்காளியாகவும் நன்கொடையாளராகவும் இருந்தார்.",
        "இந்த முயற்சியை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்தும் வகையில், SLT-MOBITEL அனுராதபுரத்தில் உள்ள ஸ்ரீ மஹா போதி வளாகத்தில் மற்றொரு மீ மரம் நடும் நிகழ்வை நிறைவு செய்தது. அனுராதபுரம் பகுதியில் வாழும் சமூகங்கள் SLT-MOBITEL அதிகாரிகளிடம் இருந்து Meetrees பெற்றனர்.",
        "SLT-MOBITEL ஆனது பூச்சிக் கட்டுப்பாட்டுக்கான அதன் பங்களிப்பு, கரிம உரம் தயாரிப்பில் பயன்படுத்தக்கூடிய திறன், காற்றைச் சுத்திகரிக்கும் திறன் மற்றும் இயற்கை மருந்தாகப் பயன்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவற்றைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு ‘மீ’ மரத்தைத் திட்டத்திற்குத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தது. மரம் நடும் திட்டத்தின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அம்சம், திட்டத்தின் முன்னேற்றத்தைக் கண்காணிக்க ‘துரு’ மொபைல் செயலியுடன் நவீன தொழில்நுட்பத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதாகும்.",
        "SLT-MOBITEL இந்த முன்முயற்சி சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்பதில் சாதகமாகப் பங்களிக்கிறது என்று உறுதியாக நம்புகிறது.",
        "எளிதான கட்டணத் திட்டங்களுடன் காப்பீட்டுத் தொகையை எளிதாக்க செலான் கார்டுகள்",
        "லுமினெக்ஸ் CSE இல் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டு பங்குச் சந்தையில் அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக நுழைகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர்*",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுச்சூழல் சமூக நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரம்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31வது ஆண்டுவிழா",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்.எம். பைசல் தீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sat Co Lanka Technology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ மஹா போதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுச்சூழல் சமூக நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலான் அட்டைகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லுமினெக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}