{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/සොරකම්-කළ-කැබ්-රථය-මුහුණු-පොතෙන්-සොයා-ගනී/11-396603",
  "time_ut": 1661415896,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සොරකම් කළ කැබ් රථය මුහුණු පොතෙන් සොයා ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The stolen cab is traced through Facebook",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Nittambune reports that a cab that had been stolen on the 21st while parked on the road in front of Kurunegala Maliyadeva College was found again within three days through a Facebook post.",
        "The cab was found this morning (25th) while it was parked in Nittambuwa city.",
        "Mr. Ananda Gunawardena, a resident of Kurunegala, is the owner of this red Mitsubishi cab worth about 40 lakh rupees. Mr. A came with his wife and went to watch a sports match in Maliadeva College. Someone stole this cab which was parked in front of the college.",
        "On checking the CCTV camera systems installed on the main roads of Kurunegala city, it was recorded that someone was driving the vehicle on the Negombo road.",
        "Mr. Sisira Valisinghe, who works in the X-ray treatment department of Kurunegala Teaching Hospital, saw a post posted by Mr. Gunawardena on his Facebook page and displayed the same post on his Facebook page asking for help in finding the missing cab.",
        "A friend of Mr. Valisingha who had seen that post saw the stolen cab parked near the Colombo road in Nittambuwa town this morning and immediately informed Mr. Valisingha about it and then informed the owner and informed the Nittambuwa police and proceeded to take the cab into police custody.",
        "The Nittambuwa Police are conducting further investigations as to whether the person who took the stolen cab had left it or had parked it and gone on another business."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Maliyadeva College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nittambuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ananda Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mitsubishi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maliadeva College",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sisira Valisinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Valisingha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nittambuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valisingha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nittambuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Nittambuwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සොරකම් කළ කැබ් රථය මුහුණු පොතෙන් සොයා ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුරුණෑගල මලිය⁣දේව විදුහල ඉදිරිපිට මාර්ගයේ නවතා තිබියදී පසුගිය 21වන දින සොරකම් කරගෙන ගොස් තිබූ කැබ් රථයක් මුහුණු පොතේ පළ කරන ලද පොස්ටුවක් මාර්ගයෙන් දින තුනක් ඇතුළත නැවත සොයා ගැනීමට හැකිවීමේ පුවතක් නිට්ටඹුවෙන් වාර්තාවේ.",
        "නිට්ටඹුව නගරයේ නවතා තිබියදී අද (25දා) පෙරවරුවේ එම කැබ් රථය සොයා ගැනීමට හැකිවී තිබේ.",
        "කුරුණෑගල පදිංචි ආනන්ද ගුණවර්ධන මහතා රතු පැහැති මිට්ෂුබිෂි වර්ගයට අයත් රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 40 ක් පමණ වටිනා මෙම කැබ් රථයේ අයිතිකරුය. ඒ මහතා තම බිරිඳද සමඟ පැමිණ මලිය⁣දේව විදුහලේ ක්‍රීඩා තරඟයක් නැරඹීම සඳහා ගොස් සිටියදී විදුහල ඉදිරිපිට නවතා ගොස් තිබූ මෙම කැබ් රථය කිසිවකු විසින් සොරකම්  කරගෙන ගොස් ඇත.",
        "ඒ පිළිබඳව කුරුණෑගල නගරයේ ප්‍රධාන මාර්ග වල සවිකර තිබූ සීසීටීවී කැමරා පද්ධති පරීක්ෂා කර බැලීමේදි කිසිවකු එම රථය මීගමුව මාර්ගයේ පදවාගෙන යන අයුරු සටහන්ව තිබී ඇත.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා තම මුහුණු පොතේ පළ කරන ලද පෝස්ටුවක් දුටු කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ එක්ස් කිරණ ප්‍රතිකාර අංශයේ සේවය කරන සිසිර වලිසිංහ මහතා එම පෝස්ටුව මුහුණු පොතේ තම පිටුවේද ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරමින් නැතිවූ කැබ් රථය සොයා ගැනීමට උදව් ඉල්ලා තිබිණි.",
        "වලිසිංහ මහතාගේ එම පෝස්ටුව දැක තිබූ ඔහුගේ මිතුරෙකු සොරකම් කර තිබූ කැබ් රථය අද පෙරවරුවේ නිට්ටඹුව නගරයේ කොළඹ මාර්ගය අසල නවතා තිබෙනු දැක වහාම ඒ බව වලිසිංහ මහතාට දැනුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව අයිතිකරුටද දන්වා ⁣⁣නිට්ටඹුව පොලීසියට දැනුම්දී කැබ් රථය පොලිස් බාරයට ගැනීමට  කටයුතු කර තිබේ.",
        "සොරකම් කරගෙන ගිය කැබ් රථය රැගෙන ගිය පුද්ගලයා දමා ගොස් තිබුණාද නැත්නම් නවතා වෙනත් කටයුත්තකට ගොස් සිටියාද යන්න සම්බන්ධයෙන් නිට්ටඹුව පොලීසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදු කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල මලියදේව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිට්ටඹුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිට්සුබිෂි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලියදේව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිසිර වලිසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වලිසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිට්ටඹුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලිසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිට්ටඹුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිට්ටඹුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திருடப்பட்ட வண்டி பேஸ்புக் மூலம் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த 21ஆம் திகதி குருநாகல் மலியதேவ கல்லூரிக்கு முன்பாக வீதியில் நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த கெப் வண்டியொன்று கடந்த 21ஆம் திகதி திருடப்பட்ட கெப் வண்டியொன்று முகநூல் பதிவின் ஊடாக மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் மீண்டும் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதாக நிட்டம்புனே தெரிவிக்கின்றது.",
        "இன்று (25) காலை நிட்டம்புவ நகரில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருந்த வேளையில் குறித்த வண்டி கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சுமார் 40 இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான இந்த சிவப்பு நிற மிட்சுபிஷி வண்டியின் உரிமையாளர் குருநாகல் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த திரு.ஆனந்த குணவர்தன ஆவார். திரு.ஏ தனது மனைவியுடன் வந்து மலியதேவ கல்லூரியில் விளையாட்டுப் போட்டியைக் காணச் சென்றுள்ளார்.கல்லூரிக்கு முன்பாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருந்த இந்த வண்டியை யாரோ திருடிச் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "குருநாகல் நகரின் பிரதான வீதிகளில் பொருத்தப்பட்டுள்ள சிசிடிவி கமரா அமைப்புகளை சோதனையிட்ட போது நீர்கொழும்பு வீதியில் வாகனத்தை யாரோ ஓட்டிச் செல்வது பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையின் எக்ஸ்ரே சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவில் கடமையாற்றும் திரு.சிசிர வலிசிங்க தனது முகநூல் பக்கத்தில் திரு.குணவர்தன இட்ட பதிவைக் கண்டு, காணாமல் போன வண்டியைக் கண்டறிய உதவுமாறு கோரி அதே பதிவை தனது முகநூல் பக்கத்தில் காட்சிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று காலை நிட்டம்புவ நகரில் கொழும்பு வீதிக்கு அருகில் திருடப்பட்ட கெப் வண்டி நிறுத்தப்பட்டிருப்பதைக் கண்ட திரு.வலிசிங்கவின் நண்பரொருவர், உடனடியாக இதுபற்றி திரு வலிசிங்கவுக்குத் தெரியப்படுத்தியதுடன் அதன் உரிமையாளருக்கு அறிவித்து நிட்டம்புவ பொலிஸாருக்கு அறிவித்து வண்டியை பொலிஸ் காவலில் எடுத்தார். .",
        "திருடப்பட்ட கெப் வண்டியை எடுத்துச் சென்றவர் அதனை விட்டுச் சென்றாரா அல்லது அதனை நிறுத்திவிட்டு வேறு தொழிலுக்குச் சென்றாரா என்பது தொடர்பில் நிட்டம்புவ பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் மலியதேவ கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிட்டம்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிட்சுபிஷி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலியதேவா கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிசிர வலிசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வலிசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிட்டம்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலிசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிட்டம்புவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிட்டம்புவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}