{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/sri-lankan-fishermen-continue-protests-for-kerosene/",
  "time_ut": 1661510640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan Fishermen continue protests for Kerosene",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Fishermen continue protests for Kerosene",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan fishermen are continuing protests demanding Kerosene to power their boats.",
        "The protest by fishermen in the fishing town of Chilaw in Sri Lanka's western coast, north of Colombo continues to protest demanding relief for Kerosene Purchases for the 11th day.",
        "Many fishermen have been compelled to abandon their trade and search for other means of employment.",
        "However, Fisheries Minister Douglas Devananda said a subsidy will be awarded for fisherfolk from the Interim Budget that will be presented next week.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake released from Colombo prison on ‘Conditional Presidential Pardon’"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerosene",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerosene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chilaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 11th day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Interim Budget",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "භූමිතෙල් ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ධීවරයෝ අඛණ්ඩ විරෝධතාවල නිරත වෙති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ධීවරයින් තම යාත්‍රා බල ගැන්වීම සඳහා භූමිතෙල් ඉල්ලා අඛණ්ඩව විරෝධතා පවත්වයි.",
        "භූමිතෙල් මිලදී ගැනීම් සඳහා සහන ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බටහිර වෙරළ තීරයේ හලාවත ධීවර නගරයේ ධීවරයින් විසින් 11 වන දිනටත් විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වේ.",
        "බොහෝ ධීවරයින්ට තම වෙළඳාම අත්හැර වෙනත් රැකියා මාර්ග සෙවීමට බල කෙරී ඇත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ලබන සතියේ ඉදිරිපත් කෙරෙන අතුරු අයවැයෙන් ධීවරයින් සඳහා සහනාධාරයක් ලබා දෙන බව ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "‘කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව’ මත රන්ජන් රාමනායක කොළඹ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "භූමිතෙල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "භූමිතෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භලාවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධීවර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරු අයවැය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மண்ணெண்ணெய் கேட்டு இலங்கை மீனவர்கள் தொடர்ந்து போராட்டம் நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை மீனவர்கள் தங்களது படகுகளுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் வழங்கக் கோரி தொடர்ந்து போராட்டம் நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "மண்ணெண்ணெய் கொள்முதலுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்கக் கோரி இலங்கையின் மேற்குக் கரையோரப் பகுதியான சிலாபத்தில் மீனவர்கள் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள போராட்டம் 11ஆவது நாளாக தொடர்கிறது.",
        "பல மீனவர்கள் தங்கள் தொழிலை கைவிட்டு வேறு வேலை தேடும் நிலைக்கு தள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அடுத்த வாரம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் இருந்து மீனவர்களுக்கு மானியம் வழங்கப்படும் என கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு சிறையிலிருந்து ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க ‘நிபந்தனைக்குட்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பில்’ விடுதலை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மண்ணெண்ணெய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்ணெண்ணெய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மீன்வளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}