{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/video/இன்று-ஜனாதிபதி-தெரிவு-முந்தப்போவது-யார்-LIVE/52-300764",
  "time_ut": 1658284218,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இன்று ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு: முந்தப்போவது யார்? (LIVE)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Presidential Election Today: Who Will Win? (LIVE)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country due to the country's insurgency, which plunged him into severe economic crisis. Ranil Wickramasinghe took over as interim president.",
        "In this case, the election to choose the new president will be held today, Wednesday. The names of Ranil Wickramasinghe, Dallas Alagamperuma and Anurakumara Dissanayake have been proposed in Parliament for the post.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, who was in the race for the post of President, has said that he will not contest for the post and has proposed the name of Dulles Beauty.",
        "Dallas Alagamperuma, 63, has held ministerial responsibilities since 2005. Another candidate, 53-year-old Anurakumara Dissanayake, belongs to the People's Liberation Front.",
        "This type of election of the President by Parliament is unprecedented since 1978. In 1982, 88, 94, 99 and in 2005, 2010, 2015 and 2019, the country has elected the President by popular vote.",
        "DB Wijetunga was unanimously elected by Parliament to fill the position left vacant in 1993 when then President Ranasinghe Premadasa was assassinated. After that, the President is to be elected by a vote in the Parliament.",
        "It is worth noting that the new president to be elected today will hold office until November 2024, the remaining term of Gotabaya Rajapaksa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Will Win",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today, Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Beauty",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alagamperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "53-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "94",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණය අද: දිනන්නේ කවුද? (සජීවි)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ ඇති වූ කැරැල්ල හේතුවෙන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පලා ගිය අතර, එය ඔහු දැඩි ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට ඇද දැමීය. අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපති ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩ භාර ගත්තේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේ මැතිවරණය අද බදාදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි. ඒ සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ඩලස් අලගම්පෙරුම සහ අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් යෝජනා වී තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණ සටනේ සිටි විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා එම තනතුරට තරඟ නොකරන බව පවසා ඩලස් බියුටිගේ නම යෝජනා කර තිබේ.",
        "63 හැවිරිදි ඩලස් අලගම්පෙරුම මහතා 2005 වසරේ සිට අමාත්‍ය ධුර දරයි. තවත් අපේක්ෂකයෙකු වන 53 හැවිරිදි අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක අයත් වන්නේ මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණටයි.",
        "1978 න් පසු පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආකාරයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයකි. 1982, 88, 94, 99 සහ 2005, 2010, 2015 සහ 2019 යන වසරවලදී රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් තෝරාගෙන ඇත.",
        "1993 වසරේ එවකට ජනාධිපති රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඝාතනය වීමත් සමඟ හිස් වූ තනතුර සඳහා ඩී.බී විජේතුංග මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ඒකමතිකව තේරී පත් විය. ඉන් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "අද තේරී පත්වන නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉතිරි ධුර කාලය වන 2024 නොවැම්බර් දක්වා ධූරයේ කටයුතු කරන බව සඳහන් කිරීම වටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දිනයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද, බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලංකාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගම්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "53 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "94",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு: முந்தப்போவது யார்? (LIVE)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித்தவிக்கும் நாட்டு மக்கள் கிளர்ச்சியால், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார். இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பொறுப்பேற்றார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான தேர்தல் இன்று புதன்கிழமை நடைபெறவுள்ளது. இப்பதவிக்காக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, டலஸ் அழகம்பெரும மற்றும் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான போட்டியில் இருந்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ, தாம் அப்பதவிக்காக போட்டியிடப் போவதில்லை என்றுகூறி, டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும பெயரை முன்மொழிந்துள்ளார்.",
        "63 வயதாகும் டலஸ் அழகம்பெரும, 2005 முதல் அமைச்சர் பொறுப்புகளை வகித்தவர். மற்றொரு வேட்பாளரான 53 வயதாகும் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியைச் சேர்ந்தவர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இதுபோன்று ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பது 1978-க்குப் பிறகு இதுவரை நடந்திராத ஒன்று. 1982, 88, 94, 99 மற்றும் 2005, 2010, 2015, 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டுகளில் மக்கள் வாக்களித்தே நாட்டில் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு நடந்திருக்கிறது.",
        "1993-இல் அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாஸ கொல்லப்பட்டபோது வெற்றிடமான பதவிக்கு DB Wijetunga நாடாளுமன்றத்தால் ஒருமனதாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். அதன் பிறகு இப்போதே பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட இருக்கிறார்.",
        "இன்று தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட உள்ள புதிய ஜனாதிபதி, கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக் காலமான 2024 நவம்பர் மாதம் வரை பதவியில் இருப்பார் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெற்றி பெறும்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று, புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகம்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "53 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "94",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}