{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/තවත්-188ක්-අද-කොරියාවට-යයි/11-394926",
  "time_ut": 1656413070,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තවත් 188ක් අද කොරියාවට යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another 188 are leaving for Korea today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "188 Sri Lankans contracted for Korean jobs are scheduled to leave for South Korea tonight (2022.06.28). This is the 721st group to leave for South Korea.",
        "Manusha Nanayakkara, Minister of Labor and Foreign Employment, in a recent discussion with Lee Chu Chul, Resident Representative of the Department of Human Resources in Korea, focused on sending 5800 Sri Lankans to Korea for employment in six months. As a result, employment agreements are being signed soon and Sri Lankans are being deported to South Korea.",
        "South Korea is recruiting people for Korean jobs in accordance with the diplomatic agreement signed between Sri Lanka and South Korea, and the Sri Lanka Bureau of Foreign Employment is expediting the recruitment process after receiving the relevant agreements. Despite some delays in recruitment and recruitment for foreign employment during the Kovid epidemic, the Bureau's continued work with the Korean government has led to an increase in the recruitment of workers for Korean jobs."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "188",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Korea",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "188",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "721st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lee Chu Chul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Human Resources",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Bureau of Foreign Employment",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kovid",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවත් 188ක් අද කොරියාවට යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා ගිවිසුම් හිමි වූ ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් 188 දෙනෙකු අද දින (2022.06.28) රාත්‍රියේ දකුණු කොරියාව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතයි. මෙම කණ්ඩායම දකුණු කොරියාව බලා පිටත්ව යන 721 වන කණ්ඩායමයි.",
        "කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍ය මනුෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා පසුගියදා කොරියානු මානව සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ මෙරට නේවාසික නියෝජිත ලී චූ චුල් මහතා සමග සිදුකළ සාකච්ඡාවේදී මාස 6ක් තුළ ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් 5800 දෙනෙකු කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා පිටත්කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානය යොමුකරන ලදී. එහි ප්‍රථිඵලයක් ලෙස කඩිනමින් රැකියා ගිවිසුම් අත්සන් කර ශ්‍රි ලාංකිකයින් දකුණු  කොරියාවට පිටත්කිරිමට කටයුතු කරමින් පවතී.",
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකාව හා දකුණු කොරියාව අතර අත්සන් කෙරුණු රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික ගිවිසුම අනුව කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා පුද්ගලයින් ගෙන්වා ගැනීම දකුණු කොරියාව විසින් සිදුකරන අතර, ශ්‍රි ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශයට අදාල ගිවිසුම් ලැබීමෙන් අනතුරුව රැකියා ලාභීන් යොමුකිරීමේ කටයුතු කඩිනමින් සිදුකරමින් සිටියි. කොවිඩ් වසංගතය සමයේ විදේශ රැකියා සඳහා ගෙන්වාගැනීමේ හා බඳවාගැනීම්වල යම් ප්‍රමාදයක් සිදුවුවද, කොරියානු රජය සමග කාර්යාංශය අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කිරීම හේතුවෙන් කොරියානු රැකියා සඳහා ශ්‍රමිකයින් ගෙන්වාගැනීම් වර්ධනය වෙමින් තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "188",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොරියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "188",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "721 වැනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලී චුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேலும் 188 பேர் இன்று கொரியா செல்கிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கு ஒப்பந்தம் செய்யப்பட்ட 188 இலங்கையர்கள் இன்று (2022.06.28) இரவு தென் கொரியாவுக்குச் செல்ல உள்ளனர். தென் கொரியாவுக்கு புறப்படும் 721வது குழு இதுவாகும்.",
        "தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார, கொரியாவில் உள்ள மனிதவளத் திணைக்களத்தின் வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி Lee Chu Chul உடனான சமீபத்திய கலந்துரையாடலில், ஆறு மாதங்களில் 5800 இலங்கையர்களை கொரியாவுக்கு வேலைக்காக அனுப்புவது குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தினார். இதனையடுத்து, விரைவில் வேலைவாய்ப்பு ஒப்பந்தங்கள் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்டு, இலங்கையர்கள் தென்கொரியாவுக்கு நாடு கடத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் தென்கொரியாவுக்கும் இடையில் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்டுள்ள இராஜதந்திர ஒப்பந்தத்தின் பிரகாரம் தென்கொரியா கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கு ஆட்களை ஆட்சேர்ப்பு செய்துவருவதுடன், இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம் உரிய உடன்படிக்கைகளை பெற்றுக்கொண்டதன் பின்னர் ஆட்சேர்ப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை துரிதப்படுத்துகிறது. கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய்களின் போது வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பிற்கான ஆட்சேர்ப்பு மற்றும் ஆட்சேர்ப்புகளில் சில தாமதங்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், கொரிய அரசாங்கத்துடன் பணியகம் தொடர்ந்து பணியாற்றுவது கொரிய வேலைகளுக்கான பணியாளர்களை ஆட்சேர்ப்பு செய்ய வழிவகுத்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "188",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொரியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "188",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "721வது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீ சு சுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதவளத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}