{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/07/cope-concerned-over-litro-gas-tender/",
  "time_ut": 1657187580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "COPE concerned over Litro Gas tender",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "COPE concerned over Litro Gas tender",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) recommended investigating the cancellation of the gas tender given to Siam Gas Company Limited and opting to purchase gas at a higher price.",
        "COPE chaired by (Prof) Charitha Herath recommended that an investigation be conducted through the Auditor General’s Department on the cancellation of the Term Tender, which had been approved by the Cabinet to buy gas from Siam Gas at USD 96 per metric ton and opting to buy 100,000 MT of gas for USD 129 per metric ton from an Oman company.",
        "This recommendation was given recently (05) when Litro Gas Lanka Ltd, Litro Gas Terminal Lanka (Private) Limited, and Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation were summoned before COPE to implement the orders given by the previous Committee on Public Enterprises and to discuss the current performance.",
        "It was disclosed that since the Term tender for the purchase of gas ended last February, tenders were invited for 2,80,000 MT of gas and three gas suppliers have submitted bids accordingly. Siam gas Company has submitted the lowest price as USD 96 per metric ton and accordingly, the Cabinet has approved the award of the tender.",
        "The Litro officials disclosed that gas could not be obtained from Siam gas Company due to the economic crisis as banks in Sri Lanka were unable to submit the Stand by Letter of Credit (SBLC) to Litro as per the conditions announced during the bidding process.",
        "They further said that despite discussions with the concerned company in this regard, the company expressed its unwillingness to supply gas without a Stand by Letter of Credit (SBLC) as per the conditions presented during the tender invitation.",
        "Due to this delay, as a temporary solution, Siam gas Company itself has negotiated to obtain 15,000 MT of gas as emergency purchases, which is the gross amount of gas required for two weeks, but it has been informed that they can supply only 6600 MT and thus was unsuccessful.",
        "Litro officials also said that the Oman company, which had sent prices at USD 129 per metric ton for the Term Tender, agreed to provide 100,000 MT of gas for 4 months at 25,000 MT per month.",
        "Accordingly, after notifying the above facts to the cabinet, it was revealed that the term tender given to Siam gas Company was canceled and the cabinet approval was received for the term tender to purchase 100,000 MT of gas from the Omani company. A USD 70 million loan from the World Bank and 20 million from Litro Gas Lanka Ltd amounting to USD 90 million in total was used for this procurement, Mr. Muditha Peiris, Chairman of Litro Lanka said.",
        "The COPE chair instructed the Auditor General’s Department to conduct a formal investigation and report whether the loan amount of USD 70 million from the World Bank was effectively used, and added that although the need for gas is a necessary emergency, buying from the Omani company at a higher price instead of the lowest bidder, Siam, may set a bad precedent in the future.",
        "The committee also focused on the inability to purchase gas with the amount of USD 160 million allocated for the purchase of gas under the Indian Credit Line. The Litro chairman said that according to the conditions of the Indian government, it is a problem to buy gas that is not produced in the country. It was also revealed that several rounds of discussions have been held regarding this. The COPE Chairman recommended to the Secretary to the Ministry of Finance to look into this immediately and report within two weeks.",
        "Attention was also drawn to the fact that the number of currently appointed members of Litro’s board of directors is only 4. It was revealed that according to the legal status, there should be 5 members. Furthermore, since the Ministry of Finance appoints the members of the Board of Directors, COPE pointed out the need to appoint the Board of Directors to consist of representatives of the parent company. The COPE Chairman recommended the Secretary to the Ministry of Finance take necessary measures in this regard.",
        "It was also discussed holding both the positions of the company’s Chairman and Chief Executive Officer by the same person. Even if the position of the company’s chairman changes, the presence of a permanent chief executive officer position is essential for the good survival of the company, so the committee emphasized the importance of working towards it as soon as possible. Furthermore, Litro Chairman said that the Board of Directors has already decided to deal with this situation as soon as this crisis is resolved. The committee recommended taking the necessary steps and submitting a report in this regard.",
        "Litro Company’s ability to obtain financial support from Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation, the parent company of the Litro Company was also looked into. The Chairman of the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation, Mr. Vijitha Herath, said that the company was able to purchase gas in the past due to the deposit of nearly 5 billion rupees in a state bank.",
        "Representing the Secretary of the Ministry of Finance, Saman Fernando. Deputy Secretary to the Treasury, Chairman of the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation, former Litro Chairman Vijitha Herath, and Litro Chairman Muditha Peiris were present at this meeting whilst Thesara Jayawardane, former chairman of Litro Company, joined online.",
        "Parliamentarians Patali Champika Ranawaka, Mahindananda Aluthgamage, Anura Dissanayaka, (Dr.) Harsha de Silva, (Dr.) Sarath Weerasekera, Jagath Pushpakumara, Indika Anuruddha, S.M Marikkar, Jayantha Samaraweera, (Dr.) Nalaka Godahewa, Premnath C. Dolawatte, and Madhuri Withanage were present at the meeting held."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Litro Gas",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas Company Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Term Tender",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Terminal Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Siam gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Term Tender",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 90 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USD 160 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Credit Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Company’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Litro Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thesara Jayawardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians Patali Champika Ranawaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jagath Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika Anuruddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godahewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premnath C. Dolawatte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madhuri Withanage",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ටෙන්ඩරය ගැන කෝප් කමිටුවේ අවධානය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සීමාසහිත සියම් ගෑස් සමාගමට ලබාදී ඇති ගෑස් ටෙන්ඩරය අවලංගු කිරීම සහ වැඩි මිලකට ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට තෝරා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කරන ලෙස පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (කෝප්) නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "සියාම් ගෑස් සමාගමෙන් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට ඩොලර් 96 බැගින් මිල දී ගැනීමට සහ මිලදී ගැනීමට තීරණය කර තිබූ කාලීන ටෙන්ඩරය අවලංගු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හරහා පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස (මහාචාර්ය) චරිත හේරත් මහතාගේ සභාපතිත්වයෙන් යුත් කෝප් කමිටුව නිර්දේශ කළේය. Oman සමාගමකින් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට USD 129කට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක්.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්, ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ටර්මිනල් ලංකා (පෞද්ගලික) සමාගම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉන්ෂුවරන්ස් කෝපරේෂන් යන ආයතන පසුගිය පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව ලබා දුන් නියෝග ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහ වත්මන් කාර්ය සාධනය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම නිර්දේශය පසුගියදා (05) ලබාදී ඇත. .",
        "පසුගිය පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමේ ටෙන්ඩරය අවසන් වූ බැවින් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 2,80,000ක් සඳහා ටෙන්ඩර් කැඳවා තිබූ අතර ඒ අනුව ගෑස් සැපයුම්කරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු ලංසු ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බවද අනාවරණය විය. සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට ඩොලර් 96ක් ලෙස අඩුම මිල ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති අතර ඒ අනුව ටෙන්ඩරය ප්‍රදානය කිරීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ලංසු තැබීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේදී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද කොන්දේසිවලට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බැංකුවලට ණයවර ලිපිය (SBLC) ලිට්‍රෝ වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නොහැකි වූ බැවින් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් සියම් ගෑස් සමාගමෙන් ගෑස් ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ බව ලිට්‍රෝ නිලධාරීන් අනාවරණය කළේය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදාළ සමාගම සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළද ටෙන්ඩර් කැඳවීමේදී ඉදිරිපත් කළ කොන්දේසිවලට අනුව ණයවර ලිපියක් නොමැතිව (SBLC) ගෑස් සැපයීමට සමාගම අකැමැති බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවද ඔවුහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසූහ.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රමාදය හේතුවෙන් තාවකාලික විසඳුමක් ලෙස සති දෙකකට අවශ්‍ය දළ ගෑස් ප්‍රමාණය වන ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000ක් හදිසි මිලදී ගැනීම් ලෙස ලබා ගැනීමට සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම විසින්ම සාකච්ඡා කර ඇතත් ඔවුන්ට සැපයිය හැක්කේ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 6600ක් පමණක් බව දන්වා ඇත. එබැවින් අසාර්ථක විය.",
        "ටර්ම් ටෙන්ඩරය සඳහා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට ඩොලර් 129 බැගින් මිල ගණන් එවූ ඕමාන් සමාගම මසකට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 25,000 බැගින් මාස 4කට ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් ලබාදීමට එකඟ වූ බවද ලිට්‍රෝ නිලධාරීහු පැවසූහ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඉහත කරුණු කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට දැනුම් දීමෙන් පසු සියම් ගෑස් සමාගමට ලබාදී තිබූ වාර ටෙන්ඩරය අවලංගු කර ඕමාන සමාගමෙන් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් මිලදී ගැනීමේ ටෙන්ඩරය සඳහා කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය හිමිවූ බව අනාවරණය විය. මෙම ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සඳහා ලෝක බැංකුවෙන් ඇ.ඩො. මිලියන 70ක ණය මුදලක් සහ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගමෙන් මිලියන 20ක ණය මුදලක් ඇ.ඩො. මිලියන 90ක් යොදවා ඇති බව ලිට්‍රෝ ලංකා සමාගමේ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලෝක බැංකුවෙන් ලබාදුන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 ක ණය මුදල ඵලදායී ලෙස භාවිත කළේ දැයි විධිමත් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා වාර්තා කරන ලෙස කෝප් සභාපතිවරයා විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට උපදෙස් දුන් අතර ගෑස් අවශ්‍යතාවය හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාවක් වුවද ඕමාන සමාගමෙන් මිලදී ගැනීම අඩුම ලංසුකරු වන සියාම් වෙනුවට ඉහළ මිලක් අනාගතයේදී නරක පූර්වාදර්ශයක් විය හැක.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය රේඛාව යටතේ ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා වෙන් කර ඇති ඩොලර් මිලියන 160 ක මුදලින් ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට නොහැකි වීම පිළිබඳව ද කමිටුවේ අවධානය යොමු විය. ලිට්රෝ සභාපතිවරයා පැවසුවේ ඉන්දීය රජයේ කොන්දේසි අනුව මෙරට නිෂ්පාදනය නොකරන ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම ගැටලුවක් බවයි. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් පවත්වා ඇති බවද අනාවරණය විය. මේ පිළිබඳව වහා සොයා බලා සති දෙකක් ඇතුළත වාර්තා කරන ලෙස කෝප් සභාපතිවරයා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයාට නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ දැනට පත් කර ඇති සාමාජිකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව 4ක් පමණක් වීම පිළිබඳව ද අවධානය යොමු විය. නීතිමය තත්ත්වය අනුව සාමාජිකයන් 5 දෙනෙකු සිටිය යුතු බව මෙහිදී අනාවරණය විය. තවද, අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින් පත් කරනු ලබන්නේ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් බැවින්, අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය මව් සමාගමේ නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වන පරිදි පත්කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව කෝප් කමිටුව පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස කෝප් සභාපතිවරයා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයාට නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "සමාගමේ සභාපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී යන තනතුරු දෙකම එකම පුද්ගලයකු විසින් දැරීම පිළිබඳව ද සාකච්ඡා විය. සමාගමේ සභාපති තනතුර වෙනස් වුවද සමාගමේ යහපත් පැවැත්ම සඳහා ස්ථිර ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරි තනතුරක් තිබීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන බැවින් හැකි ඉක්මනින් ඒ සඳහා ක්‍රියා කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම කමිටුව අවධාරණය කළේය. තවද, ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපතිවරයා පැවසුවේ, මෙම අර්බුදය සමථයකට පත් වූ වහාම මෙම තත්ත්වයට මුහුණ දීමට අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය දැනටමත් තීරණය කර ඇති බවයි. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගෙන වාර්තාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස එම කමිටුව නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ මව් සමාගම වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉන්ෂුවරන්ස් කෝපරේෂන් වෙතින් ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමට මූල්‍ය සහය ලබා ගැනීමට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳව ද සොයා බලන ලදී. ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්‍ෂණ සංස්ථාවේ සභාපති විජිත හේරත් මහතා පැවසුවේ රුපියල් බිලියන 5කට ආසන්න මුදලක් රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවක තැන්පත් කිරීම හේතුවෙන් සමාගමට පසුගිය කාලයේ ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට හැකි වූ බවයි.",
        "ඒ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් සමන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා නියෝජනය කරමින්. මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ නියෝජ්‍ය ලේකම්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාවේ සභාපති, ලිට්‍රෝ හිටපු සභාපති විජිත හේරත්, සහ ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් යන මහත්වරු මෙම හමුවට එක්ව සිටි අතර ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ හිටපු සභාපති තෙසර ජයවර්ධන අන්තර්ජාලයට එක්විය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක, මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ, අනුර දිසානායක, (ආචාර්ය) හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා, (ආචාර්ය) සරත් වීරසේකර, ජගත් පුෂ්පකුමාර, ඉන්දික අනුරුද්ධ, එස්. එම් මරික්කාර්, ජයන්ත සමරවීර, (වෛද්‍ය) දොලව් සී. සහ මධුරි විතානගේ යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් මෙම රැස්වීමට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර ටෙන්ඩරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස් පර්යන්තය ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්යාපාර පිළිබඳ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,80,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර ටෙන්ඩරය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 160 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ණය රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 5 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙසර ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජගත් පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික අනුරුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරික්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේම්නාත් සී දොලවත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධුරි විතානගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெண்டர் குறித்து கோப் கவலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சியாம் காஸ் கம்பெனி லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்திற்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட எரிவாயு டெண்டரை ரத்து செய்து, அதிக விலைக்கு எரிவாயுவை வாங்குவது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்த பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு (கோப்) பரிந்துரைத்தது.",
        "(பேராசிரியர்) சரித ஹேரத் தலைமையிலான கோப், சியாம் கேஸ் நிறுவனத்திடமிருந்து ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு 96 அமெரிக்க டொலர்களுக்கு எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்து கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு அமைச்சரவையினால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட கால டெண்டரை ரத்து செய்தமை தொடர்பில் கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடாக விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டுமென சிபாரிசு செய்தது. ஓமன் நிறுவனத்திடமிருந்து ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு USD 129க்கு 100,000 MT எரிவாயு.",
        "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட், லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா இன்சூரன்ஸ் கார்ப்பரேஷன் ஆகியவை கோப் முன் அழைக்கப்பட்டபோது, ​​பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான முந்தைய குழு வழங்கிய உத்தரவுகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தவும், தற்போதைய செயல்திறன் குறித்து விவாதிக்கவும் சமீபத்தில் (05) இந்த பரிந்துரை வழங்கப்பட்டது. .",
        "எரிவாயு கொள்முதல் செய்வதற்கான காலக்கெடு கடந்த பிப்ரவரியில் முடிவடைந்த நிலையில், 2,80,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவுக்கு டெண்டர் கோரப்பட்டு, மூன்று எரிவாயு சப்ளையர்கள் அதற்கேற்ப ஏலம் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளனர். சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம் ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு 96 அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் என மிகக் குறைந்த விலையை சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளதுடன், அதற்கமைய, டெண்டரை வழங்குவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஏலத்தின் போது அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட நிபந்தனைகளின்படி இலங்கையில் உள்ள வங்கிகள் கடன் கடிதத்தை (SBLC) Litro நிறுவனத்திற்கு சமர்ப்பிக்க முடியாததால் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து எரிவாயுவைப் பெற முடியவில்லை என்று Litro அதிகாரிகள் வெளிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "இது தொடர்பாக சம்பந்தப்பட்ட நிறுவனத்துடன் கலந்துரையாடிய போதிலும், டெண்டர் அழைப்பின் போது முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட நிபந்தனைகளின்படி, கடன் கடிதம் (SBLC) இன்றி எரிவாயு வழங்க நிறுவனம் விரும்பவில்லை என அவர்கள் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த காலதாமதத்தால் தற்காலிக தீர்வாக சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனமே 15,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவை அவசர கொள்முதலாக பெற்றுக்கொள்ள பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு தேவையான மொத்த எரிவாயு தொகையான 6600 மெட்ரிக் டன் மட்டுமே வழங்க முடியும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதனால் தோல்வியடைந்தது.",
        "டெண்டர் டெண்டருக்கு ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு 129 அமெரிக்க டாலர் என்ற விலையை அனுப்பிய ஓமன் நிறுவனம், 4 மாதங்களுக்கு 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவை மாதத்திற்கு 25,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் வழங்க ஒப்புக்கொண்டதாகவும் லிட்ரோ அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதன்படி, மேற்படி உண்மைகளை அமைச்சரவைக்கு அறிவித்ததன் பின்னர், சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனத்திற்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட கால டெண்டர் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டு, ஓமான் நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கான டெண்டருக்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் கிடைத்துள்ளது. உலக வங்கியின் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் கடனும், Litro Gas Lanka Ltd இலிருந்து 20 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களும் மொத்தமாக 90 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் இந்தக் கொள்வனவுக்காக பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டதாக Litro Lanka இன் தலைவர் திரு.முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உலக வங்கியிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் கடன் தொகை திறம்பட பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டதா என்பது குறித்து முறையான விசாரணையை நடத்தி அறிக்கை அளிக்குமாறு கோப் தலைவர் கணக்காய்வாளர் திணைக்களத்திற்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார். குறைந்த ஏலத்திற்குப் பதிலாக அதிக விலை, சியாம், எதிர்காலத்தில் மோசமான முன்னுதாரணமாக அமையலாம்.",
        "இந்திய கடன் வரியின் கீழ் எரிவாயு கொள்வனவுக்காக ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட 160 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களில் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியாத நிலை குறித்தும் குழு கவனம் செலுத்தியது. இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு அமைய நாட்டில் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படாத எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்வதே பிரச்சினை என லிட்ரோ தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இது தொடர்பில் பல சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரியவந்துள்ளது. இதனை உடனடியாக ஆராய்ந்து இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் அறிக்கை அளிக்குமாறு நிதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு கோப் தலைவர் சிபாரிசு செய்தார்.",
        "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் சபையில் தற்போது நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள உறுப்பினர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 4 மாத்திரமே எனவும் இதன்போது கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. மேலும், பணிப்பாளர் சபை உறுப்பினர்களை நிதியமைச்சகம் நியமிப்பதால், தாய் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் அடங்கிய பணிப்பாளர் சபையை நியமிக்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை கோப் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது. இது தொடர்பில் தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு கோப் தலைவர் நிதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் மற்றும் தலைமை செயல் அதிகாரி ஆகிய இரு பதவிகளையும் ஒரே நபர் வைத்திருப்பது குறித்தும் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் பதவி மாறினாலும், நிரந்தர தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி பதவி இருப்பது நிறுவனத்தின் நல்ல வாழ்வுக்கு அவசியம், எனவே விரைவில் அதை நோக்கி செயல்பட வேண்டியதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை குழு வலியுறுத்தியது. மேலும், இந்த நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணப்பட்டவுடன் இந்த நிலைமையை விரைவில் கையாள்வதற்கு பணிப்பாளர் சபை ஏற்கனவே தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக லிட்ரோ தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார். இது தொடர்பாக தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்து அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பிக்க குழு பரிந்துரைத்தது.",
        "Litro கம்பனியின் தாய் நிறுவனமான இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திடம் இருந்து Litro கம்பனியின் நிதி உதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கான திறன் குறித்தும் ஆராயப்பட்டது. இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.விஜித ஹேரத் கூறுகையில், அரச வங்கியில் சுமார் 5 பில்லியன் ரூபா வைப்புச் செய்யப்பட்டதன் காரணமாகவே கடந்த காலங்களில் எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடிந்தது.",
        "நிதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் சமன் பெர்னாண்டோவை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தினார். திறைசேரியின் பிரதிச் செயலாளர், இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தலைவர், முன்னாள் லிட்ரோ தலைவர் விஜித ஹேரத் மற்றும் லிட்ரோ தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் ஆகியோர் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டதுடன், லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் தெசர ஜயவர்தன இணையத்தில் இணைந்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க, மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே, அனுர திஸாநாயக்க, (டாக்டர்.) ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, (டாக்டர்.) சரத் வீரசேகர, ஜகத் புஷ்பகுமார, இந்திக்க அனுருத்த, எஸ்.எம் மரிக்கார், ஜயந்த சமரவீர, (டாக்டர்.) நாலக கொடஹேவா, நாலக கோதாஹேவா. மாதுரி விதானகே மற்றும் மாதுரி விதானகே ஆகியோர் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் கேஸ் கம்பெனி லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால டெண்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் வாயு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,80,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால டெண்டர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "160 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடன் வரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெசர ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜகத் புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க அனுருத்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
