{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පළාත්-රැසකට-වැසි-රහිත-කාලගුණයක්/1-615524",
  "time_ut": 1656383710,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පළාත් රැසකට වැසි රහිත කාලගුණයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No rain in many parts of the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Meteorological Department states that there will be no showers in several parts of the island today (28).",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur in the Western and Sabaragamuwa provinces and in the Kandy, Nuwara Eliya, Galle and Matara districts, a spokesman for the Department said.",
        "He added that strong winds of up to 50 kmph are expected at times in the western slopes of the central hills, in the northern, north central and northwestern provinces and in the Trincomalee and Hambantota districts."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Meteorological Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "up to 50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළාත් රැසකට වැසි රහිත කාලගුණයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ පළාත් කිහිපයක හැර සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවල අද (28) වැසි රහිත කාලගුණයක් පවතින බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත්, මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් සිහින් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවලත්, උතුරු, උතුරුමැද සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත්, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින්විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර 50 ක පමණ වේගවත් සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බව ද ඔහු කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளில் மழை இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளில் இன்று (28) மழை பெய்யாது என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும், வடக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களிலும் திருகோணமலை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}