{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/’’ස්ථාවර-රජයක්-පත්-නොකලොත්-රට-අකර්මණ්‍ය-වෙයි’’/1-616462",
  "time_ut": 1657871477,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’ස්ථාවර රජයක් පත් නොකලොත් රට අකර්මණ්‍ය වෙයි’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"If a stable government is not appointed, the country will become inactive\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe warned that if a stable government in Sri Lanka is not formed soon, the country may become dysfunctional.",
        "Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe said while participating in the BBC News Night program that there is great uncertainty whether Sri Lanka will be able to find enough foreign exchange to import fuel in the future.",
        "Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe said that the progress of the negotiations to obtain an aid program from the International Monetary Fund depends on the appointment of a stable government.",
        "Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe said that although the Central Bank will be able to provide financial facilities for at least 3 diesel ships and one or two petrol ships until the end of this month, there is great uncertainty whether it will be able to provide sufficient foreign exchange to pay for petroleum products.",
        "Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe pointed out that if sufficient foreign exchange is not found to pay for petroleum products, then a situation similar to the closure of the country may arise in Sri Lanka. Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe said that there is a need for a president, prime minister and a cabinet that can make decisions. Mr. Weerasinghe said that if there is no such mechanism, the people will have to suffer.",
        "Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe pointed out that although Sri Lanka hopes to make positive progress in the debt restructuring negotiations, it also depends on how quickly a stable government is formed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC News Night",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’ස්ථාවර රජයක් පත් නොකලොත් රට අකර්මණ්‍ය වෙයි’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාවර රජයක් ඉක්මණින් ඇති නොවූවොත් රට අකර්මණ්‍ය විය හැකි බව මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා අනතුරු ඇඟවුවේය.",
        "ඉදිරියේදී ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් විදේශ විනිමය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සොයා ගත හැකි වේ දැයි විශාල අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයක් තිබෙන බව ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා  බී.බී.සී නාලිකාවේ නිව්ස් නයිට් වැඩසටහනට සහභාගී වෙමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එහිදී ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ආධාර වැඩසටහනක් ලබා ගැනීමේ සඳහා පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡා වල ප්‍රගතිය ස්ථාවර රජයක් පත්වීම මත රඳා පවතින බව ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේය.ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාල නොසන්සුන්තාවයක් ඇති වී තිබෙන බව ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම මස අවසන් වන තෙක් අවම වශයෙන් ඩීසල් නෞකා 3කට සහ පෙට්‍රල් නෞකා එකකට හෝ දෙකකට මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් ලබා දීමට මහබැංකුවට  හැකියාව ලැබුනත් ඉන්පසු පෙට්‍රෝලියම් නිෂ්පාදන සඳහා ගෙවීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් විදේශ විනිමය ලබා දීමට හැකිවේදැයි විශාල අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයක් තිබෙන බව ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේය.",
        "පෙට්‍රෝලියම් නිෂ්පාදන සඳහා ගෙවීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් විදේශ විනිමය සොයා ගත නොහැකි වුවහොත් එවිට රට වසා දැමීම හා සමාන තත්ත්වයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උද්ගත විය හැකි බව  ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේ ය.තීරණගත හැකි ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක්,අගමැතිවරයෙක් සහ කැබිනට්ටුවක් අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ එම නිසා බව ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේය.එවැනි යාන්ත්‍රණයක් නොමැති වුවහොත් ජනතාවට දුක් විඳීමට සිදුවෙනු ඇතිබව වීරසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යූහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡාවලදී ධනාත්මක ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලාපොරොත්තු වුවත් එයද රඳා පවතින්නේ කෙතරම් ඉක්මණින් ස්ථාවර රජයක් පත්වන්නේද යන සාධකය මත බව ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී ප්‍රවෘත්ති රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிலையான அரசாங்கம் அமையாவிட்டால் நாடு செயலிழந்து விடும்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் நிலையான அரசாங்கம் விரைவில் அமைக்கப்படாவிட்டால் நாடு செயலிழக்க நேரிடும் என மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க எச்சரித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு போதுமான அந்நியச் செலாவணி கிடைக்குமா என்பதில் பெரும் நிச்சயமற்ற நிலை நிலவுவதாக பிபிசி செய்தி இரவு நிகழ்ச்சியில் கலந்துகொண்டு கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் உதவித் திட்டத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளின் முன்னேற்றம் நிலையான அரசாங்கத்தை நியமிப்பதில் தங்கியுள்ளது என்று கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இலங்கையில் பெரும் அமைதியின்மை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார். இலங்கை.",
        "இம்மாத இறுதி வரை மத்திய வங்கியினால் குறைந்த பட்சம் 3 டீசல் கப்பல்கள் மற்றும் ஒன்று அல்லது இரண்டு பெற்றோல் கப்பல்களுக்கு நிதி வசதிகளை வழங்க முடியும் என்றாலும் போதியளவு அந்நிய செலாவணியை வழங்க முடியுமா என்பதில் பெரும் நிச்சயமற்ற நிலை காணப்படுவதாக கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார். பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்களுக்கு பணம் செலுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "பெற்றோலியப் பொருட்களுக்கு போதியளவு அந்நியச் செலாவணி கிடைக்காவிடில் நாடு மூடப்படும் நிலை இலங்கையிலும் ஏற்படக்கூடும் என கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.ஜனாதிபதி ஒருவர் தேவை என கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார். பிரதம மந்திரியும் முடிவெடுக்கக் கூடிய அமைச்சரவையும்.அவ்வாறான பொறிமுறை இல்லையென்றால் மக்கள் அவதிப்பட வேண்டியிருக்கும் என வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் சாதகமான முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைய இலங்கை எதிர்பார்த்தாலும், அது எவ்வளவு விரைவாக ஒரு நிலையான அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படும் என்பதிலேயே தங்கியுள்ளது என கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி செய்தி இரவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}