{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132624",
  "time_ut": 1659284388,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சீன விஞ்ஞான ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் குறித்து கடற்படைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை - கடற்படை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy not notified of Chinese scientific research vessel - Navy",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Navy Spokesperson Captain Indika de Silva told Weerakesari that the Navy has not been informed about the Chinese scientific research vessel Yuan Wang 5, which is reported to be arriving at Ambantota Port, and that he does not know enough about it.",
        "The arrival of the said Chinese ship has now sparked a new controversy in the country. It has been reported that the said Chinese ship will arrive at Ambantota port on the 11th and will be anchored there until the 17th. India announced that it had prior knowledge of the ship's arrival in Sri Lanka.",
        "India, which has expressed strong opposition to this, has requested the government to provide a complete clarification regarding the reason for the arrival of the said ship and its activities during the period when it was anchored at Ambantota port.",
        "The high level of Delhi has sent a message to Colombo that the arrival of this ship has a direct impact on India's national security issues. After India expressed displeasure about the Chinese ship, China said it hoped that the relevant parties would refrain from interfering with its legitimate maritime activities.",
        "When asked whether any information has been provided to the navy about the Chinese ship which has caused controversy, the navy spokesperson replied as above. I believe that permission for the arrival of this ship will be obtained from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Ministry of Defense and Sri Lankan Ports Authority.",
        "However, I don't know any official information about it. Tomorrow morning (this morning) we can gather information about the arrival of this ship and whether there is any connection with the Sri Lanka Navy and provide it.' Navy spokesperson Captain Indika de Silva further informed Weerakesari"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerakesari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 17th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defense and Sri Lankan Ports Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerakesari",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාව ගැන නාවික හමුදාවට දැනුම් දී නැත - නාවික හමුදාව",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "නාවික හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක කපිතාන් ඉන්දික ද සිල්වා වීරකේසරියට පැවසුවේ අඹන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන බවට වාර්තා වන චීන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාව වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පිළිබඳව නාවික හමුදාව දැනුවත් කර නොමැති බවත් ඒ පිළිබඳව තමන් ප්‍රමාණවත් නොදන්නා බවත්ය.",
        "ඉහත කී චීන නෞකාව පැමිණීම මේ වනවිට රට තුළ නව ආන්දෝලනයකට තුඩු දී තිබේ. එම චීන නෞකාව ලබන 11 වැනිදා අඹන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන බවත්, ලබන 17 වැනිදා දක්වා එහි නැංගුරම් ලෑමට නියමිත බවත් වාර්තා වේ. නෞකාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීම පිළිබඳව තමන් කලින් දැන සිටි බව ඉන්දියාව නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව මෙයට දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කර ඇති අතර එම නෞකාව අම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලා තිබූ කාලසීමාව තුළ එහි පැමිණීමට හේතුව සහ එහි ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සම්පූර්ණ පැහැදිලි කිරීමක් කරන ලෙස රජයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික ආරක්‍ෂාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙම නෞකාවේ පැමිණීම සෘජුවම බලපාන බවට දිල්ලි නුවර ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් කොළඹට පණිවිඩයක් යවා තිබේ. චීන නෞකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව අප්‍රසාදය පළ කිරීමෙන් පසු චීනය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අදාළ පාර්ශවයන් තම නීත්‍යානුකූල නාවික කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් වීමෙන් වළකිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "ආන්දෝලනයට තුඩු දී ඇති චීන නෞකාව පිළිබඳව නාවික හමුදාවට තොරතුරු ලබා දී ඇත්දැයි විමසූ විට නාවික හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පිළිතුරු දුන්නේ ඉහත ආකාරයටය. මෙම නෞකාව පැමිණීම සඳහා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන්, ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරාය අධිකාරියෙන් අවසරය ලැබෙනු ඇතැයි මම විශ්වාස කරමි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මම ඒ ගැන නිල තොරතුරු කිසිවක් නොදනිමි. හෙට උදෑසන (අද උදෑසන) මෙම නෞකාව පැමිණීම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව සමඟ සම්බන්ධයක් තිබේද යන්න පිළිබඳව තොරතුරු රැස්කර එය ලබාදිය හැකියි.' නාවික හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක කපිතාන් ඉන්දික ද සිල්වා වීරකේසරී වෙත වැඩිදුරටත් දැනුම් දුන්නේය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරකේසරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරාය අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරකේසරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன விஞ்ஞான ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் குறித்து கடற்படைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை - கடற்படை",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு வரவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படும் சீன விஞ்ஞான ஆய்வு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 தொடர்பில் கடற்படைக்கு எதுவும் அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் , அது குறித்து தனக்கு போதுமான தகவல்கள் தெரியாது என்றும் கடற்படை பேச்சாளர் கெப்டன் இந்திக டி சில்வா வீரகேசரிக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குறித்த சீன கப்பலின் வருகையானது தற்போது நாட்டில் புதிய சர்ச்சையைத் தோற்றுவித்திருக்கிறது. எதிர்வரும் 11 ஆம் திகதி அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடையவுள்ள குறித்த சீன கப்பல் , 17 ஆம் திகதி வரை அங்கு நங்கூரமிடப்பட்டிருக்கும் என்று செய்திகள் வெளியாகியுள்ளன. இந்த கப்பலின் இலங்கை வருகை தொடர்பில் தாம் முன்னரே அறிந்திருந்ததாக இந்தியா அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கு கடும் எதிர்ப்பினை வெளியிட்டுள்ள இந்தியா , குறித்த கப்பலின் வருகைக்கான காரணம் மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நங்கூரமிடப்பட்ட காலப்பகுதியில் அதன் செயற்பாடுகள் என்பன தொடர்பில் முழுமையான தெளிவுப்படுத்தலை வழங்குமாறு அரசாங்கத்திடம் கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியாவின் தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு விடயங்களில் இந்த கப்பலின் வருகை நேரடியாகவே தாக்கம் செலுத்துகின்றமையால் இந்த விடயத்தில் முழுமையான அவதானத்துடன் இருப்பதாக  கொழும்பிற்கு டெல்லி உயர் மட்டம்  தகவல் அனுப்பியுள்ளது. சீன கப்பல் தொடர்பில் இந்தியா அதிருப்தி வெளியிட்டதையடுத்து , 'தமது சட்டபூர்வமான கடல் நடவடிக்கைகளில் தலையிடுவதை சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்புக்கள் தவிர்க்கும் என்று தாம் நம்புவதாக' சீனா தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இவ்வாறு சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ள சீன கப்பல் குறித்து கடற்படைக்கு ஏதேனும் தகவல்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதா என்று வினவிய போதே , கடற்படை பேச்சாளர் மேற்கண்டவாறு பதிலளித்தார். 'இந்த கப்பலின் வருகைக்கான அனுமதி வெளிநாட்டலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு , பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு மற்றும் இலங்கை துறைமுக அதிகாரசபை என்பவற்றிடம் பெற்றுக் கொள்ளப்படும் என்று நான் எண்ணுகின்றேன்.",
        "எனினும் எனக்கு இதுகுறித்த உத்தியோகபூர்வ தகவல்கள் தெரியாது. நாளை காலை (இன்று காலை) இந்த கப்பலின் வருகைக்கும் இலங்கை கடற்படைக்கும் ஏதேனும் தொடர்புகள் உள்ளனவா என்பது குறித்த தகவல்களை சேகரித்து , அதனை வழங்க முடியும்.' என்று கடற்படை பேச்சாளர் கெப்டன் இந்திக டி சில்வா வீரகேசரிக்கு மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரகேசரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு மற்றும் இலங்கை துறைமுக அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரகேசரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}