{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78530",
  "time_ut": 1657630080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, his wife and a bodyguard  among four passengers on board an Antonov-32 military aircraft which took off from Katunayake international airport heading for the neighbouring Maldives, according to immigration sources.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, his wife and a bodyguard  among four passengers on board an Antonov-32 military aircraft which took off from Katunayake international airport heading for the neighbouring Maldives, according to immigration sources.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s embattled President flew out of his country early on Wednesday, in a probable prelude to his resignation after months of widespread protests over the island nation’s worst-ever economic crisis.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa had promised during the weekend to resign on Wednesday and clear the way for a “peaceful transition of power”, after fleeing his official residence in Colombo just before tens of thousands of protesters overran it.",
        "As President, Mr. Rajapaksa enjoys immunity from arrest, and he is believed to have wanted to go abroad before stepping down to avoid the possibility of being detained.",
        "He, his wife and a bodyguard were among four passengers on board an Antonov-32 military aircraft which took off from the main international airport heading for the neighbouring Maldives, according to immigration sources.",
        "“Their passports were stamped and they boarded the special air force flight,” an immigration official involved in the process told AFP.",
        "The departure of the 73-year-old leader once known as ‘The Terminator’ had been stymied for more than 24 hours in a humiliating stand-off with immigration personnel at the airport.",
        "He had wanted to fly to Dubai on a commercial flight, but staff at Bandaranaike International withdrew from VIP services and insisted that all passengers had to go through public counters.",
        "The presidential party were reluctant to go through regular channels fearing public reactions, a security official said, and as a result missed four flights on Monday that could have taken them to the United Arab Emirates.",
        "Clearance for a military flight to land in the closest neighbour India was not immediately secured, a security official said, and at one point on Tuesday, the group headed to a naval base with a view to fleeing by sea.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa’s youngest brother Basil, who resigned in April as finance minister, missed his own Emirates flight to Dubai early on Tuesday after a tense standoff of his own with airport staff.",
        "Basil — who holds U.S. citizenship in addition to Sri Lankan nationality — tried to use a paid concierge service for business travellers, but airport and immigration staff said they had withdrawn from the fast track service.",
        "Basil had to obtain a new U.S. passport after leaving his behind at the presidential palace when the Rajapaksas beat a hasty retreat to avoid mobs on Saturday, a diplomatic source said.",
        "Official sources said a suitcase full of documents had also been left behind at the stately mansion along with 17.85 million rupees in cash, now in the custody of a Colombo court.",
        "There was no official word from the President’s office about his whereabouts, but he remained commander-in-chief of the armed forces with military resources at his disposal.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa is accused of mismanaging the economy to a point where the country has run out of foreign exchange to finance even the most essential imports, leading to severe hardships for the 22 million population.",
        "If he steps down as promised, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe will automatically become acting President until parliament elects an MP to serve out the presidential term, which ends in November 2024.",
        "But Mr. Wickremesinghe has himself announced his willingness to step down if consensus is reached on forming a unity government.",
        "The succession process could take between three days — the minimum time taken to convene parliament — and a maximum of 30 days allowed under the statute. If Mr. Rajapaksa does step down on Wednesday, the vote would take place on July 20, the parliamentary speaker has said.",
        "The leader of the main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya party, Sajith Premadasa, who lost the 2019 presidential election to Mr. Rajapaksa, has said he will stand for the position.",
        "Mr. Premadasa is the son of former President Ranasinghe Premadasa, who was assassinated in a Tamil rebel suicide bombing in May 1993.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted on its $51-billion foreign debt in April and is in talks with the IMF for a possible bailout.",
        "The island has nearly exhausted its already scarce supplies of petrol. The government has ordered the closure of non-essential offices and schools to reduce commuting and save fuel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Katunayake international airport",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike International",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Arab Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.85 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$51-billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් අසල්වැසි මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගිය ඇන්ටනොව්-32 හමුදා ගුවන් යානයේ මගීන් හතර දෙනෙකු අතර ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂකයෙකු ද සිටින බව ආගමන විගමන ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ මෙතෙක් පැවති දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාස ගනනාවක් පුරා පැතිර ගිය විරෝධතා වලින් පසු ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ පූර්විකාවක් ලෙස, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගැටී සිටින ජනාධිපතිවරයා බදාදා අලුයම සිය රටින් පිටත් විය.",
        "දස දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් එය යටපත් කිරීමට මොහොතකට පෙර කොළඹ පිහිටි ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසින් පලා ගිය පසු, බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වී “සාමකාමී බල සංක්‍රාන්තියක්” සඳහා මාර්ගය පැහැදිලි කරන බවට ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සති අන්තයේ පොරොන්දු වී තිබුණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලෙස රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ මුක්තිය හිමි වන අතර, රඳවා තබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව වළක්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර ඔහුට විදේශගත වීමට අවශ්‍ය වී ඇතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "අසල්වැසි මාලදිවයින බලා යන ප්‍රධාන ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත් වූ ඇන්ටනොව්-32 හමුදා ගුවන් යානයේ මගීන් හතර දෙනෙකු අතර ඔහු, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂකයෙකු සිටි බව ආගමන ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "\"ඔවුන්ගේ විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර මුද්‍රා තබා ඇති අතර ඔවුන් විශේෂ ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයට ගොඩ විය,\" ක්‍රියාවලියට සම්බන්ධ ආගමන නිලධාරියෙක් AFP වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "වරක් 'The Terminator' ලෙසින් හඳුන්වනු ලැබූ 73 හැවිරිදි නායකයාගේ නික්මයාම ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන් සමඟ නින්දා සහගත ගැටුමක් තුළ පැය 24 කට වැඩි කාලයක් බාධා කර තිබුණි.",
        "ඔහුට වාණිජ ගුවන් යානයකින් ඩුබායි වෙත යාමට අවශ්‍ය වූ නමුත් බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ප්‍රභූ සේවාවන්ගෙන් ඉවත් වූ අතර සියලුම මගීන්ට පොදු කවුන්ටර හරහා යා යුතු බව අවධාරනය කළේය.",
        "මහජන ප්‍රතිචාරවලට බියෙන් ජනාධිපති පාර්ශවය සාමාන්‍ය නාලිකා හරහා යාමට මැලි වූ බවත්, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස සඳුදා දින ඔවුන් එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට ගෙන යා හැකිව තිබූ ගුවන් ගමන් හතරක් මග හැරුණු බවත් ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "ආසන්නතම අසල්වැසි ඉන්දියාවට හමුදා ගුවන් යානයක් ගොඩබෑම සඳහා නිෂ්කාශනය ක්ෂණිකව සුරක්ෂිත නොවූ බව ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරියෙකු පැවසූ අතර, අඟහරුවාදා එක් අවස්ථාවකදී, කණ්ඩායම මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් පලා යාමේ අරමුණින් නාවික කඳවුරක් වෙත ගියහ.",
        "පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූ රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ බාල සොහොයුරා වන බැසිල්ට ගුවන් තොටුපල කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සමඟ ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාවයෙන් පසු අඟහරුවාදා අලුයම ඩුබායි බලා යාමට ඔහුගේම එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් යානය මඟ හැරුණි.",
        "බැසිල් - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතිකත්වයට අමතරව එක්සත් ජනපද පුරවැසිභාවය දරයි - ව්‍යාපාරික සංචාරකයින් සඳහා ගෙවන ලද හෘදසාක්ෂික සේවාවක් භාවිතා කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ නමුත් ගුවන් තොටුපල සහ ආගමන කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය පැවසුවේ ඔවුන් වේගවත් සේවාවෙන් ඉවත් වූ බවයි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂවරු සෙනසුරාදා මැර කල්ලි වලක්වා ගැනීම සඳහා කඩිමුඩියේ පසුබැසීමට පහර දුන් විට බැසිල්ට නව එක්සත් ජනපද විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍රයක් ලබා ගැනීමට සිදු වූයේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දමා ගිය පසුව බව රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "නිල ආරංචි මාර්ග පැවසුවේ ලේඛන පිරවූ ගමන් මල්ලක් ද රුපියල් මිලියන 17.85 ක මුදල් සමඟ අතිවිශිෂ්ට මන්දිරයේ දමා ගොස් ඇති බවත්, දැන් කොළඹ අධිකරණය භාරයේ ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "ඔහු සිටින ස්ථානය ගැන ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් නිල වචනයක් නොතිබුණද, ඔහු සතු හමුදා සම්පත් සමඟ සන්නද්ධ හමුදාවන්හි සේනාධිනායකයා ලෙස සිටියේය.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාව දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවට පත් කරමින් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ආනයන සඳහා පවා විදේශ විනිමය හිඟ වී ඇති තත්ත්වයට ආර්ථිකය වැරදි ලෙස කළමනාකරණය කළ බවට රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට චෝදනා එල්ල වී තිබේ.",
        "පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි ඔහු ඉවත් වුවහොත්, 2024 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී අවසන් වන ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා තෙක් අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ස්වයංක්‍රීයව වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති බවට පත්වනු ඇත.",
        "නමුත් සමගි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකඟතාවකට පැමිණියහොත් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සූදානම් බව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින්ම ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "අනුප්‍රාප්තික ක්‍රියාවලියට දින තුනක් ගත විය හැකිය - පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීමට ගතවන අවම කාලය - සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාව යටතේ අවසර දී ඇති උපරිම දින 30 කි. රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් ඡන්ද විමසීම ජුලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වෙන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායකවරයා පවසා තිබේ.",
        "2019 ජනාධිපතිවරණයෙන් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් පරාජයට පත් වූ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය පක්ෂයේ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා එම ධූරය සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් වන බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා 1993 මැයි මාසයේදී දෙමළ කැරලිකරුවන් මරාගෙන මැරෙන බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයකින් ඝාතනය වූ හිටපු ජනාධිපති රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ පුත්‍රයාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 ක විදේශ ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හැර ඇති අතර හැකි ඇපදීමක් සඳහා IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටී.",
        "දිවයින දැනටමත් හිඟ පෙට්‍රල් සැපයුම අවසන් කර ඇත. ගමනාගමනය අවම කිරීම සහ ඉන්ධන ඉතිරි කිරීම සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය නොවන කාර්යාල සහ පාසල් වසා දැමීමට රජය නියෝග කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24 කට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17.85 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින තුනක් අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து அண்டை நாடான மாலைதீவு நோக்கி புறப்பட்ட அன்டனோவ்-32 இராணுவ விமானத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது மனைவி மற்றும் மெய்ப்பாதுகாவலர் நான்கு பேர் பயணித்துள்ளதாக குடிவரவுத்துறை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "தீவு தேசத்தின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக பல மாதங்களாக பரவலான எதிர்ப்புக்களுக்குப் பிறகு, தனது ராஜினாமாவுக்கு ஒரு முன்னோடியாக, இலங்கையின் நெருக்கடிக்குள்ளான ஜனாதிபதி புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை தனது நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முறியடிப்பதற்கு சற்று முன்னதாகவே வெளியேறிய பின்னர், புதன்கிழமை இராஜினாமா செய்து \"அமைதியான அதிகார மாற்றத்திற்கான\" வழியை தெளிவுபடுத்துவதாக கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச வார இறுதியில் உறுதியளித்திருந்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக, திரு. ராஜபக்ச கைது செய்வதிலிருந்து விலக்கு பெறுகிறார், மேலும் அவர் தடுத்து வைக்கப்படுவதைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக பதவி விலகுவதற்கு முன் வெளிநாடு செல்ல விரும்பியதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "அண்டை நாடான மாலத்தீவுக்கு செல்லும் பிரதான சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து புறப்பட்ட அன்டோனோவ்-32 இராணுவ விமானத்தில் நான்கு பயணிகளில் அவரும் அவரது மனைவியும் ஒரு மெய்க்காப்பாளரும் அடங்குவதாக குடியேற்ற வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "\"அவர்களின் கடவுச்சீட்டுகள் முத்திரையிடப்பட்டு அவர்கள் சிறப்பு விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் ஏறினர்,\" என்று செயல்பாட்டில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த குடிவரவு அதிகாரி AFP இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "ஒரு காலத்தில் 'தி டெர்மினேட்டர்' என்று அழைக்கப்பட்ட 73 வயதான தலைவரின் புறப்பாடு விமான நிலையத்தில் குடியேற்றப் பணியாளர்களுடன் அவமானகரமான நிலையில் 24 மணி நேரத்திற்கும் மேலாக தடைபட்டது.",
        "அவர் ஒரு வணிக விமானத்தில் துபாய்க்கு பறக்க விரும்பினார், ஆனால் பண்டாரநாயக்கா இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஊழியர்கள் விஐபி சேவைகளில் இருந்து விலகி, அனைத்து பயணிகளும் பொது கவுண்டர்கள் வழியாக செல்ல வேண்டும் என்று வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கட்சி பொது எதிர்வினைகளுக்கு பயந்து வழக்கமான சேனல்களில் செல்ல தயங்கியது, ஒரு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரி கூறினார், இதன் விளைவாக திங்களன்று நான்கு விமானங்களை தவறவிட்டார், அது அவர்களை ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸுக்கு அழைத்துச் சென்றிருக்கலாம்.",
        "நெருங்கிய அண்டை நாடான இந்தியாவில் இராணுவ விமானம் தரையிறங்குவதற்கான அனுமதி உடனடியாக கிடைக்கவில்லை, ஒரு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரி கூறினார், செவ்வாயன்று ஒரு கட்டத்தில், குழு கடல் வழியாக தப்பிச் செல்லும் நோக்கில் கடற்படை தளத்திற்குச் சென்றது.",
        "ஏப்ரலில் நிதியமைச்சர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்த திரு. ராஜபக்சேவின் இளைய சகோதரர் பசில், விமான நிலைய ஊழியர்களுடனான தனது சொந்த முரண்பாட்டின் பின்னர் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை அதிகாலை தனது சொந்த எமிரேட்ஸ் விமானத்தை துபாய்க்கு தவறவிட்டார்.",
        "பசில் - இலங்கை குடியுரிமைக்கு மேலதிகமாக அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமை பெற்றவர் - வணிகப் பயணிகளுக்கு பணம் செலுத்தும் வரவேற்பு சேவையைப் பயன்படுத்த முயன்றார், ஆனால் விமான நிலைய மற்றும் குடிவரவு ஊழியர்கள் விரைவுப் பாதை சேவையிலிருந்து விலகிவிட்டதாகக் கூறினர்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று கும்பல் கும்பலைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக ராஜபக்சக்கள் அவசரமாக பின்வாங்கியபோது பசில் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் அவரை விட்டுச் சென்ற பின்னர் புதிய அமெரிக்க பாஸ்போர்ட்டைப் பெற வேண்டியிருந்தது என்று இராஜதந்திர வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "17.85 மில்லியன் ரூபா பணத்துடன், தற்போது கொழும்பு நீதிமன்றத்தின் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள ஆவணங்கள் நிறைந்த சூட்கேஸ் ஒன்றும் பிரமாண்டமான மாளிகையில் விட்டுச் செல்லப்பட்டுள்ளதாக உத்தியோகபூர்வ வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "அவர் எங்கு இருக்கிறார் என்பது குறித்து ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகத்திலிருந்து அதிகாரப்பூர்வ வார்த்தை எதுவும் இல்லை, ஆனால் அவர் தனது வசம் இராணுவ வளங்களுடன் ஆயுதப்படைகளின் தளபதியாக இருந்தார்.",
        "திரு. ராஜபக்ச, பொருளாதாரத்தை தவறாக நிர்வகிப்பதாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டுள்ளார், நாட்டின் மிக அத்தியாவசியமான இறக்குமதிகளுக்கு கூட அந்நிய செலாவணி இல்லாமல், 22 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு கடுமையான கஷ்டங்களுக்கு வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "அவர் வாக்குறுதியளித்தபடி பதவி விலகினால், 2024 நவம்பரில் முடிவடையும் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரை பாராளுமன்றம் தெரிவு செய்யும் வரை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தானாகவே தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாகிவிடுவார்.",
        "ஆனால், ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதில் இணக்கப்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டால், பதவி விலகத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கே அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வாரிசு செயல்முறை மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் ஆகலாம் - பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டுவதற்கு எடுக்கும் குறைந்தபட்ச நேரம் - மற்றும் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் அதிகபட்சம் 30 நாட்கள் அனுமதிக்கப்படும். ராஜபக்ச புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகினால், ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி வாக்கெடுப்பு நடைபெறும் என்று நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய கட்சியின் தலைவரான சஜித் பிரேமதாச, 2019 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் திரு.ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் தோல்வியுற்ற நிலையில், அந்தப் பதவிக்கு தான் நிற்பதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "திரு. பிரேமதாச முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாசவின் மகன் ஆவார், அவர் மே 1993 இல் தமிழ் கிளர்ச்சியாளர் தற்கொலைக் குண்டுத் தாக்குதலில் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் இலங்கை தனது 51 பில்லியன் டாலர் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தத் தவறிவிட்டது மற்றும் சாத்தியமான பிணை எடுப்புக்காக IMF உடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "ஏற்கனவே பற்றாக்குறையாக இருந்த பெட்ரோல் விநியோகத்தை தீவு கிட்டத்தட்ட தீர்ந்து விட்டது. பயணத்தை குறைக்கவும், எரிபொருளை சேமிக்கவும் அத்தியாவசியமற்ற அலுவலகங்கள் மற்றும் பள்ளிகளை மூட அரசு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.85 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$51 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}