{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/හමුදාව-සයිබර්-යුද්ධ-සඳහාත්-සන්නද්ධ-කළ-යුතුයි/1-618758",
  "time_ut": 1661438293,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හමුදාව සයිබර් යුද්ධ සඳහාත් සන්නද්ධ කළ යුතුයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Army should also be equipped for cyber warfare",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that Sri Lankan war heroes should be equipped with the necessary knowledge for such a technological war, as wars may take place not only on the ground, in the air, but also in cyberspace.",
        "The President said that discipline training and knowledge are needed to create a successful army and said that the Sir John Kotalawala Defense University is fulfilling all these matters.",
        "The President said this while participating in the ceremony held this afternoon (25) for the awarding of the Presidential Colors and University Colors to General Sir John Kotalawala Defense University."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "John Kotalawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Colors and University Colors to General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Kotalawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හමුදාව සයිබර් යුද්ධ සඳහාත් සන්නද්ධ කළ යුතුයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අනාගතයේදී  භූමියේ ගුවනේ මුහුදේ පමණක් නොව සයිබර් අවකාශයේ ද යුද්ධ සිදුවිය හැකි බැවින් එවැනි තාක්ෂණික යුද්ධයකට අවශ්‍ය දැනුමින් ලාංකික රණවිරුවන් සන්නද්ධ  කළ යුතු බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සාර්ථක හමුදාවක් බිහිකිරීමට විනයක් පුහුණුවක් හා දැනුමක් අවශ්‍ය බව කී ජනාධිපතිවරයා ශ්‍රීමත්  ජෝන් කොතලාවල ආරක්ෂක විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය මේ සියලු කාරණා ඉටු කරමින් සිටින බවද කීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ බව පැවසූයේ ජනරාල් ශ්‍රීමත්  ජෝන්  කොතලාවල ආරක්ෂක විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ජනාධිපතිවර්ණ හා විශ්වවිද්‍යාල වර්ණ ප්‍රදානය සිදු කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් අද (25) පස්වරුවේ පැවති උත්සවයට සහභාගි වෙමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කොතලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති වර්ණ සහ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල වර්ණ සාමාන්‍යයට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කොතලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சைபர் போருக்கு ராணுவத்தையும் தயார்படுத்த வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தரையில், ஆகாயத்தில் மட்டுமல்ல, சைபர்வெளியிலும் போர்கள் நிகழலாம் என்பதால், இலங்கை போர்வீரர்கள் அத்தகைய தொழில்நுட்பப் போருக்குத் தேவையான அறிவைப் பெற்றிருக்க வேண்டும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெற்றிகரமான இராணுவத்தை உருவாக்க ஒழுக்கப் பயிற்சியும் அறிவும் அவசியம் என தெரிவித்த ஜனாதிபதி, சேர் ஜோன் கொத்தலாவல பாதுகாப்பு பல்கலைக்கழகம் இந்த விடயங்கள் அனைத்தையும் நிறைவேற்றி வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜெனரல் சேர் ஜோன் கொத்தலாவல பாதுகாப்பு பல்கலைக்கழகத்திற்கு ஜனாதிபதி நிறங்கள் மற்றும் பல்கலைக்கழக நிறங்கள் வழங்கும் நிகழ்வில் இன்று (25) பிற்பகல் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜோன் கொத்தலாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி நிறங்கள் மற்றும் பல்கலைக்கழக நிறங்கள் முதல் பொது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன் கொத்தலாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}