{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Eastern-Brokers-sets-all-time-record-price-for-Uva-Highlands-Estate-at-Colombo-Tea-Auctions/34-738507",
  "time_ut": 1660088599,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Eastern Brokers sets all-time record price for Uva Highlands Estate at Colombo Tea Auctions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Eastern Brokers sets all-time record price for Uva Highlands Estate at Colombo Tea Auctions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At the recently concluded Colombo Tea Auction yesterday, Uva Highlands Estate established an all-time record price of Rs. 3,550/- for a BOP grade with fine seasonal quality and flavour.  This line of Tea was purchased by M/s. Enura Trading Company.",
        "Uva Highlands tea Estate is situated in the Uva hills of the Uva Province of Sri Lanka between Bandarawela and Ettampitiya main road 12 km away from Bandarawela town.",
        "The elevation of Uva highlands Estate is between 1,219-1,250 m (4,100 feet) above mean sea level. The total extent of Uva Highlands Estate is 400 hectares of which the cultivated extent is 335 hectares. With an annual production of 1 million kg of made tea.",
        "The first planter of Uva Highlands Estate was Jainudeen who was in charge from 1915 to 1925, and at present Uva Highlands Estate comes under the stewardship of Group Manager Daminda Wanigasekara who has been the person behind the success of Uva Highlands Estate in the recent past.",
        "Uva Highlands Estate is managed and owned by Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC. This line of tea was marketed and sold by Eastern Brokers Ltd."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Eastern Brokers",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Uva Highlands Estate at Colombo Tea Auctions",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Tea Auction",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva Highlands Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,550/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Enura Trading Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Uva Province of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ettampitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 1,219-1,250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,100 feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva Highlands Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "335",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva Highlands Estate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1915",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1925",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva Highlands Estate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daminda Wanigasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Brokers Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඊස්ටර්න් බ්‍රෝකර්ස් කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත සඳහා සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිලක් නියම කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගියදා අවසන් වූ කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. 3,550/- හොඳ සෘතුමය ගුණාත්මක භාවය සහ රසය සහිත BOP ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා. මෙම තේ මාර්ගය M/s විසින් මිලදී ගන්නා ලදී. එනුර වෙළඳ සමාගම.",
        "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් තේ වතුයාය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඌව පළාතේ ඌව කඳුකරයේ බණ්ඩාරවෙල සහ එට්ටම්පිටිය ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගය අතර බණ්ඩාරවෙල නගරයේ සිට කිලෝමීටර් 12 ක් දුරින් පිහිටා ඇත.",
        "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වතුයායේ උන්නතාංශය මධ්‍යන්‍ය මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට මීටර් 1,219-1,250 (අඩි 4,100) අතර වේ. ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වතුයායේ මුළු භූමි ප්‍රමාණය හෙක්ටයාර් 400ක් වන අතර ඉන් වගා කරන ලද ප්‍රමාණය හෙක්ටයාර් 335කි. නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලද තේ කිලෝග්‍රෑම් මිලියනයක වාර්ෂික නිෂ්පාදනයක් සමඟ.",
        "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්තේ ප්‍රථම වැවිලිකරු 1915 සිට 1925 දක්වා භාරව සිටි ජයිනුදීන් වන අතර වර්තමානයේ ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත පසුගිය කාලයේ ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්තේ සාර්ථකත්වය පිටුපස සිටි සමූහ කළමනාකරු දමින්ද වනිගසේකරගේ භාරකාරත්වය යටතේ පවතී.",
        "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වතුයාය කළමනාකරණය සහ හිමිකාරීත්වය මල්වත්ත වැලි ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී සතු වේ. මෙම තේ පෙළ අලෙවි කර අලෙවි කරන ලද්දේ සීමාසහිත East Brokers විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නැගෙනහිර තැරැව්කරුවන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,550/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එනුර වෙළඳ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඌව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එට්ටම්පිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 කි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,219-1,250 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩි 4,100 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "335",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ මිලියන 1 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1915",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1925",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වත්ත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daminda Wanigasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්වත්ත වැලි වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊස්ටර්න් බ්‍රෝකර්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டத்திற்கான அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையையும் ஈஸ்டர்ன் புரோக்கர்ஸ் நிர்ணயித்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அண்மையில் நிறைவடைந்த கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம் இதுவரை இல்லாத வகையில் ரூ. சிறந்த பருவகால தரம் மற்றும் சுவையுடன் BOP தரத்திற்கு 3,550/-. இந்த தேயிலை M/s ஆல் வாங்கப்பட்டது. எனுரா வர்த்தக நிறுவனம்.",
        "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தேயிலை தோட்டம் இலங்கையின் ஊவா மாகாணத்தின் ஊவா மலைப்பகுதியில் பண்டாரவளை மற்றும் எட்டம்பிட்டிய பிரதான வீதிக்கு இடையில் பண்டாரவளை நகரத்திலிருந்து 12 கி.மீ தொலைவில் அமைந்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊவா ஹைலேண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டத்தின் உயரம் சராசரி கடல் மட்டத்திலிருந்து 1,219-1,250 மீ (4,100 அடி) இடையே உள்ளது. ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டத்தின் மொத்த பரப்பளவு 400 ஹெக்டேயர் ஆகும், இதில் 335 ஹெக்டேர் பயிர் செய்யப்படுகிறது. ஆண்டுக்கு 1 மில்லியன் கிலோ தேயிலை உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டத்தின் முதல் தோட்டக்காரர் 1915 முதல் 1925 வரை பொறுப்பில் இருந்த ஜெய்னுதீன் ஆவார், தற்போது ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம் அண்மைக்காலத்தில் ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டத்தின் வெற்றியின் பின்னணியில் இருந்த குழு முகாமையாளர் தமிந்த வணிகசேகரவின் பொறுப்பில் உள்ளது.",
        "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம் மல்வத்தை வேலி பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சிக்கு சொந்தமானது மற்றும் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்த தேயிலை வரிசை ஈஸ்டர்ன் புரோக்கர்ஸ் லிமிடெட் மூலம் சந்தைப்படுத்தப்பட்டு விற்பனை செய்யப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கிழக்கு தரகர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,550/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேநீர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எனுரா வர்த்தக நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் ஊவா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,219-1,250 இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,100 அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "335",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன் கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1915",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1925",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daminda Wanigasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்ன் புரோக்கர்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}