{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78312",
  "time_ut": 1656701280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bar Association of Sri Lanka(BASL) Files   Fundamental Rights Petition  On Behalf of Citizens Suffering Shortages of Essentials Including Fuel,Gas and Medicine  Citing 43 Respondents Comprising Prime Minister,Ministers and Secretaries; pleads for  Supreme Court to take up case Speedily  for Interim Relief on July 4",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bar Association of Sri Lanka(BASL) Files   Fundamental Rights Petition  On Behalf of Citizens Suffering Shortages of Essentials Including Fuel,Gas and Medicine  Citing 43 Respondents Comprising Prime Minister,Ministers and Secretaries; pleads for  Supreme Court to take up case Speedily  for Interim Relief on July 4",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) yesterday filed a motion in the Supreme Court, asking the latter to take up on Monday for interim relief the Fundamental Rights (FR) petition lodged on behalf of the citizens over the continuous violation of the fundamental rights due to the ongoing shortages.",
        "The Petitioners including BASL President Saliya Peiris PC and three of its office bearers moved the court to consider the case as a matter of extreme urgency and national importance and have this case listed for support for interim relief on 4 July.",
        "The Petitioners also sought a permanent Bench of the SC be appointed to hear and determine this case, as there is a need for continuity in the proceedings due to the critical importance of the matters referred to in the Petition.",
        "The Petitioners have cited 43 Respondents including the Prime Minister, Cabinet of Ministers and secretaries to various ministries.",
        "The Petitioners stated that since the date of filing of the application on 24 March, adequate and timely steps have not been taken by one or more of the Respondents to ensure an uninterrupted and continuous supply of petrol, diesel, kerosene oil, LP Gas, electricity and medicines which are vital to the life and survival of the people of Sri Lanka. As a result, people have been compelled to languish in long queues and are subject to fuel quotas.",
        "The motion filed yesterday said that one or more of the Respondents have failed to duly and responsibly inform the public of the measures, if any, that have been taken to alleviate the continuing and unbearable hardship and suffering experienced by the public, due to the continued unavailability of fuel, LP Gas, electricity and medicines.",
        "It stated that the fundamental rights of the people of Sri Lanka including that of the Petitioners are being continuously violated by the action and/or inaction of the Respondents, and that unless immediate steps are taken to ensure the uninterrupted supply of fuel, LP Gas, electricity, food and medicines, the fundamental rights of the Petitioners and the people of Sri Lanka including their right to life would continue to be infringed.",
        "The BASL is represented by Dr. Kanag Iswaran PC, Uditha Egalahewa PC, Suren Gnanaraj, Pulasthi Hewamanne, Lakshmanan Jeyakumar, and Niranjan Arulpragasam instructed by G.G. Arulpragasam."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bar Association of Sri Lanka(BASL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Supreme Court",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Speedily  for Interim Relief",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bench",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petition",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Respondents",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanag Iswaran PC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uditha Egalahewa PC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suren Gnanaraj",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pulasthi Hewamanne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshmanan Jeyakumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niranjan Arulpragasam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.G. Arulpragasam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) පුරවැසියන් වෙනුවෙන් ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් සහ ඖෂධ ඇතුළු අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟයෙන් පෙළෙන බවට මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කරයි, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය, අමාත්‍යවරුන් සහ ලේකම්වරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වගඋත්තරකරුවන් 43ක් උපුටා දක්වමින්; ජුලි 4 වනදා අතුරු සහන සඳහා වන නඩුව කඩිනමින් කැඳවන ලෙස ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය ඉල්ලා සිටියි",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අඛණ්ඩව උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුරවැසියන් වෙනුවෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම අතුරු සහන ඉල්ලා සඳුදා විභාගයට ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) ඊයේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට මෝසමක් ගොනු කළේය. පවතින හිඟය හේතුවෙන්.",
        "BASL සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් සහ එහි නිලධාරීන් තිදෙනෙකු ඇතුළු පෙත්සම්කරුවන් මෙම නඩුව අතිශය හදිසි සහ ජාතික වැදගත්කමක් ලෙස සලකා ජූලි 4 වනදා අතුරු සහන සඳහා සහය දැක්වීම සඳහා මෙම නඩුව ලැයිස්තුගත කරන ලෙස අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළහ.",
        "පෙත්සමේ සඳහන් කරුණුවල තීරණාත්මක වැදගත්කම හේතුවෙන් නඩු කටයුතු අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමේ අවශ්‍යතාවක් පවතින බැවින් මෙම නඩුව විභාග කර තීරණය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ ස්ථිර විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් පත් කරන ලෙසද පෙත්සම්කරුවෝ ඉල්ලා සිටියහ.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා, අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය සහ විවිධ අමාත්‍යාංශවල ලේකම්වරුන් ඇතුළු වගඋත්තරකරුවන් 43 දෙනෙකු පෙත්සම්කරුවන් විසින් සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරුවන් කියා සිටියේ මාර්තු 24 වැනි දින අයදුම්පත ගොනු කළ දින සිට පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල්, භූමිතෙල්, LP ගෑස්, විදුලිය අඛණ්ඩව සහ අඛණ්ඩව සැපයීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා වගඋත්තරකරුවන්ගෙන් එක් අයෙකු හෝ කිහිප දෙනෙකු විසින් ප්‍රමාණවත් හා කාලෝචිත පියවර ගෙන නොමැති බවයි. සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ජීවිතයට සහ පැවැත්මට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ. මේ නිසා ජනතාව දිගු පෝලිම්වල රස්තියාදු වී ඉන්ධන කෝටාවලට යටත්ව සිටිති.",
        "ඊයේ ගොනු කරන ලද මෝසමේ සඳහන් වූයේ, අඛණ්ඩව පවතින සහ දරාගත නොහැකි දුෂ්කරතා සහ දුක්ඛිත තත්ත්වයන් හේතුවෙන් මහජනතාව අත්විඳින අඛණ්ඩ සහ දරාගත නොහැකි දුෂ්කරතා සහ දුක් වේදනා සමනය කිරීම සඳහා ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ඇත්නම් ඒවා නිසි ලෙස සහ වගකීමෙන් යුතුව මහජනතාව දැනුවත් කිරීමට වගඋත්තරකරුවන්ගෙන් එක් අයෙකු හෝ කිහිප දෙනෙකු අපොහොසත් වී ඇති බවයි. ඉන්ධන, LP ගෑස්, විදුලිය සහ ඖෂධ නොමැතිකම.",
        "වගඋත්තරකරුවන්ගේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය සහ/හෝ අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව හේතුවෙන් පෙත්සම්කරුවන් ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අඛණ්ඩව උල්ලංඝනය වන බවත්, ඉන්ධන අඛණ්ඩව සැපයීම සහතික කිරීමට කඩිනම් පියවර නොගතහොත් LP Gas, විදුලිය, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ, පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ජීවත්වීමේ අයිතිය ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අඛණ්ඩව උල්ලංඝනය වනු ඇත.",
        "BASL නියෝජනය කරන්නේ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ආචාර්ය කනග් ඊශ්වරන්, ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ උදිත එගලහේවා, සුරේන් ඥානරාජ්, පුලස්ති හේවාමාන්න, ලක්ෂ්මන් ජෙයකුමාර්, සහ නිරංජන් අරුල්ප්‍රගාසම්ගේ උපදෙස් මත ජී.ජී. අරුල්ප්‍රගාසම්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය (BASL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අතුරු සහන සඳහා ඉක්මනින්",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංකුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙත්සම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රතිචාර දැක්වූවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ කනග් ඊශ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ උදිත එගලහේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් ඥානරාජ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුලස්ති හේවාමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් ජෙයකුමාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරංජන් අරුල්ප්‍රගාසම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ජී. අරුල්ප්‍රගාසම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர், அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் செயலாளர்கள் அடங்கிய 43 பிரதிவாதிகளை மேற்கோள் காட்டி எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு மற்றும் மருந்து உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் பற்றாக்குறையால் அவதிப்படும் குடிமக்கள் சார்பாக இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்தது; ஜூலை 4-ம் தேதி இடைக்கால நிவாரணத்திற்கான வழக்கை விரைவாக விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு வேண்டுகோள்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) நேற்று உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்து, அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் தொடர்பிலான குடிமக்கள் சார்பில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் (FR) மனுவை இடைக்கால நிவாரணம் கோரி திங்கட்கிழமை விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளுமாறு கோரியுள்ளது. தற்போதைய பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக.",
        "BASL தலைவர் சாலிய பீரிஸ் PC மற்றும் அதன் மூன்று அலுவலக அதிகாரிகள் உட்பட மனுதாரர்கள் இந்த வழக்கை மிகவும் அவசரம் மற்றும் தேசிய முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த ஒரு விஷயமாக கருதி, இந்த வழக்கை ஜூலை 4 அன்று இடைக்கால நிவாரணத்திற்கு ஆதரவாக பட்டியலிடுமாறு நீதிமன்றத்தை நாடினர்.",
        "மனுதாரர்கள், மனுவில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள விஷயங்களின் முக்கியமான முக்கியத்துவம் காரணமாக, இந்த வழக்கை விசாரிக்கவும், தீர்ப்பளிக்கவும் SC இன் நிரந்தர பெஞ்ச் நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் கோரினர்.",
        "பிரதமர், அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை மற்றும் பல்வேறு அமைச்சகங்களின் செயலாளர்கள் உட்பட 43 பிரதிவாதிகளை மனுதாரர்கள் மேற்கோள் காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "மனு தாக்கல் செய்த மார்ச் 24 ஆம் தேதி முதல், பெட்ரோல், டீசல், மண்ணெண்ணெய், எல்பி எரிவாயு, மின்சாரம் தடையின்றி தொடர்ந்து வழங்கப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்ய போதுமான மற்றும் சரியான நேரத்தில் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படவில்லை என்று மனுதாரர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களின் வாழ்க்கைக்கும் உயிர்வாழ்வதற்கும் இன்றியமையாத மருந்துகள். இதனால், மக்கள் நீண்ட வரிசையில் நின்று எரிபொருள் ஒதுக்கீட்டிற்கு உட்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பொதுமக்கள் அனுபவித்து வரும் தொடர் மற்றும் தாங்க முடியாத இன்னல்கள் மற்றும் துன்பங்களைப் போக்க எடுக்கப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் ஏதேனும் இருந்தால், ஒன்று அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட பிரதிவாதிகள் முறையாகவும் பொறுப்புடனும் பொதுமக்களுக்கு தெரிவிக்கத் தவறிவிட்டனர் என்று நேற்று தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. எரிபொருள், எல்பி எரிவாயு, மின்சாரம் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் கிடைக்காத நிலை.",
        "மனுதாரர்கள் உட்பட இலங்கை மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் பிரதிவாதிகளின் நடவடிக்கை மற்றும்/அல்லது செயலற்ற தன்மையால் தொடர்ச்சியாக மீறப்படுவதாகவும், எரிபொருள், எல்பி கேஸ், தடையின்றி வழங்குவதற்கு உடனடி நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படாவிட்டால், மின்சாரம், உணவு மற்றும் மருந்துகள், மனுதாரர்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மற்றும் அவர்களின் வாழ்வுரிமை உட்பட இலங்கை மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் தொடர்ந்து மீறப்படும்.",
        "BASL ஐப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துபவர்கள் கலாநிதி கனக் ஈஸ்வரன் பிசி, உதித எகலஹேவா பிசி, சுரேன் ஞானராஜ், புலஸ்தி ஹேவாமன்னே, லக்ஷ்மணன் ஜெயக்குமார், மற்றும் நிரஞ்சன் அருள்பிரகாசம் ஆகியோர் ஜி.ஜி. அருள்பிரகாசம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்(BASL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இடைக்கால நிவாரணத்திற்கு விரைவாக",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலிய பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெஞ்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்மனுதாரர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனக ஈஸ்வரன் பிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதித எகலஹேவா பிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் ஞானராஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலஸ்தி ஹேவமான்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லட்சுமணன் ஜெயக்குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரஞ்சன் அருள்பிரகாசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.ஜி. அருள்பிரகாசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}