{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මන්ත්‍රී-නිවාසවලට-පහරදුන්-තවත්-හතරක්-අල්ලයි/101-619092",
  "time_ut": 1662000110,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මන්ත්‍රී නිවාසවලට පහරදුන් තවත් හතරක් අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four others who attacked MP's houses are arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Senior Superintendent of Police lawyer Mr. Nihal Talduwa said that 4 persons have been arrested after attacking the house of Member of Parliament Taraka Balasuriya and the house of Member of Parliament Geetha Kumarasinghe as well as the National Television and a cab of Thavalama local council.",
        "The Kegalle division investigating officers have arrested a person in Kegalle area for attacking the house of Member of Parliament Taraka Balasuriya on Bandaranayake Mawatha, Kegalle on May 9, and Welikada Maligawa Road for breaking into the house of Mrs. Geetha Kumarasinghe on Rajagiriya Nawala Road and damaging the property. A person has been arrested in the area by the Welikada Police Station.",
        "The spokesperson said that a person was arrested in Pelawatta area by Thalangama police for attacking and damaging a cab belonging to Thawalama local council on May 1st on the road in front of Thawalama post 8.",
        "In addition, on July 13, a man from Moratuwa area was handed over to the Kurunduwatta police for entering the National Television Corporation, intimidating the employees and causing damage to government property.",
        "The arrested suspects are 22, 46, 48, and 51 years old and are residents of Kegalle, Meepitiya, Rajagiriya, Moratuwa and Entre Kotte."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nihal Talduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Taraka Balasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geetha Kumarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Television",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thavalama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Taraka Balasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranayake Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada Maligawa Road",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geetha Kumarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya Nawala Road",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pelawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalangama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thawalama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thawalama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moratuwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Television Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya, Moratuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Entre Kotte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්ත්‍රී නිවාසවලට පහරදුන් තවත් හතරක් අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තාරක බාලසූරියගේ නිවසට සහ ගීතා කුමාරසිංහ මන්ත්‍රීවරියගේ නිවසට මෙන්ම ජාතික රූපවාහිනියට සහ තවලම ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ කැබ් රථයකට පහරදී අලාභානි කළ පුද්ගලයන් 4 දෙනකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇතැයි පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නීතීඥ නිහල් තල්දූව මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රී තාරක බාලසූරිය මහතාගේ කෑගල්ල බන්ඩාරනායක මාවතේ නිවසට ඉකුත් මැයි 9 වෙනි දින  පහර දී දේපළවලට අලාභානි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෑගල්ල කොට්ඨාස විමර්ශන නිලධාරීන් විසින් කෑගල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ දී පුද්ගලයකු අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර, ගීතා කුමාරසිංහ මහත්මියගේ රාජගිරිය නාවල පාර නිවසට ඇතුළු වී දේපළවලට අලාභානි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැලිකඩ මාලිගාව පාර ප්‍රදේශයේ දී පුද්ගලයකු වැලිකඩ පොලිස් ස්ථානය මගින් අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "තවද මැයි නම වෙනි දින තවලම 8 කණුව ඉදිරිපිට මාර්ගයේ දී තවලම ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවට අයත් කැබ් රථයකට පහර දී අලාභහානි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තලංගම පොලිසිය මගින් පැලවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ දී පුද්ගලයකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇතැයි මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කිය.",
        "ඊට අමතරව ඉකුත් ජුලි 13 වෙනි දින ජාතික රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට ඇතුළුවී සේවකයන් බියගන්වා රජයේ දේපළවලට අලාභහානි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මොරටුව ප්‍රදේශයේ පුද්ගලයකු කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසියට භාරදීමෙන් අනතුරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් වයස අවුරුදු 22 ,46 , 48 , හා 51 පසුවන කෑගල්ල මීපිටිය, රාජගිරිය,මොරටුව හා ඇතුල් කෝට්ටේ පදිංචිකරුවන් ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු තාරක බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගීතා කුමාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු තාරක බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ මාලිගාව පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගීතා කුමාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය නාවල පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලංගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 1 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 51 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය, මොරටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Entre Kotte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எம்பி வீடுகளை தாக்கிய மேலும் 4 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தாரக பாலசூரியவின் வீடு, நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கீதா குமாரசிங்கவின் வீடு, தேசிய தொலைக்காட்சி, தவலம உள்ளூராட்சி மன்றத்தின் கெப் வண்டி ஆகியவற்றின் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்திய 4 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் சட்டத்தரணி திரு.நிஹால் தல்துவ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மே 9 ஆம் திகதி கேகாலை பண்டாரநாயக்க மாவத்தையில் உள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தாரக பாலசூரியவின் வீடு மற்றும் வெலிக்கடை மாளிகை வீதி ராஜகிரிய நாவல வீதியில் உள்ள திருமதி கீதா குமாரசிங்கவின் வீட்டிற்குள் புகுந்து சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த நபரை கேகாலை பிரதேச புலனாய்வு அதிகாரிகள் கைது செய்துள்ளனர். வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸ் நிலைய அதிகாரிகளால் குறித்த பகுதியில் வைத்து ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மே 1 ஆம் திகதி தவலம உள்ளூராட்சி சபைக்கு சொந்தமான கெப் வண்டியொன்றை தவலம தபால் 8க்கு முன்னால் உள்ள வீதியில் வைத்து தாக்கி சேதப்படுத்திய நபர் ஒருவர் பெலவத்த பிரதேசத்தில் தலங்கம பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், ஜூலை 13ஆம் திகதி மொரட்டுவ பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஒருவர் தேசிய தொலைக்காட்சி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து ஊழியர்களை மிரட்டி அரசாங்க சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த குற்றத்திற்காக குருந்துவத்தை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 22, 46, 48 மற்றும் 51 வயதுடைய கேகாலை, மீபிட்டிய, இராஜகிரிய, மொரட்டுவ மற்றும் என்ட்ரே கோட்டே ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் தாரக பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீதா குமாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தொலைக்காட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவலம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் தாரக பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை மாளிகை வீதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீதா குமாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய நாவல வீதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸ் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெலவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலங்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவலம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவலம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தொலைக்காட்சி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய, மொரட்டுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Entre Kotte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}