{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/යුරෝපා-ගෑස්-මිල-මාර්තු-මාසයේ-සිට-ඉහළටම/3-394999",
  "time_ut": 1656650146,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යුරෝපා ගෑස් මිල මාර්තු මාසයේ සිට ඉහළටම",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "European gas prices highest since March",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "European natural gas prices hit a three-month high amid ongoing concerns about a lack of Russian supplies and EU efforts to fill storage facilities ahead of the start of the hot season.",
        "The Netherlands' TTF trading center says it will rise 6.4% to $1,630 per thousand cubic meters by August. Intercontinental exchange data in London also showed an increase to 149.15 euros ($155.05) per megawatt hour domestically. It was the first time since March 10 that natural gas prices exceeded that level.",
        "On June 14, Russian gas exporter Gazprom cut supplies to Germany via the Nord Stream pipeline by 60%, citing technical problems due to Western sanctions over Ukraine. Following the decision, Germany called for a reduction in gas consumption in the country, and several other EU countries announced measures to help use less gas, including reviving coal-fired power plants."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "European",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "March",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,630",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "149.15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "155.05",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "megawatt hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුරෝපා ගෑස් මිල මාර්තු මාසයේ සිට ඉහළටම",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියානු සැපයුම් නොලැබීම සහ උණුසුම් සමය ආරම්භ වීමට පෙර ගබඩා පහසුකම් පිරවීම සඳහා යුරෝපා සංගමයේ උත්සාහයන් පිලිබඳව පවතින කනස්සල්ල මධ්‍යයේ යුරෝපීය ස්වභාවික ගෑස් මිල මාස තුනක ඉහළම අගයක් දක්වා පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "නෙදර්ලන්තයේ TTF වෙළඳ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ අගෝස්තු වනවිට 6.4% කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඝන මීටර් දහසකට ඩොලර් 1,630ක් දක්වා ළඟාවනු ඇති බව කියයි. එමෙන්ම ගෘහාශ්‍රිතව මෙගාවොට් පැයකට යුරෝ 149.15 (ඩොලර් 155.05) දක්වා වැඩිවීමක් ලන්ඩනයේ අන්තර් මහාද්වීපික හුවමාරු දත්ත පෙන්වයි. එය පසුගිය මාර්තු 10 වැනිදායින් පසු ස්වභාවික ගෑස් මිල එම මට්ටම ඉක්මවා ගිය පළමු අවස්ථාව එය විය.",
        "යුක්රේනය ආශ්‍රිත බටහිර සම්බාධක හේතුවෙන් තාක්ෂණික ගැටළු උපුටා දක්වමින් ජූනි 14දා රුසියානු ගෑස් අපනයනකරු Gazprom Nord Stream නල මාර්ගය හරහා ජර්මනියට සැපයුම් 60%කින් කපා හැරියේය. මෙම තීරණයෙන් පසුව, ජර්මනිය රට තුළ ගෑස් පරිභෝජනය අඩු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, තවත් යුරෝපා සංගම් රටවල් කිහිපයක් ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාර පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීම ඇතුළුව අඩු ගෑස් භාවිත කිරීමට උදව් කිරීමට පියවර ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුරෝපා",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාර්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,630 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "149.15 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "155.05 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙගාවොට් පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மார்ச் மாதம் முதல் ஐரோப்பிய எரிவாயு விலை உயர்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐரோப்பிய இயற்கை எரிவாயு விலைகள் ரஷ்ய பொருட்கள் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் சூடான பருவத்தின் தொடக்கத்திற்கு முன்னர் சேமிப்பு வசதிகளை நிரப்ப ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் முயற்சிகள் பற்றிய கவலைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் மூன்று மாத உயர்வை எட்டியுள்ளன.",
        "நெதர்லாந்தின் TTF வர்த்தக மையம் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்குள் ஆயிரம் கன மீட்டருக்கு 6.4% அதிகரித்து $1,630 ஆக இருக்கும் என்று கூறுகிறது. லண்டனில் உள்ள கண்டங்களுக்கு இடையேயான பரிமாற்றத் தரவு உள்நாட்டில் ஒரு மெகாவாட் மணிநேரத்திற்கு 149.15 யூரோக்கள் ($155.05) அதிகரித்துள்ளது. மார்ச் 10ஆம் தேதிக்குப் பிறகு இயற்கை எரிவாயுவின் விலை அந்த அளவைத் தாண்டியது இதுவே முதல்முறை.",
        "ஜூன் 14 அன்று, ரஷ்ய எரிவாயு ஏற்றுமதியாளர் Gazprom உக்ரைன் மீது மேற்கத்திய பொருளாதாரத் தடைகள் காரணமாக தொழில்நுட்ப சிக்கல்களைக் காரணம் காட்டி, Nord Stream குழாய் வழியாக ஜெர்மனிக்கான விநியோகங்களை 60% குறைத்தது. இந்த முடிவைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜெர்மனி நாட்டில் எரிவாயு நுகர்வு குறைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று அழைப்பு விடுத்தது, மேலும் பல ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய நாடுகள் நிலக்கரி எரியும் மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்களுக்கு புத்துயிர் கொடுப்பது உட்பட குறைந்த எரிவாயுவைப் பயன்படுத்த உதவும் நடவடிக்கைகளை அறிவித்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "மார்ச்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "TTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.4%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,630",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "149.15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "155.05",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட் மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}