{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62144683",
  "time_ut": 1657641322,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පිටව යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa leaves the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "BBC Sinhala Service reports that President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, who fled the Presidential Palace due to public protests on July 9, has left the island early today (July 13).",
        "According to the report to Bibisia that the President has left for Maldives.",
        "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, who left the country, has reached the Maldives, where a video showing him being taken out of the airport under strict security has been published on social media.",
        "The authorities say that on the night of July 12, after receiving the approval of the immigration officials, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, his wife Ayoma and two others left for the Maldives in a Sri Lankan Air Force plane.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena announced on July 9 that he has been informed that the President will resign today (July 13). Accordingly, the people as well as the strugglers are paying close attention to it. It is still uncertain whether President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will actually announce his resignation today.",
        "Before this, it had been reported on several occasions that the President tried to leave the country.",
        "The Hindu newspaper revealed that America has rejected President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa's recent request for an American visa.",
        "The activists emphasized that the President as well as the Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should step down today.",
        "Although there were earlier reports that the President would not resign without his family members leaving the country safely, neither the speaker nor any other party had made an official statement about it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC Sinhala Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bibisia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the night of July 12",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ayoma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පිටව යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජූලි 9 වැනිදා පැවති මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ  හමුවේ ජනපති මන්දිරයෙන් පලාගිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අද (ජූලි 13) අළුයම  දිවයිනෙන් බැහැරව ගොස් ඇති බවට බීබීසී සිංහල සේවයට වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇති බවට බිබිසිය වෙත වාර්තාවේ.",
        "මෙරටින් පිටව ගිය ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මාලදිවයිනට ලඟාවී ඇති අතර එහිදී දැඩි ආරක්ෂක රැකවල් මත ගුවන් තොටුපලින්‍ ඔහුව පිටතට  රැගෙන යන අයුරු බවට දැක්වෙන වීඩියෝවක් මේ වන විට සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල පළව තිබේ.",
        "බලධාරීන් පවසන්නේ,  ජූලි 12 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ ආගමන විගමන නිලධාරීන්ගේ අනුමැතිය ලැබීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ බිරිද අයෝමා හා තවත් දෙදෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගිය බවයි.",
        "කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන ජූලි 09 වැනිදා නිවේදනය කළේ අද (ජූලි 13 වැනිදා) ජනපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවටතමන්ට දැනුම් දී ඇති බවයි. ඒ අනුව අරගලකරුවන් මෙන්ම ජනතාව ද ඒ පිළිබඳ දැඩි අවධානයකින් පසුවෙයි. සැබවින්ම ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභාය රාජපක්ෂ අද තම ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කරයි ද යන්න තවමත් අවිනිශ්චිතය.",
        "මෙයට පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරයා රටින් බැහැර වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට අවස්ථා කිහිපයක්දී වාර්තා වී තිබුණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අමෙරිකානු වීසා සඳහා මෑතකදී කළ ඉල්ලීම අමෙරිකාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇතැයි ද හින්දු පුවත්පත අනාවරණය කළේය.",
        "අරගලකරුවන් අවධාරණය කළේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙන්ම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය  රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද අද දින ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "සිය පවුලේ සාමාජිකයින් ආරක්ෂිතව රටින් පිටවීමකින් තොරව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්නොවනු ඇති බවට මීට පෙර වාර්තා පළ වුවත් කතානායකවරයා හෝ වෙනත් කිසිදු පාර්ශවයක් ඒ පිළිබඳ නිල ප්‍රකාශයක් කර නොතිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී සිංහල සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද වේලාසනින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිබිසියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12 රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයෝමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி பொதுமக்கள் எதிர்ப்பு காரணமாக ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை விட்டு வெளியேறிய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று (ஜூலை 13) அதிகாலை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ளதாக பிபிசி சிங்கள சேவை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாலைதீவுக்கு சென்றுள்ளதாக பிபிசியாவிடம் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச மாலைதீவு சென்றடைந்த நிலையில், பலத்த பாதுகாப்புடன் விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து வெளியே அழைத்துச் செல்லப்படும் காணொளி ஒன்று சமூக வலைத்தளங்களில் வெளியாகியுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 12 ஆம் திகதி இரவு குடிவரவு அதிகாரிகளின் அனுமதியைப் பெற்ற பின்னர், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது மனைவி அயோமா மற்றும் இருவர் இலங்கை விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் மாலைதீவுக்கு புறப்பட்டதாக அதிகாரிகள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இன்று (ஜூலை 13) இராஜினாமா செய்யவுள்ளதாக தனக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி அறிவித்தார். அதன்படி, மக்களும், போராட்டக்காரர்களும் தீவிர கவனம் செலுத்தி வருகின்றனர். ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இன்று தனது பதவி விலகலை அறிவிப்பாரா என்பது இன்னும் உறுதியாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற முயற்சித்ததாக பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் செய்திகள் வெளியாகியிருந்தன.",
        "அண்மையில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச விடுத்த அமெரிக்க விசா கோரிக்கையை அமெரிக்கா நிராகரித்துள்ளதாக தி ஹிந்து நாளிதழ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் இன்று பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் பாதுகாப்பாக நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறாமல் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலக மாட்டார் என முன்னர் செய்திகள் வெளியாகியிருந்த போதிலும், சபாநாயகரோ அல்லது வேறு தரப்பினரோ அது தொடர்பில் உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிக்கையை வெளியிடவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி சிங்கள சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயோமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}