{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/columns/SMEs-are-sinking-Mr-President/4-738495",
  "time_ut": 1660087518,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SMEs are sinking, Mr. President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SMEs are sinking, Mr. President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "When 75% of the GDP of the country is generated by the SME sector and IMF estimates that the country’s economy will contract by -7% one can imagine the impact to this sector. Some speculate that already almost a million SMEs are in trouble, especially the tourism industry, construction and the cottage industry of Sri Lanka.",
        "If one were to capture the reality, SMEs are struggling to service the loans at high interest rates whilst on the other side they cannot pay the capital repayments. This has resulted in the banks that are already stressed resorting to parade action which is sad but it is the reality.",
        "This will lead to the SME operations being severely affected on the working capital and delivery to the bottom line resulting in retrenchment of staff. The banks on the other hand will have to convert themselves into real estate business houses to sell properties acquired. Already we see many construction related entities are being advertised mainly in the suburbs of Sri Lanka like Gampaha, Kaduwela, Maharagama and Ja-Ela geographical pockets. On the other hand if the affected SMEs seek time through court intervention by way of injunctions, etc. the banks will have to face serious consequences due to impairment provisions that will take the balance sheet to the red. The million dollar question is, in which direction does one move when the Government has declared bankruptcy and inflation is touching 90% for food and overall number at 68%.",
        "Just like Sri Lanka having to go back to basics where the income and expenses need to be balanced before the IMF will consider us for a bailout, the major problem with this sector is that there is no proper definition for an SME. The problem is not unique to Sri Lanka since classifying an SME can depend on a multitude of variables that can change from one country to the next. Furthermore, the absence of data in this uncontrolled sector of the economy adds to its complexity. It’s time that we put this analysis right so that once we are secure financially within the next one year we can re-look at the overall strategy.",
        "In Sri Lanka some say that an enterprise which has less than 99 people and an asset base of Rs. 4 million can be termed an SME. Then another definition lists the parameters as less than 50 people with an asset base of Rs. 20 million. The World Bank states that if any enterprise has less than 99 people it can be termed an SME. Hence it is very clear that this is one key decision that Sri Lanka needs to make as a country, given that concessionary financial facilities can be targeted and specific business development services can also be made available if there is a clear classification of an SME. Apart from the fact that over 70% of the country’s GDP is generated by SMEs, another important point to note is that from the 4,700 odd exporters that generate almost $ 11 billion, nearly 80% of them are SMEs. If we look at the tea industry, from the 300 kg million of tea that Sri Lanka produces, almost 70% of it is from small holding producers that have just half an acre of land. Hence we see that there are many unsung heroes in the SME business who never get highlighted or identified so that development can be done from a State perspective.",
        "The first key task is for this sector of business to have a single line ministry. This can result in a clear and focused agenda that can be developed, which will be followed by a set of policy guidelines. If this is done, some of the key issues highlighted can be addressed straightaway with a minimum impact to the tax revenue model of the country.",
        "If I may take you back to how the SME sector evolved in Sri Lanka, way back in 1952, the World Bank had suggested that the Government develop SMEs rather than promote large industries. Then in the 1960s the Sri Lankan Government began focusing on developing cottage industries and SMEs for the sole purpose of saving foreign exchange through import substitution and employment development.",
        "Thereafter in the 1977 post-liberalised economy, SMEs were developed to drive the export market, which is actually when the SME sector became the backbone of the country’s economy.With this development came the multitude of Government agencies and private sector banks that were set up to create the policy environment to support this fast-developing business sector. These included the Department of Small Industries, CISIR, EDB, SLSI, IDB, SLECIC, the Textile Department, the National Gem and Jewellery Authority, NEDA, DFCC, NDB, the SME Bank later renamed Lankaputhra and the Regional Development Bank (RDB).  In the recent past we have seen many line ministries like the Ministry for Traditional Industries and Small Enterprises coming into the fray, which explains the fast-growing importance of this sector. I would strongly recommend that a dedicated ministry be allocated to this sector so that raising money, supporting documentation, managing P&L, and HR strategy development can be done in a more grounded sense.",
        "Visiting some of the SMEs in different parts of the country, one of the key issues that was cited was that there was no clear policy for a typical small- and medium-scale entrepreneur. Some SMEs in Ekala said that if one was to register property, it took almost 258 days and 5% of the land value, which is not conducive to fostering entrepreneurship. I guess that is why Sri Lanka’s rating in the Ease of Doing Business Index is way below that of a country.",
        "Some went on to say that very few business development services are available, such as research and development facilities, quality certification at the district level and a link to export markets. Most SMEs harp on the difficulty of accessing concessionary finance, this being the key hindrance to business development. Another point highlighted by the SMEs was that almost 60 types of taxes had to be paid to a bank during a year, which is very cumbersome and time-consuming and must be a priority item that must be addressed. Some went on to say that a typical SME being stretched for talent results in these archaic tax systems affecting the productivity of the organisation.",
        "Whilst Sri Lanka is grappling to set up an all-party administrative structure, it will be prudent that we start reforms in the public sector where we set a dedicated line ministry for the SME sector."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost a million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaduwela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharagama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ja-Ela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "million dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "68%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than 99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "as less than 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than 99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost $ 11 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 300 kg million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "just half an acre",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1952",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1960s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Small Industries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CISIR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLSI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Textile Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEDA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DFCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankaputhra",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Regional Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry for Traditional Industries and Small Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P&L",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ekala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 258 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ease of Doing Business Index",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "almost 60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සුළු හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයන් ගිලා බසී ජනාධිපතිතුමනි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් 75%ක් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසාය අංශයෙන් ජනනය වන විට සහ IMF ඇස්තමේන්තු කරන විට රටේ ආර්ථිකය -7% කින් හැකිලෙන බව කෙනෙකුට සිතාගත හැකිය. ඇතැමුන් අනුමාන කරන්නේ දැනටමත් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් මිලියනයකට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක්, විශේෂයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය, ඉදිකිරීම් සහ ගෘහ කර්මාන්තය ගැටලුවලට මුහුණ දී ඇති බවයි.",
        "යමෙක් යථාර්ථය ග්‍රහණය කර ගන්නේ නම්, කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයන් ඉහළ පොලී අනුපාත යටතේ ණය ලබා දීමට අරගල කරන අතර අනෙක් පැත්තෙන් ඔවුන්ට ප්‍රාග්ධන ආපසු ගෙවීමට නොහැකි වේ. මේ හේතුවෙන් දැනටමත් ආතතියට පත්ව සිටින බැංකු පෙළපාළි ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයකට යොමුවීම කණගාටුදායක නමුත් යථාර්ථය එයයි.",
        "මෙය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකත්ව මෙහෙයුම් කාරක ප්‍රාග්ධනයට දැඩි ලෙස බලපානු ඇති අතර කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සේවයෙන් පහකිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස පහළ මට්ටමට බෙදා හැරීමට හේතු වනු ඇත. අනෙක් අතට බැංකුවලට අත්පත් කරගත් දේපළ විකිණීම සඳහා දේපළ වෙළඳාම් ව්‍යාපාරික ආයතන බවට පරිවර්තනය වීමට සිදුවනු ඇත. මේ වන විටත් අපට බොහෝ ඉදිකිරීම් සම්බන්ධ ආයතන ප්‍රචාරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගම්පහ, කඩුවෙල, මහරගම සහ ජා-ඇල භූගෝලීය සාක්කුවල ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ය. අනෙක් අතට විපතට පත් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයන් වාරණ නියෝග ආදිය මගින් උසාවි මැදිහත්වීම් හරහා කාලය ඉල්ලා සිටියහොත් ශේෂ පත්‍රය රතු අතට ගෙන යන දුර්වලතා ප්‍රතිපාදන හේතුවෙන් බැංකුවලට බරපතළ ප්‍රතිවිපාකවලට මුහුණ දීමට සිදුවනු ඇත. ඩොලර් මිලියන ප්‍රශ්නය නම්, රජය බංකොලොත්භාවය ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති විට සහ ආහාර සඳහා උද්ධමනය 90% දක්වා සහ සමස්ත සංඛ්‍යාව 68% දක්වා ළඟා වන විට යමෙකු ගමන් කරන්නේ කුමන දිශාවටද යන්නයි.",
        "ජාමූඅ අපව ඇපදීමක් සඳහා සලකා බැලීමට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආදායම සහ වියදම් සමතුලිත විය යුතු මූලික කරුණු වෙත ආපසු යාමට සිදු වෙනවා සේම, මෙම අංශයේ ඇති ප්‍රධාන ගැටළුව වන්නේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයෙකු සඳහා නිසි අර්ථ දැක්වීමක් නොමැති වීමයි. කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් වර්ගීකරණය කිරීම එක් රටකින් තවත් රටකට වෙනස් විය හැකි විචල්‍ය රාශියක් මත රඳා පැවතිය හැකි බැවින් ගැටලුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පමණක් ආවේනික නොවේ. තවද, ආර්ථිකයේ මෙම පාලනයෙන් තොර අංශයේ දත්ත නොමැතිකම එහි සංකීර්ණත්වය වැඩි කරයි. ඉදිරි වසරක කාලය තුළ අප මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් සුරක්ෂිත වූ පසු අපට සමස්ත උපාය මාර්ගය දෙස නැවත බැලීමට හැකි වන පරිදි අපි මෙම විශ්ලේෂණය නිවැරදිව තැබීමට කාලයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇතැමුන් පවසන්නේ පුද්ගලයන් 99 ට අඩු සහ රුපියල් කෝටි 100 ක වත්කම් පදනමක් ඇති ව්‍යවසායයක් 2015 වසරේ සිට 2017-09-20 දක්වා කාලය තුළ පවතින බවයි. මිලියන 4ක් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයෙකු ලෙස හැඳින්විය හැක. එවිට තවත් නිර්වචනයක් මගින් පරාමිතීන් ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇත්තේ රුපියල් 50 ක වත්කම් පදනමක් සහිත පුද්ගලයන් 50 ට වඩා අඩුය. මිලියන 20 කි. ඕනෑම ව්‍යවසායක පුද්ගලයන් 99 ට අඩු නම් එය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයකු ලෙස හැඳින්විය හැකි බව ලෝක බැංකුව ප්‍රකාශ කරයි. එබැවින් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයෙකු පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලි වර්ගීකරණයක් තිබේ නම් සහනදායී මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් ඉලක්ක කර නිශ්චිත ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධන සේවාවන් ද ලබා ගත හැකි බැවින් මෙය රටක් වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගත යුතු එක් ප්‍රධාන තීරණයක් බව ඉතා පැහැදිලිය. රටේ දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් 70% කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් විසින් ජනනය කරනු ලබන කාරණය හැරුණු විට, අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතු තවත් වැදගත් කරුණක් නම්, ඩොලර් බිලියන 11 කට ආසන්න ආදායමක් උපයන ඔත්තේ අපනයනකරුවන් 4,700 න්, ඔවුන්ගෙන් 80% කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් වීමයි. අපි තේ කර්මාන්තය දෙස බැලුවහොත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිෂ්පාදනය කරන තේ කිලෝග්‍රෑම් මිලියන 300 න් 70% කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් අක්කර භාගයක් පමණක් ඇති කුඩා වතු හිමියන්ගෙනි. එබැවින් රාජ්‍ය දෘෂ්ටිකෝණයකින් සංවර්ධනය කළ හැකි වන පරිදි කිසි විටෙකත් ඉස්මතු නොවන හෝ හඳුනා නොගත් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර ව්‍යාපාරයේ නොගිය වීරයන් රාශියක් සිටින බව අපට පෙනේ.",
        "පළමු ප්‍රධාන කාර්යය වන්නේ මෙම ව්‍යාපාරික අංශයට තනි රේඛීය අමාත්‍යාංශයක් තිබීමයි. ප්‍රතිපත්ති මාර්ගෝපදේශ මාලාවක් අනුගමනය කරන පැහැදිලි සහ අවධානය යොමු කළ න්‍යාය පත්‍රයක් වර්ධනය කිරීමට මෙය හේතු විය හැක. මෙය සිදු කරන්නේ නම්, රටේ බදු ආදායම් ආකෘතියට අවම බලපෑමක් ඇති කරමින් ඉස්මතු කර ඇති සමහර ප්‍රධාන ගැටළු වහාම විසඳා ගත හැකිය.",
        "1952 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසාය අංශය විකාශනය වූ ආකාරය වෙත මම ඔබව ගෙන යන්නේ නම්, මහා කර්මාන්ත ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට වඩා කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට රජයට ලෝක බැංකුව යෝජනා කර ඇත. ඉන්පසුව 1960 ගණන්වල ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ආනයන ආදේශන සහ රැකියා සංවර්ධනය තුළින් විදේශ විනිමය ඉතිරි කර ගැනීමේ එකම අරමුණ සඳහා ගෘහ කර්මාන්ත සහ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකත්ව සංවර්ධනය කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කළේය.",
        "ඉන් පසුව 1977 පශ්චාත් ලිබරල් ආර්ථිකය තුළ, අපනයන වෙළෙඳපොළ මෙහෙයවීම සඳහා කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සංවර්ධනය කරන ලද අතර, ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායක අංශය රටේ ආර්ථිකයේ කොඳු නාරටිය බවට පත් වූ අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. මෙම සංවර්ධනයත් සමඟ රාජ්‍ය ආයතන සහ පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ බැංකු රාශියක් ආරම්භ විය. මෙම වේගයෙන් සංවර්ධනය වන ව්‍යාපාරික අංශයට සහාය වීම සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය පරිසරයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම. කුඩා කර්මාන්ත දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, CISIR, EDB, SLSI, IDB, SLECIC, රෙදිපිළි දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, ජාතික මැණික් හා ස්වර්ණාභරණ අධිකාරිය, NEDA, DFCC, NDB, SME බැංකුව පසුව ලංකාපුත්‍ර සහ ප්‍රාදේශීය සංවර්ධන බැංකුව (RDB) ලෙස නම් කරන ලදී. සාම්ප්‍රදායික කර්මාන්ත හා කුඩා ව්‍යවසාය අමාත්‍යාංශය වැනි බොහෝ රේඛීය අමාත්‍යාංශ ද තරග බිමට පැමිනෙනු අපි පසුගිය කාලය තුළ දුටුවෙමු, එය මෙම අංශයේ ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් වර්ධනය වන වැදගත්කම පැහැදිලි කරයි. මුදල් රැස් කිරීම, ආධාරක ලියකියවිලි, P&L කළමනාකරණය සහ මානව සම්පත් උපාය මාර්ග සංවර්ධනය වඩාත් පදනම් වූ අර්ථයකින් සිදු කළ හැකි වන පරිදි මෙම අංශයට කැප වූ අමාත්‍යාංශයක් වෙන් කළ යුතු යැයි මම තරයේ නිර්දේශ කරමි.",
        "දිවයිනේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් වෙත ගිය විට, උපුටා දක්වන ලද එක් ප්‍රධාන කරුණක් වූයේ සාමාන්‍ය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයෙකු සඳහා පැහැදිලි ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් නොතිබීමයි. ඒකල ප්‍රදේශයේ සමහර කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් කියා සිටියේ කෙනෙකුට දේපල ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමට නම් දින 258කට ආසන්න කාලයක් සහ ඉඩම් වටිනාකමෙන් 5%ක් පමණ ගත වූ බවත් එය ව්‍යවසායකත්වය පෝෂණය කිරීමට හිතකර නොවන බවත්ය. ව්‍යාපාර කිරීමේ පහසුව පිළිබඳ දර්ශකයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම රටකට වඩා බෙහෙවින් පහළ මට්ටමක පවතින්නේ ඒ නිසා යැයි මම අනුමාන කරමි.",
        "පර්යේෂණ හා සංවර්ධන පහසුකම්, දිස්ත්‍රික් මට්ටමින් තත්ත්ව සහතික කිරීම සහ අපනයන වෙළඳපොළට සම්බන්ධ කිරීම වැනි ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධන සේවා ඇත්තේ ඉතා සුළු ප්‍රමාණයක් බව ඇතැමෙක් තවදුරටත් පැවසූහ. බොහෝ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සහනදායී මූල්‍ය පහසුකම් ලබාගැනීමේ දුෂ්කරතාවය පිළිබඳව හඹා යෑම, මෙය ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධනයට ඇති ප්‍රධාන බාධාවයි. කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් විසින් අවධාරණය කරන ලද තවත් කරුණක් නම්, වසරක් තුළදී බැංකුවකට බදු වර්ග 60කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ගෙවීමට සිදු වූ අතර එය ඉතා අපහසු සහ කාලය ගතවන අතර අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතු ප්‍රමුඛතා අයිතමයක් විය යුතුය. සාමාන්‍ය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් දක්ෂතා සඳහා දිගු කිරීම මෙම පෞරාණික බදු ක්‍රමවල ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස සංවිධානයේ ඵලදායිතාවයට බලපාන බව ඇතැමුන් තවදුරටත් පැවසූහ.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික පරිපාලන ව්‍යුහයක් පිහිටුවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පොරබදමින් සිටින අතරේ, කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායක අංශය සඳහා කැප වූ රේඛීය අමාත්‍යාංශයක් පිහිටුවීමට අපි රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ආරම්භ කිරීම ඥානවන්ත වනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයකට ආසන්න",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩුවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජා-ඇල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "68%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 ට අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50ට අඩුවෙන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 ට අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70% ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 11 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "80%කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ මිලියන 300 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කර භාගයක් පමණි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1952",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1960 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුඩා කර්මාන්ත දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CISIR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊ.ඩී.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLSI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙදිපිළි දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEDA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එෆ්.සී.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකාපුත්ර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාම්ප්‍රදායික කර්මාන්ත හා කුඩා ව්‍යවසාය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P&L",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒකල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් දින 258 කි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්‍යාපාර කිරීමේ පහසුව දර්ශකය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුද්දක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SMEகள் மூழ்கிக் கொண்டிருக்கின்றன, ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 75% SME துறையால் உருவாக்கப்படுகிறது மற்றும் IMF நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் -7% சுருங்கும் என்று மதிப்பிடும்போது இந்தத் துறையின் தாக்கத்தை ஒருவர் கற்பனை செய்யலாம். இலங்கையின் சுற்றுலாத் தொழில், கட்டுமானம் மற்றும் குடிசைத் தொழில் போன்றவற்றில் ஏற்கனவே ஒரு மில்லியன் SMEகள் சிக்கலில் இருப்பதாக சிலர் ஊகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "யதார்த்தத்தை ஒருவர் புரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்றால், SMEகள் அதிக வட்டி விகிதத்தில் கடன்களை வழங்குவதில் சிரமப்படுகின்றனர், மறுபுறம் அவர்கள் மூலதனத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்த முடியாது. இதனால் ஏற்கனவே மன உளைச்சலுக்கு ஆளான வங்கிகள் அணிவகுப்பு நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபடுவது வருத்தமளிக்கிறது ஆனால் அதுதான் உண்மை.",
        "இது SME செயல்பாடுகள் செயல்பாட்டு மூலதனத்தில் கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கப்படுவதற்கும், ஊழியர்களின் ஆட்குறைப்புக்கு வழிவகுக்கும். மறுபுறம் வங்கிகள் வாங்கிய சொத்துக்களை விற்க ரியல் எஸ்டேட் வணிக நிறுவனங்களாக தங்களை மாற்றிக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். ஏற்கனவே இலங்கையின் புறநகர்ப் பகுதிகளான கம்பஹா, கடுவெல, மஹரகம மற்றும் ஜா-எல புவியியல் பகுதிகளில் பல கட்டுமானம் தொடர்பான நிறுவனங்கள் விளம்பரப்படுத்தப்படுவதைக் காண்கிறோம். மறுபுறம், பாதிக்கப்பட்ட SMEக்கள் நீதிமன்றத் தலையீட்டின் மூலம் தடை உத்தரவுகள் போன்றவற்றின் மூலம் கால அவகாசம் கோரினால், வங்கிகள் இருப்புநிலைக் குறிப்பைச் சிவப்பு நிலைக்குக் கொண்டு செல்லும் குறைபாடு விதிகள் காரணமாக கடுமையான விளைவுகளைச் சந்திக்க வேண்டியிருக்கும். ஒரு மில்லியன் டாலர் கேள்வி என்னவென்றால், அரசாங்கம் திவாலாகிவிட்டதாக அறிவித்ததும், உணவுப் பொருட்களுக்கான பணவீக்கம் 90% ஐத் தொட்டு, ஒட்டுமொத்த எண்ணிக்கை 68% ஆக இருக்கும்போது, ​​எந்தத் திசையில் நகர்வது என்பதுதான்.",
        "IMF பிணையெடுப்புக்கு எங்களைப் பரிசீலிக்கும் முன், வருமானம் மற்றும் செலவுகள் சமநிலைப்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டிய அடிப்படைகளுக்கு இலங்கை திரும்புவதைப் போலவே, இந்தத் துறையின் முக்கிய பிரச்சனை என்னவென்றால், SME க்கு சரியான வரையறை இல்லை. ஒரு SME ஐ வகைப்படுத்துவது ஒரு நாட்டிலிருந்து அடுத்த நாட்டிற்கு மாறக்கூடிய பல மாறிகள் சார்ந்தது என்பதால் இந்த பிரச்சனை இலங்கைக்கு மட்டும் அல்ல. மேலும், பொருளாதாரத்தின் இந்த கட்டுப்பாடற்ற துறையில் தரவு இல்லாதது அதன் சிக்கலை அதிகரிக்கிறது. இந்த பகுப்பாய்வை நாங்கள் சரியாக வைக்க வேண்டிய நேரம் இது, இதன் மூலம் அடுத்த ஒரு வருடத்திற்குள் நாம் நிதி ரீதியாக பாதுகாப்பாக இருந்தால், ஒட்டுமொத்த மூலோபாயத்தை மீண்டும் பார்க்கலாம்.",
        "இலங்கையில் சிலர் 99 பேருக்கும் குறைவான நபர்களைக் கொண்ட ஒரு நிறுவனமும் ரூ. 4 மில்லியனை ஒரு SME என்று அழைக்கலாம். பின்னர் மற்றொரு வரையறை 50 க்கும் குறைவான நபர்களின் சொத்துத் தளம் ரூ. 20 மில்லியன். எந்தவொரு நிறுவனமும் 99 பேருக்கும் குறைவாக இருந்தால், அதை SME என்று அழைக்கலாம் என்று உலக வங்கி கூறுகிறது. எனவே, SME இன் தெளிவான வகைப்பாடு இருந்தால், சலுகை நிதி வசதிகளை இலக்காகக் கொள்ள முடியும் மற்றும் குறிப்பிட்ட வணிக மேம்பாட்டு சேவைகளையும் வழங்க முடியும் என்பதால், ஒரு நாடாக இலங்கை எடுக்க வேண்டிய முக்கிய முடிவு இது என்பது மிகவும் தெளிவாக உள்ளது. நாட்டின் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 70% க்கும் அதிகமானவை SME களால் உருவாக்கப்படுகின்றன என்பதைத் தவிர, கவனிக்க வேண்டிய மற்றொரு முக்கியமான விஷயம் என்னவென்றால், கிட்டத்தட்ட 11 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை ஈட்டும் 4,700 ஒற்றைப்படை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களில், அவர்களில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 80% பேர் SMEகள். தேயிலை தொழிற்துறையைப் பார்த்தால், இலங்கை உற்பத்தி செய்யும் 300 கிலோ மில்லியன் தேயிலையிலிருந்து, கிட்டத்தட்ட 70% வெறும் அரை ஏக்கர் நிலத்தைக் கொண்ட சிறுதொழில் உற்பத்தியாளர்களுடையது. எனவே, SME வணிகத்தில் பல அறியப்படாத ஹீரோக்கள் இருப்பதை நாம் காண்கிறோம், அவர்கள் ஒருபோதும் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்படவோ அல்லது அடையாளம் காணப்படவோ மாட்டார்கள், இதனால் வளர்ச்சியை மாநிலக் கண்ணோட்டத்தில் செய்ய முடியும்.",
        "இந்த வணிகத் துறைக்கு ஒற்றை வரி அமைச்சகம் இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பது முதல் முக்கிய பணி. இது ஒரு தெளிவான மற்றும் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்ட நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலை உருவாக்கலாம், இது கொள்கை வழிகாட்டுதல்களின் தொகுப்பால் பின்பற்றப்படும். இதைச் செய்தால், நாட்டின் வரி வருவாய் மாதிரியில் குறைந்தபட்ச தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் வகையில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சில முக்கியப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு உடனடியாகத் தீர்வு காண முடியும்.",
        "1952 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கையில் SME துறை எவ்வாறு பரிணாம வளர்ச்சியடைந்தது என்பதை நான் மீண்டும் உங்களுக்கு எடுத்துச் சொன்னால், பெரிய கைத்தொழில்களை ஊக்குவிப்பதை விட SMEகளை அரசாங்கம் அபிவிருத்தி செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று உலக வங்கி பரிந்துரைத்திருந்தது. பின்னர் 1960 களில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் இறக்குமதி மாற்றீடு மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு மேம்பாடு மூலம் அந்நியச் செலாவணியைச் சேமிக்கும் ஒரே நோக்கத்திற்காக குடிசைக் கைத்தொழில் மற்றும் SME களை அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதில் கவனம் செலுத்தத் தொடங்கியது.",
        "அதன் பிறகு 1977 தாராளமயமாக்கலுக்குப் பிந்தைய பொருளாதாரத்தில், SMEகள் ஏற்றுமதி சந்தையை இயக்குவதற்காக உருவாக்கப்பட்டன, உண்மையில் SME துறை நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தின் முதுகெலும்பாக மாறியது. இந்த வளர்ச்சியுடன் பல அரசு நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தனியார் துறை வங்கிகள் அமைக்கப்பட்டன. இந்த வேகமாக வளரும் வணிகத் துறையை ஆதரிக்கும் கொள்கை சூழலை உருவாக்க. சிறு கைத்தொழில் திணைக்களம், CISIR, EDB, SLSI, IDB, SLECIC, ஜவுளி திணைக்களம், தேசிய இரத்தினக்கல் மற்றும் ஆபரண அதிகார சபை, NEDA, DFCC, NDB, SME வங்கி பின்னர் லங்காபுத்ரா மற்றும் பிராந்திய அபிவிருத்தி வங்கி (RDB) என மறுபெயரிடப்பட்டது. சமீப காலங்களில் பாரம்பரிய கைத்தொழில்கள் மற்றும் சிறுதொழில்களுக்கான அமைச்சகம் போன்ற பல துறை அமைச்சகங்கள் களத்தில் இறங்குவதை நாம் பார்த்திருக்கிறோம், இது இந்தத் துறையின் வேகமாக வளர்ந்து வரும் முக்கியத்துவத்தை விளக்குகிறது. நிதி திரட்டுதல், ஆவணங்களை ஆதரித்தல், P&L மற்றும் மனிதவள உத்தி மேம்பாடு ஆகியவற்றை நிர்வகித்தல் போன்றவற்றை மிகவும் அடிப்படையான அர்த்தத்தில் செய்ய இத்துறைக்கு அர்ப்பணிப்புள்ள அமைச்சகம் ஒதுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று நான் கடுமையாக பரிந்துரைக்கிறேன்.",
        "நாட்டின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள சில SMEகளை பார்வையிட்டதில், மேற்கோள் காட்டப்பட்ட முக்கிய பிரச்சினைகளில் ஒன்று, ஒரு பொதுவான சிறிய மற்றும் நடுத்தர அளவிலான தொழில்முனைவோருக்கு தெளிவான கொள்கை இல்லை. ஏகலாவில் உள்ள சில SMEகள் ஒருவர் சொத்தை பதிவு செய்ய 258 நாட்களை எடுத்துக் கொண்டதாகவும், நில மதிப்பில் 5% ஆகும் என்றும், இது தொழில் முனைவோரை வளர்ப்பதற்கு உகந்ததல்ல. அதனால்தான் எளிதாக தொழில் செய்யக்கூடிய சுட்டெண்ணில் இலங்கையின் தரமதிப்பீடு ஒரு நாட்டை விட மிகவும் குறைவாக உள்ளது என்று நான் நினைக்கிறேன்.",
        "ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு வசதிகள், மாவட்ட அளவில் தரச் சான்றிதழ் மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி சந்தைகளுக்கான இணைப்பு போன்ற மிகக் குறைவான வணிக மேம்பாட்டு சேவைகள் மட்டுமே உள்ளன என்று சிலர் கூறினர். பெரும்பாலான SMEகள் சலுகை நிதியை அணுகுவதில் உள்ள சிரமத்தை பற்றி கூறுகின்றன, இது வணிக வளர்ச்சிக்கு முக்கிய தடையாக உள்ளது. SME களால் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மற்றொரு விஷயம் என்னவென்றால், ஒரு வருடத்தில் ஒரு வங்கிக்கு கிட்டத்தட்ட 60 வகையான வரிகள் செலுத்தப்பட வேண்டும், இது மிகவும் சிக்கலானது மற்றும் நேரத்தை எடுத்துக்கொள்ளும் மற்றும் கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டிய முன்னுரிமைப் பொருளாக இருக்க வேண்டும். ஒரு பொதுவான SME திறமைக்காக நீட்டிக்கப்படுவது, இந்த தொன்மையான வரி முறைகள் நிறுவனத்தின் உற்பத்தித்திறனை பாதிக்கிறது என்று சிலர் கூறினர்.",
        "அனைத்துக் கட்சி நிர்வாகக் கட்டமைப்பை அமைப்பதற்கு இலங்கை போராடிக்கொண்டிருக்கும் வேளையில், SME துறைக்காக அர்ப்பணிப்புள்ள அமைச்சகத்தை அமைக்கும் பொதுத்துறையில் சீர்திருத்தங்களைத் தொடங்குவது விவேகமானதாக இருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "75%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜா-எல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன் டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "90%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "68%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $11 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "300 கிலோ மில்லியன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் அரை ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1952",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1960கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறு தொழில் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐஎஸ்ஐஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈடிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.எஸ்.ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜவுளி துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEDA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DFCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
