{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Islamic-Republic-of-Iran-pledges-medical-assistance-to-Sri-Lanka/56-736660",
  "time_ut": 1656096402,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Islamic Republic of Iran pledges medical assistance to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Islamic Republic of Iran pledges medical assistance to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Islamic Republic of Iran has pledged urgently needed medical assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "Vipulatheja Wishwanath Aponsu met several key dignitaries including Health Deputy Minister Dr. Mohammed Hossein Niknam, Foreign Ministry of Iran Director General (West Asia) Dr. Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi and Head of the Iranian Red Crescent Society (IRCS) Dr. Pir Hossein Kolivandon recently at their offices in Tehran.",
        "The main objective of the meetings were to develop collaboration in health and pharmaceutical sectors between Sri Lanka and Iran under the framework of South-South cooperation.",
        "While appreciating Iran’s continued assistance to Sri Lanka, the Sri Lankan envoy outlined the current challenges in Sri Lanka particularly the lack of pharmaceuticals and medical utilities.",
        "Highlighting the longstanding friendly relations between Iran and Sri Lanka, the Iranian dignitaries assured that the Government of Iran would continue extending assistance to Sri Lanka in every possible way to overcome the current challenges in Sri Lanka.",
        "In response to the Ambassador’s request on urgent requirement of medical equipment, Head of the IRCS conveyed that his organisation will able to offer medical aid to Sri Lanka after reviewing Sri Lanka’s needs.",
        "Further, the Iranian key personnel expressed that the Islamic Republic of Iran is ready to provide medical education and trainings, medical equipment and pharmaceuticals items to Sri Lanka. They also stated that Iran is willing to invest in health and pharmaceutical sectors in Sri Lanka.",
        "The Head of IRCS Dr. Kolivand stated that if Sri Lanka is interested in obtaining health services, the IRCS can dispatch its health team to Sri Lanka as appropriate for treatment of patients who are in unprivileged areas. The Sri Lanka Ambassador Aponsu assured them to bring the Iranian proposals to the attention of health authorities in Sri Lanka for consideration.",
        "The Ambassador thanked the above dignitaries for facilitating the productive deliberations and conveyed the deep appreciation of the Government of Sri Lanka to Iran’s pledge of donation of medical aid.",
        "Expert (West Asia) of the Iranian Foreign Ministry Mohomad Deldhari was also present at the discussions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Islamic Republic of Iran",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Islamic Republic of Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed Hossein Niknam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry of Iran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Iranian Red Crescent Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pir Hossein Kolivandon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tehran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iranian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Iran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iranian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Islamic Republic of Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kolivand",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aponsu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iranian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "West Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Iranian Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohomad Deldhari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය ආධාර ලබා දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කඩිනමින් වෛද්‍ය ආධාර ලබා දෙන බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත.",
        "Vipulatheja Wishwanath Aponsu මහතා සෞඛ්‍ය නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය වෛද්‍ය Mohammed Hossein Niknam, ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් (බටහිර ආසියාව) Dr Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi සහ ඉරාන රතු ක්‍රෙසන්ට් සංගමයේ (IRCS) ප්‍රධානී Dr Pir Hossein Kolivandon ඇතුළු ප්‍රධාන සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු පසුගියදා හමුවිය. ටෙහෙරානයේ ඔවුන්ගේ කාර්යාල.",
        "දකුණු-දකුණු සහයෝගීතාවයේ රාමුව යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඉරානය අතර සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ඖෂධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සහයෝගීතාව වර්ධනය කිරීම මෙම රැස්වීම්වල ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ විය.",
        "ඉරානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදෙන අඛණ්ඩ සහය අගය කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අභියෝග විශේෂයෙන්ම ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය උපයෝගිතා හිඟය ගෙනහැර දැක්වීය.",
        "ඉරානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර දීර්ඝ කාලීන මිත්‍ර සබඳතා ඉස්මතු කළ ඉරාන සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා ඉරාන රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි සෑම ආකාරයකින්ම අඛණ්ඩව සහය ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය.",
        "හදිසි වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ අවශ්‍යතාවය පිළිබඳ තානාපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලීමට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් IRCS හි ප්‍රධානියා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අවශ්‍යතා සමාලෝචනය කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය ආධාර පිරිනැමීමට තම සංවිධානයට හැකි බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "තවද, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය අධ්‍යාපනය සහ පුහුණුව, වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ සහ ඖෂධ ද්‍රව්‍ය ලබාදීමට ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය සූදානම් බව ඉරාන ප්‍රධාන පිරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කළහ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ඖෂධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ආයෝජනය කිරීමට ඉරානය කැමැත්තෙන් සිටින බවද ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා ලබාගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උනන්දු වන්නේ නම්, වරප්‍රසාද නොමැති ප්‍රදේශවල සිටින රෝගීන්ට ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම සඳහා සුදුසු පරිදි IRCS ආයතනයට තම සෞඛ්‍ය කණ්ඩායම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එවිය හැකි බව IRCS ප්‍රධානී වෛද්‍ය Kolivand ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ඉරාන යෝජනා සලකා බැලීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන්ගේ අවධානයට යොමු කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති අපොන්සු ඔවුන්ට සහතික විය.",
        "ඵලදායී සාකච්ඡා සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීම පිළිබඳව තානාපතිවරයා ඉහත සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන්ට ස්තූතිය පුද කළ අතර ඉරානයේ වෛද්‍ය ආධාර පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඥාව වෙත ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ගැඹුරු ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළේය.",
        "මෙම සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ විශේෂඥ (බටහිර ආසියාව) මොහොමඩ් ඩෙල්ධාරි ද සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් හොසේන් නික්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙයිද් රසූල් මුසාවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන රතු ක්‍රෙසන්ට් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pir Hossein Kolivandon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙහෙරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොලිවාන්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aponsu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් දෙල්ධාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு மருத்துவ உதவிகளை வழங்குவதாக ஈரான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசு உறுதியளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசு இலங்கைக்கு அவசரமாக மருத்துவ உதவி வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "விபுலதேஜ விஷ்வநாத் அபோன்சு, சுகாதார பிரதி அமைச்சர் டாக்டர் மொஹமட் ஹொசைன் நிக்னம், ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் (மேற்கு ஆசியா) டாக்டர் செயிட் ரசூல் மௌசவி மற்றும் ஈரானிய செம்பிறை சங்கத்தின் (IRCS) தலைவர் டாக்டர் பிர் ஹொசைன் கோலிவாண்டன் உட்பட பல முக்கிய பிரமுகர்களை அண்மையில் சந்தித்தார். தெஹ்ரானில் உள்ள அவர்களின் அலுவலகங்கள்.",
        "தென்-தெற்கு ஒத்துழைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கும் ஈரானுக்கும் இடையில் சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் மருந்துத் துறைகளில் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவதே சந்திப்புகளின் முக்கிய நோக்கமாகும்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஈரானின் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவிகளைப் பாராட்டிய இலங்கைத் தூதுவர், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சவால்களை குறிப்பாக மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் மருத்துவப் பயன்பாடுகளின் பற்றாக்குறையை கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார்.",
        "ஈரானுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான நீண்டகால நட்புறவுகளை எடுத்துரைத்த ஈரானிய பிரமுகர்கள், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சவால்களை வெற்றிகொள்வதற்கு ஈரான் அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு சகல வழிகளிலும் தொடர்ந்து உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என உறுதியளித்தனர்.",
        "மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களின் அவசரத் தேவை குறித்த தூதுவரின் கோரிக்கைக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில், IRCS இன் தலைவர், இலங்கையின் தேவைகளை மீளாய்வு செய்ததன் பின்னர் தனது அமைப்பு இலங்கைக்கு மருத்துவ உதவிகளை வழங்க முடியும் என்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், இலங்கைக்கு மருத்துவக் கல்வி மற்றும் பயிற்சிகள், மருத்துவ உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பொருட்களை வழங்க ஈரான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசு தயாராக இருப்பதாக ஈரானிய முக்கியப் பணியாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். இலங்கையில் சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் மருந்துத் துறைகளில் முதலீடு செய்ய ஈரான் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சுகாதார சேவைகளைப் பெறுவதில் இலங்கை ஆர்வமாக இருந்தால், வசதியற்ற பகுதிகளில் உள்ள நோயாளிகளுக்கு சிகிச்சை அளிப்பதற்காக IRCS தனது சுகாதாரக் குழுவை இலங்கைக்கு அனுப்ப முடியும் என்று IRCS இன் தலைவர் டாக்டர் கோலிவண்ட் தெரிவித்தார். ஈரானிய முன்மொழிவுகளை இலங்கையில் உள்ள சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளின் கவனத்திற்கு கொண்டு வந்து பரிசீலிப்பதாக இலங்கை தூதுவர் அபோன்சு உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "ஆக்கபூர்வமான கலந்துரையாடல்களை எளிதாக்கியதற்காக மேற்கண்ட உயரதிகாரிகளுக்கு தூதுவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்ததுடன், ஈரானின் மருத்துவ உதவிகளை நன்கொடையாக வழங்கும் உறுதிமொழிக்கு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆழ்ந்த பாராட்டுகளையும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் நிபுணர் (மேற்கு ஆசியா) முகமது டெல்தாரியும் கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்து கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமிய குடியரசு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமிய குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது ஹொசைன் நிக்னம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்யித் ரசூல் மௌசவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய ரெட் கிரசண்ட் சொசைட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிர் ஹொசைன் கோலிவாண்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஆர்சிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமிய குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஆர்சிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோலிவந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஆர்சிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aponsu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது டெல்தாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Islamic Republic of Iran pledges medical assistance to Sri Lanka",
  "body_lines": [
    "The Islamic Republic of Iran has pledged urgently needed medical assistance to Sri Lanka.",
    "Vipulatheja Wishwanath Aponsu met several key dignitaries including Health Deputy Minister Dr. Mohammed Hossein Niknam, Foreign Ministry of Iran Director General (West Asia) Dr. Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi and Head of the Iranian Red Crescent Society (IRCS) Dr. Pir Hossein Kolivandon recently at their offices in Tehran.",
    "The main objective of the meetings were to develop collaboration in health and pharmaceutical sectors between Sri Lanka and Iran under the framework of South-South cooperation.",
    "While appreciating Iran’s continued assistance to Sri Lanka, the Sri Lankan envoy outlined the current challenges in Sri Lanka particularly the lack of pharmaceuticals and medical utilities.",
    "Highlighting the longstanding friendly relations between Iran and Sri Lanka, the Iranian dignitaries assured that the Government of Iran would continue extending assistance to Sri Lanka in every possible way to overcome the current challenges in Sri Lanka.",
    "In response to the Ambassador’s request on urgent requirement of medical equipment, Head of the IRCS conveyed that his organisation will able to offer medical aid to Sri Lanka after reviewing Sri Lanka’s needs.",
    "Further, the Iranian key personnel expressed that the Islamic Republic of Iran is ready to provide medical education and trainings, medical equipment and pharmaceuticals items to Sri Lanka. They also stated that Iran is willing to invest in health and pharmaceutical sectors in Sri Lanka.",
    "The Head of IRCS Dr. Kolivand stated that if Sri Lanka is interested in obtaining health services, the IRCS can dispatch its health team to Sri Lanka as appropriate for treatment of patients who are in unprivileged areas. The Sri Lanka Ambassador Aponsu assured them to bring the Iranian proposals to the attention of health authorities in Sri Lanka for consideration.",
    "The Ambassador thanked the above dignitaries for facilitating the productive deliberations and conveyed the deep appreciation of the Government of Sri Lanka to Iran’s pledge of donation of medical aid.",
    "Expert (West Asia) of the Iranian Foreign Ministry Mohomad Deldhari was also present at the discussions."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Islamic Republic of Iran pledges medical assistance to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Islamic Republic of Iran has pledged urgently needed medical assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "Vipulatheja Wishwanath Aponsu met several key dignitaries including Health Deputy Minister Dr. Mohammed Hossein Niknam, Foreign Ministry of Iran Director General (West Asia) Dr. Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi and Head of the Iranian Red Crescent Society (IRCS) Dr. Pir Hossein Kolivandon recently at their offices in Tehran.",
        "The main objective of the meetings were to develop collaboration in health and pharmaceutical sectors between Sri Lanka and Iran under the framework of South-South cooperation.",
        "While appreciating Iran’s continued assistance to Sri Lanka, the Sri Lankan envoy outlined the current challenges in Sri Lanka particularly the lack of pharmaceuticals and medical utilities.",
        "Highlighting the longstanding friendly relations between Iran and Sri Lanka, the Iranian dignitaries assured that the Government of Iran would continue extending assistance to Sri Lanka in every possible way to overcome the current challenges in Sri Lanka.",
        "In response to the Ambassador’s request on urgent requirement of medical equipment, Head of the IRCS conveyed that his organisation will able to offer medical aid to Sri Lanka after reviewing Sri Lanka’s needs.",
        "Further, the Iranian key personnel expressed that the Islamic Republic of Iran is ready to provide medical education and trainings, medical equipment and pharmaceuticals items to Sri Lanka. They also stated that Iran is willing to invest in health and pharmaceutical sectors in Sri Lanka.",
        "The Head of IRCS Dr. Kolivand stated that if Sri Lanka is interested in obtaining health services, the IRCS can dispatch its health team to Sri Lanka as appropriate for treatment of patients who are in unprivileged areas. The Sri Lanka Ambassador Aponsu assured them to bring the Iranian proposals to the attention of health authorities in Sri Lanka for consideration.",
        "The Ambassador thanked the above dignitaries for facilitating the productive deliberations and conveyed the deep appreciation of the Government of Sri Lanka to Iran’s pledge of donation of medical aid.",
        "Expert (West Asia) of the Iranian Foreign Ministry Mohomad Deldhari was also present at the discussions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Islamic Republic of Iran",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Islamic Republic of Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed Hossein Niknam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry of Iran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Iranian Red Crescent Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pir Hossein Kolivandon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tehran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iranian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Iran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iranian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Islamic Republic of Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kolivand",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aponsu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iranian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "West Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Iranian Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohomad Deldhari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය ආධාර ලබා දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කඩිනමින් වෛද්‍ය ආධාර ලබා දෙන බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත.",
        "Vipulatheja Wishwanath Aponsu මහතා සෞඛ්‍ය නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය වෛද්‍ය Mohammed Hossein Niknam, ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් (බටහිර ආසියාව) Dr Seyyed Rasoul Mousavi සහ ඉරාන රතු ක්‍රෙසන්ට් සංගමයේ (IRCS) ප්‍රධානී Dr Pir Hossein Kolivandon ඇතුළු ප්‍රධාන සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු පසුගියදා හමුවිය. ටෙහෙරානයේ ඔවුන්ගේ කාර්යාල.",
        "දකුණු-දකුණු සහයෝගීතාවයේ රාමුව යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඉරානය අතර සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ඖෂධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සහයෝගීතාව වර්ධනය කිරීම මෙම රැස්වීම්වල ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ විය.",
        "ඉරානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදෙන අඛණ්ඩ සහය අගය කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අභියෝග විශේෂයෙන්ම ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය උපයෝගිතා හිඟය ගෙනහැර දැක්වීය.",
        "ඉරානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර දීර්ඝ කාලීන මිත්‍ර සබඳතා ඉස්මතු කළ ඉරාන සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා ඉරාන රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි සෑම ආකාරයකින්ම අඛණ්ඩව සහය ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය.",
        "හදිසි වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ අවශ්‍යතාවය පිළිබඳ තානාපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලීමට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් IRCS හි ප්‍රධානියා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අවශ්‍යතා සමාලෝචනය කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය ආධාර පිරිනැමීමට තම සංවිධානයට හැකි බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "තවද, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය අධ්‍යාපනය සහ පුහුණුව, වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ සහ ඖෂධ ද්‍රව්‍ය ලබාදීමට ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය සූදානම් බව ඉරාන ප්‍රධාන පිරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කළහ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ඖෂධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ආයෝජනය කිරීමට ඉරානය කැමැත්තෙන් සිටින බවද ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා ලබාගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උනන්දු වන්නේ නම්, වරප්‍රසාද නොමැති ප්‍රදේශවල සිටින රෝගීන්ට ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම සඳහා සුදුසු පරිදි IRCS ආයතනයට තම සෞඛ්‍ය කණ්ඩායම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එවිය හැකි බව IRCS ප්‍රධානී වෛද්‍ය Kolivand ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ඉරාන යෝජනා සලකා බැලීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන්ගේ අවධානයට යොමු කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති අපොන්සු ඔවුන්ට සහතික විය.",
        "ඵලදායී සාකච්ඡා සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීම පිළිබඳව තානාපතිවරයා ඉහත සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන්ට ස්තූතිය පුද කළ අතර ඉරානයේ වෛද්‍ය ආධාර පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඥාව වෙත ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ගැඹුරු ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළේය.",
        "මෙම සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ විශේෂඥ (බටහිර ආසියාව) මොහොමඩ් ඩෙල්ධාරි ද සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් හොසේන් නික්නම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙයිද් රසූල් මුසාවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන රතු ක්‍රෙසන්ට් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pir Hossein Kolivandon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙහෙරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොලිවාන්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aponsu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් දෙල්ධාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு மருத்துவ உதவிகளை வழங்குவதாக ஈரான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசு உறுதியளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசு இலங்கைக்கு அவசரமாக மருத்துவ உதவி வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "விபுலதேஜ விஷ்வநாத் அபோன்சு, சுகாதார பிரதி அமைச்சர் டாக்டர் மொஹமட் ஹொசைன் நிக்னம், ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் (மேற்கு ஆசியா) டாக்டர் செயிட் ரசூல் மௌசவி மற்றும் ஈரானிய செம்பிறை சங்கத்தின் (IRCS) தலைவர் டாக்டர் பிர் ஹொசைன் கோலிவாண்டன் உட்பட பல முக்கிய பிரமுகர்களை அண்மையில் சந்தித்தார். தெஹ்ரானில் உள்ள அவர்களின் அலுவலகங்கள்.",
        "தென்-தெற்கு ஒத்துழைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கும் ஈரானுக்கும் இடையில் சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் மருந்துத் துறைகளில் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவதே சந்திப்புகளின் முக்கிய நோக்கமாகும்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஈரானின் தொடர்ச்சியான உதவிகளைப் பாராட்டிய இலங்கைத் தூதுவர், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சவால்களை குறிப்பாக மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் மருத்துவப் பயன்பாடுகளின் பற்றாக்குறையை கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார்.",
        "ஈரானுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான நீண்டகால நட்புறவுகளை எடுத்துரைத்த ஈரானிய பிரமுகர்கள், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சவால்களை வெற்றிகொள்வதற்கு ஈரான் அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு சகல வழிகளிலும் தொடர்ந்து உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என உறுதியளித்தனர்.",
        "மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களின் அவசரத் தேவை குறித்த தூதுவரின் கோரிக்கைக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில், IRCS இன் தலைவர், இலங்கையின் தேவைகளை மீளாய்வு செய்ததன் பின்னர் தனது அமைப்பு இலங்கைக்கு மருத்துவ உதவிகளை வழங்க முடியும் என்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், இலங்கைக்கு மருத்துவக் கல்வி மற்றும் பயிற்சிகள், மருத்துவ உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பொருட்களை வழங்க ஈரான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசு தயாராக இருப்பதாக ஈரானிய முக்கியப் பணியாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். இலங்கையில் சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் மருந்துத் துறைகளில் முதலீடு செய்ய ஈரான் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சுகாதார சேவைகளைப் பெறுவதில் இலங்கை ஆர்வமாக இருந்தால், வசதியற்ற பகுதிகளில் உள்ள நோயாளிகளுக்கு சிகிச்சை அளிப்பதற்காக IRCS தனது சுகாதாரக் குழுவை இலங்கைக்கு அனுப்ப முடியும் என்று IRCS இன் தலைவர் டாக்டர் கோலிவண்ட் தெரிவித்தார். ஈரானிய முன்மொழிவுகளை இலங்கையில் உள்ள சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளின் கவனத்திற்கு கொண்டு வந்து பரிசீலிப்பதாக இலங்கை தூதுவர் அபோன்சு உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "ஆக்கபூர்வமான கலந்துரையாடல்களை எளிதாக்கியதற்காக மேற்கண்ட உயரதிகாரிகளுக்கு தூதுவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்ததுடன், ஈரானின் மருத்துவ உதவிகளை நன்கொடையாக வழங்கும் உறுதிமொழிக்கு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆழ்ந்த பாராட்டுகளையும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் நிபுணர் (மேற்கு ஆசியா) முகமது டெல்தாரியும் கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்து கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமிய குடியரசு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமிய குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது ஹொசைன் நிக்னம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்யித் ரசூல் மௌசவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய ரெட் கிரசண்ட் சொசைட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிர் ஹொசைன் கோலிவாண்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஆர்சிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் இஸ்லாமிய குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஆர்சிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோலிவந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஆர்சிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aponsu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரானிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது டெல்தாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}