{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/15/sri-lankan-underworld-don-s-shooter-arrested/",
  "time_ut": 1660536180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan underworld Don’s shooter arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan underworld Don’s shooter arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A shooter working for notorious underworld don 'Harak Kata' was arrested by Sri Lanka Police on Sunday (14) night in Boralesgamuwa.",
        "Notorious Underworld Criminal Gang leader Naduna Chinthaka aka 'Harak Kata' was arrested in Dubai, confirmed Sri Lanka's  Public Security Ministry on Sunday (14).",
        "Sri Lanka Police said that the 27-year-old suspect identified as Prabodha Kumara alias 'Kadira' was arrested from a house in Boralesgamuwa, and Police said that he was using the location as a safe house to carry out a contract issued by 'Harak Kata'.",
        "'Kadira' is connected to a series of crimes, said Sri Lanka Police adding that the suspect on the instructions of 'Harak Kata' shot and injured two men in Weligama identified as 'Chooti Mama' and Roshan alias 'Jacka'.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said that the suspect was wanted for rape, murder, and theft, and seized a locally manufactured firearm, three live rounds, and 17 grams of heroin from the possession of the suspect.",
        "The suspect was handed over to the Matara Crimes Prevention Division for further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boralesgamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naduna Chinthaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabodha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boralesgamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kadira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harak Kata'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weligama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Matara Crimes Prevention Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාතාල දොන් වෙඩික්කරු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කුප්‍රකට පාතාල නායක 'හරක් කට' වෙනුවෙන් සේවය කරන වෙඩික්කරුවෙකු ඉරිදා (14) රාත්‍රියේ බොරලැස්ගමුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "කුප්‍රකට පාතාල අපරාධ කල්ලි නායක නඳුන චින්තක හෙවත් 'හරක් කට' ඩුබායිහිදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ  මහජන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය ඉරිදා (14) තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රබෝධ කුමාර නොහොත් ‘කදිර’ නමැති 27 හැවිරිදි සැකකරු බොරලැස්ගමුව ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසකින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර, ඔහු එම ස්ථානය ‘හරක්’ විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද කොන්ත්‍රාත්තුවක් සඳහා ආරක්‍ෂිත නිවසක් ලෙස භාවිත කරමින් සිටි බව පොලිසිය පවසයි. කට'.",
        "‘කදිර’ අපරාධ රැසකට සම්බන්ධ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේ ‘හරක් කට’ ගේ උපදෙස් මත සැකකරු වැලිගමදී වෙඩි තබා තුවාල කළ ‘චූටි මාමා’ සහ රොෂාන් නොහොත් ‘ජැකා’ යන දෙදෙනෙකි.",
        "සැකකරු ස්ත්‍රී දූෂණය, මිනීමැරීම සහ සොරකම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍යව සිටි අයෙකු බවත්, සැකකරු සන්තකයේ තිබී මෙරට නිෂ්පාදිත ගිනි අවියක්, ජීව උණ්ඩ තුනක් සහ හෙරොයින් ග්‍රෑම් 17ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "සැකකරු වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සඳහා මාතර අපරාධ නිවාරණ කොට්ඨාශය වෙත භාරදී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරලැස්ගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නඳුන චින්තක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රබෝධ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කදිරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරලැස්ගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කදිරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරක් කට'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 17 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර අපරාධ නිවාරණ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பாதாள உலக டான் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பிரபல பாதாள உலக தாதாவான ஹரக் கட்டாவுக்காக பணிபுரியும் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் பொரலஸ்கமுவவில் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (14) இரவு இலங்கை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பிரபல பாதாள உலகக் குற்றக் கும்பலின் தலைவன் நடுன சிந்தகா அல்லது 'ஹரக் கட்டா' துபாயில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக இலங்கையின்  பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (14) உறுதிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "பொரலஸ்கமுவவில் உள்ள வீடொன்றில் இருந்து 27 வயதுடைய பிரபோத குமார எனப்படும் 'கதீரா' என்ற சந்தேகநபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்ததுடன், ஹரக் வழங்கிய ஒப்பந்தத்தை மேற்கொள்வதற்காக அவர் அந்த இடத்தை பாதுகாப்பான வீடாக பயன்படுத்தியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். கேட்டா'.",
        "'கதீரா' தொடர் குற்றச்செயல்களுடன் தொடர்புடையவர், ஹரக் கட்டாவின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் சந்தேகநபர் வெலிகமவில் 'சூட்டி மாமா' மற்றும் 'ஜாக்கா' என அழைக்கப்படும் ரொஷான் ஆகிய இருவரை சுட்டுக் காயப்படுத்தியதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் கற்பழிப்பு, கொலை மற்றும் திருட்டு போன்ற குற்றங்களுக்காக தேடப்பட்டு வந்தவர் என்றும், சந்தேகநபரிடம் இருந்து உள்நாட்டில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கி, மூன்று துப்பாக்கிகள் மற்றும் 17 கிராம் ஹெரோயின் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டதாகவும் இலங்கை போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக மாத்தறை குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரலஸ்கமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நடுன சிந்தகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபோதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரலஸ்கமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கதிரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரக் கட்டா'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}