{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/04/cbk-to-open-nawa-lanka-freedom-party-office/",
  "time_ut": 1662273900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CBK to open Nawa Lanka Freedom Party Office",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CBK to open Nawa Lanka Freedom Party Office",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The party office of the Nawa Lnka Freedom Party, led by MP Kumara Welgama, is due to be opened on Monday (5).",
        "The new party office will be opened by former President Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga.",
        "Parliamentarian Welgama said that the new party office will be established in Battaramulla, and said that youth below the age of 40 will be trained, and will be made into a corruption-free, youth political movement in the future."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nawa Lanka Freedom Party Office",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nawa Lnka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Welgama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 40",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ කාර්යාලය විවෘත කිරීමට සී.බී.කේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ කාර්යාලය සඳුදා (5) විවෘත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "නව පක්ෂ කාර්යාලය හිටපු ජනාධිපතිනි චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක කුමාරතුංග මහත්මිය අතින් විවෘත කෙරේ.",
        "නව පක්ෂ කාර්යාලය බත්තරමුල්ලේ ආරම්භ කරන බව පැවසූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෙල්ගම, වයස අවුරුදු 40ට අඩු තරුණ තරුණියන් පුහුණු කර ඉදිරියේදී දූෂණයෙන් තොර තරුණ දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් බවට පත් කරන බවද පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 40 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நவ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி அலுவலகத்தை திறக்க சி.பி.கே",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கம தலைமையிலான நாவ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் கட்சி அலுவலகம் திங்கட்கிழமை (5) திறந்து வைக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "புதிய கட்சி அலுவலகம் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்கவினால் திறந்து வைக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "பத்தரமுல்லையில் புதிய கட்சி அலுவலகம் அமைக்கப்படும் என தெரிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வெல்கம, 40 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட இளைஞர்களுக்கு பயிற்சியளிக்கப்பட்டு, எதிர்காலத்தில் ஊழலற்ற இளைஞர் அரசியல் இயக்கமாக உருவாக்கப்படும் என்றும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நவ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி அலுவலகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாவ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வெல்கம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயது 40",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}