{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අර්බුදයෙන්-මිදෙන්න-ලංකාවට-නොමද-සහාය-දෙනවා/11-396670",
  "time_ut": 1661681797,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අර්බුදයෙන් මිදෙන්න ලංකාවට නොමද සහාය දෙනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "They are supporting Sri Lanka to get out of the crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Chi Shenhong, the Chinese Ambassador, said in Kandy that the Chinese government will continue to support Sri Lanka in order to rescue Sri Lanka from the temporary economic crisis it is currently facing.",
        "He came to Kandy yesterday (27) and visited the Malwatu Asgiri elders and emphasized that in the media and further said:",
        "\"Although the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka will not end overnight, it is the belief of the Chinese government that Sri Lanka has the ability to get out of it within a short and reasonable period of time. In addition to the Chinese government's cooperation aid grant, the Chinese Buddhist Association has planned a program to provide aid for the revival of temples and Buddhism in this country.",
        "Although there have been various changes in Sri Lanka recently, there has been no change in the Sri Lanka-China friendship. The aim of the Chinese government is to maintain bilateral relations between the two countries. We believe that Sri Lanka has the ability to get out of the difficult situation. The Chinese government also supports it.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Buddhist Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka-China",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදයෙන් මිදෙන්න ලංකාවට නොමද සහාය දෙනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වන විට මුහුණ දී තිබෙන තාවකාලික ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන් මුදවා ගැනීම සඳහා චීන රජයේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය හිමිවන බව චීන තානාපති චී ෂෙන්හොං මහතා මහනුවර දී පැවසීය .",
        "ඒ මහතා ඊයේ (27)  මහනුවරට පැමිණ මල්වතු අස්ගිරි මහනාහිමිවරුන් බැහැදැක මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ ඒ බව අවධාරණය කරමින් වැඩිදුරටත් මෙසේ පැවසීය .",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මේ වන පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය එක් රැයකින් නිමා නොවුනත් කෙටි සාධාරණ කාලයක් තුළදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන් මිදීමට හැකියාව පවතින බව චීන රජයේ විශ්වාසයයි . චීන රජයේ සහයෝගිතා ආධාර ප්‍රදානයට අමතරව චීන බෞද්ධ සංගමය මගින් මෙරට විහාරස්ථාන හා බුදු දහමේ පුනර්ජීවනය උදෙසා ආධාර ලබාදීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සැලසුම් කොට තිබෙනවා .",
        "ඉකුත් කාලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ විවිධ වෙනස්කම් සිදු වුවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා චීන මිත්‍රත්වය තුළ කිසිදු වෙනස්වීමක් සිදු වූයේ නැහැ. දෙරට අතර දී ද්විපාක්ෂික සම්බන්ධතා අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වා ගැනීම චීන රජයේ අරමුණයි. පවතින අසීරු තත්ත්වයෙන් මිදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකියාව තිබෙන බව අපගේ විශ්වාසයයි. එය සඳහා චීන රජයේ නොමද සහය පළ කරනවා”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන බෞද්ධ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව-චීනය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விடுபட இலங்கையை ஆதரிக்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கி வரும் தற்காலிக பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து இலங்கையை மீட்பதற்கு சீன அரசாங்கம் தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என சீன தூதுவர் திரு.சி ஷென்ஹோங் கண்டியில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நேற்று (27) கண்டிக்கு வந்த அவர், மல்வத்து அஸ்கிரிய பெரியவர்களைச் சந்தித்து, ஊடகங்களில் இதனை வலியுறுத்தி மேலும் தெரிவித்ததாவது:",
        "“இலங்கையில் தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி ஒரே இரவில் முடிவுக்கு வராது என்றாலும், குறுகிய மற்றும் நியாயமான காலத்திற்குள் அதிலிருந்து வெளியேறும் திறன் இலங்கைக்கு உள்ளது என்பது சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் நம்பிக்கை. சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் ஒத்துழைப்பு உதவி மானியத்திற்கு மேலதிகமாக, சீன பௌத்த சங்கம் இந்த நாட்டில் கோவில்கள் மற்றும் பௌத்தத்தின் மறுமலர்ச்சிக்கான உதவிகளை வழங்கும் திட்டத்தை திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அண்மைக்காலமாக இலங்கையில் பல்வேறு மாற்றங்கள் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும் இலங்கை-சீன நட்புறவில் எந்த மாற்றமும் ஏற்படவில்லை. இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை பேணுவதே சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் நோக்கமாகும். இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்து வெளியேறும் திறன் இலங்கைக்கு இருப்பதாக நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். சீன அரசும் இதற்கு ஆதரவளிக்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chi Shenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன புத்த சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-சீனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}