{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/caption_story/Navy-lends-helping-hand-to-devotees-engaged-in-Paada-Yaathra/110-242108",
  "time_ut": 1659242857,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy lends helping hand to devotees engaged in ‘Paada Yaathra’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy lends helping hand to devotees engaged in ‘Paada Yaathra’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Navy, as it has been the practice, is lending its helping hand to devotees who are engaged in foot pilgrimage, known as ‘Paada Yaathra’ along the route from the entrance of Kumana National Park to Kumbukkan Oya. The traditional foot pilgrimage marches from Jaffna to Sella Kataragama annually, with the participation of many devotees."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Paada Yaathra’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paada Yaathra’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumana National Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumbukkan Oya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාද යාත්‍රාවේ යෙදී සිටින බැතිමතුන්ට නාවික හමුදාවෙන් අත්වැලක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුමන ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානයේ පිවිසුමේ සිට කුඹුක්කන් ඔය දක්වා දිවෙන මාර්ගයේ ‘පාද යාත්‍රා’ නමින් හැඳින්වෙන පාද වන්දනාවේ යෙදී සිටින බැතිමතුන් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පුරුද්දක් ලෙස තම ආධාර උපකාර ලබාදෙයි. සාම්ප්‍රදායික පාද වන්දනාව වාර්ෂිකව බොහෝ බැතිමතුන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් යාපනයේ සිට සෙල්ලකතරගම දක්වා ගමන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාද යාත්‍රා'",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාද යාත්‍රා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමන ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුඹුක්කන් ඔය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாத யாத்திரையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள பக்தர்களுக்கு கடற்படை உதவி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குமண தேசிய பூங்காவின் நுழைவாயிலில் இருந்து கும்புக்கன் ஓயா வரையிலான பாதையில் பாத யாத்திரை எனப்படும் பாத யாத்திரையில் ஈடுபடும் பக்தர்களுக்கு இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் கைகொடுத்து வருகின்றனர். பாரம்பரிய பாத யாத்திரை யாழ்பாணத்தில் இருந்து செல்ல கதிர்காமம் வரை வருடந்தோறும் பல பக்தர்களின் பங்குபற்றுதலுடன் நடைப்பெற்று வருகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாத யாத்திரை’",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத யாத்திரை’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமண தேசிய பூங்கா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கும்புக்கன் ஓயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}