{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/world-food-program-to-continue-support-for-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1662132060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "World Food Program to continue support for Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "World Food Program to continue support for Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); World Food Programme (WFP) Regional Director for Asia and the Pacific John Aylieff, currently on a visit to Sri Lanka, paid a courtesy call on the Minister of Foreign Affairs, Ali Sabry on Thursday (1).",
        "The Foreign Minister appreciated the support extended by WFP to Sri Lanka over the past decades in many areas including the national health system by supporting national nutrition programs, the National School Meal Programme, in strengthening food systems to ensure access and availability of food and in developing shock-responsive safety net programs, particularly with the Department of Samurdhi.",
        "He apprised the Regional Director of the efforts taken by the Government of Sri Lanka in dialogue with all stakeholders including domestic and international partners, to emerge from the challenges facing the country.",
        "The Regional Director briefed the Foreign Minister on the progress of the ongoing WFP programs in the country, particularly the social safety net programs, and added that the WFP will continue to support and cooperate closely with the Government of Sri Lanka during this challenging time.",
        "It’s a good budget – Mahinda Rajapaksa on Budget Amendment 2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "World Food Program",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Food Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Aylieff",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National School Meal Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Samurdhi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Regional",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දැක්වීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහනේ (WFP) ආසියා සහ පැසිෆික් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජෝන් අයිලීෆ් මහතා දැනට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරතව සිටින අතර බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (1) විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "ජාතික පෝෂණ වැඩසටහන්, ජාතික පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන, ආහාර ප්‍රවේශය සහ ලබා ගැනීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ආහාර පද්ධති ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේදී සහ සංවර්ධනය කිරීමේදී ජාතික සෞඛ්‍ය පද්ධතිය ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවකට WFP විසින් පසුගිය දශක කිහිපය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් සහයෝගය විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් අගය කරන ලදී. විශේෂයෙන් සමෘද්ධි දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සමඟ කම්පනයට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වන ආරක්ෂිත දැල් වැඩසටහන්.",
        "රට මුහුණ දී සිටින අභියෝගවලින් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා දේශීය හා ජාත්‍යන්තර හවුල්කරුවන් ඇතුළු සියලුම පාර්ශ්වකරුවන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ගන්නා උත්සාහයන් පිළිබඳව ඔහු ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "රට තුළ දැනට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන WFP වැඩසටහන්වල ප්‍රගතිය, විශේෂයෙන්ම සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ ජාල වැඩසටහන්වල ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා දැනුවත් කළ අතර, මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාලය තුළ WFP ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සමඟ සමීපව සහයෝගය දැක්වීමට සහ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කරන බව පැවසීය.",
        "ඒක හොඳ අයවැයක් - මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ 2022 අයවැය සංශෝධනය ගැන"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් අයිලීෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශක කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමෘද්ධි දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලාපීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உலக உணவுத் திட்டம் இலங்கைக்கான ஆதரவைத் தொடரும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தற்போது இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ள உலக உணவுத் திட்டத்தின் (WFP) ஆசிய மற்றும் பசுபிக் பிராந்தியத்திற்கான பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் ஜோன் அய்லிஃப், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியை வியாழன் (1) சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "கடந்த தசாப்தங்களாக இலங்கைக்கு WFP வழங்கிய ஆதரவை, தேசிய ஊட்டச்சத்து திட்டங்கள், தேசிய பள்ளி உணவு திட்டம், உணவு முறைகளை வலுப்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் உணவு கிடைப்பதை உறுதி செய்தல் மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதில் தேசிய சுகாதார அமைப்பு உட்பட பல துறைகளில் வழங்கிய ஆதரவை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் பாராட்டினார். அதிர்ச்சி-பதிலளிக்கக்கூடிய பாதுகாப்பு வலைத் திட்டங்கள், குறிப்பாக சமுர்த்தி திணைக்களத்துடன்.",
        "நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்களில் இருந்து வெளிவருவதற்கு உள்நாட்டு மற்றும் சர்வதேச பங்காளிகள் உட்பட அனைத்து பங்குதாரர்களுடனும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் எடுத்த முயற்சிகள் குறித்து அவர் பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளரிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் நடைபெற்று வரும் WFP திட்டங்களின் முன்னேற்றம், குறிப்பாக சமூக பாதுகாப்பு வலையமைப்பு திட்டங்கள் குறித்து வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சருக்கு பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் விளக்கமளித்ததுடன், இந்த சவாலான நேரத்தில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்துடன் WFP தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளித்து ஒத்துழைக்கும் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "இது ஒரு நல்ல வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் - வரவு செலவுத் திருத்தம் 2022 இல் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் அய்லிஃப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பள்ளி உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமுர்த்தி திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிராந்தியமானது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}