{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/united-states-to-appoint-first-arctic-ambassador/",
  "time_ut": 1661597940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "United States to appoint first Arctic Ambassador",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "United States to appoint first Arctic Ambassador",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(BBC); The United States is planning to appoint an Ambassador for the Arctic, amid increased Russian military activity in the region.",
        "The Ambassador-at-Large will be put in place to advance US policy in the northern polar region, a Department of State spokesman said.",
        "On Friday, Nato chief Jens Stoltenberg warned of the threat posed by Russia in the northern polar regions.",
        "The new US ambassador will engage with the seven other Arctic nations – Canada, Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, and Russia – as well as indigenous groups and other stakeholders, said State Department spokesman Vedant Patel.",
        "Peace and stability in the region are of \"critical strategic importance\" to the US and a priority for Secretary of State Antony Blinken, he added.",
        "Blinken will soon name the ambassador, whose appointment is subject to Senate approval.",
        "The announcement comes as Russia steps up its presence near the North Pole, while China has been building Arctic research stations.",
        "Nato's Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg visited the Canadian Arctic on Friday, where he said Russia's capabilities in the North are a strategic challenge for the military alliance.",
        "He said the challenges include the reopening of \"hundreds of new and former Soviet-era Arctic military sites\" and Russia's use of the high north \"as a testbed for the most advanced weapons including hypersonic missiles\".",
        "Stoltenberg also expressed concern about China's reach into the Arctic for shipping and resources exploration.",
        "\"Beijing and Moscow have also pledged to intensify practical operations in the Arctic.",
        "This forms part of the deepening strategic partnership that challenges our values and our interests,\" he said.",
        "He also outlined how climate change is making the high north more important because melting ice is making the area more accessible.",
        "Lisa Murkowski, a Republican Senator for Alaska, welcomed the appointment of an Arctic Ambassador.",
        "She said the US had been the only Arctic nation without dedicated diplomatic representation for the region at the ambassador level.",
        "The new ambassador will replace the previous US position of Arctic Coordinator, held by career diplomat Jim DeHart."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "United States",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Arctic",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nato",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jens Stoltenberg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Denmark",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iceland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norway",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sweden",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vedant Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Antony Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Pole",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nato",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jens Stoltenberg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Stoltenberg",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lisa Murkowski",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Republican",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alaska",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arctic Coordinator",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jim DeHart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළමු ආක්ටික් තානාපතිවරයා පත් කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(බීබීසී); කලාපයේ රුසියානු හමුදා ක්‍රියාකාරකම් වැඩිවීම මධ්‍යයේ ආක්ටික් ප්‍රදේශය සඳහා තානාපතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය සැලසුම් කරයි.",
        "උතුරු ධ්‍රැව කලාපයේ එක්සත් ජනපද ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා තානාපතිවරයා පත් කරන බව රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "සිකුරාදා, නේටෝ ප්‍රධානී ජෙන්ස් ස්ටෝල්ටන්බර්ග්, උතුරු ධ්‍රැව ප්‍රදේශවල රුසියාවෙන් එල්ල කරන තර්ජනය ගැන අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "නව එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිවරයා අනෙකුත් ආක්ටික් ජාතීන් හත - කැනඩාව, ඩෙන්මාර්කය, ෆින්ලන්තය, අයිස්ලන්තය, නෝර්වේ, ස්වීඩනය සහ රුසියාව - මෙන්ම ස්වදේශික කණ්ඩායම් සහ අනෙකුත් පාර්ශවකරුවන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වනු ඇති බව රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශක වේදන්ට් පටෙල් පැවසීය.",
        "කලාපයේ සාමය සහ ස්ථාවරත්වය එක්සත් ජනපදයට \"විවේචනාත්මක උපායමාර්ගික වැදගත්කමක්\" වන අතර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන්ට ප්‍රමුඛතාවයක් වන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "බ්ලින්කන් ඉක්මනින්ම තානාපතිවරයා නම් කරනු ඇත, ඔහුගේ පත්වීම සෙනෙට් අනුමැතියට යටත් වේ.",
        "චීනය ආක්ටික් පර්යේෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථාන ගොඩනඟමින් සිටින අතර රුසියාව උත්තර ධ්‍රැවය ආසන්නයේ සිය පැවැත්ම වේගවත් කරන විට මෙම නිවේදනය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "නේටෝ මහලේකම් ජෙන්ස් ස්ටෝල්ටන්බර්ග් සිකුරාදා කැනේඩියානු ආක්ටික් ප්‍රදේශයට ගිය අතර එහිදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ උතුරේ රුසියාවේ හැකියාවන් මිලිටරි සන්ධානයට උපායමාර්ගික අභියෝගයක් බවයි.",
        "\"අලුත් සහ පැරණි සෝවියට් යුගයේ ආක්ටික් හමුදා ස්ථාන සිය ගණනක්\" නැවත විවෘත කිරීම සහ රුසියාව \"හයිපර්සොනික් මිසයිල ඇතුළු අති දියුණු ආයුධ සඳහා පරීක්ෂණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් ලෙස ඉහළ උතුර\" භාවිතා කිරීම අභියෝගවලට ඇතුළත් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නාවික ගමනාගමනය සහ සම්පත් ගවේෂණය සඳහා චීනය ආක්ටික් ප්‍රදේශයට ළඟාවීම පිළිබඳව ද ස්ටෝල්ටන්බර්ග් කනස්සල්ල පළ කළේය.",
        "\"බීජිං සහ මොස්කව් ආක්ටික් ප්‍රදේශයේ ප්‍රායෝගික මෙහෙයුම් තීව්‍ර කිරීමට ද ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත.",
        "මෙය අපගේ සාරධර්ම සහ අපගේ අවශ්‍යතාවලට අභියෝග කරන ගැඹුරු වන උපායමාර්ගික හවුල්කාරිත්වයේ කොටසකි, ”ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අයිස් දියවීම ප්‍රදේශයට වඩාත් ප්‍රවේශ විය හැකි බැවින් දේශගුණික විපර්යාස ඉහළ උතුර වඩාත් වැදගත් කරන්නේ කෙසේදැයි ඔහු විස්තර කළේය.",
        "ඇලස්කාවේ රිපබ්ලිකන් සෙනෙට් සභික ලීසා මුර්කොව්ස්කි ආක්ටික් තානාපතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීම පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "තානාපති මට්ටමින් කලාපය සඳහා කැපවූ රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික නියෝජනයක් නොමැති එකම ආක්ටික් ජාතිය එක්සත් ජනපදය බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "නව තානාපතිවරයා වෘත්තීය රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයෙකු වන ජිම් ඩීහාර්ට් විසින් දරන ලද ආක්ටික් සම්බන්ධීකාරක ලෙස මීට පෙර එක්සත් ජනපදයේ තනතුර ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආක්ටික්",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙන්ස් ස්ටෝල්ටන්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෙන්මාර්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆින්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයිස්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේදාන්ත පටෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Blinken",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උත්තර ධ්‍රැවය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නේටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙන්ස් ස්ටෝල්ටන්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්ටෝල්ටන්බර්ග්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලීසා මුර්කොව්ස්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිපබ්ලිකන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලස්කාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආක්ටික් සම්බන්ධීකාරක",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිම් ඩිහාර්ට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முதல் ஆர்க்டிக் தூதரை அமெரிக்கா நியமிக்க உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(பிபிசி); ஆர்க்டிக் பகுதியில் ரஷ்ய ராணுவ நடவடிக்கை அதிகரித்துள்ள நிலையில், அந்த பகுதிக்கான தூதரை நியமிக்க அமெரிக்கா திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வடக்கு துருவப் பிராந்தியத்தில் அமெரிக்காவின் கொள்கையை முன்னெடுப்பதற்காக தூதுவர்-அட்-லார்ஜ் வைக்கப்படும் என்று வெளியுறவுத்துறை செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெள்ளியன்று, நேட்டோ தலைவர் ஜென்ஸ் ஸ்டோல்டன்பெர்க், வடக்கு துருவப் பகுதிகளில் ரஷ்யாவால் ஏற்படும் அச்சுறுத்தல் குறித்து எச்சரித்தார்.",
        "புதிய அமெரிக்க தூதர் கனடா, டென்மார்க், பின்லாந்து, ஐஸ்லாந்து, நார்வே, ஸ்வீடன் மற்றும் ரஷ்யா ஆகிய ஏழு ஆர்க்டிக் நாடுகளுடனும், உள்நாட்டு குழுக்கள் மற்றும் பிற பங்குதாரர்களுடனும் ஈடுபடுவார் என்று வெளியுறவுத்துறை செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் வேதாந்த் படேல் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பிராந்தியத்தில் அமைதி மற்றும் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை அமெரிக்காவிற்கு \"முக்கியமான மூலோபாய முக்கியத்துவம்\" மற்றும் வெளியுறவு செயலாளர் ஆண்டனி பிளிங்கனுக்கு முன்னுரிமை, அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "பிளிங்கன் விரைவில் தூதரை பெயரிடுவார், அவருடைய நியமனம் செனட் ஒப்புதலுக்கு உட்பட்டது.",
        "ஆர்க்டிக் ஆராய்ச்சி நிலையங்களை சீனா கட்டி வரும் நிலையில், வட துருவத்திற்கு அருகே ரஷ்யா தனது இருப்பை முடுக்கிவிட்ட நிலையில் இந்த அறிவிப்பு வந்துள்ளது.",
        "நேட்டோவின் பொதுச்செயலாளர் ஜென்ஸ் ஸ்டோல்டன்பெர்க் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை கனேடிய ஆர்க்டிக்கிற்கு விஜயம் செய்தார், அங்கு அவர் வடக்கில் ரஷ்யாவின் திறன்கள் இராணுவக் கூட்டணிக்கு ஒரு மூலோபாய சவால் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "\"நூற்றுக்கணக்கான புதிய மற்றும் முன்னாள் சோவியத் கால ஆர்க்டிக் இராணுவ தளங்களை\" மீண்டும் திறப்பது மற்றும் ரஷ்யாவின் உயர் வடக்கை \"ஹைப்பர்சோனிக் ஏவுகணைகள் உட்பட மிகவும் மேம்பட்ட ஆயுதங்களுக்கான சோதனைக் களமாக\" பயன்படுத்துவது ஆகியவை சவால்களில் அடங்கும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்டோல்டன்பெர்க் ஆர்க்டிக்கில் கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் வளங்களை ஆராய்வதற்காக சீனா சென்றடைவது குறித்தும் கவலை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பெய்ஜிங் மற்றும் மாஸ்கோ ஆர்க்டிக்கில் நடைமுறை நடவடிக்கைகளை தீவிரப்படுத்த உறுதியளித்துள்ளன.",
        "இது நமது மதிப்புகள் மற்றும் எங்கள் நலன்களை சவால் செய்யும் ஆழமான மூலோபாய கூட்டாண்மையின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "காலநிலை மாற்றம் எவ்வாறு உயர் வடக்கை மிகவும் முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்ததாக ஆக்குகிறது என்பதையும் அவர் கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார்.",
        "அலாஸ்காவிற்கான குடியரசுக் கட்சியின் செனட்டரான லிசா முர்கோவ்ஸ்கி, ஆர்க்டிக் தூதர் நியமனத்தை வரவேற்றார்.",
        "தூதர் மட்டத்தில் பிராந்தியத்திற்கான அர்ப்பணிப்பு இராஜதந்திர பிரதிநிதித்துவம் இல்லாத ஒரே ஆர்க்டிக் நாடு அமெரிக்கா என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய தூதுவர் முந்தைய அமெரிக்க பதவியான ஆர்க்டிக் ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் பதவிக்கு பதிலாக, தொழில் தூதர் ஜிம் டிஹார்ட் வகித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநிலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜென்ஸ் ஸ்டோல்டன்பெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டென்மார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஸ்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேதாந்த் படேல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டனி பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண் சிமிட்டுதல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட துருவம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜென்ஸ் ஸ்டோல்டன்பெர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டோல்டன்பெர்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிசா முர்கோவ்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடியரசுக் கட்சி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலாஸ்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்க்டிக் ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிம் டிஹார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}