{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83460/navy-foils-two-illegal-migration-attempts-apprehends-53-people",
  "time_ut": 1657091400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy foils two illegal migration attempts, apprehends 53 people",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy foils two illegal migration attempts, apprehends 53 people",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In two separate search operations carried out in beach areas of Trincomalee and Mannar last night (July 05), Sri Lanka Navy apprehended 53 persons who were attempting to illegally migrate from the country via sea routes.",
        "The operations also led to the apprehension of 02 human smugglers, the navy said in a statement.",
        "A special operation mounted at Erakkandi Beach yesterday in coordination with the Kuchchaveli Police, SLNS Vijayaba in the Eastern Naval Command led to the apprehension of 46 people suspected to be attempting to illegally migrate from the country by sea.",
        "Among the group that was remaining at the beach were 12 males, 11 females and 23 children.",
        "They were identified as residents of Kinniya, Muthur and Kumburupiddi areas, aged between 01 to 52 years. The group was handed over to the Kuchchaveli Police for onward legal action.",
        "Meanwhile, in a search operation carried out by SLNS Gajaba in the North Central Naval Command 07 people, suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country by a dinghy, were apprehended along with 02 human smugglers on the beach area of Talpadu yesterday.",
        "The group consisted of 03 males, 01 female and 03 children. The Navy also took hold of the dinghy to be used for the illegal act.",
        "The suspects held in the operation are residents of Colombo, Badulla, Vavuniya and Mannar, who are from 05 to 48 years of age. They were handed over to the Mannar Police for onward legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "53",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee and Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Erakkandi Beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kuchchaveli Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Vijayaba",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kinniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muthur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumburupiddi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 01 to 52 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kuchchaveli Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Gajaba",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talpadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Badulla, Vavuniya and Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 to 48 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mannar Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණික උත්සාහයන් දෙකක් නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ව්‍යර්ථ කර 53ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ (ජුලි 05) රාත්‍රියේ ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ මන්නාරම මුහුදු තීරයේ සිදු කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුම් දෙකකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ පුද්ගලයින් 53 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුම් මගින් මිනිස් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් 02 දෙනෙකු ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට හැකි වූ බව නාවික හමුදාව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා විජයබා නෞකාව සහ කුච්චවේලි පොලිසියේ සම්බන්ධීකරණයෙන් එරක්කණ්ඩි වෙරළ තීරයේ ඊයේ ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටින් මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 46 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මුහුදු වෙරළේ රැඳී සිටි පිරිස අතර පිරිමි 12 ක්, කාන්තාවන් 11 ක් සහ ළමුන් 23 ක් විය.",
        "ඔවුන් වයස අවුරුදු 01 ත් 52 ත් අතර වයස්වල පසුවන කින්නියා, මුතූර් සහ කුඹුරුපිඩ්ඩි ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. මෙම පිරිස ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා කුච්චවේලි පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා ගජබා නෞකාව මගින් උතුරුමැද නාවික විධානයට අයත් නාවික හමුදාව විසින් සිදුකළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවකින් විදේශ රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 07 දෙනෙකු තල්පාඩු වෙරළ තීරයේදී මිනිස් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් 02 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඊයේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා. .",
        "මෙම පිරිස පිරිමි 03 දෙනෙකු, ගැහැණු 01 දෙනෙකු සහ ළමුන් 03 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත විය. නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියාව සඳහා යොදා ගැනීමට තිබූ ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙහෙයුමේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් කොළඹ, බදුල්ල, වවුනියාව සහ මන්නාරම ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි අවුරුදු 05 සිට 48 දක්වා වයස්වල පසුවන්නන්. ඔවුන් ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා මන්නාරම පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "53",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එරක්කන්ඩි වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුච්චවේලි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා විජයබා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කින්නියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුතූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුඹුරුපිඩ්ඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 01 සිට 52 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුච්චවේලි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා ගජබා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තල්පාඩු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල, වවුනියාව සහ මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 05 සිට 48 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டு சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சிகளை கடற்படை முறியடித்து, 53 பேரை கைது செய்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "திருகோணமலை மற்றும் மன்னார் கடற்கரைப் பகுதிகளில் நேற்று (ஜூலை 05) இரவு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இரண்டு தனித்தனியான தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கைகளில் இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் நாட்டிலிருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயன்ற 53 பேரை கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் 02 மனித கடத்தல்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கடற்படை அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குச்சவெளி பொலிஸ், கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையின் SLNS விஜயபா மற்றும் குச்சவெளி பொலிஸாரின் ஒருங்கிணைப்பில் நேற்று ஏறக்கண்டி கடற்கரையில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் நாட்டிலிருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 46 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்கரையில் எஞ்சியிருந்த குழுவில் 12 ஆண்கள், 11 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 23 குழந்தைகள் இருந்தனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் கிண்ணியா, மூதூர் மற்றும் கும்புறுப்பிட்டி பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 01 வயதுக்கும் 52 வயதுக்கும் இடைப்பட்டவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர். குறித்த குழுவினர் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக குச்சவெளி பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையில் SLNS கஜபாவினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில், டிங்கி படகு மூலம் வெளிநாட்டுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 07 பேர், தல்பாடு கடற்கரை பகுதியில் 02 மனித கடத்தல்காரர்களுடன் நேற்று கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். .",
        "குழுவில் 03 ஆண்கள், 01 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 03 குழந்தைகள் இருந்தனர். சட்டவிரோத செயலுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட இருந்த டிங்கி படகுகளையும் கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றினர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் கொழும்பு, பதுளை, வவுனியா மற்றும் மன்னார் ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள், அவர்கள் 05 முதல் 48 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்கள். அவர்கள் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக மன்னார் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "53",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை மற்றும் மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏறக்கண்டி கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குச்சவெளி காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS விஜயபா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிண்ணியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூதூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கும்புறுபிடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01 முதல் 52 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குச்சவெளி காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS கஜபா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தல்பாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை, வவுனியா மற்றும் மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 முதல் 48 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}