{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජනපති-ජීවතුන්-අතරද--නැත්ද-/11-395091",
  "time_ut": 1656930256,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ජීවතුන් අතරද? නැත්ද?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Is the president alive? no",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Naleen Bandara, Member of Parliament of Samagi Jana Balavega said that the country cannot move forward when a president of a country is in hiding, and accordingly, a reference should be made about whether President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is alive or not.",
        "He mentioned this while addressing a question in Parliament today (04th).",
        "Minister Prasanna Ranatunga, the chief organizer of the ruling party, said that while the President performs his duties from the Presidential Palace, he also travels to various places and some security measures have been taken due to the current security situation in the country.",
        "However, although the minister mentioned that the president is going to various places, it is not possible to see him like that, Samagi Jana Balawega MP Mujibar Rahman said.",
        "Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga said that President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa visited the Parliament in the past few days, however the President does not mention his whereabouts to the members of the opposition or the members of the ruling party."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Naleen Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujibar Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ජීවතුන් අතරද? නැත්ද?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටක ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් සැගවී සිටියදී රට ඉදිරියට නොයන බවත්, ඒ අනුව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජීවතුන් අතර සිටිනවාද නැද්ද යන්න පිළිබඳ සඳහනක් කළ යුතු බවත් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නලීන් බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අද (04දා) ප්‍රශ්නයක් යොමු කරමින් හෙතෙම මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය කාර්ය භාරය ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ සිට සිදු කරන අතර, ඔහු විවිධ ස්ථාන වලට ගමන් කිරීමද සිදු කරන බවත්, රටේ පවතින ආරක්ෂක තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් යම් යම් ආරක්ෂක ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගෙන තිබෙන බවත් ඊට පිළිතුරු ලබා දෙමින් ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විවිධ ස්ථාන වලට යන බවට අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළද එලෙස දැක ගැනීමට නොහැකි බව එහිදී අදහස් පළ කරමින් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මුජිබර් රහුමාන්මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගිය දින වල පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි බවත්, කෙසේ වෙතත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා යන එන තැන් විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට හෝ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට සඳහන් නොකරන බවත් ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி உயிருடன் இருக்கிறாரா? இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒரு நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதி மறைந்திருக்கும் போது நாட்டை முன்னோக்கி கொண்டு செல்ல முடியாது எனவும், அதன்படி ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ உயிருடன் இருக்கிறாரா இல்லையா என்பது குறித்து ஆராயப்பட வேண்டுமென சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.நளீன் பண்டார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இன்று (04) கேள்வி எழுப்பிய போதே அவர் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து தனது கடமைகளை நிறைவேற்றும் போது அவரும் பல்வேறு இடங்களுக்குச் செல்வதாகவும் தற்போது நாட்டில் நிலவும் பாதுகாப்பு நிலைமைகள் காரணமாக சில பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளரான அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி பல்வேறு இடங்களுக்கு செல்வதாக அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ள போதிலும், அவரை அவ்வாறு பார்க்க முடியாது என சமகி ஜன பலவேக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் முஜிபர் ரஹ்மான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ கடந்த சில தினங்களுக்கு முன்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு விஜயம் செய்ததாகவும், எனினும் ஜனாதிபதி அவர் இருக்கும் இடத்தை எதிர்க்கட்சி அல்லது ஆளும் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களிடம் குறிப்பிடவில்லை எனவும் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நளீன் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}