{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අටේ-ඇලේ-දිය-නෑ-09-හැවිරිදි-දරුවෙකු-මරුට/11-395162",
  "time_ut": 1657091234,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අටේ ඇලේ දිය නෑ 09 හැවිරිදි දරුවෙකු මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A 9-year-old child died",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Sevanagala Police, a nine-year-old child drowned yesterday (05th) while swimming in Ate Canal in Mahagama Urusitawewa, which belongs to the Sevanagala Police Domain.",
        "The deceased was a child named Dasun Induwara Samaraweera, a resident of Pelagahawatta West in Hakmana Narawalpita.",
        "This child was studying in Gnanaloka Pirivene at the Mahagama Subhadrarama Temple and was aspiring for ordination.",
        "Twelve lay monks, including the temple vicar, had gone to the canal to swim with this boy.",
        "While swimming in the canal, the child drifted down the canal and drowned.",
        "The child was recovered and taken to the Sevanagala Regional Hospital, but the investigation revealed that the child had already died. The autopsy on the child's death is scheduled to be held today (06th) at Embilipitiya Base Hospital."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sevanagala Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "in Ate Canal",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahagama Urusitawewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sevanagala Police Domain",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dasun Induwara Samaraweera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pelagahawatta West",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hakmana Narawalpita",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gnanaloka Pirivene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mahagama Subhadrarama Temple",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twelve",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sevanagala Regional Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Embilipitiya Base Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අටේ ඇලේ දිය නෑ 09 හැවිරිදි දරුවෙකු මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෙවනගල  පොලිස් වසමට අයත් මහගම ඌරුසිටාවැවේ අටේ ඇලේ දියනාමින් සිටි නව හැවිරිදි දරුවෙකු ඊයේ (05දා) දියේ ගිලී මියගොස් ඇතැයි සෙවනගල පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ හක්මන නරවල්පිට බටහිර පෑලගහවත්ත පදිංචි නම්මුණිආරච්චිගේ දසුන් ඉඳුවර සමරවීර නැමති දරුවෙකි.",
        "මෙම දරුවා මහගම සුභද්‍රාරාම විහාරස්ථානයේ ඤාණාලෝක පිරිවෙනේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන අතර පැවිදිවීමට අපේක්ෂාවෙන් සිටි අයෙකි.",
        "විහාරාධිපති ස්වාමීන්වහන්සේ ඇතුළු සාමණේර ස්වාමීන්වහන්සේලා දොළොස් නමක් මෙම ළමයා සමඟ දියනෑමට ඇලට ගොස් ඇත.",
        "ඇලේ දියනාමින් සිටියදී දරුවා ඇලේ පහළට ගසාගෙන ගොස් දියේ ගිලී ඇත.",
        "ළමයා ගොඩගෙන සෙවනගල ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහලට රැගෙන ගොස් ඇතත් ඒවන විටත් ළමයා මියගොස් සිටි බව පරීක්ෂණ වලදී අනාවරණයවී ඇත. දරුවාගේ මරණය පිළිබඳ හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂණය අද (06දා) ඇඹිලිපිටිය මූලික රෝහලේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9 හැවිරිදි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙවනගල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇටේ ඇලේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහගම උරුසිටවැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙවනගල පොලිස් වසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දසුන් ඉඳුවර සමරවීර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැලගහවත්ත බටහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හක්මන නරවල්පිට",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඤාණාලෝක පිරිවෙන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහගම සුභද්‍රාරාම විහාරස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දොළහයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙවනගල ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඹිලිපිටිය මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "9 வயது குழந்தை உயிரிழந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "செவனகல பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட மஹகம உருசிதவெவ, அத்தே கால்வாயில் நீராடச் சென்ற ஒன்பது வயது குழந்தை நேற்று (05) நீரில் மூழ்கி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக செவனகல பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஹக்மன நரவல்பிட்ட பெலகஹவத்த மேற்கு பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த தசுன் இந்துவர சமரவீர என்ற குழந்தையே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த குழந்தை மகாகம சுபத்ராராம கோவிலில் உள்ள ஞானலோக பிரிவேனில் கல்வி பயின்று, அர்ச்சனைக்கு ஆசைப்பட்டுக் கொண்டிருந்தது.",
        "இந்த சிறுவனுடன் கோவில் விகாரை உட்பட 12 பாமர பிக்குகள் நீராட கால்வாய்க்கு சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "கால்வாயில் நீந்திக் கொண்டிருந்த போது, ​​குழந்தை கால்வாயில் தவறி விழுந்து நீரில் மூழ்கியது.",
        "குழந்தை மீட்கப்பட்டு செவனகல பிரதேச வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட போதிலும், குழந்தை ஏற்கனவே உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது. குழந்தையின் மரணம் தொடர்பான பிரேத பரிசோதனை இன்று (06) எம்பிலிபிட்டிய ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செவனகல பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏட் கால்வாயில்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாகம உருசிதவெவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவனகல பொலிஸ் களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தசுன் இந்துவர சமரவீர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலகஹாவத்த மேற்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹக்மனா நரவல்பிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞானலோக பிரிவேனே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாகம சுபத்ராராம ஆலயம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னிரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவனகல பிராந்திய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்பிலிபிட்டிய ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}