{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/18/laptop-thieves-arrested-in-wattala/",
  "time_ut": 1660814040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Laptop Thieves arrested In Wattala",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Laptop Thieves arrested In Wattala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police arrested two suspects for stealing 21 laptops from a warehouse of a private company in the Wattala area.",
        "The suspects are aged 26 and 36 years and are residents of the Elakanda, and Madinnagoda areas.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said one suspect is in fact an employee at the Private Company in question, and reports revealed that he had stolen laptops on multiple occasions.",
        "After the suspects were presented to the Welisara Magistrate's Court, the main suspect was remanded until the 23rd of August.",
        "Sri Lanka: Inflation will peak in September and trend down – CBSL Governor",
        "Restructuring domestic debt would lead to an issue – CBSL Chief",
        "China To Participate In Russia Military Drills, Says India Will Join Too"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Laptop Thieves",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wattala",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 and 36 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elakanda",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Private Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Welisara Magistrate's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 23rd of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලැප්ටොප් හොරු වත්තලදී අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වත්තල ප්‍රදේශයේ පෞද්ගලික ආයතනයක ගබඩාවකින් ලැප්ටොප් පරිගණක 21ක් සොරකම් කළ සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් අවුරුදු 26 සහ 36 වයස්වල පසුවන ඇලකන්ද සහ මාදින්නාගොඩ ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ එක් සැකකරුවෙකු ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම අදාළ පෞද්ගලික සමාගමේ සේවකයෙකු වන අතර ඔහු අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී ලැප්ටොප් සොරකම් කර ඇති බවට වාර්තා අනාවරණය වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් වැලිසර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රධාන සැකකරු අගෝස්තු මස 23 වනදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කෙරුණා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී උද්ධමනය උපරිම වන අතර ප්‍රවණතාව පහළ යනු ඇත - මහ බැංකු අධිපති",
        "දේශීය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ගැටලුවකට තුඩු දෙනු ඇත - මහ බැංකු ප්‍රධානියා",
        "රුසියාවේ හමුදා අභ්‍යාසවලට චීනය සහභාගී වීමට ඉන්දියාව ද එක්වන බව කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලැප්ටොප් හොරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "වත්තල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26 සහ 36",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලකන්ද",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුද්ගලික සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ වැලිසර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයෙන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 23 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வத்தளையில் மடிக்கணினி திருடர்கள் கைது!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வத்தளை பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள தனியார் நிறுவனம் ஒன்றின் களஞ்சியசாலையில் 21 மடிக்கணினிகளை திருடிய இரு சந்தேக நபர்களை இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் 26 மற்றும் 36 வயதுடைய எலகந்த மற்றும் மதின்னாகொட பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்கள்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் ஒருவர் உண்மையில் குறித்த தனியார் நிறுவனத்தில் பணிபுரிபவர் எனவும், அவர் பல தடவைகளில் மடிக்கணினிகளை திருடியுள்ளதாகவும் இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் வெலிசர நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டதை அடுத்து, பிரதான சந்தேகநபர் ஆகஸ்ட் 23ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை: செப்டம்பரில் பணவீக்கம் உச்சத்தை எட்டும் மற்றும் போக்கு குறையும் - CBSL ஆளுநர்",
        "உள்நாட்டுக் கடனை மறுசீரமைப்பது ஒரு சிக்கலுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும் - CBSL தலைவர்",
        "ரஷ்யாவின் ராணுவப் பயிற்சியில் பங்கேற்கும் சீனா, இந்தியாவும் இணையும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மடிக்கணினி திருடர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "வத்தளை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 மற்றும் 36 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏலகண்டா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிசர நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}