{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/சர்வகட்சி-அரசாங்கத்தை-அமைக்க-சுதந்திர-கட்சி-தயார்/175-303158",
  "time_ut": 1661713142,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "’சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க சுதந்திர கட்சி தயார் ’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'Independence Party ready to form all-party government'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has said that the Sri Lanka Freedom Party is going to form a proper all-party government in collaboration with the Left parties.",
        "He said this while participating in an event held yesterday (28) in Maharakami. He further stated,",
        "This government is headed by budding party leaders. They have no desire to form an all-party government.",
        "Therefore, in the future, we will take steps to form a stable all-party government in collaboration with the Sri Lanka Freedom Party and the Left parties. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Independence Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Left",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharakami",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Left",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "'සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට නිදහස් පක්ෂය සූදානම්'",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය වමේ පක්ෂ සමඟ එක්ව නිසි සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට යන බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ මහරකාමි ප්‍රදේශයේ ඊයේ (28) පැවති උත්සවයකට එක්වෙමින්. එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දැක්වූ ඒ මහතා,",
        "මේ ආණ්‌ඩුව මෙහෙයවන්නේ අංකුර පක්‍ෂ නායකයන්. ඔවුන්ට සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් හදන්න කිසිම උවමනාවක් නැහැ.",
        "ඒ නිසා ඉදිරියේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය සහ වමේ පක්ෂ සමඟ එක්ව ස්ථාවර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට අපි කටයුතු කරනවා. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරකාමි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "’சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க சுதந்திர கட்சி தயார் ’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி, இடதுசாரி கட்சிகளுடன் இணைந்து முறையான சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க உள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திர கட்சியின் தலைவர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்ரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மஹரகமையில் நேற்று (28) இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வொன்றில் கலந்துக்கொண்டு கருத்துரைத்த போதே அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில்,",
        "இந்த அரசாங்கத்தை மொட்டு கட்சித் தலைவர்களே வழிநடத்துகின்றனர். சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க அவர்களுக்கு விருப்பம் இல்லை.",
        "ஆகையால் எதிர்காலத்தில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி, இடதுசாரி கட்சிகளுடன் இணைந்து ஸ்திரமான சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க நாம் நடவடிக்கை எடுப்போம் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விட்டு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாரகமி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விட்டு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}