{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/රුසියානු-ජනපතිගෙන්-ජනපති-රනිල්ට-ලිපියක්/11-395724",
  "time_ut": 1658740853,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රුසියානු ජනපතිගෙන් ජනපති රනිල්ට ලිපියක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A letter from the Russian President to President Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Russian President Vladimir Putin has sent a letter to President-elect Ranil Wickremesinghe as the new President of Sri Lanka.",
        "The letter was handed over to the President by the Russian Ambassador to Sri Lanka Mr. Yuri Materi this morning.",
        "The Russian President states in his letter that the actions taken by President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the head of Sri Lanka will be for the stability and security of the people of both countries as well as the region.",
        "The Russian President's letter further states that the relations between Sri Lanka and Russia are friendly and he wishes the new President success."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuri Materi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියානු ජනපතිගෙන් ජනපති රනිල්ට ලිපියක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනපතිවරයා වශවෙන් තේරි පත්වු ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත රුසියානු ජනපති ව්ලැඩ්මීර් පුටිං මහතා සිය සුබ පැතුම් එක්කරමින් ලිපියක් යොමුකර තිබේ.",
        "එම ලිපිය ශ්‍රි ලංකාවේ රුසියානු තානාපති යූරි මැටේරි මහතා විසින් ජනපතිවරයා වෙත අද පෙරවරුවේ භාර දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ගන්නා වූ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග දෙරටේ ජනතාවගේ මෙන්ම කලාපයේ ස්ථාවරත්වය හා ආරක්ෂාව වෙනුවෙන්  හේතුවෙනු ඇතැයි රුසියානු ජනපතිවරයා සිය ලිපියෙන් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හා රුසියාව අතර සබඳතා මිත්‍ර ශීලී වූ බවත් නව ජනපතිවරයාට සාර්ථකත්වය වෙනුවෙන් සුබ පැතුම් එක්කරන බවත් රුසියානු ජනපතිවරයාගේ ලිපියේ වැඩිදුරටත් දැක්වෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූරි මැටේරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதியினால் ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலுக்கு கடிதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் புதிய அதிபராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் கடிதம் ஒன்றை அனுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான ரஷ்ய தூதுவர் திரு யூரி மேட்டேரியினால் இன்று முற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் இந்த கடிதம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தலைவர் என்ற வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மேற்கொள்ளும் நடவடிக்கைகள் இரு நாட்டு மக்கள் மற்றும் பிராந்திய மக்களின் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பிற்காக இருக்கும் என ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி தனது கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் ரஷ்யாவுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகள் நட்பு ரீதியில் இருப்பதாகவும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி வெற்றியடைய வாழ்த்துவதாகவும் ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதியின் கடிதத்தில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூரி மேட்டரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}