{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/04/young-man-dies-after-falling-off-waterfall/",
  "time_ut": 1662266280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Young man dies after falling off waterfall",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Young man dies after falling off waterfall",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A youth had died after falling near a waterfall at the Sun Valley estate in Udaweriya, Haldummulla, after he had attempted to take a photograph near the waterfall.",
        "The police said that the deceased as heen identified as a 24-year-old resident of Welamitiyawa,  Guruthalawa.",
        "The victim had visited the waterfall with another person on Saturday (4), where he attempted to take a picture near the waterfall, however he had missed his step and fallen off.",
        "Later, during a joint search operation conducted by the police and local residents, the police said that the body was found in a waterhole about 200 meters below the site of the incident.",
        "If IMF reforms not implemented, Sri Lanka goes back to square one – CBSL Chief"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sun Valley",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaweriya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haldummulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welamitiyawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guruthalawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 200 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිය ඇල්ලෙන් වැටී තරුණයෙක් මිය යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හල්දුම්මුල්ල, උඩවේරිය, සන්වැලි වතුයායේ දියඇල්ල අසලදී ඡායාරූපයක් ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළ තරුණයෙකු දියඇල්ල අසලට ඇද වැටී මිය ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ  ගුරුතලාව, වැලමිටියාව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 24 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකු බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා සෙනසුරාදා (4) තවත් පුද්ගලයෙකු සමඟ දිය ඇල්ල නැරඹීමට ගොස් ඇති අතර එහිදී ඔහු දිය ඇල්ල අසල පින්තූරයක් ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළද ඔහුගේ පියවර වැරදී වැටී ඇත.",
        "පසුව පොලිසිය සහ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් එක්ව සිදුකළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී සිද්ධිය වූ ස්ථානයේ සිට මීටර් 200ක් පමණ පහළින් පිහිටි දිය වළක තිබී මළ සිරුර සොයාගත් බව පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකළහොත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පළමු තැනට යයි - මහ බැංකුවේ ප්‍රධානියා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරු නිම්නය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩවේරිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හල්දුම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලමිටියාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරුතලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 200 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீர்வீழ்ச்சியில் இருந்து தவறி விழுந்து இளைஞர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஹல்துமுல்ல, உடவேரிய சன் வேலி தோட்டத்திலுள்ள நீர்வீழ்ச்சிக்கு அருகில் புகைப்படம் எடுக்க முற்பட்ட இளைஞர் ஒருவர் அருவிக்கு அருகில் விழுந்து உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் வெலமிட்டியாவ  குருதலாவ பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 24 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நபர் சனிக்கிழமை (4) மற்றொரு நபருடன் நீர்வீழ்ச்சிக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ளார், அங்கு அவர் நீர்வீழ்ச்சிக்கு அருகில் படம் எடுக்க முற்பட்டார், ஆனால் அவர் தனது அடியை தவறவிட்டு கீழே விழுந்தார்.",
        "பின்னர், பொலிஸாரும் பிரதேசவாசிகளும் இணைந்து மேற்கொண்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​சம்பவம் இடம்பெற்ற இடத்திலிருந்து சுமார் 200 மீற்றர்களுக்கு கீழே உள்ள நீர்க்குழாய் ஒன்றில் சடலம் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படாவிட்டால், இலங்கை மீண்டும் முதல் நிலைக்குச் செல்லும் - CBSL தலைவர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூரிய பள்ளத்தாக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடவெரிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹல்துமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலமிட்டியவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருதலவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 200 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}