{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/iusf-goes-to-hrcsl-over-arrests/",
  "time_ut": 1661950620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IUSF goes to HRCSL over arrests",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IUSF goes to HRCSL over arrests",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Inter-University Student Union lodged a complaint at the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka (HRCSL) with regard to Tuesday's (30) incidents, including the arrest of 28 members.",
        "Venerable Pokunavita Piyasoma Thera, a representative of the IUSF asked how the Government continues to deploy the police to stop the protests, when the people of the country do not have enough food, cooking gas, and medicines.",
        "Venerable Pokunavita Piyasoma Thera pointed out that due to these factors, children's education has also come to a halt.",
        "\"We cannot wait at home when these things are happening. We have to take it to the streets. They attacked the protestors who took it to the streets. But the Rajapaksa regime chased these peaceful protestors around with batons in hand, and even attacked them with water cannon and tear gas,\" Ven. Piyasoma Thero said.",
        "28 members of the IUSF, who were arrested during a protest staged in Maradana on Tuesday (30), were released on bail on Wednesday (31).",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Inter-University Student Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Piyasoma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Piyasoma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piyasoma Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maradana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවිශිබම HRCSL වෙත යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සාමාජිකයින් 28 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම ඇතුළු අඟහරුවාදා (30) සිදුවීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සංගමය ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවට (HRCSL) පැමිණිල්ලක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "රටේ ජනතාවට ප්‍රමාණවත් තරම් ආහාර, පිසින ගෑස් සහ බෙහෙත් නොමැති විට, විරෝධතා නැවැත්වීමට රජය තවදුරටත් පොලිසිය යොදවන්නේ කෙසේදැයි අවිශිබමයේ නියෝජිත පූජ්‍ය පොකුණවිට පියසෝම හිමියෝ විමසා සිටියහ.",
        "මෙම කරුණු හේතුවෙන් දරුවන්ගේ අධ්‍යාපන කටයුතුද ඇනහිට ඇති බවයි පූජ්‍ය පොකුණවිට පියසෝම හිමියන් පෙන්වා දුන්නේ.",
        "“මේ දේවල් වෙන කොට අපිට ගෙදර බලාගෙන ඉන්න බැහැ, පාරට බහින්න වෙනවා, පාරට බැස්ස උද්ඝෝෂකයන්ට පහර දුන්නා, නමුත් රාජපක්ෂ පාලනය මේ සාමකාමී උද්ඝෝෂකයන්ට බැටන් පොලුවලින් එළවා එළවා පහර පවා දුන්නා. ජල ප්‍රහාරවලින් සහ කඳුළු ගෑස්වලින්\" හාමුදුරුවෝ පියසෝම හිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා (30) මරදානේ පැවැත්වූ විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුර අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අවිශිබම සාමාජිකයින් 28 දෙනා බදාදා (31) ඇප මත මුදා හරින ලදී.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පියසෝම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පියසෝම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියසෝම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරදාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IUSF கைதுகள் தொடர்பாக HRCSL க்கு செல்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 28 உறுப்பினர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டமை உட்பட செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (30) இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் ஒன்றியம் இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவில் (HRCSL) முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு போதிய உணவு, சமையல் எரிவாயு மற்றும் மருந்துகள் கிடைக்காத நிலையில், போராட்டங்களை நிறுத்துவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் எவ்வாறு பொலிஸாரைத் தொடர்ந்து நிலைநிறுத்துகிறது என IUSF இன் பிரதிநிதி வணக்கத்துக்குரிய பொகுணாவிட்ட பியசோம தேரர் வினவினார்.",
        "இந்த காரணிகளினால் பிள்ளைகளின் கல்வியும் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வணக்கத்துக்குரிய பொகுணாவிட பியசோம தேரர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "\"இவைகள் நடக்கும் போது நாங்கள் வீட்டில் காத்திருக்க முடியாது, நாங்கள் அதை வீதிக்கு கொண்டு வர வேண்டும், தெருவில் இறங்கிய போராட்டக்காரர்களை அவர்கள் தாக்கினர். ஆனால் ராஜபக்சே ஆட்சி இந்த அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்களை கையில் பொல்லுகளுடன் துரத்தியது, அவர்களைத் தாக்கியது. நீர் பீரங்கி மற்றும் கண்ணீர்ப்புகை மூலம்,\" வென். பியசோம தேரர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மருதானையில் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (30) முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது கைது செய்யப்பட்ட IUSF உறுப்பினர்கள் 28 பேர் புதன்கிழமை (31) பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பியசோம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பியசோம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியசோம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருதானை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}