{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83493/cope-calls-for-audit-on-lp-gas-purchases-by-litro",
  "time_ut": 1657204740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "COPE calls for audit on LP gas purchases by Litro",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "COPE calls for audit on LP gas purchases by Litro",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) has recommended that an investigation be conducted on the cancellation of the Term tender, which had been approved by the Cabinet to purchase LP gas from Siam Gas at USD 96 per metric ton and opting to buy 100,000 MT of gas at a cost of USD 129 per metric ton from an Oman company.",
        "The investigation will be carried out through the Auditor General’s Department.",
        "This recommendation was given on Wednesday when Litro Gas Lanka Ltd, Litro Gas Terminal Lanka (Pvt) Ltd. and Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation were summoned before COPE to implement the orders given by the previous Committee on Public Enterprises and to discuss the current performance.",
        "It was revealed that since the Term tender for the purchase of gas ended last February, tenders were invited for 280,000 MT of gas and three gas suppliers had submitted bids accordingly. Siam gas Company submitted the lowest price as USD 96 per metric ton and thereby the Cabinet was received to award the tender.",
        "The Litro officials said LP gas could not be obtained from Siam gas Company due to the economic crisis as banks in Sri Lanka were unable to submit the Standby Letter of Credit (SBLC) to Litro pursuant to the conditions announced during the bidding process.",
        "They further stated that the company, despite the discussions held with its officials, expressed its unwillingness to supply LP gas without an SBLC as per the conditions presented during the tender invitation.",
        "Due to this delay, as a temporary solution, Siam Gas Company itself has negotiated to obtain 15,000 MT of gas as emergency purchases, which is the gross amount of gas required for two weeks, but it was informed that they can supply only 6,600 MT and thus was unsuccessful.",
        "Litro officials also said that the Omani company, which had offered prices at USD 129 per metric ton for the Term Tender, agreed to provide 100,000 MT of gas for 4 months at 25,000 MT per month.",
        "Accordingly, after notifying the above facts to the cabinet, it was revealed that the term tender given to Siam Gas Company was cancelled and the Cabinet approval was received for the term tender to purchase 100,000 MT of LP gas from the Omani company.",
        "A USD 70 million loan from the World Bank and 20 million of Litro Gas Lanka Ltd amounting to the tune of USD 90 million was used for this procurement, Chairman of Litro Lanka Muditha Peiris said.",
        "The COPE chairman instructed the Auditor General’s Department to conduct a formal investigation and report whether the loan amount of USD 70 million from the World Bank was effectively used, and added that although the need for LP gas is a necessary emergency, buying from the Omani company at a higher price instead of the lowest bidder, Siam Gas company, may set a bad precedent in the future.",
        "The committee also focused on the inability to purchase LP gas with the amount of USD 160 million allocated for the purchase of gas under the Indian credit line. The Litro chairman said that according to the conditions of the Indian government, it is a problem to purchase LP gas that is not produced in the country. It was also revealed that several rounds of discussions were held regarding this. The COPE chairman made a recommendation to the Secretary to the Ministry of Finance to look into this immediately and report within two weeks.",
        "Attention was also drawn to the fact that the number of currently appointed members of Litro’s board of directors is only four. It was revealed that according to the legal status, there should be 5 members. Furthermore, since the Ministry of Finance appoints the members of the Board of Directors, COPE pointed out the need to appoint the Board of Directors to consist of representatives of the parent company. The COPE chairman recommended the Secretary to the Ministry of Finance to take necessary measures in this regard.",
        "The COPE also discussed about holding both one official holding the company’s chairpersonship and Chief Executive Officer position. Even if the position of the company’s chairman changes, the presence of a permanent CEO position is essential for the good survival of the company. Hence, the committee emphasized the importance of working towards it as soon as possible. Furthermore, Litro Chairman said the Board of Directors has already taken a decision to deal with this situation as soon as this crisis is resolved. The committee recommended to take necessary steps and submit a report on this regard.",
        "Litro Company’s ability to obtain financial support from Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation, the parent company of the Litro Company was also looked into. The chairman of the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation, Vijitha Herath said the company was able to purchase LP gas in the past due to the deposit of nearly 5 billion rupees in a state bank.",
        "Representing the Secretary of the Ministry of Finance, Saman Fernando, Deputy Secretary to the Treasury, Chairman of the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation and former Litro Chairman Vijitha Herath, Litro Chairman Muditha Peiris were present at this meeting whilst Thesara Jayawardane, former chairman of Litro Company, joined online.",
        "Parliamentarians Patali Champika Ranawaka, Mahindananda Aluthgamage, Anura Dissanayaka, Harsha de Silva, Sarath Weerasekera, Jagath Pushpakumara, Indika Anuruddha, S.M Marikkar, Jayantha Samaraweera, Nalaka Godahewa, Premnath C. Dolawatte and Madhura Withanage were present at the meeting held."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Litro",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Term",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Terminal Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "280,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 6,600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Term Tender",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT of LP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USD 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 90 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siam Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "USD 160 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Company’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Litro Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thesara Jayawardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians Patali Champika Ranawaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Weerasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jagath Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika Anuruddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godahewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premnath C. Dolawatte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම විසින් LP ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම් පිළිබඳ විගණනය සඳහා කෝප් කමිටුව ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සියම් ගෑස් වෙතින් LP ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට ඩොලර් 96 බැගින් මිලදී ගැනීමට සහ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් මිලදී ගැනීමට තීරණය කර තිබූ කාලීන ටෙන්ඩරය අවලංගු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPE) නිර්දේශ කර ඇත. Oman සමාගමකින් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට USD 129 බැගින්.",
        "විමර්ශනය විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හරහා සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "පසුගිය බදාදා ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්, ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ටර්මිනල් ලංකා (පෞද්ගලික) සමාගම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉන්ෂුවරන්ස් කෝපරේෂන් කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවා පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ පසුගිය කාරක සභාව ලබා දුන් නියෝග ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහ වත්මන් කාර්ය සාධනය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට බදාදා මෙම නිර්දේශය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමේ ටෙන්ඩරය අවසන් වූ බැවින් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 280,000ක් සඳහා ටෙන්ඩර් කැඳවා තිබූ අතර ඒ අනුව ගෑස් සැපයුම්කරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු මිල ගණන් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබූ බව අනාවරණය විය. සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට ඩොලර් 96ක් ලෙස අඩුම මිල ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර එමඟින් ටෙන්ඩරය ප්‍රදානය කිරීමට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ලැබිණි.",
        "ලංසු තැබීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේදී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද කොන්දේසිවලට අනුකූලව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බැංකුවලට පොරොත්තු ලිපිය (SBLC) ලිට්‍රෝ වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නොහැකි වූ බැවින් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් සියම් ගෑස් සමාගමෙන් LP ගෑස් ලබා ගත නොහැකි බව Litro නිලධාරීහු පැවසූහ.",
        "සමාගම සිය නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළද ටෙන්ඩර් කැඳවීමේදී ඉදිරිපත් කළ කොන්දේසිවලට අනුව SBLC නොමැතිව LP ගෑස් සැපයීමට සමාගම අකැමැති බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවද ඔවුහු වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළහ.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රමාදය හේතුවෙන් තාවකාලික විසඳුමක් ලෙස සති දෙකකට අවශ්‍ය දළ ගෑස් ප්‍රමාණය වන ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000ක් හදිසි මිලදී ගැනීම් ලෙස ලබා ගැනීමට සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම විසින්ම සාකච්ඡා කර ඇතත් ඔවුන්ට සැපයිය හැක්කේ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 6600ක් පමණක් බවත්, එබැවින් අසාර්ථක විය.",
        "ටර්ම් ටෙන්ඩරය සඳහා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් එකකට ඩොලර් 129 බැගින් මිල ගණන් ඉදිරිපත් කළ ඕමාන් සමාගම මසකට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 25,000 බැගින් මාස 4කට ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් ලබාදීමට එකඟ වූ බවද ලිට්‍රෝ නිලධාරීහු පැවසූහ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඉහත කරුණු කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට දැනුම් දීමෙන් පසු සියම් ගෑස් සමාගමට ලබාදී තිබූ ටෙන්ඩරය අවලංගු කර ඕමාන සමාගමෙන් එල්පී ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000ක් මිලදී ගැනීමේ ටෙන්ඩරය සඳහා කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය හිමිවූ බව අනාවරණය විය.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සඳහා ලෝක බැංකුවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 ක ණයක් සහ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගමෙන් මිලියන 20 ක ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 ක ණයක් යොදා ගත් බව ලිට්‍රෝ ලංකා සමාගමේ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලෝක බැංකුවෙන් ලබාගෙන ඇති ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 ක ණය මුදල ඵලදායී ලෙස භාවිත කළේ දැයි විධිමත් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා වාර්තා කරන ලෙස කෝප් සභාපතිවරයා විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට උපදෙස් දුන් අතර, LP ගෑස් අවශ්‍යතාවය හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාවයක් වුවද ඕමාන සමාගමෙන් මිලදී ගැනීමක් සිදු කරන බව ද පැවසීය. අඩුම ලංසුකරුවා වෙනුවට වැඩි මිලකට, සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම අනාගතයේදී නරක පූර්වාදර්ශයක් ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය රේඛාව යටතේ ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා වෙන් කර ඇති ඩොලර් මිලියන 160 ක මුදලින් එල්පී ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට නොහැකි වීම පිළිබඳව ද කමිටුවේ අවධානය යොමු විය. ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපතිවරයා පැවසුවේ ඉන්දීය රජයේ කොන්දේසිවලට අනුව මෙරට නිෂ්පාදනය නොකරන LP ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීම ගැටලුවක් බවයි. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් පැවැත් වූ බවද අනාවරණය විය. මේ පිළිබඳව වහාම සොයා බලා සති දෙකක් ඇතුළත වාර්තා කරන ලෙස කෝප් සභාපතිවරයා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයාට නිර්දේශයක් කළේය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ දැනට පත් කර ඇති සාමාජිකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව හතර දෙනෙකු පමණක් වීම පිළිබඳව ද අවධානය යොමු විය. නීත්‍යානුකූල තත්ත්වයට අනුව මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 5 දෙනෙකු සිටිය යුතු බව අනාවරණය විය. තවද, අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින් පත් කරනු ලබන්නේ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් බැවින්, අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය මව් සමාගමේ නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වන පරිදි පත්කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව කෝප් කමිටුව පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස කෝප් සභාපතිවරයා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයාට නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "සමාගමේ සභාපතිත්වය සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී යන තනතුරු දෙකම එක් නිලධාරියකු දැරීම පිළිබඳව ද කෝප් කමිටුව සාකච්ඡා කළේය. සමාගමේ සභාපති තනතුර වෙනස් වුවද, සමාගමේ යහපත් පැවැත්ම සඳහා ස්ථිර ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී තනතුරක් තිබීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ. එබැවින් හැකි ඉක්මනින් ඒ සඳහා කටයුතු කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම කමිටුව අවධාරණය කළේය. තවද, ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපතිවරයා පැවසුවේ, මෙම අර්බුදය සමථයකට පත් වූ වහාම මෙම තත්ත්වයට මුහුණ දීමට අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය දැනටමත් තීරණයක් ගෙන ඇති බවයි. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගෙන වාර්තාවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස එම කමිටුව නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ මව් සමාගම වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉන්ෂුවරන්ස් කෝපරේෂන් වෙතින් ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමට මූල්‍ය සහය ලබා ගැනීමට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳව ද සොයා බලන ලදී. ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්‍ෂණ සංස්ථාවේ සභාපති විජිත හේරත් මහතා පැවසුවේ රුපියල් බිලියන 5කට ආසන්න මුදලක් රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවක තැන්පත් කිරීම හේතුවෙන් සමාගමට මීට පෙර LP ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට හැකි වූ බවයි.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් සමන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, මහා භාණ්ඩාගාර නියෝජ්‍ය ලේකම්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාවේ සභාපති සහ ලිට්‍රෝ හි හිටපු සභාපති විජිත හේරත්, ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් යන මහත්වරු මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගි වූ අතර ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ හිටපු සභාපති තෙසර ජයවර්ධන මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ. , සබැඳිව සම්බන්ධ විය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක, මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ, අනුර දිසානායක, හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා, සරත් වීරසේකර, ජගත් පුෂ්පකුමාර, ඉන්දික අනුරුද්ධ, එස්. එම් මරික්කාර්, ජයන්ත සමරවීර, නාලක ගොඩහේවා, ප්‍රේම්නාත් සී. දොලවත්ත, මධුර යන මහත්වරු මෙම රැස්වීමට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස් පර්යන්තය ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්යාපාර පිළිබඳ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "280,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර ටෙන්ඩරය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LP හි MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියම් ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 160 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 5 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙසර ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජගත් පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික අනුරුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරික්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේම්නාත් සී දොලවත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிட்ரோவினால் எல்பி எரிவாயு கொள்வனவுகள் மீதான தணிக்கைக்கு கோப் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சியாம் கேஸில் இருந்து ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன்னுக்கு 96 அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு எல்பி எரிவாயுவை வாங்குவதற்கும், 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் வாங்குவதற்கும் அமைச்சரவையால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட கால டெண்டரை ரத்து செய்தது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என்று பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு (கோப்) பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளது. ஓமான் நிறுவனத்திடமிருந்து ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு 129 அமெரிக்க டாலர் செலவில் எரிவாயு.",
        "கணக்காய்வாளர் திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடாக விசாரணை மேற்கொள்ளப்படும்.",
        "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான முன்னைய குழு வழங்கிய கட்டளைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கும் தற்போதைய செயற்பாடுகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கும், புதன்கிழமையன்று Litro Gas Lanka Ltd, Litro Gas Terminal Lanka (Pvt) Ltd. மற்றும் Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation ஆகியவை கோப் முன் அழைக்கப்பட்ட போது இந்த பரிந்துரை வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "எரிவாயு கொள்முதல் செய்வதற்கான டெண்டர் கடந்த பிப்ரவரி மாதம் முடிவடைந்ததால், 280,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவுக்கு டெண்டர் கோரப்பட்டு, அதன்படி மூன்று எரிவாயு வழங்குநர்கள் விலைமனு தாக்கல் செய்திருப்பது தெரியவந்தது. சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம் ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு USD 96 என மிகக் குறைந்த விலையை சமர்ப்பித்தது மற்றும் அதன் மூலம் டெண்டரை வழங்குவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை பெறப்பட்டது.",
        "ஏல நடவடிக்கையின் போது அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு இணங்க, இலங்கையில் உள்ள வங்கிகள் காத்திருப்பு கடனுதவியை (SBLC) Litro நிறுவனத்திற்கு சமர்ப்பிக்க முடியாததால், பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து LP எரிவாயுவைப் பெற முடியவில்லை என Litro அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நிறுவனம், அதன் அதிகாரிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடிய போதிலும், டெண்டர் அழைப்பின் போது முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட நிபந்தனைகளின்படி, SBLC இன்றி LP எரிவாயுவை வழங்குவதற்கு நிறுவனம் விரும்பவில்லை என்று அவர்கள் மேலும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த காலதாமதத்தால் தற்காலிக தீர்வாக சியாம் காஸ் நிறுவனமே 15,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எரிவாயுவை அவசர கொள்முதலாக பெற பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தியது, அதாவது இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு தேவைப்படும் மொத்த எரிவாயு அளவு 6,600 மெட்ரிக் டன் மட்டுமே வழங்க முடியும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதனால் தோல்வியடைந்தது.",
        "டெண்டர் டெண்டருக்கு ஒரு மெட்ரிக் டன் ஒன்றுக்கு USD 129 என்ற விலையை வழங்கிய ஓமானி நிறுவனம், 4 மாதங்களுக்கு 100,000 MT எரிவாயுவை மாதத்திற்கு 25,000 MT என வழங்க ஒப்புக்கொண்டதாகவும் Litro அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதன்படி, மேற்படி உண்மைகளை அமைச்சரவைக்கு அறிவித்ததன் பின்னர், சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனத்திற்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட கால டெண்டர் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும், ஓமான் நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து 100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எல்பி எரிவாயு கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கான டெண்டருக்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் கிடைத்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "உலக வங்கியிடமிருந்து 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் கடனும், லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்டின் 20 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் 90 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களும் இந்த கொள்வனவுக்காக பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக லிட்ரோ லங்காவின் தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "உலக வங்கியிடமிருந்து பெறப்பட்ட 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் கடன் தொகையானது திறம்பட பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டதா என்பது குறித்து முறையான விசாரணை நடத்தி அறிக்கை அளிக்குமாறு கோப் தலைவர் கணக்காய்வாளர் திணைக்களத்திற்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார். மிகக் குறைந்த ஏலத்திற்குப் பதிலாக அதிக விலைக்கு, சியாம் கேஸ் நிறுவனம், எதிர்காலத்தில் மோசமான முன்னுதாரணமாக அமையலாம்.",
        "இந்திய கடன் வரியின் கீழ் எரிவாயு வாங்குவதற்காக ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட 160 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் தொகையில் எல்பி எரிவாயுவை வாங்க முடியாத நிலை குறித்தும் குழு கவனம் செலுத்தியது. இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு அமைய நாட்டில் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படாத LP எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்வதில் சிக்கல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக Litro தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இது தொடர்பாக பல சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் நடத்தப்பட்டதாகவும் தெரியவந்துள்ளது. இதனை உடனடியாக ஆராய்ந்து இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு கோப் தலைவர் நிதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு பரிந்துரை செய்தார்.",
        "லிட்ரோவின் பணிப்பாளர் சபையில் தற்போது நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள உறுப்பினர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 4 பேர் மாத்திரமே என்பது குறித்தும் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. சட்டப்படி 5 பேர் உறுப்பினர்களாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பது தெரியவந்தது. மேலும், பணிப்பாளர் சபை உறுப்பினர்களை நிதியமைச்சகம் நியமிப்பதால், தாய் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் அடங்கிய பணிப்பாளர் சபையை நியமிக்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை கோப் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது. இது தொடர்பில் தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு கோப் தலைவர் நிதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி பதவிகளில் ஒரு அதிகாரியை வைத்திருப்பது குறித்தும் கோப் ஆலோசித்தது. நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் பதவி மாறினாலும், நிரந்தர சிஇஓ பதவி இருப்பது நிறுவனத்தின் நல்ல வாழ்வுக்கு அவசியம். எனவே, கூடிய விரைவில் அதற்கான பணிகளை மேற்கொள்வதன் அவசியத்தை குழு வலியுறுத்தியது. மேலும், இந்த நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணப்பட்டவுடன் இந்த நிலைமையை கையாள்வதற்கு பணிப்பாளர் சபை ஏற்கனவே தீர்மானம் எடுத்துள்ளதாக லிட்ரோ தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார். இது தொடர்பாக தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்து அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பிக்க குழு பரிந்துரைத்தது.",
        "Litro கம்பனியின் தாய் நிறுவனமான இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திடம் இருந்து Litro கம்பனியின் நிதி உதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கான திறன் குறித்தும் ஆராயப்பட்டது. இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தலைவர் விஜித ஹேரத் கூறுகையில், அரச வங்கியில் சுமார் 5 பில்லியன் ரூபா வைப்புச் செய்யப்பட்டதன் காரணமாகவே கடந்த காலங்களில் LP எரிவாயுவை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடிந்தது.",
        "நிதியமைச்சின் செயலாளர் சமன் பெர்னாண்டோ, திறைசேரியின் பிரதிச் செயலாளர், இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் தலைவர் விஜித ஹேரத், லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ், லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் திசர ஜயவர்தன ஆகியோர் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டனர். , ஆன்லைனில் சேர்ந்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க, மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே, அனுர திஸாநாயக்க, ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, சரத் வீரசேகர, ஜகத் புஷ்பகுமார, இந்திக அனுருத்த, எஸ்.எம்.மரிக்கார், ஜயந்த சமரவீர, நாலக கொடஹேவா, பிரேம்நாத் சி.தொலவத்த, மதுர ஆகியோர் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "லிட்ரோ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் வாயு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் டெர்மினல் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "280,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால டெண்டர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சியாம் எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்பியின் எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாம் வாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "160 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெசர ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜகத் புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க அனுருத்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேம்நாத் சி. டோலவத்தே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}