{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-to-surround-Presidents-House-tomorrow/108-240615",
  "time_ut": 1657269892,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB to surround President’s House tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB to surround President’s House tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) today said its entire party machinery will come to Colombo tomorrow and surround the President's House and will remain there till President Gotabaya Rajapaksa leaves office.",
        "“We will  gather at Fort Railway station and will march  towards the President's House later and remain there till the President resigns, “ SJB General Secretary Ranjith Madduma Bandara and two other MPs Rajitha Senaratne and Mujibur Rahman told a press conference today.",
        "“We call on all people to violate curfew in such an eventuality and join in the final battle to grab power,” the MPs said.",
        "“We also urge security forces and  the police  not to follow orders given by the top and join in the uprising,” Mr. Madduma Bandara said.",
        "He said top brass of the government had  ordered the relevant institutions to stop the distribution of fuel in order to prevent the people from coming to the capital today. “ There is a move to stop railway transportation through an act of sabotage,” he said.",
        "“Parliament will be convened if the President leaves today  to choose a successor,” he also said.",
        "SJB also called for the resignation of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe saying he is also proven to be a failure.(Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort Railway",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujibur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today  ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB හෙට ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය වටලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තම පක්ෂ යාන්ත්‍රණය හෙට කොළඹට පැමිණ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය වට කර ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වන තුරු එහි රැඳී සිටින බවයි.",
        "\"අපි කොටුව දුම්රිය ස්ථානයට එකතු වී පසුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය දෙසට පා ගමනින් ගොස් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු එහි සිටිමු\" යනුවෙන් SJB ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර සහ තවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන රාජිත සේනාරත්න සහ මුජිබර් රහ්මාන් අද මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "“එවැනි අවස්ථාවක ඇඳිරි නීතිය කඩකර බලය ලබා ගැනීමේ අවසන් සටනට එක්වන ලෙස අපි සියලු ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා,” මන්ත්‍රීවරු පැවසූහ.",
        "“අපි ආරක්‍ෂක අංශවලින් සහ                                        නිලධාරීන්                              වරුන්                                                                           '",
        "ජනතාව අද අගනුවරට පැමිණීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම නතර කරන ලෙස රජයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ අය අදාළ ආයතනවලට නියෝග කර ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය. කඩාකප්පල්කාරී ක්‍රියාවක් හරහා දුම්රිය ප්‍රවාහනය නැවැත්වීමේ පියවරක් පවතින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා අද පිටව ගියහොත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවනවා\" යැයිද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ද අසාර්ථක බව ඔප්පු වී ඇති බව පවසමින් ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව SJB ද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.(යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව දුම්රිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB நாளை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிடவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமது முழு கட்சி இயந்திரமும் நாளை கொழும்பு வந்து ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை சுற்றிவளைத்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகும் வரை அங்கேயே தங்கியிருக்கும் என சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“நாங்கள்  கோட்டை புகையிரத நிலையத்தில் ஒன்று கூடுவோம்  பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை நோக்கி  பேரணியாகச் செல்வோம், ஜனாதிபதி இராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை அங்கேயே இருப்போம்” என்று SJB பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார மற்றும் இரண்டு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ராஜித சேனாரத்ன மற்றும் முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான் ஆகியோர் இன்று செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "“இவ்வாறான ஒரு சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை மீறி அதிகாரத்தைக் கைப்பற்றுவதற்கான இறுதிப் போரில் இணையுமாறு அனைத்து மக்களையும் நாங்கள் அழைக்கிறோம்,” என்று எம்.பி.க்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "\"உயர்மட்டத்தின் உத்தரவுகளைப் பின்பற்ற வேண்டாம் என்றும், கிளர்ச்சியில் இணைய வேண்டாம் என்றும் நாங்கள் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரையும்  காவல்துறையையும் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம்\" என்று திரு. மத்தும பண்டார கூறினார்.",
        "மக்கள் இன்று தலைநகருக்கு வருவதைத் தடுக்கும் வகையில் எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை நிறுத்துமாறு சம்பந்தப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்களுக்கு அரசாங்கத்தின் உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார். நாசவேலையின் மூலம் ரயில் போக்குவரத்தை நிறுத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, என்றார்.",
        "\"ஒரு வாரிசைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்காக குடியரசுத் தலைவர் இன்று வெளியேறினால் நாடாளுமன்றம் கூட்டப்படும்\" என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் தோல்வியடைந்தவர் என்பது நிரூபணமாகியுள்ளதால் அவர் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் எனவும் SJB வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.(யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை இரயில்வே",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}