{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84411/90-day-detention-order-issued-on-two-including-iusf-convenor",
  "time_ut": 1660924200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "90-day detention order issued on two including IUSF convenor",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "90-day detention order issued on two including IUSF convenor",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Defence Ministry has issued detention orders on IUSF convenor Wasantha Mudalige and Hashan Gunathilake, who were arrested following a protest march in Colombo yesterday.",
        "Accordingly, the Defence Ministry has granted permission for them to be detained for 90 days and questioned by the police.",
        "Earlier today, sixteen individuals who were arrested following the protest at Union Place in Colombo on Thursday (Aug 18) were granted bail by the Colombo Additional Magistrate.",
        "Meanwhile, police had said that detention orders will be sought on three arrestees namely the Inter University Students’ Federation (IUSF) convenor Wasantha Mudalige, Ven. Galwewa Siridhamma Thera and Hashantha Jawantha Gunathilake.",
        "Police had stated that IUSF convenor Wasantha Mudalige was arrested as there is a pending arrest warrant against him.",
        "The arrests were made after police used water cannons and tear gas to disperse protesting university students who were marching through Town Hall and towards Union Place despite police blockades.",
        "The protest march had been organized by Inter University Students Federation (IUSF) against the incumbent government led by President Ranil Wickremesinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "90-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashan Gunathilake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixteen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Union Place in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter University Students’ Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galwewa Siridhamma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashantha Jawantha Gunathilake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Town Hall",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Union Place",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Inter University Students Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අවිශිබම කැඳවුම්කරු ඇතුළු දෙදෙනෙකුට දින 90ක රැඳවුම් නියෝගයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ කොළඹ පැවති විරෝධතා පාගමනකින් අනතුරුව අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අවිශිබම කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ සහ හෂාන් ගුණතිලකට ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් රැඳවුම් නියෝග නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඔවුන් දින 90ක කාලයක් රඳවාගෙන පොලිසියෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමට ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය අවසර ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (අගෝස්තු 18) කොළඹ යුනියන් පෙදෙසේ පැවති විරෝධතාවයෙන් පසු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයන් දහසය දෙනෙකුට කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා විසින් ඇප නියම කරන ලදී.",
        "මේ අතර, අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ (අවිශිබම) කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ, පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය හිමියන් ඇතුළු තිදෙනෙකු රඳවා තබා ගැනීමේ නියෝග ඉල්ලා සිටින බව පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය. ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි සහ හශාන්ත ජවන්ත ගුණතිලක.",
        "අවිශිබමයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට වරෙන්තුවක් පවතින බැවින් ඔහුව අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණි.",
        "විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත විශ්වවිද්‍යාල සිසුන් පුරහල හරහා යුනියන් පෙදෙස දෙසට ගමන් කරමින් සිටි විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරය විසුරුවා හැරීමට පොලිසිය ජල ප්‍රහාර සහ කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව පොලිස් අවහිර කිරීම් නොතකා මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ වත්මන් රජයට එරෙහිව අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය (අවිශිබම) විසින් මෙම විරෝධතා පා ගමන සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "90-දින",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවිශිබම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෂාන් ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහසය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ යුනියන් පෙදෙස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හශාන්ත ජවන්ත ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් පෙදෙස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IUSF கன்வீனர் உட்பட இருவரை 90 நாள் காவலில் வைக்க உத்தரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் நேற்றைய தினம் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்ட பேரணியை அடுத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்ட IUSF அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே மற்றும் ஹஷான் குணதிலக்க ஆகியோரை தடுப்புக்காவலில் வைக்குமாறு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, அவர்களை 90 நாட்கள் காவலில் வைத்து போலீசார் விசாரிக்க பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு யூனியன் பிளேஸில் வியாழக்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 18) இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை அடுத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பதினாறு நபர்களுக்கு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் பிணை வழங்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, கைதுசெய்யப்பட்ட பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் (IUSF) ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே, வண. கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர் மற்றும் ஹஷந்த ஜவந்த குணதிலக்க.",
        "IUSF ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகேவுக்கு எதிராக கைது பிடியாணை நிலுவையில் உள்ளதால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக போலீசார் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் தடைகளை மீறி டவுன் ஹால் ஊடாக யூனியன் பிளேஸ் நோக்கி பேரணியாக சென்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்களை கலைக்க பொலிஸார் நீர்த்தாரை மற்றும் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை பிரயோகித்ததையடுத்து இவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக அனைத்து பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தினால் (IUSF) இந்த எதிர்ப்பு பேரணி ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "90-நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷான் குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதினாறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் யூனியன் பிளேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷந்த ஜவந்த குணதிலகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நகர மண்டபம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் இடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}