{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/PUCSL-to-complete-unbundling-of-CEBs-distribution-operations-soon/108-240063",
  "time_ut": 1656527673,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PUCSL to complete unbundling of CEB’s distribution operations soon",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PUCSL to complete unbundling of CEB’s distribution operations soon",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "CEB’s distribution operation to be unbundled into five independent units, including LECO",
        "PUCSL says it will enhance transparency and efficiency of electricity sector",
        "CEB Engineers Union and other labour unions allege unbundling is aimed at privatisation of CEB",
        "Undertaking the first major reform in Sri Lanka’s electricity sector since 2002, the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) this week announced plans to complete the stalled unbundling of the Ceylon Electricity Board’s (CEB) distribution operations into four independent units over the next couple of weeks, with an aim to enhance efficiency and transparency of the country’s electricity sector.",
        "“In order to bring efficiency, we need to move forward with the unbundling process. This is a large organisation employing over 22,000 people. Initially, we won’t be able to go for competition in generation. However, as similar to the teleco sector, unbundling will allow the units within the CEB to compete among each other, resulting in an efficient service at the lowest production cost to the consumer,” PUCSL Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said.",
        "Despite the partial unbundling of the CEB following the electricity sector reforms carried out in 2022, with Electricity Reforms Act No. 28 of 2002, the four CEB-owned distribution licensees and transmission licensee have not yet been made independent of each other.",
        "The Asian Development Bank (ADB) and Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) have recommended the unbundling of the CEB in several studies.",
        "“The next stage of reform requires establishing six independent companies out of the CEB’s generation, transmission and four distribution licensees. The organisation culture in the government-owned company LECO needs to be replicated in the CEB’s distribution licensees by creating corporate entities that report to the CEB holding company.",
        "The functional business units currently established within the CEB are adequately staffed and organised to enable the formation of six corporate entities. The corporatisation need not involve privatisation, if political decision makers do not wish to involve private capital more fully in the sector, provided the state-owned firms operate as independent commercial companies,” ADB said in a report published in 2015.",
        "However, the CEB Engineers Union (CEBEU) and other labour unions affiliated to the CEB allege that the unbundling of the CEB units is aimed at privatisation of the organisation.",
        "With the completion of the unbundling of the CEB’s distribution operations, there will be five independent licensees in power distribution, including LECO.",
        "Meanwhile, the PUCSL announced that it would direct the CEB to introduce an independent audit system for the process of purchasing electricity in order grant proposed revision in electricity tariffs.",
        "Accordingly, Ratnayake noted that an independent third party reputed firm is likely to be appointed to undertake to provide monthly audits.",
        "Further, the CEB will also be required to cut its operational costs by 10 percent, which will be invested in renewable power generation projects."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LECO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB Engineers Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next couple of weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "over 22,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Asian Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan International Cooperation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LECO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the CEB Engineers Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LECO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංවිම බෙදාහැරීමේ මෙහෙයුම් කඩිනමින් අවසන් කිරීමට PUCSL",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංවිම බෙදාහැරීමේ මෙහෙයුම LECO ඇතුළු ස්වාධීන ඒකක පහකට බෙදීමට නියමිතය",
        "එය විදුලිබල අංශයේ විනිවිදභාවය සහ කාර්යක්ෂමතාව ඉහළ නංවන බව PUCSL පවසයි",
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය පෞද්ගලීකරණය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් බදු ඉවත් කිරීම සිදු කරන බවට ලංවිම ඉංජිනේරු සංගමය සහ අනෙකුත් කම්කරු සංගම් චෝදනා කරයි",
        "2002 වසරෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලිබල ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රථම ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය සිදු කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) මේ සතියේ ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (CEB) බෙදාහැරීමේ මෙහෙයුම් ඇණහිට ඇති කොටස් ඉවත් කිරීම ස්වාධීන ඒකක හතරකට ඊළඟ යුවල තුළ සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබේ. රටේ විදුලිබල අංශයේ කාර්යක්ෂමතාව සහ විනිවිදභාවය ඉහළ නැංවීමේ අරමුණින් සති කිහිපයකින්.",
        "“කාර්යක්ෂමතාව ගෙන ඒම සඳහා, අපි ගොඩබෑමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සමඟ ඉදිරියට යා යුතුය. මෙය 22,000 කට අධික පිරිසක් සේවය කරන විශාල සංවිධානයකි. මුලදී, අපට පරම්පරාවෙන් තරඟයට යාමට නොහැකි වනු ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ටෙලිකෝ ක්ෂේත‍්‍රය හා සමානව, බණ්ඩල් කිරීම මගින් ලංවිම තුළ ඇති ඒකක එකිනෙක අතර තරඟකාරී වීමට ඉඩ සැලසෙන අතර එමඟින් පාරිභෝගිකයාට අවම නිෂ්පාදන පිරිවැයට කාර්යක්ෂම සේවාවක් ලැබෙනු ඇත.",
        "2002 අංක 28 දරන විදුලිබල ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පනතට අනුව 2022 දී සිදු කරන ලද විදුලිබල අංශයේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලින් පසු විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය අර්ධ වශයෙන් ඉවත් කළද, ලංවිම සතු බෙදාහැරීමේ බලපත්‍රලාභීන් සහ සම්ප්‍රේෂණ බලපත්‍රලාභියා තවමත් එකිනෙකින් ස්වාධීන වී නොමැත.",
        "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව (ADB) සහ ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා නියෝජිතායතනය (JICA) විසින් අධ්‍යයන කිහිපයකදී ලංවිම ඉවත් කිරීම නිර්දේශ කර ඇත.",
        "ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණයේ මීළඟ අදියර සඳහා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ උත්පාදනය, සම්ප්‍රේෂණ සහ බෙදාහැරීමේ බලපත්‍රලාභීන් හතර දෙනාගෙන් ස්වාධීන සමාගම් හයක් පිහිටුවීම අවශ්‍ය වේ. රජයට අයත් සමාගමක් වන LECO හි සංවිධාන සංස්කෘතිය ලංවිම බෙදාහැරීමේ බලපත්‍රලාභීන් තුළ ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කළ යුතු වන්නේ ලංවිම භාරකාර සමාගමට වාර්තා කරන ආයතනික ආයතන නිර්මාණය කිරීමෙනි.",
        "දැනට ලංවිම තුළ පිහිටුවා ඇති ක්‍රියාකාරී ව්‍යාපාරික ඒකක ප්‍රමාණවත් පරිදි කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයකින් සහ ආයතනික ආයතන හයක් පිහිටුවීමට හැකිවන පරිදි සංවිධානය වී ඇත. රාජ්‍ය ආයතන ස්වාධීන වාණිජ සමාගම් ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක වන්නේ නම්, දේශපාලන තීරණ ගන්නන් පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රාග්ධනය වඩාත් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ක්ෂේත්‍රයට සම්බන්ධ කර ගැනීමට අකමැති නම්, සංස්ථාපිතකරණයට පුද්ගලීකරනය සම්බන්ධ විය යුතු නැත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ලංවිම ඉංජිනේරු සංගමය (CEBEU) සහ ලංවිමට අනුබද්ධ අනෙකුත් කම්කරු සංගම් චෝදනා කරන්නේ ලංවිම ඒකක ගලවා දැමීම සංවිධානය පුද්ගලීකරනය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් බවයි.",
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ බෙදාහැරීමේ මෙහෙයුම් අවසන් වීමත් සමඟ, LECO ඇතුළුව විදුලිය බෙදා හැරීමේ ස්වාධීන බලපත්‍රලාභීන් පස් දෙනෙකු සිටිනු ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, යෝජිත විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධනයක් ලබා දීම සඳහා විදුලිය මිලදී ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සඳහා ස්වාධීන විගණන ක්‍රමයක් හඳුන්වා දෙන ලෙස ලංවිමට උපදෙස් දෙන බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව මාසික විගණන කටයුතු සිදුකිරීම සඳහා ස්වාධීන තුන්වන පාර්ශ්ව පිළිගත් සමාගමක් පත්කිරීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ ඇති බව රත්නායක සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තවද, පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති උත්පාදන ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජනය කෙරෙන සිය මෙහෙයුම් පිරිවැය සියයට 10 කින් කපා හැරීමට ද ලංවිමට සිදුවනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙකෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම ඉංජිනේරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙකෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම ඉංජිනේරු සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙකෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "PUCSL விரைவில் CEBயின் விநியோக செயல்பாடுகளை துண்டிக்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "LECO உட்பட ஐந்து சுயாதீன அலகுகளாக CEBயின் விநியோக செயல்பாடு பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "இது மின்சாரத் துறையின் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை மற்றும் செயல்திறனை மேம்படுத்தும் என்று PUCSL கூறுகிறது",
        "CEB பொறியாளர்கள் சங்கம் மற்றும் பிற தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் CEB ஐ தனியார்மயமாக்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டவை என்று குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றன.",
        "2002 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்குப் பின்னர் இலங்கையின் மின்சாரத் துறையில் முதல் பெரிய சீர்திருத்தத்தை மேற்கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) இந்த வாரம் இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின் (CEB) விநியோகச் செயற்பாடுகளை அடுத்த இரண்டு சுயாதீன அலகுகளாக நான்கு சுயாதீன அலகுகளாகப் பூர்த்தி செய்யும் திட்டத்தை அறிவித்தது. நாட்டின் மின்சாரத் துறையின் செயல்திறன் மற்றும் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையை மேம்படுத்தும் நோக்கத்துடன் வாரங்கள்.",
        "\"செயல்திறனைக் கொண்டுவருவதற்கு, நாம் பிரித்தெடுக்கும் செயல்முறையுடன் முன்னேற வேண்டும். இது 22,000 பேருக்கு மேல் பணிபுரியும் ஒரு பெரிய நிறுவனமாகும். ஆரம்பத்தில், நாம் தலைமுறையாக போட்டிக்கு செல்ல முடியாது. எவ்வாறாயினும், தொலைத்தொடர்புத் துறையைப் போலவே, CEB க்குள் உள்ள அலகுகள் ஒன்றுக்கொன்று போட்டியிட அனுமதிக்கும், இதன் விளைவாக நுகர்வோருக்கு குறைந்த உற்பத்தி செலவில் திறமையான சேவை கிடைக்கும்,\" PUCSL தலைவர் ஜானக ரத்நாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "2022 இல் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மின்சாரத் துறை சீர்திருத்தங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து, 2002 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 28 ஆம் இலக்க மின்சாரச் சீர்திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ், CEB இன் பகுதியளவு துண்டிக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும், CEB-க்கு சொந்தமான நான்கு விநியோக உரிமதாரர்கள் மற்றும் ஒலிபரப்பு உரிமம் பெற்றவர்கள் இன்னும் ஒருவரையொருவர் சுயாதீனமாக்கவில்லை.",
        "ஆசிய அபிவிருத்தி வங்கி (ADB) மற்றும் ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச கூட்டுறவு முகமை (JICA) ஆகியவை பல ஆய்வுகளில் CEB யின் கட்டுகளை அகற்ற பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளன.",
        "அடுத்த கட்ட சீர்திருத்தத்திற்கு, CEBயின் தலைமுறை, பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் நான்கு விநியோக உரிமம் பெற்றவர்களில் இருந்து ஆறு சுயாதீன நிறுவனங்களை நிறுவ வேண்டும். அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனமான LECO இல் உள்ள நிறுவன கலாச்சாரம், CEB ஹோல்டிங் நிறுவனத்திற்கு அறிக்கை செய்யும் பெருநிறுவன நிறுவனங்களை உருவாக்குவதன் மூலம் CEB இன் விநியோக உரிமதாரர்களில் பிரதிபலிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "CEB க்குள் தற்போது நிறுவப்பட்டுள்ள செயல்பாட்டு வணிக அலகுகள் போதுமான பணியாளர்கள் மற்றும் ஆறு பெருநிறுவனங்களை உருவாக்குவதற்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன. அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்கள் சுதந்திரமான வணிக நிறுவனங்களாக செயல்படும் பட்சத்தில், அரசியல் முடிவெடுப்பவர்கள் தனியார் மூலதனத்தை முழுமையாக இத்துறையில் ஈடுபடுத்த விரும்பவில்லை என்றால், பெருநிறுவனமயமாக்கல் தனியார்மயமாக்கலை உள்ளடக்கியிருக்க வேண்டியதில்லை” என்று ADB 2015 இல் வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், CEB பொறியாளர்கள் ஒன்றியம் (CEBEU) மற்றும் CEB உடன் இணைந்த பிற தொழிற்சங்கங்கள், CEB அலகுகளின் தொகுப்புகளை அகற்றுவது நிறுவனத்தை தனியார்மயமாக்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது என்று குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றன.",
        "CEBயின் விநியோக நடவடிக்கைகள் முடிவடையும் போது, ​​LECO உட்பட மின்சார விநியோகத்தில் ஐந்து சுயாதீன உரிமதாரர்கள் இருப்பார்கள்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், மின் கட்டணத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட திருத்தத்தை வழங்குவதற்காக மின்சாரம் வாங்கும் செயல்முறைக்கு ஒரு சுயாதீனமான கணக்காய்வு முறையை அறிமுகப்படுத்த CEBக்கு உத்தரவிடுவதாக PUCSL அறிவித்தது.",
        "இதன்படி, மாதாந்த கணக்காய்வுகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்காக சுயாதீன மூன்றாம் தரப்பு புகழ்பெற்ற நிறுவனமொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட உள்ளதாக ரத்நாயக்க குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மேலும், CEB அதன் செயல்பாட்டு செலவினங்களை 10 சதவிகிதம் குறைக்க வேண்டும், இது புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க மின் உற்பத்தி திட்டங்களில் முதலீடு செய்யப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெகோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB பொறியாளர்கள் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெகோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏடிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB பொறியாளர்கள் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEBEU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெகோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}