{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කෝටි-6ක-අබිලි--රේගුවේ-හිරවෙයි/101-619029",
  "time_ut": 1661879094,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝටි 6ක අබිලි  රේගුවේ හිරවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "6 Crore Abili gets stuck in customs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Customs Media Spokesperson Mr. Sudatta Silva, Director of Customs, 10 twenty-foot containers containing scrap metal worth over 6 crore rupees, which an Indian businessman tried to illegally export from the country, were seized by the officers of the Central Intelligence Division of Sri Lanka Customs.",
        "Customs says that 140 metric tons of scrap copper, aluminum and iron were found in those ten containers and that these containers contained 140 metric tons of natural crepe rubber in the customs declaration submitted by the exporter to Sri Lanka Customs.",
        "The Customs stated that three suspects have been arrested and remanded in custody regarding this illegal export. The Central Intelligence Division of the Sri Lanka Customs is conducting further investigations on this matter."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Customs Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudatta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "twenty-foot",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Intelligence Division of Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Central Intelligence Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටි 6ක අබිලි  රේගුවේ හිරවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියන් ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරිකයෙක් නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටින් අපනයනය කිරීමට උත්සහ කල රුපියල් කෝටි 6 කට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුත් අබලි ලෝහ අඩංගු අඩි විස්සේ බහාලුම් 10 ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මධ්‍යම බුද්ධි අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව රේගු මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක රේගු අධ්‍යක්ෂ සුදත්ත සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එම බහාලුම් දහය තුල තිබී අබලි තඹ, ඇලුමිනියම් සහ යකඩ මෙට්‍රික්ටොන් 140 ක් අත්අඩංගුව තිබූ බවත් මෙම බහාලුම් තුල ස්වාභාවික ක්‍රේප් රබර් මෙට්‍රික්ටොන් 140 ක් අඩංගු වන බව අපනයනකරු ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද රේගු ප්‍රකාශනයේ සඳහන් කර තිබූ බවත් රේගුව පවසයි.",
        "මෙම නීති විරෝධී අපනයනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන මේ වන විට රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර ඇති බව ටී රේගුව මේ පිළිබඳව වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මධ්‍යම බුද්ධි අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරමින් සිටින අතර විමර්ශන අවසානයේ ලෝහ තොගය රාජසන්තක කර සැකකරුවන්ට දඩ පැනවීමට නියමිත බවද රේගුව සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගු මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදත්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩි විස්සක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මධ්‍යම බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 140 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 140 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "6 கோடி அபிலி சுங்கச்சாவடியில் சிக்கினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய வர்த்தகர் ஒருவர் இலங்கையிலிருந்து சட்டவிரோதமாக ஏற்றுமதி செய்ய முயன்ற 6 கோடி ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பழைய உலோகம் அடங்கிய 10 இருபது அடி கொள்கலன்களை மத்திய புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் கைப்பற்றியதாக சுங்க ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் திரு.சுதத்த சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். இலங்கை சுங்கத்துறை.",
        "அந்த பத்து கொள்கலன்களில் 140 மெற்றிக் தொன் குப்பைத் தாமிரம், அலுமினியம் மற்றும் இரும்பு ஆகியவை காணப்பட்டதாகவும், இலங்கை சுங்கத்திற்கு ஏற்றுமதியாளர் சமர்ப்பித்த சுங்கப் பிரகடனத்தில் இந்த கொள்கலன்களில் 140 மெற்றிக் தொன் இயற்கையான க்ரீப் ரப்பர் இருப்பதாகவும் சுங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த சட்டவிரோத ஏற்றுமதி தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சுங்க திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.இது தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை இலங்கை சுங்க மத்திய புலனாய்வு பிரிவினர் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்க ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதத்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபது அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் மத்திய புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய உளவுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}