{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රාජ්‍ය-ආයතන-වල-මුල්-පුටු-හිතුමතේ-වෙනස්-කිරීම-නවත්වයි/101-618187",
  "time_ut": 1660628624,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන වල මුල් පුටු හිතුමතේ වෙනස් කිරීම නවත්වයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Stops arbitrary change of heads of government institutions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe has appointed a committee to obtain prior approval for new appointments or changes to the positions of chairman and director of state corporations, statutory boards and state-owned enterprises.",
        "Chief Secretary Anura Dissanayake, Cabinet Secretary W.M.D.J. Messrs. Fernando and Mr.",
        "Mr. Chaminda Kularatne, Additional Secretary to the President, has been appointed as the secretary of the committee.",
        "If it is necessary to change the positions of chairman and board of directors of state corporations, statutory boards and state-owned enterprises, it is mandatory to submit nominations to the above committee with justifiable reasons and obtain prior approval.",
        "This committee has been appointed by focusing on the written requests made to the President from time to time and some informal appointments to change the positions of chairman and board of directors of state corporations, statutory boards and state-owned enterprises without prior agreement.",
        "In this regard, a letter has been sent directly to all the secretaries of the ministries with the signature of the President's Secretary, and copies have been sent to the Prime Minister's Secretary and the Ministry of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policy for making the necessary arrangements."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.M.D.J.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Kularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන වල මුල් පුටු හිතුමතේ වෙනස් කිරීම නවත්වයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල හා රජය සතු ව්‍යවසාය ආයතනවල සභාපති සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ තනතුරු සඳහා නව පත්කිරීම් සිදු කිරීමේ දී හෝ වෙනස් කිරීමේ දී පූර්ව අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් කමිටුවක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ සභාපතිත්වයෙන් යුත් කමිටුවේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් ලෙස අග්‍රමාත්‍ය ලේකම් අනුර දිසානායක,  අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල ලේකම්  ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ. ප්‍රනාන්දු යන මහත්වරු කටයුතු කරති.",
        "කමිටුවේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් චමින්ද කුලරත්න මහතා පත් කර ඇත.",
        "රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල හා රජය සතු ව්‍යවසාය ආයතනවල සභාපති සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල තනතුරු වෙනස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් සාධාරණීකරණය කළ හැකි හේතු සහිතව නාම යෝජනා ඉහත කමිටුවට ඉදිරිපත් කර පූර්ව අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම අනිවාර්යය කර තිබේ.",
        "පූර්ව එකඟතාවකින් තොරව රාජ්‍ය සංස්ථා, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මණ්ඩල හා රජය සතු ව්‍යවසාය ආයතනවල සභාපති සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල තනතුරු වෙනස් කිරීමට විටින් විට  ජනාධිපති වෙත කෙරෙන ලිඛිත ඉල්ලීම් සහ ඇතැම් අවිධිමත් පත්කිරීම් පිළිබඳ අවධානය යොමු කරමින් මෙම කමිටුව පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපති ලේකම්ගේ අත්සනින් යුතුව සියලුම අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන්ට සෘජුව ලිපියක් යොමු කර ඇති අතර, ඒ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු සම්පාදනය වෙනුවෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් හා මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ හා ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයට පිටපත් යොමු කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එම්.ඩී.ජේ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்களை தன்னிச்சையாக மாற்றுவதை நிறுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரச கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள், சட்ட சபைகள் மற்றும் அரச நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பணிப்பாளர் பதவிகளில் புதிய நியமனங்கள் அல்லது மாற்றங்களுக்கு முன் அனுமதி பெறுவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க குழுவொன்றை நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதம செயலாளர் அனுர திஸாநாயக்க, அமைச்சரவை செயலாளர் டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே. பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் திரு.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவின் செயலாளராக ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் திரு.சமிந்த குலரத்ன நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரச கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள், சட்ட சபைகள் மற்றும் அரச நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பணிப்பாளர் பதவிகளை மாற்றுவதற்கு அவசியமானால், நியாயமான காரணங்களுடன் மேற்படி குழுவிடம் பரிந்துரைகளை சமர்ப்பித்து முன் அனுமதி பெறுவது கட்டாயமாகும்.",
        "அரச கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள், சட்ட சபைகள் மற்றும் அரச நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர் மற்றும் பணிப்பாளர் பதவிகளை முன் உடன்படிக்கையின்றி மாற்றுவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அவ்வப்போது விடுக்கப்பட்ட எழுத்து மூலமான கோரிக்கைகள் மற்றும் சில முறைசாரா நியமனங்கள் தொடர்பில் கவனம் செலுத்தி இந்தக் குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பாக ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளரின் கையொப்பத்துடன் அனைத்து அமைச்சுக்களின் செயலாளர்களுக்கும் நேரடியாக கடிதம் அனுப்பப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், அதற்கான பிரதிகள் பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் மற்றும் நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கை அமைச்சுக்கு அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஏற்பாடுகள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.எம்.டி.ஜே.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த குலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}