{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84393/japan-provides-jpy-500-million-medical-grant-to-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1660879980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan provides JPY 500 million medical grant to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan provides JPY 500 million medical grant to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japan has provided JPY 500 million worth of modern Japanese medical equipment to Sri Jayewardenepura General Hospital to strengthen the hospital capabilities to combat Non-Communicable Diseases (NCDs) and enhance the social and humanitarian development in Sri Lanka, which has been highly affected due to present dire economic conditions.",
        "On August 18, Ambassador Hideaki Mizukoshi signed an Exchange of Note for the grant assistance, the Embassy of Japan in Colombo said in a statement.",
        "Sri Jayewardenepura General Hospital was constructed in 1983 with the grant aid from the Japanese government as a token of appreciation and friendship to former President Mr. J. R. Jayewardene for his generous encouragement of Japan’s return to the international community at the San Francisco Peace Conference.",
        "Augmenting the historical relationship, Japan will provide latest equipment such as CT angiography, catheter surgical equipment, transplantation devices, ophthalmology equipment, as well as establishing the new dental ward, to enhance treatment and surgical capabilities for NCDs including cancer, stroke, and diabetes, while reducing the rate of blindness and caries in Sri Lanka.",
        "NCDs patients account for over 80% of all deaths in Sri Lanka and they tend to be at higher risk of severe symptoms and death when infected with COVID-19.",
        "Furthermore, the current economic crisis poses a significant risk of increased NCDs due to deteriorating health and nutritional status to many citizens. “We hope this assistance will improve diagnosis and treatment of NCDs and help reduce related mortality and incidence in Sri Lanka, especially in the Western Province, the embassy said further.",
        "“At this historic milestone of the 70th anniversary of the diplomatic relationships between Japan and Sri Lanka, we believe that Sri Jayewardenepura General Hospital will become another landmark to represent the close bilateral relationship.”",
        "The statement read that Japan remain committed to help overcome this economic crisis together as a long-standing development partner of Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "500 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Jayewardenepura General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Non-Communicable Diseases",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideaki Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "an Exchange of Note",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Embassy of Japan in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Jayewardenepura General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "J. R. Jayewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the San Francisco Peace Conference",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "over 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Jayewardenepura General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වෛද්‍ය ආධාර මිලියන 500ක් ලබා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වර්තමානය වන විට දැඩි ලෙස බලපා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බෝ නොවන රෝග (NCD) වලට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීමට සහ සමාජීය හා මානුෂීය සංවර්ධනය නංවාලීම සඳහා රෝහල් හැකියාවන් ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා ජපානය විසින් JPY මිලියන 500 ක් වටිනා නවීන ජපන් වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර මහ රෝහල වෙත ලබා දී ඇත. දරුණු ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයන්.",
        "අගෝස්තු 18 වන දින, තානාපති Hideaki Mizukoshi ප්‍රදාන ආධාර සඳහා මුදල් හුවමාරු පත්‍රයකට අත්සන් කළ බව කොළඹ ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර මහ රෝහල 1983 වසරේ සැන් ෆ්‍රැන්සිස්කෝ සාම සමුළුවේදී ජපානය නැවත ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව වෙත ගෙන ඒම වෙනුවෙන් කළ නොමසුරු දිරිගැන්වීම වෙනුවෙන් හිටපු ජනාධිපති ජේ.ආර්.",
        "ඓතිහාසික සබඳතාව වර්ධනය කරමින්, පිළිකා, ආඝාතය සහ දියවැඩියාව ඇතුළු NCD සඳහා ප්‍රතිකාර සහ ශල්‍ය හැකියාවන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ජපානය CT angiography, කැතීටර් ශල්‍ය උපකරණ, බද්ධ කිරීමේ උපකරණ, අක්ෂි වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ මෙන්ම නව දන්ත වාට්ටුව පිහිටුවීම වැනි නවීන උපකරණ ලබා දෙනු ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අන්ධභාවය සහ දිරාපත් වීමේ වේගය අඩු කරන අතරතුර.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම මරණ වලින් 80% කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් NCD රෝගීන් වන අතර ඔවුන් COVID-19 ආසාදනය වූ විට දරුණු රෝග ලක්ෂණ සහ මරණයට පත්වීමේ වැඩි අවදානමක් ඇත.",
        "තවද, වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය බොහෝ පුරවැසියන්ගේ සෞඛ්‍ය හා පෝෂණ තත්ත්වය පිරිහීම හේතුවෙන් NCDs වැඩි වීමේ සැලකිය යුතු අවදානමක් මතු කරයි. “මෙම ආධාරය මගින් NCDs හඳුනාගැනීම සහ ප්‍රතිකාර කිරීම වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමටත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ, විශේෂයෙන්ම බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ඒ ආශ්‍රිත මරණ සහ සිදුවීම් අවම කිරීමටත් හැකිවනු ඇතැයි අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා, තානාපති කාර්යාලය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ජපානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතාවලට වසර 70ක් සපිරෙන මෙම ඓතිහාසික සන්ධිස්ථානයේදී ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර මහ රෝහල සමීප ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතාව නියෝජනය කරන තවත් සන්ධිස්ථානයක් බවට පත්වනු ඇතැයි අපි විශ්වාස කරමු.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දීර්ඝ කාලීන සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවෙකු ලෙස එක්ව මෙම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ජය ගැනීමට ජපානය කැපවී සිටින බව එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 500 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝ නොවන රෝග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideaki Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සටහන් හුවමාරුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "J. R. ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැන් ෆ්රැන්සිස්කෝ සාම සමුළුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80% ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் இலங்கைக்கு JPY 500 மில்லியன் மருத்துவ உதவிகளை வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் சமூக மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான அபிவிருத்தியை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும், தொற்றாத நோய்களை (NCD) தடுப்பதற்கும் மருத்துவமனைத் திறனை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்காக ஜப்பான் 500 மில்லியன் பெறுமதியான நவீன ஜப்பானிய மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களை ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பொது வைத்தியசாலைக்கு வழங்கியுள்ளது. மோசமான பொருளாதார நிலைமைகள்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 18 அன்று, தூதர் ஹிடேகி மிசுகோஷி மானிய உதவிக்கான பரிமாற்றக் குறிப்பில் கையெழுத்திட்டார் என்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜப்பான் தூதரகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பொது வைத்தியசாலை 1983 ஆம் ஆண்டு சான்பிரான்சிஸ்கோ சமாதான மாநாட்டில் ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச சமூகத்திற்கு திரும்புவதற்கு தாராளமாக ஊக்குவித்தமைக்காக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி திரு. ஜே.ஆர்.",
        "வரலாற்று உறவை மேம்படுத்தும் வகையில், புற்றுநோய், பக்கவாதம் மற்றும் நீரிழிவு உள்ளிட்ட NCD களுக்கு சிகிச்சை மற்றும் அறுவை சிகிச்சை திறன்களை மேம்படுத்த, CT ஆஞ்சியோகிராபி, வடிகுழாய் அறுவை சிகிச்சை உபகரணங்கள், மாற்று சாதனங்கள், கண் மருத்துவ உபகரணங்கள், அத்துடன் புதிய பல் வார்டு நிறுவுதல் போன்ற சமீபத்திய உபகரணங்களை ஜப்பான் வழங்கும். இலங்கையில் குருட்டுத்தன்மை மற்றும் நோய்களின் வீதத்தை குறைக்கும் போது.",
        "இலங்கையில் 80% க்கும் அதிகமான இறப்புகளுக்கு NCD நோயாளிகள் காரணமாக உள்ளனர், மேலும் அவர்கள் COVID-19 நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட போது கடுமையான அறிகுறிகள் மற்றும் இறப்புக்கான அதிக ஆபத்தில் உள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியானது, பல குடிமக்களின் உடல்நலம் மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து நிலை மோசமடைந்து வருவதால், அதிகரித்த NCDகளின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க ஆபத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது. “இந்த உதவியானது NCD களின் நோயறிதல் மற்றும் சிகிச்சையை மேம்படுத்துவதோடு, இலங்கையில் குறிப்பாக மேல் மாகாணத்தில் தொடர்புடைய இறப்பு மற்றும் நிகழ்வுகளைக் குறைக்க உதவும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம், தூதரகம் மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "\"ஜப்பானுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளின் 70 வது ஆண்டு நிறைவின் இந்த வரலாற்று மைல்கல்லில், ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பொது மருத்துவமனை நெருங்கிய இருதரப்பு உறவைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் மற்றொரு அடையாளமாக மாறும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்.\"",
        "இலங்கையின் நீண்டகால அபிவிருத்தி பங்காளியாக இணைந்து இந்த பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க ஜப்பான் அர்ப்பணிப்புடன் இருப்பதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "500 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொற்றா நோய்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hideaki Mizukoshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறிப்பு பரிமாற்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜப்பான் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சான் பிரான்சிஸ்கோ அமைதி மாநாடு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}