{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/speculation-on-impending-tax-hikes-brings-down-bourse/",
  "time_ut": 1661362140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Speculation on impending tax hikes brings down bourse",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speculation on impending tax hikes brings down bourse",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "CSE stocks slipped in mid-day trade yesterday, pushed down by retail and banking shares. During the day selling pressure was noted due to the forthcoming budget to be presented to parliament on August 30 by the Finance Minister/ President Ranil Wickremesinghe, which hinted at probable government revenue increases through taxes, stock market analysts said.",
        "“We are seeing profit- taking in index heavy shares that gained in the previous sessions and are seeing a lot of selling in the banking shares because the investors are speculating on a domestic debt recovery to take place. Further, tax increase would likely affect many sectors in the stock market, analysts told The Island Financial Review.",
        "Both the Central Bank Governor Nandalal Weerasinghe and the co-Cabinet spokesperson said that a local debt restructuring will not take place as it will collapse the already illiquid banking system.",
        "Amid those profit- takings, speculation on the interim budget tax increases has created some negative investor sentiment. Therefore, both indices moved downwards. The main All -Share Price Index declined 60.29 points (0.66 per cent) to end at 9011.24 and S and P SL20 declined by 45.28 points (1.51 per cent) to end the day at 2944.50.",
        "Turnover stood at Rs 2.55 billion with three crossings. Those crossings were reported in JKH, which crossed 1.2 million shares to the tune of Rs 159 million, its shares traded at Rs 123.50, Kahawatte Plantations one million shares crossed to the tune of Rs 36.5 million, its shares traded at Rs 36.50 and Horana Plantations 500,000 shares crossed to the tune of Rs 30.5 million; its shares fetched Rs 61.",
        "In the retail market top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were, Lanka IOC Rs 430 million (2.4 million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 277 million (1.2 million shares traded), Kotagala Plantations Rs 187 million (20.1 million shares traded), Kahawatte Plantations Rs 100.3 million (2.6 million shares traded), Horana Plantations Rs 79 million (1.4 million shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 70.7 million (8.9 million shares traded) and Asiya Siyaka Commodities Rs 67.6 million (16.8 million shares traded). During the day 115 million share volumes changed hands in 31000 share transactions.",
        "Yesterday, the Central Bank’s dollar selling rate was Rs 368.71 and the selling rate Rs 357.40.",
        "DIF managed by BOV Capital leads LKR 205 million funding round for IFINITY",
        "Dialog’s Govi Mithuru partners TRI to extend advisory services on tea cultivation",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Island Financial Review",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60.29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.66 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "45.28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.51 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2944.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "159 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "123.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kahawatte Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horana Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC Rs 430 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "277 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotagala Plantations Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "187 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kahawatte Plantations Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horana Plantations Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "79 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.71",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs 357.40",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DIF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOV Capital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "205 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFINITY",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Govi Mithuru",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TRI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එළඹෙන බදු ඉහල දැමීම් පිලිබඳ සමපේක්ෂනය කොටස් වෙලඳාම පහතට ඇද දමයි",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "CSE කොටස් ඊයේ මධ්‍යම දින වෙළඳාමේ දී පහත වැටුණු අතර සිල්ලර සහ බැංකු කොටස් මගින් පහත වැටුණි. මුදල් අමාත්‍ය/ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත අයවැය හේතුවෙන් බදු මගින් රාජ්‍ය ආදායම ඉහළ යා හැකි බවට ඉඟි පළ කිරීම හේතුවෙන් දිවා කාලයේදී විකුණුම් පීඩනයක් ඇති වූ බව කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "“පසුගිය සැසිවාරවල දී ලබා ගත් දර්ශක බර කොටස්වල ලාභ ලැබීමක් අපි දකින අතර බැංකු කොටස්වල විශාල වශයෙන් විකිණීමක් දකින්නේ ආයෝජකයින් දේශීය ණය ප්‍රතිසාධනයක් සිදුවනු ඇතැයි අනුමාන කරන බැවිනි. තවද, බදු වැඩිවීම කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ බොහෝ අංශවලට බලපානු ඇතැයි විශ්ලේෂකයින් The Island Financial Review වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ සහ සම කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක යන දෙදෙනාම පැවසුවේ දැනටමත් ද්‍රවශීල බැංකු පද්ධතිය බිඳ වැටෙන බැවින් දේශීය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමක් සිදු නොවන බවයි.",
        "එම ලාභ ඉපැයීම් මධ්‍යයේ, අතුරු අයවැය බදු වැඩිවීම් පිළිබඳ සමපේක්ෂනය ආයෝජකයන්ගේ යම් ඍණාත්මක මනෝභාවයක් ඇති කර තිබේ. එබැවින් දර්ශක දෙකම පහළට ගමන් කළේය. ප්‍රධාන සියලු කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 60.29 කින් (සියයට 0.66) පහළ ගොස් 9011.24 න් අවසන් වූ අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 45.28 කින් (සියයට 1.51) පහළ ගොස් 2944.50 ක් විය.",
        "හරස් මාර්ග තුනක් සමඟ පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 2.55 ක් විය. JKH හි කොටස් මිලියන 1.2 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 159 දක්වාත්, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 123.50 දක්වාත්, කහවත්ත ප්ලාන්ටේෂන්ස් කොටස් මිලියනයක් හරහා රුපියල් මිලියන 36.5 දක්වාත්, එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 36.50 දක්වාත්, හොරණ වැවිලි සමාගමෙන්ද එම හරස්වීම් වාර්තා විය. කොටස් 500,000 ක් රුපියල් මිලියන 30.5 දක්වා ඉක්මවා ඇත; එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 61ක් ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ සමාගම් හත වන්නේ, ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 430 (කොටස් මිලියන 2.4 ක්), එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 277 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.2 ක්), කොටගල වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 187 ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 20.1 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) , කහවත්ත වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 100.3ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 2.6ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත), හොරණ වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 79ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 1.4ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත), Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 70.7ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 8.9ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ Asiya Siyaka Commodities රුපියල් මිලියන 67.6ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 16.8ක් වෙළඳාම් කර ඇත). දවස තුළ කොටස් ගනුදෙනු 31000 කදී කොටස් වෙළුම් මිලියන 115 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "ඊයේ මහ බැංකුවේ ඩොලරයේ විකුණුම් අගය රුපියල් 368.71 ක් වූ අතර විකුණුම් මිල රුපියල් 357.40 ක් විය.",
        "BOV Capital විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරන ලද DIF IFINITY සඳහා LKR මිලියන 205 ක අරමුදල් වටයේ පෙරමුණ ගෙන සිටී.",
        "Dialog හි Govi ​​Mithuru තේ වගාව පිළිබඳ උපදේශන සේවා දීර්ඝ කිරීමට TRI හවුල් වේ",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අයිලන්ඩ් මූල්‍ය සමාලෝචනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60.29 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 0.66 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "45.28 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.51 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2944.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.කේ.එච්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 159 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "123.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කහවත්ත වතු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 36.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොරණ වැවිලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 30.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 430 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 277 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටගල වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 187 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 20.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කහවත්ත වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොරණ වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 79 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 70.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 67.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 115 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.71 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 357.40 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DIF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOV ප්රාග්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 205 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFINITY",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොවි මිතුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TRI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வரவிருக்கும் வரி உயர்வுகள் பற்றிய ஊகங்கள் பங்குச் சந்தையைக் குறைக்கின்றன",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "சில்லறை வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் வங்கிப் பங்குகளால் நேற்றைய வர்த்தகத்தில் சிஎஸ்இ பங்குகள் சரிவைச் சந்தித்தன. நிதியமைச்சர்/ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் ஆகஸ்ட் 30ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டம் காரணமாக பகலில் விற்பனை அழுத்தம் காணப்பட்டது.",
        "\"முந்தைய அமர்வுகளில் பெறப்பட்ட குறியீட்டு கனமான பங்குகளில் லாபம் பெறுவதை நாங்கள் காண்கிறோம் மற்றும் வங்கி பங்குகளில் அதிக விற்பனையைப் பார்க்கிறோம், ஏனெனில் முதலீட்டாளர்கள் உள்நாட்டுக் கடன் மீட்பு நடைபெற வேண்டும் என்று ஊகிக்கிறார்கள். மேலும், வரி அதிகரிப்பு பங்குச் சந்தையில் பல துறைகளை பாதிக்கும் என்று ஆய்வாளர்கள் தி ஐலண்ட் பைனான்சியல் ரிவியூவிடம் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுனர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க மற்றும் இணை அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் இருவரும், உள்ளுர் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட மாட்டாது எனத் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். ஏனெனில் இது ஏற்கனவே பணவீக்கமற்ற வங்கி முறையை தகர்த்தெறியும்.",
        "அந்த லாபம் எடுப்பதற்கு மத்தியில், இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் வரி அதிகரிப்பு குறித்த ஊகங்கள் சில எதிர்மறை முதலீட்டாளர்களின் உணர்வை உருவாக்கியுள்ளன. அதனால், இரு குறியீடுகளும் கீழ்நோக்கி நகர்ந்தன. முக்கிய அனைத்துப் பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 60.29 புள்ளிகள் (0.66 சதவீதம்) சரிந்து 9011.24 ஆகவும், S மற்றும் P SL20 45.28 புள்ளிகள் (1.51 சதவீதம்) குறைந்து 2944.50 ஆகவும் முடிவடைந்தன.",
        "மூன்று குறுக்குவழிகள் மூலம் புரள்வு ரூ.2.55 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. JKH இல் 1.2 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் 159 மில்லியன் ரூபாவாகவும், அதன் பங்குகள் 123.50 ரூபாவாகவும், கஹவத்தை பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் ஒரு மில்லியன் பங்குகள் 36.5 மில்லியன் ரூபாவாகவும், அதன் பங்குகள் 36.50 ரூபாவாகவும், ஹொரணை பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திலும் அந்த கடவுகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன. 500,000 பங்குகள் ரூ. 30.5 மில்லியனைக் கடந்தன; அதன் பங்குகள் ரூ.61.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சந்தையில், லங்கா ஐஓசி 430 மில்லியன் (2.4 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 277 மில்லியன் (1.2 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), கொட்டகலை பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் ரூ 187 மில்லியன் (20.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) ஆகியவை முக்கிய பங்களிப்பை வழங்கிய ஏழு நிறுவனங்களாகும். , Kahawatte Plantations Rs 100.3 மில்லியன் (2.6 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), ஹொரண தோட்டங்கள் Rs 79 மில்லியன் (1.4 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), Browns Investments Rs 70.7 மில்லியன் (8.9 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் Asiya Siyaka Commodities Rs 67.6 மில்லியன் (16.8 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்). நாளின் போது 31000 பங்கு பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 115 மில்லியன் பங்கு அளவுகள் மாறின.",
        "நேற்று, மத்திய வங்கியின் டொலர் விற்பனை விலை 368.71 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை விலை 357.40 ரூபாவாகவும் இருந்தது.",
        "BOV மூலதனத்தால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும் DIF ஆனது IFINITYக்கான LKR 205 மில்லியன் நிதி சுற்றுக்கு முன்னணியில் உள்ளது",
        "தேயிலை பயிர்ச்செய்கை தொடர்பான ஆலோசனை சேவைகளை விரிவுபடுத்த Dialog's Govi ​​Mithuru பங்குதாரர்கள் TRI",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்தியானம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தீவின் நிதி ஆய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60.29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.66 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "45.28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.51 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2944.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.கே.எச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "159 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "123.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஹாவத்தை தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொரண தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி 430 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "277 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகலை தோட்டங்கள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "187 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஹாவத்தை தோட்டங்கள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொரண தோட்டங்கள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "79 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "67.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "115 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.71",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ.357.40",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DIF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOV மூலதனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "205 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFINITY",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோவி மிதுரு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஆர்ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}