{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83387/galle-road-obstructed-between-ambalangoda-and-hikkaduwa",
  "time_ut": 1656774420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Galle Road obstructed between Ambalangoda and Hikkaduwa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Galle Road obstructed between Ambalangoda and Hikkaduwa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Police says that vehicular traffic along the road from Usmudunawa in Ambalangoda to Kumarakanda in Hikkaduwa has been obstructed due to sea waves crashing on to the side of the road.",
        "Motorists are advised to use alternate routes, police said. Meanwhile it is reported that the Alakanda Road is also risky for travel.",
        "Earlier today, the Department of Meteorology issued a ‘Red’ alert for gusty winds and rough seas, advising the fishing and naval communities not to venture out into the sea areas off the coast extending from Colombo to Hambantota via Galle within the next 24 hours.",
        "In its advisory, the Meteorology Department said the wind speeds can increase up to 60-70 kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Colombo, Galle and Hambantota due to the active south-west monsoon condition.",
        "The swell waves (about 2.5 m – 3.5 m) height (this is not for land areas) are likely to increase in the above-mentioned sea areas and these sea areas will be rough to very rough.",
        "There is a possibility that nearshore sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Matara via Colombo and Galle, may experience surges due to swell waves, it said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Galle Road",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hikkaduwa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Usmudunawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambalangoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumarakanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hikkaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Alakanda Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Meteorology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "west monsoon",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගාලු පාර අම්බලන්ගොඩ හා හික්කඩුව අතර අවහිර වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අම්බලන්ගොඩ උස්මුදුනාව සිට හික්කඩුව කුමාරකන්ද දක්වා මුහුදු රළ මාර්ගය දෙපසට කඩා වැටීම හේතුවෙන් එම මාර්ගයේ වාහන ගමනාගමනයට බාධා එල්ල වී ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "රථ වාහන රියදුරන්ට විකල්ප මාර්ග භාවිත කරන ලෙස දන්වා සිටින බව පොලිසිය පවසයි. මේ අතර අලකන්ද මාර්ගය ද ගමනාගමනයට අවදානම් බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "තද සුළං සහ රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ පිළිබඳ ‘රතු’ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කළ කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, ඉදිරි පැය 24 තුළ කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල හරහා හම්බන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවර සහ නාවික ප්‍රජාවට නොයන ලෙස දැනුම් දෙයි.",
        "සක්‍රීය නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.",
        "ඉහත සඳහන් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ වල රළ (මීටර් 2.5 – 3.5 පමණ) උසින් (මෙය ගොඩබිම් සඳහා නොවේ) වැඩි වීමට ඉඩ ඇති අතර එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ රළු සිට ඉතා රළු වේ.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ සහ ගාල්ල හරහා මාතර දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල රළ රළ ඇතිවීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතින බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගාලු පාර",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hikkaduwa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "උස්මුදුනාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරකන්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hikkaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලකන්ද පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර මෝසම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அம்பலாங்கொட மற்றும் ஹிக்கடுவைக்கு இடையில் காலி வீதி தடைப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அம்பலாங்கொடை உஸ்முதுனாவ தொடக்கம் ஹிக்கடுவை குமாரகந்த வரையான வீதியின் ஓரத்தில் கடல் அலைகள் மோதுவதால் அவ்வீதியின் வாகன போக்குவரத்து தடைப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "வாகன சாரதிகள் மாற்று வழிகளைப் பயன்படுத்துமாறு பொலிஸார் அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளனர். இதேவேளை, அலகந்த வீதியும் பயணத்திற்கு ஆபத்தானதாக உள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து காலி ஊடாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளுக்கு அடுத்த 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குள் மீன்பிடி மற்றும் கடற்படை சமூகத்தினர் செல்ல வேண்டாம் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் இன்று அதிகாலை ‘சிவப்பு’ எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "தென்மேற்குப் பருவப்பெயர்ச்சி நிலை காரணமாக புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 60-70 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேற்கூறிய கடற்பகுதிகளில் அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.5 மீ – 3.5 மீ) உயரம் (இது நிலப்பகுதிகளுக்கானது அல்ல) அதிகரிக்க வாய்ப்புள்ளது மேலும் இந்த கடல் பகுதிகள் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் மிகவும் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் இருக்கும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும் காலி ஊடாக மாத்தறை வரையான கரையோரத்திற்கு அண்மித்த கடற்பரப்புகளில் அலைகள் எழும்புவதால் எழுச்சி ஏற்படலாம் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காலி வீதி",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hikkaduwa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உஸ்முதுனாவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பலாங்கொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமரகந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hikkaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலகண்டா சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை ஆய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு பருவமழை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}