{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/වතුකර-ජනතාවට-ඔන්ලයින්-ක්‍රමයට-වෛද්‍ය-සේවාවක්/1-618280",
  "time_ut": 1660730321,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වතුකර ජනතාවට ඔන්ලයින් ක්‍රමයට වෛද්‍ය සේවාවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Online medical service for plantation people",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga, Minister of Urban Development and Housing, said that an online medical treatment and counseling service will be started from September 1 for the plantation people.",
        "The Minister mentioned that the New Village Development Authority under the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing will launch this service focusing on Badulla and Idalgashinnawatta.",
        "This medical treatment service project is named as O - DOC, and it costs 100 rupees per month per family.",
        "The minister also said that medical and counseling services can be obtained for all members of the family, and the services of more than 150 doctors are available 24 hours a day.",
        "The Minister said this. Urban Development and Housing Minister Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga said this in a discussion held yesterday (16) at the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing in Setsiripaye, Battaramulla with the officials of Estate Housing Division."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the New Village Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Idalgashinnawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing in Setsiripaye",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Estate Housing Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වතුකර ජනතාවට ඔන්ලයින් ක්‍රමයට වෛද්‍ය සේවාවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වතුකර ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් මාර්ගගත ක්‍රමවේදය යටතේ (online) වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර හා උපදේශන සේවාවක් සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වැනිදා සිට ආරම්භ කරන බව නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍ය  ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ ඇති නව ගම්මාන සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය මගින් බදුල්ල, ඉදල්ගස්හින්නවත්ත කේන්ද්‍ර කර ගනිමින් මෙම සේවාව දියත් කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර සේවා ව්‍යාපෘතිය  O - DOCලෙස නම් කර ඇති අතර,  ඒ සදහා එක් පවුලකට මසකට රුපියල් 100 ක මුදලක් වැය වේ.",
        "ඉන් පවුලේ සියලු සාමාජිකයින් වෙනුවෙන් වෛද්‍ය හා උපදේශන සේවා ලබා ගත හැකි අතර, මෙහිදී පැය 24 පුරාම වෛද්‍යවරු 150 කට වැඩි පිරිසකගේ සේවාව ලබා ගත හැකි බව ද ඇමතිවරයා කීය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍ය  ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා මේ බව පැවසුවේ වතු නිවාස අංශයේ නිළධාරීන් සමඟ බත්තරමුල්ල, සෙත්සිරිපායේ පිහිටි නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී ඊයේ (16) පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව ගම් සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදල්ගස්හින්නවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙත්සිරිපායේ නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වතු නිවාස අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெருந்தோட்ட மக்களுக்கான இணையவழி மருத்துவ சேவை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெருந்தோட்ட மக்களுக்கான இணையவழி மருத்துவ சிகிச்சை மற்றும் ஆலோசனை சேவை செப்டெம்பர் முதலாம் திகதி முதல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள புதிய கிராம அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபையானது பதுளை மற்றும் இடல்கசின்னாவத்தையை மையப்படுத்தி இந்த சேவையை ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இந்த மருத்துவ சிகிச்சை சேவை திட்டத்திற்கு O - DOC என பெயரிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் ஒரு குடும்பத்திற்கு மாதம் 100 ரூபாய் செலவாகும்.",
        "குடும்பத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் மருத்துவ மற்றும் ஆலோசனை சேவைகளை பெற்றுக் கொள்ள முடியும் எனவும், 150க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வைத்தியர்களின் சேவை 24 மணி நேரமும் கிடைக்கப்பெறுவதாகவும் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.பத்தரமுல்லை செத்சிறிபாயிலுள்ள நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சில் நேற்று (16) தோட்ட வீடமைப்பு பிரிவு அதிகாரிகளுடன் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் போதே நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதிய கிராம அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடல்கசின்னவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சு செத்சிரிபாயே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்டேட் வீட்டுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}