{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/30/25-iusf-activists-arrested-during-protest/",
  "time_ut": 1661862360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "25 IUSF activists arrested during protest",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "25 IUSF activists arrested during protest",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Inter-University Student's Federation protested in Colombo on Tuesday, only to be met by Tear and Water Cannons from Police.",
        "25 people were later arrested for taking part in the protest.",
        "The Inter-Univesity Student's Federation gathered opposite the Elphinstone Theatre in Maradana, Colombo on Tuesday (30) evening to protest against the arrests made via the Prevention of Terrorism Act.",
        "The protest march was joined by civil activists as well, however, Sri Lanka Police informed them that the protest march cannot go ahead as it did not have any prior approval.",
        "The ISUF then commenced its protest march, while Sri Lanka Police, the Special Task Force, and the Riot Police had obstructed their path from the Technical Junction in Colombo.",
        "The protestors then attempted to reroute their protest march to Lipton Circus via Maradana, and steps were taken to disperse them from opposite the Health Ministry premises.",
        "Health workers protested against the arrest of several protestors, and several of them were also arrested.",
        "The protestors were driven to Technical Junction in Maradana, by Sri Lanka Police, the Special Task Force, and Riot Place.",
        "Bangladesh will never face a situation like Sri Lanka: PM Sheikh Hasina"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Inter-University Student's Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tear and Water Cannons from Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Inter-Univesity Student's Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Elphinstone Theatre",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maradana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ISUF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Riot Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Technical Junction in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lipton Circus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maradana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maradana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Riot Place",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Sheikh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාවයේදී අවිශිබම ක්‍රියාකාරීන් 25ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අන්තර් විශ්ව විද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය අඟහරුවාදා කොළඹදී විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ අතර, ඊට පොලිසියෙන් කඳුළු සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කිරීමට සිදු විය.",
        "විරෝධතාවයට සහභාගි වූ පුද්ගලයන් 25 දෙනෙකු පසුව අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත හරහා සිදුකළ අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම්වලට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය අඟහරුවාදා (30) සවස කොළඹ මරදාන එල්ෆින්ස්ටන් රඟහල ඉදිරිපිටට රැස්විය.",
        "මෙම විරෝධතා පා ගමනට සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ද එක්ව සිටි අතර, කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය ඔවුන්ට දන්වා සිටියේ විරෝධතා පා ගමනට පූර්ව අනුමැතියක් නොමැති බැවින් එය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "අනතුරුව ISUF සිය විරෝධතා පාගමන ආරම්භ කළ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය, විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය සහ කැරලි මර්දන පොලිසිය කොළඹ ටෙක්නිකල් හන්දියෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ මාර්ගයට බාධා කර ඇත.",
        "අනතුරුව විරෝධතාකරුවන් සිය විරෝධතා පාගමන මරදාන හරහා ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම දක්වා ගමන් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ අතර සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශ පරිශ්‍රය ඉදිරිපිටින් ඔවුන් විසුරුවා හැරීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට එරෙහිව සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින් විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ අතර ඔවුන්ගෙන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් මරදාන ටෙක්නිකල් හන්දිය දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය, විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය සහ කැරලි මර්දන පෙදෙසට ගෙන යන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි තත්ත්වයකට බංග්ලාදේශයට කිසිදා මුහුණ නොදෙන බව අගමැතිනි ෂෙයික් හසීනා පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසියෙන් කඳුළු සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ෆින්ස්ටන් රඟහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරදාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ISUF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැරලි මර්දන පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ටෙක්නිකල් හන්දිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිප්ටන් වටරවුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරදාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මරදාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැරලි පෙදෙස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති ෂීක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டத்தின் போது 25 IUSF செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனம் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கொழும்பில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதுடன், பொலிஸாரினால் கண்ணீர் மற்றும் நீர்த்தாரை பிரயோகங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டன.",
        "இதையடுத்து போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட 25 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட கைதுகளுக்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனம் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (30) மாலை கொழும்பு மருதானை எல்பின்ஸ்டோன் திரையரங்கிற்கு எதிரே ஒன்று கூடியது.",
        "இந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்ட பேரணியில் சிவில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களும் கலந்துகொண்டனர், எனினும், எந்தவித முன் அனுமதியும் பெறாததால், எதிர்ப்பு பேரணியை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்ல முடியாது என இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் ISUF தனது எதிர்ப்பு அணிவகுப்பை ஆரம்பித்தது, அதேவேளை இலங்கை பொலிஸ், விசேட அதிரடிப்படை மற்றும் கலகத்தடுப்பு பொலிஸார் கொழும்பில் உள்ள டெக்னிக்கல் சந்தியிலிருந்து அவர்களின் பாதையை தடுத்தனர்.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பின்னர் மருதானை ஊடாக லிப்டன் சுற்றுவட்டத்திற்கு தமது கண்டன பேரணியை மாற்றியமைக்க முற்பட்டதுடன், சுகாதார அமைச்சின் வளாகத்திற்கு எதிரில் இருந்து அவர்களை கலைக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பல போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதற்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து சுகாதார ஊழியர்கள் போராட்டம் நடத்தினர், அவர்களில் பலர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மருதானையில் உள்ள டெக்னிக்கல் சந்தி, சிறிலங்கா காவல்துறை, சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை மற்றும் கலவரப் பகுதி ஆகியவற்றால் விரட்டப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கையைப் போன்ற ஒரு சூழ்நிலையை வங்கதேசம் சந்திக்காது: பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்துறையினரின் கண்ணீர் மற்றும் நீர் பீரங்கிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்பின்ஸ்டோன் தியேட்டர்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருதானை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ISUF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலக தடுப்பு போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள டெக்னிக்கல் சந்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிப்டன் சர்க்கஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருதானை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மருதானை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலவர இடம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM ஷேக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}