{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ඇෆ්ගන්-වෙත-තවත්-මානුෂීය-ආධාර-දීමට-චීනය-සූදානම්/3-394909",
  "time_ut": 1656393083,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඇෆ්ගන් වෙත තවත් මානුෂීය ආධාර දීමට චීනය සූදානම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China ready to provide more humanitarian aid to Afghanistan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese Premier and Foreign Minister Wang Yi has said that China is ready to provide more timely assistance to Afghanistan based on China's needs, and hopes that the country will be united in rebuilding its homes as soon as possible to recover from the recent earthquake disaster.",
        "He made the remarks during a telephone conversation with Amir Khan Mutaki, acting Foreign Minister of the Interim Government of Afghanistan.",
        "Wang again expressed condolences to Afghanistan over the quake, saying that China, as a friendly neighbor and sincere friend, has been working with the Afghan people during difficult times.",
        "He said various Chinese agencies, from central and local governments to social organizations and enterprises, were continuing to work to provide emergency humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan and to assist the Afghan people.",
        "According to Wang, the first group will provide tents, blankets and other supplies by special aircraft, while cash and other relief supplies will be delivered to Afghanistan as soon as possible."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Afghanistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amir Khan Mutaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Interim Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇෆ්ගන් වෙත තවත් මානුෂීය ආධාර දීමට චීනය සූදානම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ අවශ්‍යතා මත පදනම්ව ඇෆ්ගනිස්තානයට වඩාත් කාලෝචිත සහාය ලබා දීමට චීනය සූදානම් බවත්, මෑත කාලීන භූමිකම්පා ව්‍යසනයෙන් මිදීමටත් හැකි ඉක්මනින් නිවාස නැවත ගොඩනඟා ගනිමින්, රට එක්සත්ව සිටිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත් චීන රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රී සහ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය වැන්ග් යී පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ ඇෆ්ගන් අන්තර්වාර රජයේ වැඩබලන විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අමීර් ඛාන් මුටාකි සමග පැවති දුරකථන සංවාදයකදී බව චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "වැන්ග් නැවතත් භූමිකම්පාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයට ශෝකය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර, මිත්‍ර අසල්වැසියෙකු සහ අවංක මිතුරෙකු ලෙස චීනය දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවක ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථාන ජනතාව සමග රැඳෙමින් කටයුතු කරන කරන බව පැවසීය.",
        "මධ්‍යම සහ ප්‍රාදේශීය ආණ්ඩුවල සිට සමාජ සංවිධාන සහ ව්‍යවසායන් දක්වා චීනයේ විවිධ ආයතන විසින් ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයට හදිසි මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබා දීමට සහ ඇෆ්ගන් ජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීමට තවදුරටත් වැඩ කරමින් ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "වැන්ග්ට අනුව, පළමු කණ්ඩායම කූඩාරම්, බ්ලැන්කට් සහ අනෙකුත් සැපයුම් විශේෂ ගුවන් යානා මගින් ලබා දෙන අතර මුදල් සහ අනෙකුත් සහන සැපයුම් හැකි ඉක්මනින් ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය වෙත ලබාදෙන බව සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමීර් ඛාන් මුටාකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර්වාර රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தானுக்கு மேலும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை வழங்க சீனா தயாராக உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் தேவைகளின் அடிப்படையில் ஆப்கானிஸ்தானுக்கு உரிய நேரத்தில் உதவிகளை வழங்க சீனா தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும், சமீபத்திய நிலநடுக்க பேரழிவில் இருந்து மீண்டு விரைவில் வீடுகளை மீண்டும் கட்டுவதில் அந்நாடு ஒன்றுபடும் என்றும் சீனப் பிரதமரும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சருமான வாங் யீ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆப்கானிஸ்தானின் இடைக்கால வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அமீர் கான் முட்டாகியுடன் தொலைபேசியில் உரையாடிய போது அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நிலநடுக்கம் குறித்து ஆப்கானிஸ்தானுக்கு வாங் மீண்டும் இரங்கல் தெரிவித்தார், சீனா, நட்பு அண்டை நாடாகவும், நேர்மையான நண்பராகவும், கடினமான காலங்களில் ஆப்கானிஸ்தான் மக்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றி வருவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "ஆப்கானிஸ்தானுக்கு அவசர மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளை வழங்கவும், ஆப்கானிஸ்தான் மக்களுக்கு உதவவும் மத்திய மற்றும் உள்ளூர் அரசாங்கங்கள் முதல் சமூக அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் நிறுவனங்கள் வரை பல்வேறு சீன ஏஜென்சிகள் தொடர்ந்து பணியாற்றி வருவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "வாங்கின் கூற்றுப்படி, முதல் குழு கூடாரங்கள், போர்வைகள் மற்றும் பிற பொருட்களை சிறப்பு விமானம் மூலம் வழங்கும், அதே நேரத்தில் பணம் மற்றும் பிற நிவாரணப் பொருட்கள் விரைவில் ஆப்கானிஸ்தானுக்கு வழங்கப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமீர் கான் முட்டாகி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடைக்கால அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கான்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கான்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}