{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මිතුරාට-අවසන්-ගෞරව-දක්වන්න-ජනපති-ජපන්-යයි/101-618359",
  "time_ut": 1660834113,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මිතුරාට අවසන් ගෞරව දක්වන්න ජනපති ජපන් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President will go to Japan to pay his last respects to his friend",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe is going to Japan at the end of this month to attend the funeral ceremony of the former Prime Minister of Japan, Mr. Shinsho Abe.",
        "The former Prime Minister of Japan is a long-term political friend of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "According to political sources, Mr. Shinsho Abe supported the development of Sri Lanka as the Prime Minister of Japan when Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe was the Prime Minister.",
        "While addressing a political meeting, Mr. Shinsho Abe passed away after being shot by a terrorist on July 8th.",
        "The funeral of Mr. Shinsho Abe is scheduled to be done in Japan on the 27th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 8th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිතුරාට අවසන් ගෞරව දක්වන්න ජනපති ජපන් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපානයේ හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ෂින්ෂෝ අබේ මහතාගේ අවමංගල්‍ය උත්සවයට  සහභාගී වීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ මාසයේ අග ජපානයට යාමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජපානයේ හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ දිගු කාලීන දේශපාලන මිතුරෙකි.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු අවස්ථාවලදී ෂින්ෂො අබේ මහතා ජපාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දියුණුව වෙනුවෙන් සහයෝගය දක්වා ඇතැයි දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "දේශපාලන  රැස්වීමක් අමතමින් සිටියදී ඉකුත් ජුලි 8වැනිදා සාහසිකයකුගේ වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරයකට ලක්ව ෂින්ෂො අබෙි මහතා අභාවප්‍රාප්ත විය.",
        "ෂින්ෂො  අබේ මහතාගේ දේහය පිළිබඳ අවසන් කටයුතු ලබන 27 වැනිදා ජපානයේ දී සිදු සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත ව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 8 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தனது நண்பருக்கு கடைசி மரியாதை செலுத்த ஜப்பானுக்குச் செல்வார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானின் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் திரு.ஷின்ஷோ அபேயின் இறுதிச் சடங்கில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இம்மாத இறுதியில் ஜப்பான் செல்லவுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜப்பானின் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் நீண்டகால அரசியல் நண்பராவார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக இருந்த போது ஜப்பானின் பிரதமராக ஷின்ஷோ அபே இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்திக்கு ஆதரவளித்ததாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஒரு அரசியல் கூட்டத்தில் உரையாற்றியபோது, ​​திரு. ஷின்ஷோ அபே ஜூலை 8 ஆம் தேதி பயங்கரவாதியால் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்ட பின்னர் காலமானார்.",
        "திரு. ஷின்ஷோ அபேவின் இறுதிச் சடங்குகள் 27 ஆம் தேதி ஜப்பானில் செய்ய திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 8",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinsho Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}