{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/three-protestors-arrested-in-sri-lanka-for-selling-stolen-items-from-presidents-house-97880/",
  "time_ut": 1658737260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three protestors arrested in Sri Lanka for selling stolen items from President’s House",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three protestors arrested in Sri Lanka for selling stolen items from President’s House",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Three protesters in Sri Lanka have been arrested for attempting to sell gold-plated brass curtain sockets that were allegedly stolen from the President’s House in Colombo after protestors stormed the place on July 09.",
        "“We received a complaint from Rajagiriya over three individuals selling items from the President’s House,” the officer in charge (OIC) of the Welikada police station said.",
        "The suspects, aged 28, 34 and 37 and residing at Obeysekarapura in Rajagiriya,  had nabbed forty gold-plated brass curtain sockets.",
        "Police had launched separate investigations into the storming and occupation of several state-owned buildings by protestors. Sensitive evidence is now being gathered, police said.",
        "The three arrested protestors have been  handed overr to the Colombo (North) Criminal Investigation Division.",
        "Further investigations are underway in collaboration with the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) and the Scene of Crime Officers (SOCO) department, police said.",
        "The Presidential Secretariat which was reclaimed by the authorities prior to its handover by protestors on July 22 has now resumed work and renovations are underway. (Colombo/Jul25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28, 34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Obeysekarapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "forty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයෙන් සොරකම් කළ භාණ්ඩ අලෙවි කළ විරෝධතාකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජූලි 09 වන දින විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු සොරකම් කළ බව කියන රන් ආලේපිත පිත්තල තිර රෙදි අලෙවි කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "\"ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ භාණ්ඩ අලෙවි කරන පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු සම්බන්ධයෙන් රාජගිරියෙන් අපට පැමිණිල්ලක් ලැබී ඇති බව\" වැලිකඩ පොලිස් ස්ථානය භාර නිලධාරි (OIC) පැවසීය.",
        "රාජගිරිය ඔබේසේකරපුර ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු 28, 34 සහ 37 යන වයස්වල පසුවන සැකකරුවන් විසින් රන් ආලේපිත පිත්තල තිර රෙදි හතළිහක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් රජය සතු ගොඩනැගිලි කිහිපයකට කඩා වැදී ඒවා අත්පත් කර ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිසිය වෙනම විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කර තිබුණි. මේ වනවිට සංවේදී සාක්ෂි රැස්කරමින් පවතින බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් තිදෙනා කොළඹ (උතුර) අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශය වෙත භාර දී ඇත.",
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) සහ Scene of Crime Officers (SOCO) දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සහයෝගයෙන් වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන ක්‍රියාත්මක බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පසුගිය ජූලි 22 වැනිදා විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් භාරදීමට පෙර බලධාරීන් විසින් ගොඩගනු ලැබූ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය මේ වන විට යළි වැඩ ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කටයුතු සිදුවෙමින් පවතී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28, 34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔබේසේකරපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතළිහක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து திருடப்பட்ட பொருட்களை விற்பனை செய்த மூன்று ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையில் ஜூலை 09 அன்று ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையிலிருந்து திருடப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் தங்க முலாம் பூசப்பட்ட பித்தளை திரைச்சீலைகளை விற்க முயன்ற மூன்று போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தின் பொறுப்பதிகாரி (OIC) கூறுகையில், “ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து பொருட்களை விற்பனை செய்த மூன்று நபர்கள் தொடர்பில் ராஜகிரியவில் இருந்து எங்களுக்கு முறைப்பாடு கிடைத்துள்ளது.",
        "ராஜகிரிய ஒபேசேகரபுரவில் வசிக்கும் 28, 34 மற்றும் 37 வயதுடைய சந்தேகநபர்கள் நாற்பது தங்க முலாம் பூசப்பட்ட பித்தளை திரைச்சீலைகளை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்களால் அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான பல கட்டிடங்களை தாக்கி ஆக்கிரமித்தது குறித்து போலீசார் தனித்தனியாக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டனர். தற்போது முக்கிய ஆதாரங்கள் சேகரிக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மூவரும் கொழும்பு (வடக்கு) குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் (CID) மற்றும் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரின் (SOCO) திணைக்களத்துடன் இணைந்து மேலதிக விசாரணைகள் இடம்பெற்று வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 22ஆம் திகதி ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களால் கையளிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர் அதிகாரிகளால் மீட்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் தற்போது மீண்டும் வேலைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதுடன், புனரமைப்பு பணிகள் இடம்பெற்று வருகின்றன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28, 34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒபேசேகரபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாற்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}