{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Energy-Minister-applauds-development-partners-of-National-Fuel-Pass/34-738894",
  "time_ut": 1660931894,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Energy Minister applauds development partners of National Fuel Pass",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Energy Minister applauds development partners of National Fuel Pass",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera yesterday recognised the contribution of all the development partners and volunteers of the National Fuel Pass.",
        "“An event was held with the development partners of the National Fuel Pass QR System. NFP was developed for the Ministry of Power and Energy by ICTA, Dialog and Millennium IT ESP for free-of-charge. I thank our development partners, officials, CPC, LIOC, volunteers for their assistance and commitment,” Wijesekera said in a tweet.",
        "The QR system helped the country to overcome the fuel shortage and kilometres long queues, whilst allowing people to continue their day-today work as usual."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "National Fuel Pass",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Fuel Pass",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Fuel Pass QR System",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "day-today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රයේ සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන්ට ප්‍රශංසා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රයේ සියලුම සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන්ගේ සහ ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන්ගේ දායකත්වය විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා විසින් ඊයේ ඇගයීමට ලක් කළේය.",
        "“National Fuel Pass QR System හි සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ උත්සවයක් පැවැත්විණි. ICTA, Dialog සහ Millennium IT ESP මගින් විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය සඳහා NFP නොමිලයේ සංවර්ධනය කරන ලදී. අපගේ සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන්, නිලධාරීන්, CPC, LIOC, ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන්ගේ සහාය සහ කැපවීම වෙනුවෙන් මම ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා,” විජේසේකර ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "QR පද්ධතිය රටේ ඉන්ධන හිඟය සහ කිලෝමීටර් ගණන් දිගු පෝලිම් මඟහරවා ගැනීමට උපකාරී වූ අතර, මිනිසුන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ එදිනෙදා වැඩ සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි කරගෙන යාමට ඉඩ සලසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්ර QR පද්ධතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එදිනෙදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸின் வளர்ச்சி பங்காளிகளை எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் பாராட்டுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸின் அனைத்து அபிவிருத்தி பங்காளிகள் மற்றும் தன்னார்வலர்களின் பங்களிப்பை மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர நேற்று அங்கீகரித்தார்.",
        "“தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR அமைப்பின் அபிவிருத்தி பங்காளிகளுடன் ஒரு நிகழ்வு நடைபெற்றது. ICTA, Dialog மற்றும் Millennium IT ESP ஆகியவற்றால் மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகத்திற்காக NFP உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. எங்கள் அபிவிருத்தி பங்காளிகள், அதிகாரிகள், CPC, LIOC, தன்னார்வத் தொண்டர்கள் அவர்களின் உதவி மற்றும் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்காக நான் நன்றி கூறுகிறேன், ”என்று விஜேசேகர ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் கிலோமீட்டர் நீளமான வரிசைகளை சமாளிக்க க்யூஆர் அமைப்பு நாட்டுக்கு உதவியது, அதே நேரத்தில் மக்கள் தங்கள் அன்றாட வேலைகளை வழக்கம் போல் தொடர அனுமதித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளுக்கு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}