{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/still-no-chairmen-to-cope-copa-why-the-delay-sajith/",
  "time_ut": 1661789160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Still, no Chairmen to COPE & COPA, why the delay? – Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Still, no Chairmen to COPE & COPA, why the delay? – Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa on Monday (29) questioned the government on the delay in appointing the Chairmen for the two Parliament Watchdogs the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) and Committee on Public Accounts (COPA).",
        "\"When the President was the Prime Minister, on multiple occasions accepted that MPs Harsha De Silva, Kabir Hashim, and Eran Wickramaratne must be appointed to COPF, COPE, and COPA,\" said Premadasa while questioning why the MPs were not appointed to those committees as promised.",
        "SJB MP Harsha de Silva has already been appointed chair of the Committee on Public Finance.",
        "Opposition leader Premadasa and chief opposition whip Lakshman Kiriella questioned whether standing orders in parliament were going to be suspended to make the appointments.",
        "Leader of the House and Education Minister Susil Premajayantha proposed that an agreement on the matter be reached at the next meeting of the Committee on Parliamentary Business chaired by Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena who is currently out of the country.",
        "However, MP Kiriella noted that a ruling party Member of Parliament had noted that promises made during the Aragalaya are not valid.",
        "US will support Sri Lanka through IMF, if agreement can be reached",
        "“Sinharaja Hotel is Legal”: Rohitha warns Legal Action Against Allegations.",
        "MMA: Kasun “Kaz” De Silva wins again at Thailand Fighting Championship"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chairmen",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPE & COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairmen",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Watchdogs the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kabir Hashim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rohitha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kasun “Kaz” De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand Fighting Championship",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවමත්, COPE & COPA වලට සභාපතිවරු නැහැ, ඇයි ප්‍රමාදය? - සජිත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සඳුදා (29) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මුර බල්ලන් වන පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPE) සහ රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව (COPA) සඳහා සභාපතිවරුන් පත් කිරීම ප්‍රමාද කිරීම පිළිබඳව රජයෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "“ජනාධිපතිවරයා අගමැතිව සිටියදී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා, කබීර් හෂීම් සහ එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් COPF, COPE සහ COPA සඳහා පත් කළ යුතු බව අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදීම පිළිගත්තා,” ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ එම කමිටුවලට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පත් නොකළේ මන්දැයි ප්‍රශ්න කරමිනි. පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි.",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා දැනටමත් රාජ්‍ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "එම පත්කිරීම් සිදුකිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්ථාවර නියෝග අත්හිටුවීමට යන්නේදැයි විපක්ෂ නායක ප්‍රේමදාස සහ විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල ප්‍රශ්න කළා.",
        "දැනට රටින් බැහැරව සිටින කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රැස්වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ මීළඟ රැස්වීමේදී ඒ පිළිබඳ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය යුතු බවට සභානායක සහ අධ්‍යාපන ඇමැති සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අරගල සමයේ දුන් පොරොන්දු වලංගු නොවන බවට ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු සඳහන් කර ඇති බවයි කිරිඇල්ල මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය හැකි නම් IMF හරහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය වනු ඇත",
        "“සිංහරාජ හෝටලය නීත්‍යානුකූලයි”: චෝදනාවලට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා බවට රෝහිත අනතුරු අඟවයි.",
        "ඵම්එම්ඒ: කසුන් “කාස්” ද සිල්වා තායිලන්ත සටන් ශූරතාවලියේදී යළිත් ජය ලබයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සභාපතිවරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෝප් සහ කෝපා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපතිවරු",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව මුරකාවල් කරයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කබීර් හෂීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කසුන් \"කස්\" ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්ත සටන් ශූරතාවලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்னும், COPE & COPA க்கு தலைவர்கள் இல்லை, ஏன் தாமதம்? – சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் எதிர்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, இரண்டு பாராளுமன்ற கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்களுக்கான பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு (கோப்) மற்றும் பொதுக் கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு (கோபா) ஆகியவற்றுக்கான தலைவர்களை நியமிப்பதில் தாமதம் குறித்து அரசாங்கத்திடம் திங்கட்கிழமை (29) கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "“ஜனாதிபதி பிரதமராக இருந்தபோது, ​​பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, கபீர் ஹாசிம் மற்றும் எரான் விக்ரமரத்ன ஆகியோர் COPF, COPE மற்றும் COPA ஆகியவற்றிற்கு நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டனர்,” என்று பிரேமதாச கேள்வி எழுப்பினார். உறுதியளித்த படி.",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா ஏற்கனவே பொது நிதி தொடர்பான குழுவின் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நியமனங்களை வழங்குவதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளைகள் இடைநிறுத்தப்படப் போகின்றனவா என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி பிரதம கொறடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல ஆகியோர் கேள்வி எழுப்பினர்.",
        "தற்போது நாட்டிற்கு வெளியே உள்ள சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழுவின் அடுத்த கூட்டத்தில் இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் இணக்கப்பாடு எட்டப்படும் என அவைத் தலைவரும் கல்வி அமைச்சருமான சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த முன்மொழிந்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அரகலய காலத்தில் வழங்கப்பட்ட வாக்குறுதிகள் செல்லுபடியாகாது என ஆளும் கட்சி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் குறிப்பிட்டதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கிரியெல்ல குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டால், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு அமெரிக்கா ஆதரவளிக்கும்",
        "“சிங்கராஜா ஹோட்டல் சட்டபூர்வமானது”: குற்றச்சாட்டுகளுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என ரோஹித எச்சரிக்கை.",
        "MMA: தாய்லாந்து சண்டை சாம்பியன்ஷிப்பில் கசுன் “காஸ்” டி சில்வா மீண்டும் வெற்றி பெற்றார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தலைவர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோப் & கோபா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழுவை கண்காணிக்கிறது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபீர் ஹாசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஹிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கசுன் “காஸ்” டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து சண்டை சாம்பியன்ஷிப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}