{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/sri-lankans-have-right-to-peacefully-raise-their-voices-blinken/",
  "time_ut": 1657464480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankans have right to peacefully raise their voices – Blinken",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankans have right to peacefully raise their voices – Blinken",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The US Secretary of State, Antony Blinken states that the Sri Lankan people have a right to peacefully raise their voices, and called for a full investigation, arrest, prosecution of anyone involved in any protest-related violence and incidents of violence.",
        "Responding to media during a press availability in Bangkok, Thailand, the US Secretary of State also condemned any violence against peaceful protestors and journalists.",
        "Responding to a question regarding the Sri Lankan crisis and the President’s anticipated resignation, the US Secretary of State said that the US is closely following the events and the political developments, and mentioned that he has seen thousands of people of all backgrounds taking to the streets, looking for accountability, looking for transparency, looking for a better future.",
        "He also notes that the Prime Minister announced that he will step down when all parties agree to form a new Government, in addition to reports from the Sri Lankan Parliament, the speaker, who said the President intends to step down on July 13th, which they are tracking.",
        "“We would urge the Sri Lankan Parliament to approach this with a commitment to the betterment of the country, not any one political party,” he added.",
        "Afterwards, he stated that it incumbent on the Government, whether a new, constitutionally-selected Government or the existing Government, to work quickly to try to identify and implement solutions that will bring back the prospect of long-term economic stability, address the Sri Lankan people’s discontent, which is so powerful and palpable, over the worsening economic conditions, including power, including food and fuel shortages.",
        "The US Secretary of State remarked that the Russian aggression in Ukraine on food insecurity could be one of the factors that contributed to the current crisis in Sri Lanka, among many others.",
        "Sri Lankans have right to peacefully raise their voices – Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Antony Blinken",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සාමකාමීව හඬ නැගීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට අයිතියක් ඇත - Blinken",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන් ප්‍රකාශ කරන්නේ සාමකාමීව හඬ නැඟීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට අයිතියක් ඇති බවත්, විරෝධතාවයට සම්බන්ධ ඕනෑම ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයකට සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවලට සම්බන්ධ ඕනෑම අයෙකු පූර්ණ පරීක්ෂණයක්, අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමක්, නඩු පැවරීමක් සිදු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත්ය.",
        "තායිලන්තයේ බැංකොක් නුවර පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී මාධ්‍ය වෙත ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම්වරයා සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට සහ මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට එරෙහි ඕනෑම ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හෙළා දකින ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ අපේක්ෂිත ඉල්ලා අස්වීම පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දුන් එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම්වරයා, එක්සත් ජනපදය සිදුවීම් සහ දේශපාලන වර්ධනයන් සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරන බවත්, සෑම තරාතිරමකම මිනිසුන් දහස් ගණනක් වීදි බැස සිටිනු තමා දුටු බවත් සඳහන් කළේය. , වගවීම සොයමින්, විනිවිදභාවය සොයමින්, යහපත් අනාගතයක් සොයමින්.",
        "නව ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට සියලු පාර්ශව එකඟ වූ පසු තමන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවත්, ඊට අමතරව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වාර්තාවලට අමතරව, ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට අදහස් කරන බවත් කථානායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කරයි. ලුහුබඳිමින් සිටිති.",
        "“කිසිදු දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක් නොව රටේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සඳහා කැපවීමෙන් මෙයට ප්‍රවේශ වන ලෙස අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමු,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්පසුව, ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, නව, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිතව තෝරාගත් රජයක් හෝ පවතින රජයක් වේවා, දීර්ඝ කාලීන ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වයේ අපේක්ෂාව නැවත ගෙන ඒමට හැකි විසඳුම් හඳුනාගෙන ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට කඩිනමින් ක්‍රියා කිරීම රජයට පැවරී ඇති බව ය. ආහාර හා ඉන්ධන හිඟය ඇතුළු බලශක්තිය ඇතුළු නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයන් පිළිබඳව එතරම් බලගතු සහ පැහැදිලි ලාංකීය ජනතාවගේ අතෘප්තිය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ආහාර අනාරක්‍ෂිතතාවය සම්බන්ධයෙන් යුක්‍රේනයේ රුසියානු ආක්‍රමණය තවත් බොහෝ දේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අර්බුදයට දායක වූ එක් සාධකයක් විය හැකි බවයි.",
        "සාමකාමීව හඬ නැගීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට අයිතියක් ඇත - Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ටනි බ්ලින්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்ப இலங்கையர்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு – பிளிங்கன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்புவதற்கு இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு என அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கச் செயலர் ஆண்டனி பிளின்கன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். மேலும், போராட்டம் தொடர்பான வன்முறைகள் மற்றும் வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களில் ஈடுபட்ட எவரையும் முழு விசாரணை, கைது செய்தல், வழக்குத் தொடுத்தல் போன்றவற்றுக்கு இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தாய்லாந்தின் பாங்காக்கில் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது ஊடகங்களுக்கு பதிலளித்த அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை செயலர், அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மற்றும் பத்திரிகையாளர்களுக்கு எதிரான எந்தவொரு வன்முறையையும் கண்டித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை நெருக்கடி மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் ராஜினாமா தொடர்பான கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கச் செயலாளர், நிகழ்வுகள் மற்றும் அரசியல் முன்னேற்றங்களை அமெரிக்கா உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருவதாகவும், அனைத்துப் பின்னணியிலும் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் வீதியில் இறங்கியதைக் கண்டதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டார். , பொறுப்புக்கூறலைத் தேடுவது, வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையைத் தேடுவது, சிறந்த எதிர்காலத்தைத் தேடுவது.",
        "புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளும் சம்மதித்ததும், தாம் பதவி விலகுவதாகவும் பிரதமர் அறிவித்துள்ளதாகவும், இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் அறிக்கைகளுக்கு மேலதிகமாக, ஜனாதிபதி ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகவுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார். கண்காணிக்கிறார்கள்.",
        "எந்தவொரு அரசியல் கட்சியுடனும் அல்லாமல், நாட்டின் முன்னேற்றத்துக்கான அர்ப்பணிப்புடன் இதனை அணுகுமாறு இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தை நாங்கள் வலியுறுத்துவோம் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அதன்பிறகு, புதிய, அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியில் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட அரசாங்கமோ அல்லது தற்போதுள்ள அரசாங்கமோ, நீண்டகால பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கான வாய்ப்பை மீண்டும் கொண்டு வரும் தீர்வுகளை கண்டறிந்து செயல்படுத்துவதற்கு விரைவாக செயல்படுவது அரசாங்கத்தின் பொறுப்பாகும் என்று அவர் கூறினார். உணவு மற்றும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு உட்பட மின்சாரம் உட்பட மோசமான பொருளாதார நிலைமைகள் குறித்து இலங்கை மக்களின் அதிருப்தி, மிகவும் சக்திவாய்ந்த மற்றும் வெளிப்படையானது.",
        "உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை மீதான உக்ரேனில் உள்ள ரஷ்ய ஆக்கிரமிப்பு, இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு பங்களிக்கும் காரணிகளில் ஒன்றாக இருக்கலாம் என அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கச் செயலர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்ப இலங்கையர்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு – பிளிங்கன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டனி பிளிங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}