{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ආහාර-සුරක්ෂිතතාවයට-ඩොලර්-ගිණුමක්-ඇරඹීමට-අවධානය/11-395845",
  "time_ut": 1659066049,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවයට ඩොලර් ගිණුමක් ඇරඹීමට අවධානය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Focus on starting a dollar account for food security",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dr. Suren Batagoda, Chairman of the Presidential Committee on Food Security, said that if Sri Lanka's food security is not established, the people of the country will have to face a major nutritional deficiency next year.",
        "Yesterday (29) afternoon, a discussion was held at the Ministry of Wildlife and Forest Resources under the chairmanship of Minister Mahinda Amaraweera about the work to be carried out by the Ministry of Agriculture on food security.",
        "Dr. Suren Batagoda, secretaries of the ministry Mr. Rohana Pushpakumara and Mr. Chandra Herath as well as Moneragala and Hambantota district secretaries and a group of officials participated in the discussion.",
        "It was emphasized here about the breakdowns that have occurred in our country's milk, egg and poultry products. At present, liquid milk production has decreased by 19.8 percent, chicken meat production by 12.1 percent and egg production by 34.9 percent.",
        "If this situation continues, there is a risk of complete collapse of poultry and egg production next year. It was emphasized here that the livestock industry has collapsed due to the lack of maize and other products required for the production of animal feed, as well as the shortage of chemical fertilizers and fuel.",
        "To avoid this situation, there is a need of 900 million dollars for the future activities of agriculture. Dr. Suren Batagoda, Chairman of the President's Committee on Food Security, proposed to focus on starting a dollar account for the future development of agriculture as there is difficulty in obtaining such amount from the government treasury at once.",
        "He emphasized that Sri Lankans working in foreign countries, international organizations and other aid groups can arrange to get the amount for this account.",
        "Accordingly, the Minister of Agriculture Mahinda Amaraweera instructed the Secretary of the Ministry to prepare a Cabinet Memorandum to maintain a dollar account.",
        "Apart from that, it was suggested to start a program of providing urea fertilizer for the maize grown in this year's season as well as providing seeds and urea fertilizer for growing maize in more land in the next season. Accordingly, the minister mentioned that 25,000 hectares of Moneragala, 5000 acres of Maduru Oya, 500 acres of Kantale and 3000 acres of Kandakadu farm are planned to be cultivated.",
        "Dr. Suren Batagoda also mentioned that in order to achieve the success achieved in the Sri Lankan agriculture in 2018, those reforms should be implemented again.",
        "Due to the reforms brought by Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera, who was the Minister of Agriculture at that time, it was possible to obtain the highest rice harvest and maize harvest in the last four decades in the 2018/19 season. It was also emphasized in this discussion that it was possible to achieve great improvement in other crop productions as well."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Batagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Committee on Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Wildlife",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Batagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohana Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19.8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "34.9 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "900 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suren Batagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this year's season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 hectares",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moneragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5000 acres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maduru Oya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 acres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000 acres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandakadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Batagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last four decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2018/19 season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවයට ඩොලර් ගිණුමක් ඇරඹීමට අවධානය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවය තහවුරු නොකළහොත් ලබන වසරේ දී විශාල පෝෂණ ඌනතාවයකට රටේ ජනතාවට මුහුණ දීමට සිදුවනු ඇතැයි ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවය පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති කමිටුවේ සභාපති ආචාර්ය සුරේන් බටගොඩ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඊයේ (29)  පස්වරුවේ වනජීවි  හා වන සම්පත් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ දී අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවය පිලිබඳ කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින්  ක්‍රියාත්මක කළයුතු වැඩ කටයුතු පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවක් පවත්වනු ලැබීය.",
        "එම සාකච්ඡාවට ආචාර්ය සුරේන් බටගොඩ, අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරුන් වන රෝහණ පුෂ්පකුමාර හා චන්ද්‍රා හේරත් මහත්ම මහත්මීහු මෙන්ම මොනරාගල හා හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම්වරු ඇතුළු නිලධාරිහු පිරිසක් සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "මේ වනවිට අප රටේ කිරි, බිත්තර, හා කුකුළුමස් නිෂ්පාදනයන්හි ඇති වී ඇති බිඳ වැටීම් පිළිබඳව මෙහිදි අවධාරණය විය. මේ වනවිට දියර කිරි නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 19.8කින්, කුකුළු මස් නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 12.1කින් හා බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 34.9කින් ද පහළට ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය දිගටම පැවතියහොත් ලබන වසරේ දී කුකුළු මස් හා බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදනය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම බිඳ වැටීමේ අවදානමක් පවතී. විශේෂයෙන් සත්ව ආහාර නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය බඩඉරිඟු හා වෙනත් නිෂ්පාදන මෙන්ම  රසායනික පොහොර හිඟය හා ඉන්ධන හිඟය නිසා පශු සම්පත් කර්මාන්තය බිඳ වැටී ඇති බව මෙහිදී අවධාරණය විය.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය වළක්වා ගැනීමට නම් කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ ඉදිරි කටයුතූ සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 900ක අවශ්‍යතාවයක් පවතී. එවැනි මුදලක් රජයේ භාණ්ඩාගාරයෙන් එකවර ලබා ගැනීමේ අපහසුතා පවතින හෙයින් කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ ඉදිරි සංවර්ධන කටයුතු සඳහා ඩොලර් ගිණුමක් ආරම්භ කිරීමට අවධානය යොමු කිරීමට ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාවය පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති කමිටුවේ සභාපති ආචාර්ය සුරේන් බටගොඩ මහතා යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "මෙම ගිණුම සඳහා විදේශ රටවල සේවය කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්, ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන හා වෙනත් ආධාර කණ්ඩායම් මඟින් එම මුදල ලබා ගැනීමට කටයුතු කළ හැකි  බවත් හෙතෙම අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඩොලර් ගිණුමක් පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල සන්දේශයක් සකස් කරන ලෙස කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයාට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඊට අමතරව මෙවර යල කන්නයේ දී වගා කර ඇති බඩඉරිගු සඳහා යුරියා පොහොර ලබා දීම මෙන්ම ලබන මහ කන්නයේ දී වැඩි ඉඩම් ප්‍රමාණයක බඩඉරිගු වගා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය බීජ හා යුරියා පොහොර ලබා දීමේ වැඩ සටහනක් කඩිනමින් ආරම්භ කිරීමට යෝජනා විය.  ඒ අනුව මොනරාගල හෙක්ටෙයාර් 25,000ක්, මාදුරු ඔය අක්කර 5000ක්, කන්තලේ අක්කර 500ක්, කන්දකාඩු ගොවිපළේ අක්කර 3000ක බඩඉරිගු වගා කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇතැයි අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "2018 වසරේ මෙරට කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ ලැබූ සාර්ථකත්වය ලඟා කර ගැනීමට නම් එම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ නැවත ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතුව ඇතැයි ද ආචාර්ය සුරෙන් බටගොඩ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එම කාලයේ දී කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් කටයුතු කළ මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ ඇති කළ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ නිසා   පසුගිය දශක හතරක දී එක් කන්නයක ලද වැඩිම වී අස්වැන්න හා බඩඉරිගු අස්වැන්න 2018/19 මහ කන්නයේ දී ලබා ගැනීමට හැකි විය.  එමෙන්ම අනිකුත් බෝග නිෂ්පාදනයන්හි ද විශාල දියුණුවක් ලබා ගැනීමට හැකි වුව බව ද මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේ දී අවධාරණය විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් බටගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් බටගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහණ පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 19.8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 12.1 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 34.9 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 900 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් බටගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව පිළිබඳ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම වසරේ සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙක්ටයාර 25,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොණරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කර 5000ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maduru Oya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කර 500ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කර 3000ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්දකාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් බටගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශක හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018/19 සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பிற்காக டாலர் கணக்கைத் தொடங்குவதில் கவனம் செலுத்துங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பை ஏற்படுத்தாவிட்டால் அடுத்த வருடம் நாட்டு மக்கள் பாரிய போசாக்கு பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்ள வேண்டியிருக்கும் என உணவு பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதி குழுவின் தலைவர் கலாநிதி சுரேன் படகொட தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நேற்று (29) பிற்பகல் வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் அமைச்சில் அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தலைமையில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பில் விவசாய அமைச்சினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் பணிகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடல் ஒன்று இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "கலாநிதி சுரேன் படகொட, அமைச்சின் செயலாளர்களான திரு.ரோஹன புஷ்பகுமார மற்றும் திரு.சந்திர ஹேரத் மற்றும் மொனராகலை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்ட செயலாளர்கள் மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் குழு இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "நமது நாட்டு பால், முட்டை, கோழிப் பொருட்களில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பழுதடைவுகள் குறித்து இங்கு வலியுறுத்தப்பட்டது. தற்போது திரவ பால் உற்பத்தி 19.8 சதவீதமும், கோழி இறைச்சி உற்பத்தி 12.1 சதவீதமும், முட்டை உற்பத்தி 34.9 சதவீதமும் குறைந்துள்ளது.",
        "இதே நிலை நீடித்தால் அடுத்த ஆண்டு கோழி மற்றும் முட்டை உற்பத்தி முற்றிலும் அழியும் அபாயம் உள்ளது. கால்நடைத் தீவன உற்பத்திக்குத் தேவையான சோளம் மற்றும் பிற பொருட்கள் இல்லாததாலும், இரசாயன உரங்கள் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாட்டாலும் கால்நடை வளர்ப்புத் தொழில் நலிவடைந்துள்ளதாக இங்கு வலியுறுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்நிலையை தவிர்க்க விவசாயத்தின் எதிர்கால நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு 900 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் தேவை. அரசாங்க திறைசேரியில் இருந்து ஒரேயடியாக பணம் கிடைப்பதில் சிரமம் இருப்பதால் எதிர்கால விவசாய வளர்ச்சிக்காக டாலர் கணக்கை தொடங்குவதில் கவனம் செலுத்துமாறு உணவு பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதி குழுவின் தலைவர் கலாநிதி சுரேன் படகொட முன்மொழிந்தார்.",
        "வெளிநாடுகளில் பணிபுரியும் இலங்கையர்கள், சர்வதேச நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் பிற உதவிக் குழுக்கள் இந்தக் கணக்கிற்கான தொகையைப் பெறுவதற்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்ய முடியும் என அவர் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, டொலர் கணக்கைப் பேணுவதற்கான அமைச்சரவைப் பத்திரம் ஒன்றை தயாரிக்குமாறு விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர, அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார்.",
        "அதுமட்டுமல்லாமல், இந்த ஆண்டு பருவத்தில் பயிரிடப்படும் சோளத்திற்கு யூரியா உரம் வழங்கும் திட்டத்தையும், அடுத்த பருவத்தில் அதிக நிலத்தில் சோள சாகுபடிக்கு விதை மற்றும் யூரியா உரம் வழங்கும் திட்டத்தையும் தொடங்க ஆலோசனை வழங்கப்பட்டது. இதன்படி, மொனராகலையில் 25,000 ஹெக்டேயர், மாதுரு ஓயாவில் 5000 ஏக்கர், கந்தளேயில் 500 ஏக்கர் மற்றும் கந்தகாடு பண்ணை 3000 ஏக்கரில் பயிர் செய்ய திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "2018ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை விவசாயத்தில் பெற்ற வெற்றியை அடைவதற்கு அந்த சீர்திருத்தங்களை மீண்டும் நடைமுறைப்படுத்த வேண்டும் எனவும் கலாநிதி சுரேன் படகொட குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அப்போது விவசாய அமைச்சராக இருந்த திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீர அவர்கள் கொண்டு வந்த சீர்திருத்தங்களினால் கடந்த நான்கு தசாப்தங்களில் அதிகூடிய நெல் அறுவடை மற்றும் சோள அறுவடையை 2018/19 பருவத்தில் பெற முடிந்தது. ஏனைய பயிர் உற்பத்திகளிலும் பெரும் முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைய முடியும் எனவும் இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் வலியுறுத்தப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் படகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்புக்கான ஜனாதிபதி குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் படகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹன புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திர ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "34.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "900 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் படகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்பு குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 ஹெக்டேர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5000 ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maduru Oya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3000 ஏக்கர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டகாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் படகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த நான்கு தசாப்தங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018/19 சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}