{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Three-ministers-on-diplomatic-missions-to-seek-support-amidst-crisis/56-736728",
  "time_ut": 1656275841,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three ministers on diplomatic missions to seek support amidst crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three ministers on diplomatic missions to seek support amidst crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Three ministers including the Power and Energy Minister will be on diplomatic visits this week to seek support from the world amidst the worst economic crisis.",
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara yesterday announced that two ministers will fly to Russia on a diplomatic visit and to explore possibilities of importing fuel as well.",
        "He said the Government expects a positive response from Russia during the diplomatic visit by the two ministers.",
        "Minister Wijesekara will also leave today, on the invitation of the Qatari Emir. He is expected to discuss fuel imports among other things.",
        "He said the Government is ready to provide necessary facilities to any individual who receives fuel shipments from Russia, by sending a mere written request to the President of Russia.",
        "The Minister also said they received an additional $ 500 million credit line from India after months of discussions.",
        "Minister Wijesekera said the source of fuel should be irrelevant, adding the main objective of the Government is to obtain fuel at the lowest cost."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatari Emir",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "an additional $ 500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුද මධ්‍යයේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමට රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික දූත මණ්ඩලවල ඇමතිවරු තිදෙනෙක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ලෝකයෙන් සහයෝගය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා ඇතුළු අමාත්‍යවරු තිදෙනෙක් මේ සතියේ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සංචාරයක නිරත වෙති.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සංචාරයක් සඳහා රුසියාව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිත බවත් ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමේ හැකියාව සොයා බැලීමටත් නියමිත බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනාගේ රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික සංචාරයේදී රුසියාවෙන් ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක් රජය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කටාර් එමීර්වරයාගේ ආරාධනයෙන් විජේසේකර අමාත්‍යවරයා ද අද පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතයි. ඉන්ධන ආනයනය සම්බන්ධයෙන්ද ඔහු සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "රුසියාවෙන් ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කරන ඕනෑම පුද්ගලයෙකුට රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත ලිඛිත ඉල්ලීමක් යැවීමෙන් අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් සැපයීමට රජය සූදානම් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාස ගණනක සාකච්ඡාවලින් පසුව ඔවුන්ට ඉන්දියාවෙන් අමතර ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක ණය මුදලක් ලැබුණු බව ද අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "අඩුම මිලට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම රජයේ ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ බව කී අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා, ඉන්ධන ප්‍රභවය අදාළ නොවිය යුතු බව පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් එමීර්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் ஆதரவைப் பெற மூன்று அமைச்சர்கள் தூதரகப் பணிகளில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் உலக நாடுகளின் ஆதரவைப் பெற மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் உட்பட மூன்று அமைச்சர்கள் இந்த வாரம் இராஜதந்திர விஜயங்களை மேற்கொள்ளவுள்ளனர்.",
        "இரண்டு அமைச்சர்கள் இராஜதந்திர விஜயமொன்றை மேற்கொண்டு, எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராய்வதற்காக ரஷ்யாவிற்கு செல்லவுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர நேற்று அறிவித்தார்.",
        "இரு அமைச்சர்களின் இராஜதந்திர விஜயத்தின் போது ரஷ்யாவிடமிருந்து சாதகமான பதிலை அரசாங்கம் எதிர்பார்க்கிறது என்றார்.",
        "கட்டார் அமீரின் அழைப்பின் பேரில் அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகரவும் இன்று செல்லவுள்ளார். எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி குறித்தும் அவர் விவாதிப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ரஷ்யாவில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதியைப் பெறும் எந்தவொரு நபருக்கும் ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எழுத்துப்பூர்வ கோரிக்கையை அனுப்புவதன் மூலம் தேவையான வசதிகளை வழங்க அரசாங்கம் தயாராக உள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "பல மாத விவாதங்களுக்குப் பிறகு இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து கூடுதலாக 500 மில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் பெற்றதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருளின் ஆதாரம் பொருத்தமற்றதாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறிய அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர, குறைந்த விலையில் எரிபொருளைப் பெறுவதே அரசாங்கத்தின் முக்கிய நோக்கமாகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் எமிர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் $500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}