{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-executive-presidency-opposed-by-70-pct-poll-97598/",
  "time_ut": 1658195400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka executive presidency opposed by 70-pct: Poll",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka executive presidency opposed by 70-pct: Poll",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Around 70 percent of respondents to a nation-wide survey had opposed the executive presidency, a poll by Verete Research, a Colombo-based think tank said.",
        "Only 15 percent favoured the continuation of the executive presidency. The 15 percent had several opinions such as reducing powers instead of abolishing it, the report said.",
        "Sri Lanka brought in a powerful executive presidency after the severe trade and exchange controls in amid the forex shortages of the 1970s.",
        "Sri Lanka closed the entire economy in the 1970s as the Bretton Woods system of soft-pegs collapsed and the central bank became the top owner of Treasury bills.",
        "The central bank continued to print money in the 1980s and also started depreciating the currency according to what Anglo-Saxon Mercantilists called the BBC (Basket Band Crawl) policy in the 1980s and was called REER targeting in the past 5 years after even more Treasury bills were bought and the country defaulted.",
        "The distribution of opinion was very similar across all age groups, Verete said.",
        "The Southern, Eastern and Northern Provinces had a similar distribution of opinion – with over 80 percent (+/- 2 percent) saying the executive presidency should be abolished."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Around 70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Verete Research",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Only 15 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "The 15 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1970s",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1970s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bretton Woods",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 1980s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anglo",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basket Band Crawl",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1980s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 5 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Verete",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 80 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමයට සියයට 70ක් විරුද්ධයි: මත විමසුම",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජාතික මට්ටමේ සමීක්ෂණයකට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූවන්ගෙන් සියයට 70 ක් පමණ විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමයට විරුද්ධ වී ඇති බව Verete Research විසින් කරන ලද මත විමසුමකට අනුව, කොළඹ පදනම් වූ චින්තන මණ්ඩලයක් පවසයි.",
        "විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමය දිගටම පවත්වාගෙන යාමට කැමැත්ත පළ කළේ සියයට 15ක් පමණයි. සියයට 15 බලතල අහෝසි කිරීම වෙනුවට බලතල අඩු කිරීම වැනි මත කිහිපයක් තිබූ බවද වාර්තාවේ.",
        "1970 ගණන්වල විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය මධ්‍යයේ ඇති වූ දැඩි වෙළඳ හා විනිමය පාලනයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලවත් විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමයක් ගෙන ආවේය.",
        "1970 ගනන්වල බ්‍රෙටන්වුඩ්ස් ක්‍රමය බිඳවැටී මහා බැංකුව භාණ්ඩාගාර බිල්පත්වල ඉහළම හිමිකරු බවට පත් වීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුළු ආර්ථිකයම වසා දැමුවේය.",
        "මහ බැංකුව 1980 ගණන්වල මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීම දිගටම කරගෙන ගිය අතර ඇන්ග්ලෝ-සැක්සන් මර්කන්ටිලිස්ට්වරු 1980 ගණන්වල බීබීසී (බාස්කට් බෑන්ඩ් ක්‍රෝල්) ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ලෙස හැඳින්වූ දෙයට අනුව මුදල් අවප්‍රමාණය කිරීමට පටන් ගත් අතර ඊටත් වඩා භාණ්ඩාගාර බිල්පත් ගෙවීමෙන් පසු පසුගිය වසර 5 තුළ REER ඉලක්ක කිරීම ලෙස හැඳින්විණි. මිලදී ගෙන රට පැහැර හැරිය.",
        "සියලුම වයස් කාණ්ඩ අතර මත බෙදා හැරීම බෙහෙවින් සමාන බව වෙරෙටේ පැවසීය.",
        "දකුණ, නැඟෙනහිර සහ උතුරු පළාත්වල ද සමාන මත බෙදා හැරීමක් තිබුණි - සියයට 80 (සියයට +/- 2) වැඩි පිරිසක් විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමය අහෝසි කළ යුතු බව ප්‍රකාශ කළහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Verete පර්යේෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15ක් පමණයි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15යි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රෙටන් වුඩ්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1980 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇංග්ලෝ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basket Band Crawl",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 5 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙරෙටේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 80 කට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 2 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி முறைக்கு 70 சதவீத மக்கள் எதிர்ப்பு: கருத்துக்கணிப்பு",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - நாடு தழுவிய கணக்கெடுப்புக்கு பதிலளித்தவர்களில் 70 சதவீதத்தினர் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி முறையை எதிர்த்துள்ளனர் என்று கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு சிந்தனைக் குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி முறை தொடர்வதற்கு 15 வீதமானவர்கள் மட்டுமே ஆதரவளித்துள்ளனர். 15 சதவிகிதத்தினர் அதிகாரங்களை ஒழிப்பதற்குப் பதிலாகக் குறைப்பது போன்ற பல கருத்துக்களைக் கொண்டிருந்தனர் என்று அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "1970 களின் அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறைக்கு மத்தியில் கடுமையான வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் பரிமாற்றக் கட்டுப்பாடுகளுக்குப் பிறகு இலங்கை ஒரு சக்திவாய்ந்த நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி முறையைக் கொண்டு வந்தது.",
        "1970 களில் பிரெட்டன் வூட்ஸ் அமைப்பு பொறிந்து போனதால் இலங்கை முழுப் பொருளாதாரத்தையும் மூடியது மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி திறைசேரி உண்டியல்களின் முதன்மை உரிமையாளராக மாறியது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி 1980 களில் பணத்தை அச்சிடுவதைத் தொடர்ந்தது மற்றும் ஆங்கிலோ-சாக்சன் வணிகர்கள் 1980 களில் BBC (Basket Band Crawl) கொள்கையின்படி நாணயத்தின் மதிப்பைக் குறைக்கத் தொடங்கினர், மேலும் கடந்த 5 ஆண்டுகளில் இன்னும் அதிகமான கருவூல பில்களுக்குப் பிறகு REER இலக்கு என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டது. வாங்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் நாடு தவறிவிட்டது.",
        "அனைத்து வயதினருக்கும் கருத்து விநியோகம் மிகவும் ஒத்ததாக இருந்தது, வெரேட் கூறினார்.",
        "தெற்கு, கிழக்கு மற்றும் வடக்கு மாகாணங்களில் ஒரே மாதிரியான கருத்து விநியோகம் இருந்தது - 80 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமானோர் (+/- 2 சதவீதம்) நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி முறை ஒழிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று கூறியுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெரேட் ஆராய்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15 சதவீதம் மட்டுமே",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரெட்டன் வூட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1980கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலோ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடை இசைக்குழு வலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 5 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "80 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}