{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/மே-9-வன்முறை-சம்பவங்கள்-சு-கவின்-முக்கியஸ்தர்-கைது/175-302830",
  "time_ut": 1661183883,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மே 9 வன்முறை சம்பவங்கள்; சு.கவின் முக்கியஸ்தர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "May 9 incidents of violence; S. Gavi's important person arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Following the violent incidents that took place in the country on May 09, a member of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party has been arrested in connection with the violent incidents in Piliyandal.",
        "A Freedom Party member of Kesbewa Municipality has been arrested. Investigations have revealed that the suspect is connected with 6 incidents of violence in Piliyandala.",
        "According to the police, the suspect is connected to 6 violent incidents including the attack and damage to the house of Kesbewa Mayor Laxman Perera, the attack on his sister's house and the attack on the house of Kamini Lokke MP's brother."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "May 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "S. Gavi's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piliyandal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesbewa Municipality",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piliyandala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kesbewa",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Laxman Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamini Lokke MP's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැයි 9 ප්‍රචණ්ඩ සිදුවීම්; එස්.ගවිගේ වැදගත් පුද්ගලයා අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය මැයි 09 වැනිදා රට තුළ ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී සිදුවීම්වලින් අනතුරුව පිළියන්දල ප්‍රදේශයේ ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "කැස්බෑව නගර සභාවේ නිදහස් පක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා. සැකකරු පිළියන්දල ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා 6කට සම්බන්ධ අයකු බවද විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වී තිබේ.",
        "කැස්බෑව නගරාධිපති ලක්ෂ්මන් පෙරේරාගේ නිවසට පහරදී අලාභහානි සිදුකිරීම, ඔහුගේ නැගණියගේ නිවසට පහරදීම,කාමිණී ලොක්කේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ සොහොයුරාගේ නිවසට පහරදීම ඇතුළු ප්‍රචණ්ඩ සිදුවීම් 6කට සැකකරු සම්බන්ධ බවයි පොලිසිය පවසන්නේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මැයි 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "S. Gavi's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිළියන්දල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැස්බෑව මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිළියන්දල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැස්බෑව",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමිණී ලොක්කේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மே 9 வன்முறை சம்பவங்கள்; சு.கவின் முக்கியஸ்தர் கைது",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மே 09ஆம் திகதி நாட்டில் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து பிலியந்தலயிலும் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களுடன் தொடர்புடைய ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் நகரசபை உறுப்பினர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கெஸ்பேவ நகரசபையின் சுதந்திரக் கட்சி உறுப்பினரே இவ்வாறு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார். பிலியந்தலயில் இடம்பெற்ற 6 வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களுடன் சந்தேகநபருக்கு தொடர்பிருப்பதாக விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "கெஸ்பேவ மேயர் லக்ஷமன் பெரேராவின் வீட்டைத் தாக்கி சேதம் விளைவித்தமை, அவரது சகோதரியின் வீட்டைத் தாக்கியமை, காமினி லொக்குகே எம்.பியின் சகோதரரின் வீட்டைத் தாக்கியமை உள்ளிட்ட 6 வன்முறைச் சம்பவங்களுடன் சந்தேகநபருக்கு தொடர்பிருப்பதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மே 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.கவியின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலியந்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஸ்பேவ நகரசபை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலியந்தலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஸ்பேவா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஸ்மன் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி லோக்கே எம்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}