{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/06/gammadda-food-aid-expands-nationwide-footprint/",
  "time_ut": 1657080540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gammadda ‘ Food Aid ‘ Expands Nationwide Footprint.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gammadda ‘ Food Aid ‘ Expands Nationwide Footprint.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Gammadda Movement stepped up its on-going efforts to support impoverished rural communities, by distributing Emergency Food Ration Packs.",
        "The Food Aid that began as soon as Sri Lanka’s economic crisis intensified months ago, has continued unabated, with the need for a square meal increasing almost daily.",
        "Sri Lankan families, and in particular children, are at risk of malnutrition as a result of economic hardships and failing crops, according to humanitarian organisations including UNICEF.",
        "“Despite the despondency, Sri Lankans both here and overseas had come forward to help. This is what makes our people special. We will continue to do what we can, even though, it’s very difficult out there.’, noted Chevaan Daniel, Group Director of the Sirasa Media Network, also the head of The Gammadda Movement.",
        "Gammadda has also continued with its people-centric projects across Sri Lanka, including Water Purification Plans, rural bridges, roads, Community Halls and school renovations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Gammadda Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNICEF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chevaan Daniel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sirasa Media Network",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Gammadda Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Water Purification Plans",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Community Halls",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගම්මැද්ද ‘ආහාර ආධාර’ රටපුරා පියසටහන් පුළුල් කරයි.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගම්මැද්ද ව්‍යාපාරය හදිසි ආහාර සලාක අසුරන බෙදාහැරීම මගින් දිළිඳු ග්‍රාමීය ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීමේ එහි අඛණ්ඩ උත්සාහයන් වේගවත් කළේය.",
        "මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වූ වහාම ආරම්භ වූ ආහාර ආධාර අඛණ්ඩව අඛණ්ඩව සිදුවෙමින් පවතින අතර, හතරැස් ආහාර වේලක අවශ්‍යතාවය දිනපතාම පාහේ වැඩි වේ.",
        "යුනිසෙෆ් ඇතුළු මානුෂීය සංවිධානවලට අනුව ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා සහ වගාවන් අසාර්ථක වීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පවුල් සහ විශේෂයෙන්ම දරුවන් මන්දපෝෂණයේ අවදානමකට ලක්ව සිටිති.",
        "“අධෛර්යමත් වුවද, මෙහි සහ විදේශයන්හි සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් උදව් කිරීමට ඉදිරිපත් වී සිටියහ. මේක තමයි අපේ මිනිස්සුන්ගේ විශේෂත්වය. එලියේ ගොඩක් අමාරු වුණත් අපිට කරන්න පුළුවන් දේ අපි දිගටම කරනවා.’, ගම්මැද්ද ව්‍යාපාරයේ ප්‍රධානී, සිරස මාධ්‍ය ජාලයේ සමූහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ Chevan Daniel සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ගම්මැද්ද ජල පවිත්‍රකරණ සැලසුම්, ග්‍රාමීය පාලම්, මාර්ග, ප්‍රජා ශාලා සහ පාසල් ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා ජනතා කේන්ද්‍රීය ව්‍යාපෘති සමඟ ද අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක වී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්මැද්ද ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතාම පාහේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනිසෙෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙවාන් ඩැනියෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස මාධ්‍ය ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්මැද්ද ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජල පිරිසිදු කිරීමේ සැලසුම්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජා ශාලා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Gammadda 'உணவு உதவி' நாடு தழுவிய தடயத்தை விரிவுபடுத்துகிறது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவசரகால உணவு ரேஷன் பொதிகளை விநியோகிப்பதன் மூலம், வறிய கிராமப்புற சமூகங்களை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான அதன் தொடர் முயற்சிகளை கம்மத்தா இயக்கம் முடுக்கிவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்னர் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி உக்கிரமடைந்தவுடன் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட உணவு உதவி, ஒரு சதுர உணவின் தேவை கிட்டத்தட்ட நாளாந்தம் அதிகரித்து வருவதால், தடையின்றி தொடர்கிறது.",
        "UNICEF உள்ளிட்ட மனிதாபிமான அமைப்புகளின்படி, பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள் மற்றும் பயிர்கள் தோல்வியடைந்ததன் விளைவாக இலங்கை குடும்பங்கள் மற்றும் குறிப்பாக குழந்தைகள் ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாட்டிற்கு ஆளாகியுள்ளனர்.",
        "“விரக்தி இருந்தபோதிலும், இங்கும் வெளிநாடுகளிலும் உள்ள இலங்கையர்கள் உதவ முன்வந்தனர். இதுவே நம் மக்களின் சிறப்பு. வெளியில் மிகவும் கடினமாக இருந்தாலும், எங்களால் முடிந்ததை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து செய்வோம்.’ என்று சிரச ஊடக வலையமைப்பின் குழு இயக்குனரும், தி கம்மடா இயக்கத்தின் தலைவருமான செவான் டேனியல் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "நீர் சுத்திகரிப்புத் திட்டங்கள், கிராமப் பாலங்கள், வீதிகள், சமூகக் கூடங்கள் மற்றும் பாடசாலை புனரமைப்புகள் உட்பட இலங்கை முழுவதிலும் உள்ள மக்களை மையப்படுத்திய திட்டங்களுடன் Gammadda தொடர்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்மடா இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனிசெஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவான் டேனியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச ஊடக வலையமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்மடா இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர் சுத்திகரிப்பு திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமுதாய கூடங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}