{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/01/stop-trying-to-suppress-sirasa-opposition-leader-tells-president/",
  "time_ut": 1662011520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Stop trying to suppress Sirasa’ – Opposition Leader tells President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Stop trying to suppress Sirasa’ – Opposition Leader tells President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa has called for an immediate end to media suppression.",
        "Speaking in Parliament on Thursday (1), Sajith Premadasa said the government must immediately stop the suppression.",
        "\"When Keheliya Rambukwella was the Media Minister, I warned them NOT to suppress the Sirasa Media, as they were drafting plans to do so. That plan was suspended,\" said the Opposition Leader.",
        "He said even today there are attempts being made to suppress the Sirasa Media Network, which was instrumental in introducing programs such as Gammadda strengthening the poor people of the country.",
        "He reminded the President that when the former was the Prime Minister in 2002 he removed the Criminal Defamation Law.",
        "The Opposition Leader requested the President to end the suppression of Sirasa Media, and stop preparing plans to terminate the license of Sirasa Media.",
        "\"This will send a very wrong message to the Human Rights Council in Geneva in September 2022,\" warned the Opposition Leader, adding that the use of the PTA also poses a similar situation.",
        "Recalling the incident where several Sirasa (News 1st) Journalists were brutally assaulted, the Opposition Leader questioned the delay in probing the attack.",
        "He reminded the President that it was the Sirasa Media Network that at one time support him to move forward in his political career.",
        "\"The suppression of the Sirasa Media, Social Media, Journalists must end and pave the way for media freedom,\" stressed the Opposition Leader.",
        "‘Stop trying to suppress Sirasa’ – Opposition Leader tells President",
        "Jeyaraj Murder Case: Former SP & Ex-LTTE cadre acquitted and released"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sirasa’",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "When Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sirasa Media Network",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Defamation Law",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa Media",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sirasa Media Network",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Social Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeyaraj Murder Case",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SP & Ex-LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘සිරස මර්ධනය කරන්න හදන එක නවත්වන්න’ – විපක්ෂ නායක ජනපතිට කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මාධ්‍ය මර්දනය වහා නතර කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (1) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අදහස් දක්වමින් සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුව මර්දනය වහා නතර කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "\"කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල මහතා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටියදී සිරස මාධ්‍ය මර්දනය කරන්න එපා කියලා මම ඔවුන්ට අවවාද කළා. ඒ අය ඒ සඳහා සැලසුම් සම්පාදනය කරන නිසා. ඒ සැලැස්ම අත්හිටෙව්වා\" විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "රටේ දුප්පත් ජනතාව ශක්තිමත් කරන ගම්මැද්ද වැනි වැඩසටහන් හඳුන්වා දීමට මුල් වූ සිරස මාධ්‍ය ජාලය අදත් මර්දනය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා 2002 වසරේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටියදී අපරාධ අපහාස නීතිය ඉවත් කළ බව ඔහු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සිහිපත් කළා.",
        "සිරස මාධ්‍ය මර්දනය අවසන් කරන ලෙසත් සිරස මාධ්‍ය බලපත්‍රය අහෝසි කිරීමේ සැලසුම් සකස් කිරීම නවත්වන ලෙසත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා.",
        "\"මෙය 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයට ඉතා වැරදි පණිවිඩයක් ලබා දෙනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් අනතුරු ඇඟවූ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා, ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත භාවිතා කිරීම ද එවැනිම තත්වයක් ඇති කරන බව පැවසීය.",
        "සිරස (News 1st) මාධ්‍යවේදීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට අමානුෂික ලෙස පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සිහිපත් කළ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එම ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බැලීම ප්‍රමාද කිරීම පිළිබඳව ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "තම දේශපාලන ගමන ඉදිරියට යාමට වරෙක සහය දුන්නේ සිරස මාධ්‍ය ජාලය බවද ඔහු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "\"සිරස මාධ්‍ය, සමාජ මාධ්‍ය, මාධ්‍යවේදීන් මර්දනය අවසන් කර මාධ්‍ය නිදහසට මග පෑදිය යුතුයි\" විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "‘සිරස මර්ධනය කරන්න හදන එක නවත්වන්න’ – විපක්ෂ නායක ජනපතිට කියයි",
        "ජෙයරාජ් ඝාතන නඩුව: හිටපු එස්පී සහ හිටපු එල්ටීටීඊ සාමාජිකයා නිදොස් කොට නිදහස් කෙරේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිරස'",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල විට",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස මාධ්‍ය ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ අපහාස නීතිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස මාධ්‍ය ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමාජ මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෙයරාජ් ඝාතන නඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්පී සහ හිටපු එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘சிரசவை ஒடுக்கும் முயற்சியை நிறுத்துங்கள்’ – எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஊடக அடக்குமுறையை உடனடியாக நிறுத்துமாறு இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசா வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "வியாழன் (1) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உரையாற்றிய சஜித் பிரேமதாச, அடக்குமுறையை அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக நிறுத்த வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சராக இருந்தபோது, ​​சிரச ஊடகத்தை ஒடுக்க வேண்டாம் என நான் எச்சரித்தேன், அதற்காக அவர்கள் திட்டங்களை வகுத்துக்கொண்டிருந்தார்கள். அந்தத் திட்டம் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டது என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் வறிய மக்களைப் பலப்படுத்தும் கம்மத்த போன்ற வேலைத்திட்டங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதில் முக்கிய பங்காற்றிய சிரச ஊடக வலையமைப்பை நசுக்குவதற்கு இன்றும் முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "2002 ஆம் ஆண்டு முன்னாள் பிரதமராக இருந்த போது குற்றவியல் அவதூறு சட்டத்தை நீக்கியதை அவர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நினைவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "சிரச ஊடக அடக்குமுறையை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டு வருமாறும், சிரச ஊடகத்தின் உரிமத்தை ரத்து செய்வதற்கான திட்டங்களை தயாரிப்பதை நிறுத்துமாறும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "2022 செப்டம்பரில் ஜெனிவாவில் நடைபெறும் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவைக்கு இது மிகவும் தவறான செய்தியை அனுப்பும்” என எச்சரித்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதும் இதேபோன்றதொரு சூழ்நிலையை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது என்றார்.",
        "சிரச (News 1st) ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் பலர் கொடூரமான முறையில் தாக்கப்பட்ட சம்பவத்தை நினைவு கூர்ந்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்துவதில் தாமதம் குறித்து கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "தனது அரசியல் வாழ்க்கையில் முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கு ஒரு காலத்தில் சிரச ஊடக வலையமைப்பே உறுதுணையாக இருந்ததாகவும் அவர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நினைவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "“சிரச ஊடகங்கள், சமூக ஊடகங்கள், ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான ஒடுக்குமுறை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டுவரப்பட்டு ஊடக சுதந்திரத்திற்கு வழி வகுக்க வேண்டும்” என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "‘சிரசவை ஒடுக்கும் முயற்சியை நிறுத்துங்கள்’ – எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "ஜெயராஜ் கொலை வழக்கு: முன்னாள் எஸ்பி மற்றும் முன்னாள் விடுதலைப் புலி உறுப்பினர் விடுதலை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிரச’",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல போது",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச ஊடக வலையமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றவியல் அவதூறு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச மீடியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச மீடியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச ஊடக வலையமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமூக ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயராஜ் கொலை வழக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்பி & முன்னாள் எல்டிடிஇ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}