{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83563/india-stands-with-people-of-sri-lanka-mea-spokesman",
  "time_ut": 1657457640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘India stands with people of Sri Lanka’: MEA spokesman",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘India stands with people of Sri Lanka’: MEA spokesman",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian government on Sunday showing its support to the crisis-hit neighbouring island nation said that India is continuously following the recent developments in Sri Lanka.",
        "In a statement, India’s Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Arindam Bagchi said, “We are aware of the many challenges that Sri Lanka and its people have been facing, and we have stood with the Sri Lankan people as they have tried to overcome this difficult period.”",
        "Maintaining that India is Sri Lanka’s closest neighbour, the MEA said India has extended ‘unprecedented’ support of over $3.8 billion for ameliorating the serious economic situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "“We continue to follow closely the recent developments in Sri Lanka. India stands with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realize their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values, established institutions and constitutional framework,” the MEA spokesperson said.",
        "The Indian Foreign Ministry further stated, “India stands with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realize their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values, established institutions and constitutional framework.”",
        "Earlier in the day, Jaishankar said that India has been providing assistance to Sri Lanka and is monitoring the developments in the island nation adding that there is no refugee crisis now."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "MEA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier in the day",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ සිටයි’: MEA ප්‍රකාශක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අර්බුදකාරී අසල්වැසි දූපත් රාජ්‍යයට සහාය දක්වන ඉන්දීය රජය ඉරිදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෑත කාලීන වර්ධනයන් ඉන්දියාව අඛණ්ඩව අනුගමනය කරන බවයි.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi පැවසුවේ, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ එහි ජනතාව මුහුණ දී ඇති බොහෝ අභියෝග පිළිබඳව අපි දන්නා අතර, මෙම දුෂ්කර කාල පරිච්ඡේදය ජය ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාව උත්සාහ කළ බැවින් අපි ඔවුන් සමඟ සිටිමු. .”",
        "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමීපතම අසල්වැසියා බව පෙන්වා දෙන MEA, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බරපතල ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සමනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කට අධික ‘පෙර නොවූ විරූ’ සහය ලබා දී ඇති බව පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෑත කාලීන වර්ධනයන් සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටිමු. ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා සමෘද්ධිය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන විට ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ සිටී.",
        "\"ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමෘද්ධිය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා වූ ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන විට ඉන්දියාව ඔවුන් සමඟ සිටින බව ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය වැඩිදුරටත් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර ලබා දෙන බවත් දිවයිනේ වර්ධනයන් නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටින බවත් සරණාගත අර්බුදයක් දැන් නොමැති බවත් ජයිශංකර් මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "MEA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින් දවසේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியா நிற்கிறது’: MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அண்டை தீவு நாட்டிற்கு தனது ஆதரவைக் காட்டும் இந்திய அரசாங்கம் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை இலங்கையில் சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்களை இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து பின்பற்றுகிறது என்று கூறியது.",
        "இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில், “இலங்கை மற்றும் அதன் மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பல சவால்களை நாங்கள் அறிவோம், மேலும் இந்த கடினமான காலகட்டத்தை கடக்க முயன்ற இலங்கை மக்களுடன் நாங்கள் நின்றோம். .\"",
        "இந்தியா இலங்கையின் நெருங்கிய அண்டை நாடாக இருப்பதைப் பராமரித்த MEA, இலங்கையின் தீவிரமான பொருளாதார நிலைமையை சீர்செய்வதற்காக இந்தியா முன்னோடியில்லாத வகையில் $3.8 பில்லியன் ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "“இலங்கையில் அண்மைய முன்னேற்றங்களை நாம் தொடர்ந்தும் உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருகிறோம். ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள், நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க முயலும் இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியா நிற்கிறது” என்று MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள், நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் இலங்கை மக்கள் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க முயலும் போது இந்தியா அவர்களுடன் நிற்கிறது\" என்று இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "முன்னதாக, ஜெய்சங்கர், இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு உதவி செய்து வருவதாகவும், தீவு தேசத்தின் வளர்ச்சிகளை கண்காணித்து வருவதாகவும், இப்போது அகதிகள் நெருக்கடி இல்லை என்றும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "MEA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}