{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62249169",
  "time_ut": 1658450432,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන: නව අගමැතිවරයා ගැන මේ තොරතුරු ඔබ දන්නවාද?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dinesh Gunawardena: Do you know this information about the new Prime Minister?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dinesh Gunawardena was sworn in today (July 22) as the new Prime Minister of the new interim government led by President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "He was sworn in before President Ranil Wickremesinghe at the Prime Minister's office in Malpara, Colombo.",
        "The three armed forces chiefs and other members of parliament also participated in this event.",
        "Also, a spokesperson of the President's office said that the new cabinet will also be sworn in today at around 12.30 pm.",
        "Abhinava Agramatya Dinesh Gunawardena's parents are Phillip Gunawardena, nicknamed Boralugoda Sinhaya, the father of socialism in this country, and Kusuma Gunawardena, known as Rathu Kusuma of the Left.",
        "Born on March 2, 1949, Dinesh Gunawardena has been the leader of the People's United Front since 1973, after the death of Philip Gunawardena.",
        "Dinesh Gunawardena received his schooling from the Royal College, Colombo. Later, he earned associate degrees in business administration, management, and business administration, management and international transportation from the Netherlands Business University and the University of Oregon.",
        "She died suddenly in the mid-1980s and his two children are Yadamini Gunawardena and Sankhapali Gunawardena, a current Member of Parliament.",
        "Indika Gunawardena who was a minister, Githanjana Gunawardena who held the post of Deputy Speaker as well as Deputy Minister twice, Prasanna Gunawardena who was the mayor of Colombo and writer Lakmali Gunawardena are his brothers and sisters.",
        "Dinesh Gunawardena, the leader of the People's United Front, was the candidate for Avissawella in the 1977 parliamentary elections, but failed to get elected. But in the by-election of 1983, he was the Maharagama candidate of the People's United Front and entered the Parliament for the first time with a historic victory in that election.",
        "Since then, he represented the Parliament from time to time, failed to win in the general election held in 1994, won again in the election held in the year 2000 from the Colombo district and held many senior ministerial posts in many governments."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malpara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 12.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abhinava Agramatya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Phillip Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boralugoda Sinhaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusuma Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathu Kusuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Left",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "March 2, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's United Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philip Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal College, Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Netherlands Business University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Oregon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the mid-1980s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yadamini Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sankhapali Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indika Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Githanjana Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmali Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's United Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharagama",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's United Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන: නව අගමැතිවරයා ගැන මේ තොරතුරු ඔබ දන්නවාද?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් නව අන්තර් කාලීන ආණ්ඩුවේ නව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන අද (ජූලි 22 වැනිදා) දිව්රුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "කොළඹ මල්පාරේ පිහිටි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඉදිරියේ ඔහු දිව්රුම් දෙනු ලැබීය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන් සහ සෙසු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු ද සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "එසේම අද දහවල් 12.30ට පමණ නව ඇමැති මණ්ඩලය ද දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිත බවට ජනපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශකයකු පැවසීය.",
        "අභිනව අග්‍රමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනගේ මා-පිය දෙපළ වන්නේ, මෙරට සමාජවාදයේ පියා වන, බොරළුගොඩ සිංහයා යන විරුදාවලිය ලැබූ, පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධනයන් සහ වමේ රතු කුසුම ලෙස හඳුන්වන කුසුමා ගුණවර්ධනය.",
        "1949 මාර්තු 02 උපන් දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන,  පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධනගේ අභාවයෙන් පසු, 1973 සිට මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ නායකයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී.",
        "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන පාසල් අධ්‍යාපනය ලැබුවේ, කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයෙනි. පසුව, ව්‍යාපාර පරිපාලනය, කළමනාකරණය ආශ්‍රිත මෙන්ම ව්‍යාපාර පරිපාලනය, කළමනාකරණය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රවාහනය පිළිබඳ උපාධි හිමිකර ගත්තේ, නෙදර්ලන්ත ව්‍යාපාරික විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙන් හා ඔරිගන් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙනි.",
        "1980 මැද භාගයේ ඇය හදිසියේ මියගිය අතර ඔහුගේ  දරු දෙදෙනා වන්නේ, වර්තමාන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු වන යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන හා සංඛපාලි ගුණවර්ධනයි.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයකු වූ ඉන්දික ගුණවර්ධන, නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායක ධුරය මෙන්ම දෙවරක් නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ධුර දැරූ ගීතාංජන ගුණවර්ධන, කොළඹ පුරපති වූ ප්‍රසන්න ගුණවර්ධන, ලේඛිකා ලක්මාලි ගුණවර්ධන  ඔහුගේ සහෝදර සහෝදරියන්ය.",
        "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ නායක දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන, 1977 පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේ දී අවිස්සාවේල්ලේ අපේක්ෂකයා වූ නමුත්, තේරී පත්වීමට අසමත් විය. එහෙත් 1983 අතුරු මැතිවරණයේදී මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ මහරගම අපේක්ෂකයා වූ ඔහු එම මැතිවරණයෙන් ඓතිහාසික ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබමින් පළමු වරට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය.",
        "එතැන් පටන් විටින් විට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන ඔහු, 1994 දි පැවති මහමැතිවරණයෙන් ජය ගැනීමට අපොහොසත්ව නැවතත් 2000 වසරේ සිට පැවති මැතිවරණයෙන්  කොළඹ දිත්‍රික්කයෙන් ජයගෙන ආණ්ඩු රැසක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ අමාත්‍ය ධුර රැසක් හොඹවන ලදි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල්පාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.30 පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අභිනව අග්‍රමාත්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරළුගොඩ සිංහයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසුමා ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතු කුසුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 2, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්ත ව්‍යාපාරික විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔරිගන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1980 ගණන්වල මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංඛපාලි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගීතාංජන ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාලි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன: புதிய பிரதமர் பற்றிய இந்த தகவல் உங்களுக்கு தெரியுமா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான புதிய இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தின் புதிய பிரதமராக தினேஷ் குணவர்தன இன்று (ஜூலை 22) பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "கொழும்பு மல்பாராவில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் அவர் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் முப்படைகளின் பிரதானிகள் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "மேலும், புதிய அமைச்சரவையும் இன்று நண்பகல் 12.30 மணியளவில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்ளவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்நாட்டின் சோசலிசத்தின் தந்தை என அழைக்கப்படும் பொரலுகொட சின்ஹயா என்ற புனைப்பெயர் கொண்ட பிலிப் குணவர்தன மற்றும் இடதுசாரிகளின் ரது குசுமா என அழைக்கப்படும் குசுமா குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் அபினவ அக்ரமத்ய தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவின் பெற்றோர்கள்.",
        "1949ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் மாதம் 2ஆம் திகதி பிறந்த தினேஸ் குணவர்தன, பிலிப் குணவர்தனவின் மறைவுக்குப் பின்னர் 1973ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணியின் தலைவராக இருந்து வருகிறார்.",
        "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன கொழும்பு றோயல் கல்லூரியில் தனது பள்ளிப்படிப்பைப் பெற்றார். பின்னர், நெதர்லாந்து வணிக பல்கலைக்கழகம் மற்றும் ஒரேகான் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் வணிக நிர்வாகம், மேலாண்மை மற்றும் வணிக நிர்வாகம், மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சர்வதேச போக்குவரத்து ஆகியவற்றில் இணை பட்டங்களைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "1980 களின் நடுப்பகுதியில் அவர் திடீரென இறந்தார் மற்றும் அவரது இரண்டு குழந்தைகள் யாதாமினி குணவர்தன மற்றும் தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரான சங்கபாலி குணவர்தன.",
        "அமைச்சராக இருந்த இந்திக்க குணவர்தன, பிரதி சபாநாயகராக இருமுறை பிரதி அமைச்சர் பதவிகளை வகித்த கிதாஞ்சன குணவர்தன, கொழும்பு மேயராக இருந்த பிரசன்ன குணவர்தன, எழுத்தாளர் லக்மாலி குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் சகோதர சகோதரிகளாவர்.",
        "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணியின் தலைவரான தினேஷ் குணவர்தன 1977ஆம் ஆண்டு நடைபெற்ற நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் அவிசாவளை வேட்பாளராக களமிறங்கினார், ஆனால் அவர் தேர்தலில் வெற்றி பெறவில்லை. ஆனால் 1983 ஆம் ஆண்டு நடைபெற்ற இடைத்தேர்தலில் மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணியின் மஹரகம வேட்பாளராக களமிறங்கி அத்தேர்தலில் வரலாற்றுச் சிறப்புமிக்க வெற்றியுடன் முதன்முறையாக பாராளுமன்றம் நுழைந்தார்.",
        "அப்போதிருந்து, அவர் அவ்வப்போது பாராளுமன்றத்தைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தினார், 1994 இல் நடந்த பொதுத் தேர்தலில் வெற்றிபெறத் தவறினார், 2000 ஆம் ஆண்டில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் நடந்த தேர்தலில் மீண்டும் வெற்றி பெற்றார் மற்றும் பல அரசாங்கங்களில் பல மூத்த அமைச்சர் பதவிகளை வகித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மல்பாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபிநவ அக்ரமத்யா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரலுகொட சின்ஹாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசுமா குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்து குசுமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விட்டு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2, 1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் கல்லூரி, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து வணிக பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரேகான் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1980களின் மத்தியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாதாமினி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கபாலி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீதாஞ்சன குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மாலி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் ஐக்கிய முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}