{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/german-biz-chamber-helps-sri-lanka-firms-enter-eu-organic-market-99437/",
  "time_ut": 1662297720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "German biz chamber helps Sri Lanka firms enter EU organic market",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "German biz chamber helps Sri Lanka firms enter EU organic market",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The Delegation of German Industry and Commerce in Sri Lanka (AHK Sri Lanka) with the European Chamber of Commerce of Sri Lanka (ECCSL) had brought together domestic organic food suppliers and European buyers.",
        "Sri Lanka firms have been support European and German business chamber in Sri Lanka had organised a virtual interactive session",
        "The ‘Organic Food Production and Exports by SMEs in Sri Lanka’ conference allowed small and medium enterprises meet buyers in the EU.",
        "The online forum had drawn over 155 partipants such as SME traders, exporters, medium-scale farmers and other agri-food producers.",
        "European importers and retailers (including Rewe Far East Limited, Biokorntakt Vertriebs GmbH, and",
        "Herbaria Kräuterparadies GmbH from Germany, Tradin Organic Agriculture B.V. from Netherlands, Renee",
        "Voltaire from Sweden, JJM Group from Slovakia, and Greenest from Estonia) met Sri Lanka suppliers.",
        "They were interested in organic coconut-based products, tropical fruits, vegetables, and spice products among others from Sri Lanka.",
        "About 30 Sri Lankan SMEs who had the criteria of European Buyers for specific product portfolios, EU organic certified status, and other certifications and standards for special B2B matchmaking meetings with European importers were selected following the forum.",
        "Country Director of GIZ Sri Lanka Petra Mutlu, Charge d’Affaires, Delegation of the European Union, Thorsten Bargfrede, Chairman of Export Development Board – Suresh de Mel, and Chief Delegate of the Delegation of German Industry and Commerce in Sri Lanka (AHK Sri Lanka), Marie Antonia von Schönburg and President of European Chamber of Commerce of Sri Lanka (ECCSL), Arnold Perera and Buddhi Marambe, Senior Professor in Agriculture, University of Peradeniya were in the forum. (Colombo/Sep04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "German",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Chamber of Commerce of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "German",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The ‘Organic Food Production and Exports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rewe Far East Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biokorntakt Vertriebs GmbH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Herbaria Kräuterparadies GmbH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tradin Organic Agriculture B.V.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Renee",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sweden",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JJM Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Slovakia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Estonia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "About 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "European Buyers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GIZ Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petra Mutlu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delegation of the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thorsten Bargfrede",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Export Development Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marie Antonia von Schönburg",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "European Chamber of Commerce of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arnold Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhi Marambe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Peradeniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජර්මානු බිස් වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාගම්වලට යුරෝපා සංගමයේ කාබනික වෙළඳපොළට ඇතුළු වීමට උපකාර කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජර්මානු කර්මාන්ත සහ වාණිජ නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායම (AHK Sri Lanka) ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුරෝපීය වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය (ECCCSL) සමඟ දේශීය කාබනික ආහාර සැපයුම්කරුවන් සහ යුරෝපීය ගැනුම්කරුවන් එක් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාගම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යුරෝපීය සහ ජර්මානු ව්‍යාපාරික මණ්ඩලය විසින් අතථ්‍ය අන්තර්ක්‍රියාකාරී සැසියක් සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි",
        "‘ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සුළු හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් විසින් කාබනික ආහාර නිෂ්පාදනය සහ අපනයනය’ සමුළුව කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයන්ට යුරෝපා සංගමයේ ගැනුම්කරුවන් හමුවීමට ඉඩ සැලසීය.",
        "කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාරිකයින්, අපනයනකරුවන්, මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ගොවීන් සහ අනෙකුත් කෘෂි ආහාර නිෂ්පාදකයින් වැනි 155 දෙනෙකුට වැඩි පිරිසක් මෙම අන්තර්ජාල සංසදයට සහභාගී වී ඇත.",
        "යුරෝපීය ආනයනකරුවන් සහ සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දන් (Rewe Far East Limited, Biokorntakt Vertriebs GmbH, සහ",
        "ජර්මනියේ Herbaria Kräuterparadies GmbH, නෙදර්ලන්තයෙන් Tradin කාබනික කෘෂිකර්ම B.V., Renee",
        "ස්වීඩනයේ වෝල්ටෙයාර්, ස්ලෝවැකියාවේ JJM සමූහය සහ එස්තෝනියාවේ Greenest) ශ්‍රී ලංකා සැපයුම්කරුවන් හමුවිය.",
        "ඔවුන් කාබනික පොල් ආශ්‍රිත නිෂ්පාදන, නිවර්තන කලාපීය පලතුරු, එළවළු සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් වෙනත් කුළුබඩු නිෂ්පාදන කෙරෙහි උනන්දු වූහ.",
        "විශේෂිත නිෂ්පාදන කළඹ සඳහා යුරෝපීය ගැනුම්කරුවන්ගේ නිර්ණායක, EU කාබනික සහතික කළ තත්ත්වය සහ යුරෝපීය ආනයනකරුවන් සමඟ විශේෂ B2B ගැලපීම් රැස්වීම් සඳහා වෙනත් සහතික කිරීම් සහ ප්‍රමිතීන් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකික කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් 30ක් පමණ තෝරා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "GIZ ශ්‍රී ලංකා හි රටේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ Petra Mutlu, භාරකාරත්වය, යුරෝපා සංගමයේ නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායම, Thorsten Bargfrede, අපනයන සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපති - සුරේෂ් ද මෙල් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජර්මානු කර්මාන්ත හා වාණිජ නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායමේ ප්‍රධාන නියෝජිත (AHK ශ්‍රී. ලංකා), Marie Antonia von Schönburg සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුරෝපීය වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ (ECSCSL) සභාපති ආර්නෝල්ඩ් පෙරේරා සහ පේරාදෙණිය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ කෘෂිකර්මය පිළිබඳ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මහාචාර්ය බුද්ධි මාරඹේ යන මහත්ම මහත්මීහු මෙම සංසදයට එක්ව සිටියහ. (කොළඹ/සැප්.04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජර්මානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යුරෝපීය වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාබනික ආහාර නිෂ්පාදනය සහ අපනයනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rewe Far East Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biokorntakt Vertriebs GmbH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Herbaria Kräuterparadies GmbH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tradin කාබනික කෘෂිකර්ම B.V.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙනී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JJM සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ලෝවැකියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්තෝනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය ගැනුම්කරුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GIZ Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රා මුට්ලු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමයේ නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thorsten Bargfrede",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයන සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාරි ඇන්ටෝනියා වොන් ෂොන්බර්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යුරෝපීය වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්නෝල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධි මාරඹේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜேர்மன் பிஸ் சேம்பர் இலங்கை நிறுவனங்களுக்கு ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றிய கரிம சந்தையில் நுழைவதற்கு உதவுகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையில் ஜேர்மன் கைத்தொழில் மற்றும் வர்த்தக பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு (AHK Sri Lanka) இலங்கையின் ஐரோப்பிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்துடன் (ECCCSL) உள்நாட்டு கரிம உணவு வழங்குநர்கள் மற்றும் ஐரோப்பிய வாங்குபவர்களை ஒன்றிணைத்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஐரோப்பிய மற்றும் ஜேர்மன் வணிக அறைக்கு இலங்கை நிறுவனங்கள் ஆதரவாக ஒரு மெய்நிகர் ஊடாடும் அமர்வை ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தன",
        "‘இலங்கையில் SME களின் கரிம உணவு உற்பத்தி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி’ மாநாடு சிறிய மற்றும் நடுத்தர தொழில் நிறுவனங்கள் ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தில் வாங்குபவர்களை சந்திக்க அனுமதித்தது.",
        "SME வர்த்தகர்கள், ஏற்றுமதியாளர்கள், நடுத்தர அளவிலான விவசாயிகள் மற்றும் பிற விவசாய உணவு உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் என 155 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பங்கேற்பாளர்களை ஆன்லைன் மன்றம் ஈர்த்துள்ளது.",
        "ஐரோப்பிய இறக்குமதியாளர்கள் மற்றும் சில்லறை விற்பனையாளர்கள் (Rewe Far East Limited, Biokorntakt Vertriebs GmbH, மற்றும்",
        "ஜெர்மனியைச் சேர்ந்த ஹெர்பேரியா க்ருடர்பாரடீஸ் ஜிஎம்பிஹெச், நெதர்லாந்திலிருந்து டிரேடின் ஆர்கானிக் அக்ரிகல்ச்சர் பி.வி., ரெனீ",
        "ஸ்வீடனைச் சேர்ந்த வோல்டேர், ஸ்லோவாக்கியாவிலிருந்து ஜேஜேஎம் குழுமம் மற்றும் எஸ்டோனியாவைச் சேர்ந்த கிரீனெஸ்ட்) இலங்கை சப்ளையர்களை சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "அவர்கள் ஆர்கானிக் தேங்காய் அடிப்படையிலான பொருட்கள், வெப்பமண்டல பழங்கள், காய்கறிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கையில் இருந்து மசாலா பொருட்கள் போன்றவற்றில் ஆர்வமாக இருந்தனர்.",
        "ஐரோப்பிய இறக்குமதியாளர்களுடனான விசேட B2B மேட்ச்மேக்கிங் சந்திப்புகளுக்கான குறிப்பிட்ட தயாரிப்பு போர்ட்ஃபோலியோக்கள், EU கரிம சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட அந்தஸ்து மற்றும் பிற சான்றிதழ்கள் மற்றும் தரநிலைகளுக்கு ஐரோப்பிய வாங்குபவர்களின் அளவுகோல்களைக் கொண்ட சுமார் 30 இலங்கை SMEக்கள் மன்றத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "GIZ இலங்கையின் நாட்டுப் பணிப்பாளர் Petra Mutlu, பொறுப்பாளர், ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியப் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு, Thorsten Bargfrede, ஏற்றுமதி அபிவிருத்திச் சபையின் தலைவர் – சுரேஷ் டி மெல் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான ஜேர்மன் கைத்தொழில் மற்றும் வர்த்தகப் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவின் பிரதான பிரதிநிதி (AHK Sri) இலங்கை), Marie Antonia von Schönburg மற்றும் இலங்கையின் ஐரோப்பிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் (ECCCSL) தலைவர் அர்னால்ட் பெரேரா மற்றும் பேராதனைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் விவசாயப் பிரிவின் சிரேஷ்ட பேராசிரியர் புத்தி மரம்பே ஆகியோர் மன்றத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டனர். (கொழும்பு/செப்04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜெர்மன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் ஐரோப்பிய வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்கானிக் உணவு உற்பத்தி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெவ் ஃபார் ஈஸ்ட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biokorntakt Vertriebs GmbH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹெர்பேரியா க்ரூட்டர்பாரடீஸ் ஜிஎம்பிஹெச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரேடின் ஆர்கானிக் விவசாயம் பி.வி.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேஜேஎம் குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்லோவாக்கியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்டோனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய வாங்குபவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GIZ இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரா முட்லு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோர்ஸ்டன் பார்க்ஃப்ரெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதி மேம்பாட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேரி அன்டோனியா வான் ஷான்பர்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் ஐரோப்பிய வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ECCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்னால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தி மரம்பே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}