{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132027",
  "time_ut": 1658490607,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "களவாடிய துப்பாக்கிகள் எங்கே ? ஜே.வி.பி.யின் தலைவரை கேட்ட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Where are the rifles? President Ranil asked the leader of JVP",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Observing the changes and events in Sri Lanka's national politics is always a cause for concern.",
        "It is the first time in Sri Lanka's and world's political history that a person has been elected president with just 134 votes.",
        "However, Ranil Wickramasinghe has realized his long-held dream of the throne. Elections did not help him to achieve this goal of political success. Instead, it was the 'sanctuary' struggle that led.",
        "As the situation is like this, as the voting for the election of the President was held on Wednesday, Anukumara Dissanayake of the People's Liberation Front (JVP) has come against him by entering the Parliament that day.",
        "\"Where are the two guns?\" asked President Ranil. Anura replied that which guns with a small chainsaw.",
        "Anura said that President Ranil said that he would ask for those guns if you went to Kalawadi from the army during the parliamentary demonstration, but don't joke and ask the people who took them away. President Ranil left there saying that it is okay to hand over to the army as soon as possible.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe took the oath of office the next day Thursday on the 2nd floor of Parliament where the offices of the President and Prime Minister are located.",
        "Many party leaders were also present in this event. The President mentioned to the party leaders who congratulated President Ranil Wickremesinghe after his swearing-in that he would take steps to establish an all-party government as soon as possible.",
        "During this, Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa said, I will not call you 'Athimedaku'. President Ranil said to Wickremesinghe that you have mentioned not to call like that.",
        "The President replied, \"I have banned the word 'Athimethaku'.\" So he said with a smile that if you use that word, you will be punished. The bystanders, including the Leader of the Opposition, had a silent smile.",
        "In both these incidents, the political repercussions of President Ranil Wickremesinghe can be felt.",
        "President Ranil is the one who can fully use the executive power given in the constitution.",
        "After Gotabaya Rajapaksa took office, he abolished the 19th constitution and regained executive power, but the media could not benefit from that power.",
        "On the other hand, Ranil Wickramasinghe handed over the complete executive power he had acquired and fled the country.",
        "Today, Ranil Wickremesinghe is in office as the Executive President. Play the Game But Follow the Rules (Play the Game But Follow the Rules) Former President J.R. This text is Jayawardena's political teaching.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe has come to power after years of waiting. Although nothing is possible before the Lok Sabha, the political games of President Ranil Wickremesinghe who followed the rule for a short period of time can be seen."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "JVP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just 134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anukumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalawadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J.R.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රයිෆල් කොහෙද? ජනාධිපති රනිල් ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායකයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික දේශපාලනයේ සිදුවන වෙනස්කම් සහ සිදුවීම් නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සැමවිටම කනස්සල්ලට කරුණකි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ ලෝක දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ ඡන්ද 134 කින් පුද්ගලයකු ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් වූ පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙය වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තම දිගුකාලීන රාජ්‍ය සිහිනය සැබෑ කර ඇත. මෙම දේශපාලන ජයග්‍රහණයේ ඉලක්කය සපුරා ගැනීමට මැතිවරණ ඔහුට උදව් කළේ නැත. ඒ වෙනුවට ඊට නායකත්වය දුන්නේ ‘අභයභූමි’ අරගලයයි.",
        "තත්ත්වය මෙසේ වන බැවින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ඡන්ද විමසීම බදාදා පැවති බැවින් ඔහුට එරෙහිව මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ අනුකුමාර දිසානායක මහතා එදින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණ ඇත.",
        "\"කෝ තුවක්කු දෙක\" ජනාධිපති රනිල් ඇසුවේය. අනුර පිළිතුරු දුන්නේ කුඩා දම්වැල් කියතකින් තුවක්කුවකි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පෙළපාලියේදී හමුදාවෙන් කලවාඩියට ගියොත් ඒ තුවක්කු ඉල්ලනවා යැයි ජනපති රනිල් කී බවත් විහිලුවට ලක් නොකර ඒවා රැගෙන ගිය අයගෙන් අසන්න බවත් අනුර කීවේය. හැකි ඉක්මනින් හමුදාවට බාර දුන්නට කමක් නැහැ යැයි කියමින් ජනපති රනිල් එතැනින් පිටත් විය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේ පසුදා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති කාර්යාල පිහිටි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 2 වැනි මහලේ දී ය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට පක්ෂ නායකයින් රැසක්ද එක්ව සිටියා. ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව සුබපැතුම් එක් කළ පක්ෂ නායකයින් හමුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් කඩිනමින් පිහිටුවීමට කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතරවාරයේ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ මම ඔබට ‘ඇතිමැදකු’ නොකියන බවයි. එහෙම කතා කරන්න එපා කියලා ඔබතුමා සඳහන් කළා යැයි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට කීවේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා පිළිතුරු දුන්නේ ‘‘මම අතිමෙතකු කියන වචනය තහනම් කළා. ඉතින් ඒ වචනය පාවිච්චි කළොත් දඩුවම් කරනවා යැයි ඔහු සිනාමුසු මුහුණින් පැවසීය. විපක්‍ෂ නායකතුමා ඇතුළු අසල සිටි පිරිස නිහඬ සිනහවකින් මුව සරසා ගත්හ.",
        "මේ සිදුවීම් දෙකේදීම දැනෙන්නේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිවිපාකයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් ලබාදී ඇති විධායක බලය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම භාවිත කළ හැක්කේ රනිල් ජනාධිපතිවරයාටය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු 19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අහෝසි කර විධායක බලය යළි ලබා ගත් නමුත් එම බලයෙන් මාධ්‍යයට ප්‍රයෝජන ගැනීමට නොහැකි විය.",
        "අනෙක් අතට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ තමන් ලබාගත් සම්පූර්ණ විධායක බලය පවරා දී රටින් පැන ගියේය.",
        "අද විධායක ජනාධිපති ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බලයේ සිටී. Play the Game But Follow the Rules (Play the Game But Follow the Rules) හිටපු ජනාධිපති ජේ.ආර්. මෙම පාඨය ජයවර්ධනගේ දේශපාලන ඉගැන්වීමයි.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බලයට පැමිණ ඇත්තේ වසර ගණනාවක් බලා සිටීමෙන් පසුවය. ලෝක් සභාව හමුවේ කිසිවක් කළ නොහැකි වුවත් කෙටි කලක් පාලනය අනුගමනය කළ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ දේශපාලන ගේම් දක්නට ලැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "134 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලවාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂයේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.ආර්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "களவாடிய துப்பாக்கிகள் எங்கே ? ஜே.வி.பி.யின் தலைவரை கேட்ட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தேசிய அரசியலில் ஏற்படும் மாற்றங்களையும் சம்பவங்களையும் அவதானிக்கையில் எப்போதுமே ஒரு சஞ்சலத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவதாகவே உள்ளது.",
        "அதுவும் வெறும் 134 வாக்குளால் ஒருவர் ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார் என்றால் இலங்கையில் மாத்திரம் அல்ல உலக அரசியல் வரலாற்றிலேயே இதுவே முதற்தடவையாகும்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் தனது நீண்டகால சிம்மாசன கனவை ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நனவாக்கியுள்ளார். இந்த அரசியல் வெற்றி இலக்கை அடைவதற்கு அவருக்கு தேர்தல்கள் கைகொடுக்கவில்லை. மாறாக 'அரகலய' போராட்டமே வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "நிலைமை இவ்வாறு இருக்க, ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவுக்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு புதன்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற நிலையில் அன்றைய தினம் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் செல்லகையில் மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் (ஜே.வி.பி) அநுகுமார திசாநாயக்க எதிரே வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "'இரு துப்பாக்கிகளும் எங்கே' என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் கேட்டுள்ளார். சிறு சஞ்சலத்துடன் எந்த துப்பாக்கிகள் என இதன்போது அநுர பதிலளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது இராணுவத்திடமிருந்து களவாடி சென்றீர்களே அந்த துப்பாக்கிகளை தான் கேட்கிறேன் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் குறிப்பிடவே, கேலி செய்யாது எடுத்துச் சென்றவர்களிடம் கேளுங்கள் என அநுர கூறியுள்ளார். பரவாயில்லை கூடிய விரைவில் இராணுவத்திடம் ஒப்படைத்து விடுங்கள் என கூறியவாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் அங்கிருந்து சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "மறுநாள் வியாழக்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தின் 2 ஆவது மாடியில் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் அலுவலகங்கள் அமைந்துள்ள பகுதியில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதி பதவிப்பிரமாணம்  செய்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் கட்சி தலைவர்கள் பலரும் கலந்துகொண்டிருந்தனர். பதவிப்பிரமாணத்தின் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு வாழ்த்து கூறிய கட்சி தலைவர்களிடம் கூடிய விரைவில் சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதாக ஜனாதிபதி குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன் போது எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, 'அதிமேதகு' என உங்களை அழைக்க மாட்டேன். ஏனெனில் அவ்வாறு அழைக்க வேண்டாமென நீங்கள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கு பதிலளித்த ஜனாதிபதி, 'அதிமேதகு' என்ற சொல்லுக்கு தடைவிதித்துள்ளேன். எனவே அந்த சொல்லை பயன்படுத்தினால் தண்டனையை அனுபவிக்க நேரிடும் என புன்னகையுடன் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் உட்பட அருகில் இருந்தவர்கள் மௌனித்த புன்னகையுடன் இருந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த இரு சம்பவங்களிலுமே ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசியல் பிரதிப்பலிப்புகளை உணர முடிகின்றன.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பில் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரத்தை முழுமையாக பயன்படுத்த கூடியவராகவே ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் தற்போதுள்ளார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் 19 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பை நீக்கி மீண்டும் நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரத்தை தன்னகப்படுத்திய போதிலும் அந்த அதிகாரத்தின் ஊடக பயன்பெற முடியாது போனது.",
        "மறுபுறம் தன்னகப்படுத்திய முழுமையான நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரத்தை ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கையளித்து விட்டு நாட்டை விட்டே தப்பிச்சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரமிக்க ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று  பதவியில் உள்ளார்.  விளையாடு ஆனால் விதியை பின்பற்று ( Play the Game But Follow the Rules) என்பது முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஜே.ஆர். ஜயவர்தனவின் அரசியல் போதனையாகவே இந்த வாசகம் உள்ளது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பல ஆண்டுக்கால காத்திருப்பின் பின்னர் அதிகாரத்தை அடைந்துள்ளார். மக்களாணைக்கு முன் எதுவும் சாத்தியமில்லை என்றாலும் குறுகிய காலத்திற்கேனும் விதியை பின்பற்றிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசியல் விளையாட்டுக்களை காண கூடியதாக இருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் 134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலவாடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}