{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/main_picture/අරලියගහ-මැදුරත්-වනසති:තැන-තැන-ගුල්-හාරති/11-616285",
  "time_ut": 1657604430,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අරලියගහ මැදුරත් වනසති:තැන තැන ගුල් හාරති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The temple tree is also wild: it digs holes everywhere",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Agramatya Media Unit has complained to the Kollupitiya Police that the equipment from the media section of the Araliyagaha Mandir has been stolen.",
        "According to the Prime Minister's Media Division, two laptops, a video camera and other camera equipment were stolen from the media department.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe did not move to Araliyagaha Mandir after assuming the office of Prime Minister and only a part of the Prime Minister's Media Unit was established in a building in Araliyagaha Mandir premises.",
        "The Prime Minister's Media Unit states that these equipments have been lost after the activists entered the temple building on the 9th.",
        "The Prime Minister's Media Unit also mentions that holes have been dug between the walls of the Araliyagaha Mandir, door locks have been broken and documents have been destroyed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Agramatya Media Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kollupitiya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Araliyagaha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Araliyagaha Mandir",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Araliyagaha Mandir",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Araliyagaha Mandir",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරලියගහ මැදුරත් වනසති:තැන තැන ගුල් හාරති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ තිබූ උපකරණ සොරාගෙන ගොස් ඇතැයි අග්‍රමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය කොල්ලුපිටිය පොලිසියට පැමිණිලි කර තිබේ.",
        "මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ තිබූ ලැප්ටොප් දෙකක් වීඩියෝ කැමරාවක් හා තවත් කැමරා උපකරණ මෙලෙස සොරාගෙන ගොස් ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ පදිංචියට නොගිය අතර අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය ඒකකයේ කොටසක් පමණක් අරලියගහ මන්දිර පරිශ්‍රයෙහි ගොඩනැගිල්ලක ස්ථාපිත කෙරිණි.",
        "ඉකුත් නව වැනි දා අරගලකරුවන් අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට ඇතුළත් වීමෙන් පසුව මෙම උපකරණ නැති වී ඇතැයි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ බිත්ති අතර ගුල් හාරා ඇතැයි ද දොර අගුළු කඩා දමා ලියකියවිලි විනාශ කර ඇතැයි ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අග්‍රමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோவில் மரமும் காடு: எங்கும் குழி தோண்டுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அராலியகஹா மன்றின் ஊடகப் பிரிவில் இருந்த உபகரணங்கள் திருடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அக்ரமத்ய ஊடகப் பிரிவு கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊடகப் பிரிவில் இருந்து இரண்டு மடிக்கணினிகள், வீடியோ கமரா மற்றும் ஏனைய கமரா உபகரணங்கள் திருடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அவர்கள் பிரதமராக பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் அரலியகஹா மன்றத்திற்கு செல்லவில்லை, மேலும் பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவின் ஒரு பகுதி மாத்திரமே அராலியக மந்திர் வளாகத்தில் உள்ள கட்டிடத்தில் நிறுவப்பட்டது.",
        "கடந்த 9ஆம் திகதி ஆலய கட்டிடத்திற்குள் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் பிரவேசித்ததன் பின்னர் இந்த உபகரணங்கள் காணாமல் போயுள்ளதாக பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அரலியகஹா மந்திரின் சுவர்களுக்கு இடையில் குழி தோண்டப்பட்டு கதவு பூட்டுகள் உடைக்கப்பட்டு ஆவணங்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு குறிப்பிடுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்ரமத்யா ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரலியகஹா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரலியகஹா மந்திர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரலியகஹா மந்திர்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரலியகஹா மந்திர்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}