{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/U-S-rejects-GRs-visa-request-after-recent-ousting-by-mass-protests/108-240923",
  "time_ut": 1657631834,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "U.S. ‘rejects’ GR’s visa request after recent ousting by mass protests",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "U.S. ‘rejects’ GR’s visa request after recent ousting by mass protests",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United States rejected Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s recent request for a visa,  The Hindu learns from a top official, amid growing speculation over the besieged leader’s “attempts to flee” the country after promising to quit office.",
        "Mr. Gotabaya, formerly a dual citizen of Sri Lanka and the U.S., gave up his American citizenship ahead of the 2019 elections because of a law that barred foreign nationals from running for the presidency. He won the election with a thumping majority but became, arguably, the country’s most unpopular leader mid-term, amid a severe economic meltdown that is stifling citizens.",
        "“He sought a safe passage to the U.S. after the recent events, but it was denied,” the Colombo-based official said on Tuesday. Mr. Gotabaya’s reported attempt to leave the island follows his decision to resign, prompted by a sensational citizens’ protest on Saturday. Resisting his failed response to the unprecedented economic crisis gripping the island, a wave of protesters stormed the Presidential Secretariat and residence in Colombo in a dramatic escalation of months-long protests demanding that Mr. Gotabaya “go home”.  He was evacuated from his official residence hours before the incident, officials said. However, his whereabouts remain unknown since.",
        "The Hindu sought a comment from the American Embassy in Colombo but is yet to receive a response. In a statement on Sunday, American Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung called upon all parties “to cooperate to achieve a peaceful, democratic transition of power”. It signalled a clear shift from the U.S.’s position just a month ago, when President Gotabaya appointed PM Ranil Wickremesinghe as Premier, disregarding widespread citizens’ agitations, to prolong the life of his government that a majority of Sri Lankans had deemed untenable. “Look forward to working w/ @RW_UNP. His appointment as PM, and the quick formation of an inclusive government, are first steps to addressing the crisis & promoting stability. We encourage meaningful progress at the IMF & long-term solutions that meet the needs of all Sri Lankans,” the Ambassador said in a tweet on May 12. (The Hindu)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "U.S.",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the American Embassy in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just a month ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහජන විරෝධතා මගින් මෑතදී නෙරපා හැරීමෙන් පසු එක්සත් ජනපදය GR ගේ වීසා ඉල්ලීම 'ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි'",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ මෑතදී වීසා බලපත්‍රයක් සඳහා කරන ලද ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය,  ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට පොරොන්දු වීමෙන් පසු වටලනු ලැබූ නායකයාගේ “පලායාමට උත්සාහ කිරීම” පිළිබඳ වැඩෙන සමපේක්ෂන මධ්‍යයේ, ඉහළ නිලධාරියෙකුගෙන් ද හින්දු පුවත්පතට දැනගන්නට ලැබුණි.",
        "කලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ද්විත්ව පුරවැසියෙකු වූ ගෝඨාභය මහතා, 2019 මැතිවරණයට පෙර ඔහුගේ ඇමරිකානු පුරවැසිභාවය අත්හැරියේ විදේශ ජාතිකයින්ට ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වයට තරඟ කිරීම තහනම් කරන නීතියක් නිසාය. ඔහු අති විශාල බහුතරයකින් මැතිවරණය ජයග්‍රහණය කළ නමුත්, රටවැසියන් හිරකරමින් සිටින දරුණු ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීමක් මධ්‍යයේ, මධ්‍යකාලීනව රටේ වඩාත්ම ජනප්‍රිය නොවන නායකයා බවට පත් විය.",
        "\"මෑත සිදුවීම් වලින් පසු ඔහු එක්සත් ජනපදයට ආරක්ෂිත මාර්ගයක් සෙවූ නමුත් එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප විය,\" කොළඹ පදනම් වූ නිලධාරියා අඟහරුවාදා පැවසීය. ගෝඨාභය මහතා දිවයිනෙන් පිටව යාමට ගත් උත්සාහය සෙනසුරාදා ආන්දෝලනාත්මක පුරවැසියන්ගේ විරෝධතාවක් හේතුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ගත් තීරණයෙන් පසුව වාර්තා වේ. දිවයිනේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට ඔහුගේ අසාර්ථක ප්‍රතිචාරයට එරෙහි වෙමින්, ගෝඨාභය මහතාට “ගෙදර යන්න” යැයි බල කරමින් මාස ගණනාවක් පුරා පැවති විරෝධතා නාටකාකාර ලෙස උත්සන්න කරමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් රැල්ලක් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට සහ කොළඹ නිවසට කඩා වැදුණි. සිද්ධියට පැය කිහිපයකට පෙර ඔහු සිය නිල නිවසින් ඉවත් කළ බව නිලධාරීහු පවසති. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එතැන් සිට ඔහු සිටින ස්ථානය තවමත් නොදනී.",
        "හින්දු පුවත්පත මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ ඇමරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලයෙන් අදහස් විමසූ නමුත් තවමත් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබී නොමැත. ඉරිදා ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් සියලු පාර්ශවයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ \"සාමකාමී, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී බල සංක්‍රාන්තියක් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස\" ය. ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් බහුතරයක් විසින් දරාගත නොහැකි යැයි සැලකූ තම ආන්ඩුවේ ආයු කාලය දීර්ඝ කිරීම සඳහා පුලුල්ව පැතිරුනු පුරවැසි උද්ඝෝෂණ නොසලකා හරිමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය විසින් අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අගමැති ලෙස පත්කිරීමෙන් මාසයකට පෙර එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ස්ථාවරයෙන් පැහැදිලි වෙනසක් එය සංඥා කලේය. \"@RW_UNP සමග වැඩ කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන්න. ඔහු අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කිරීම සහ සියල්ලන් ඇතුළත් රජයක් ඉක්මනින් පිහිටුවීම, අර්බුදය විසඳීමට සහ ස්ථාවරත්වය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ පළමු පියවරයි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ අර්ථවත් ප්‍රගතිය සහ සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලන දිගු කාලීන විසඳුම් අපි දිරිමත් කරමු,” තානාපතිවරයා මැයි 12 දා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පැවසීය. (ද හින්දු)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස-දිග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ඇමරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට පමණ පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புகளால் சமீபத்தில் வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட GR இன் விசா கோரிக்கையை அமெரிக்கா ‘நிராகரித்தது’",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தபய ராஜபக்சேவின் விசாவிற்கான சமீபத்திய கோரிக்கையை அமெரிக்கா நிராகரித்தது,  முற்றுகையிடப்பட்ட தலைவரின் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக உறுதியளித்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறும் \"தப்பிவிட முயற்சிகள்\" பற்றிய ஊகங்கள் அதிகரித்து வரும் நிலையில், உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவரிடமிருந்து தி ஹிந்து அறிந்து கொள்கிறது.",
        "முன்னர் இலங்கை மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவின் இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமை பெற்ற திரு. கோத்தபய, 2019 தேர்தலுக்கு முன்னதாக, வெளிநாட்டுப் பிரஜைகள் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதைத் தடுக்கும் சட்டத்தின் காரணமாக தனது அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமையை கைவிட்டார். அவர் பெரும்பான்மையுடன் தேர்தலில் வெற்றி பெற்றார், ஆனால் குடிமக்களை திணறடிக்கும் கடுமையான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சிக்கு மத்தியில், நாட்டின் மிகவும் செல்வாக்கற்ற தலைவராக இடைக்காலமாக ஆனார்.",
        "\"சமீபத்திய நிகழ்வுகளுக்குப் பிறகு அவர் அமெரிக்காவிற்கு பாதுகாப்பான பாதையை நாடினார், ஆனால் அது மறுக்கப்பட்டது\" என்று கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட அதிகாரி செவ்வாயன்று கூறினார். சனிக்கிழமையன்று பரபரப்பான குடிமக்களின் எதிர்ப்பால் தூண்டப்பட்ட அவரது ராஜினாமா முடிவைத் தொடர்ந்து திரு. கோட்டாபய தீவை விட்டு வெளியேற முயற்சித்ததாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. தீவில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு அவரது தோல்வியுற்ற பதிலை எதிர்த்து, கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் இல்லத்தை முற்றுகையிட்ட போராட்டக்காரர்கள், திரு. கோட்டாபயவை \"வீட்டிற்குச் செல்ல வேண்டும்\" என்று கோரி பல மாதங்களாக நீடித்த போராட்டங்கள் வியத்தகு முறையில் அதிகரித்தன. சம்பவத்திற்கு சில மணி நேரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் அவர் தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்திலிருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்டதாக அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர். இருப்பினும், அவர் எங்கிருக்கிறார் என்பது தெரியவில்லை.",
        "தி இந்து கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க தூதரகத்திடம் கருத்து கேட்டது ஆனால் இன்னும் பதில் கிடைக்கவில்லை. ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஒரு அறிக்கையில், இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங், \"அமைதியான, ஜனநாயக முறையிலான அதிகார மாற்றத்தை அடைய ஒத்துழைக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று அனைத்துத் தரப்பினருக்கும் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார். ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்னர், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக நியமித்தபோது, ​​பரந்த குடிமக்களின் கிளர்ச்சிகளைப் புறக்கணித்து, தனது அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆயுளை நீடிக்க, பெரும்பான்மையான இலங்கையர்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாததாகக் கருதிய போது, ​​அமெரிக்காவின் நிலைப்பாட்டில் இருந்து தெளிவான மாற்றத்தை இது சமிக்ஞை செய்தது. @RW_UNP உடன் பணிபுரிய எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம். பிரதமராக அவர் நியமனம், மற்றும் அனைவரையும் உள்ளடக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை விரைவாக உருவாக்குவது ஆகியவை நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிப்பதற்கும் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் முதல் படிகளாகும். சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தில் அர்த்தமுள்ள முன்னேற்றம் மற்றும் அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களின் தேவைகளையும் பூர்த்தி செய்யும் நீண்ட கால தீர்வுகளை நாங்கள் ஊக்குவிக்கிறோம்,” என்று தூதுவர் மே 12 அன்று ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் கூறினார். (தி இந்து)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள் நீடித்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}