{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/All-time-record-price-for-Dunsinane-Estate/34-738032",
  "time_ut": 1659037165,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All-time record price for Dunsinane Estate",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All-time record price for Dunsinane Estate",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dunsinane Estate, which comes under the purview of Elpitiya Plantations, and situated in Pundaluoya achieved an all-time record price of Rs. 1,180 per kg for BPS grade in the CTC High Grown Category at the weekly tea auction held on 26 July.",
        "This line of tea was purchased by Akbar Brothers Ltd. and was marketed and sold by tea broker John Keells."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dunsinane Estate",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Elpitiya Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pundaluoya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Akbar Brothers Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩන්සිනාන් වතුයායේ සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇල්පිටිය වැවිලි සමාගමට අයත් පුණ්ඩළුඔය ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ඩන්සිනාන් වතුයාය සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 26 වෙනිදා පැවති සතිපතා තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී CTC High Grown කාණ්ඩයේ BPS ශ්‍රේණිය සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 1,180 කි.",
        "මෙම තේ පෙළ සීමාසහිත අක්බාර් බ්‍රදර්ස් විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති අතර තේ තැරැව්කරු ජෝන් කීල්ස් විසින් අලෙවි කර අලෙවි කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩන්සිනාන් වත්ත",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇල්පිටිය වැවිලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pundaluoya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අක්බාර් බ්‍රදර්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டன்சினேன் தோட்டத்திற்கான அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எல்பிட்டிய பிளான்டேஷன்ஸின் கீழ் வரும் டன்சினேன் தோட்டம், பூண்டலுஓயாவில் அமைந்துள்ள அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையாக ரூ. ஜூலை 26 அன்று நடைபெற்ற வாராந்திர தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் CTC உயர் வளர்ச்சி பிரிவில் பிபிஎஸ் தரத்திற்கு ஒரு கிலோ ரூ.1,180.",
        "இந்த தேயிலை அக்பர் பிரதர்ஸ் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் தேயிலை தரகர் ஜான் கீல்ஸால் சந்தைப்படுத்தப்பட்டு விற்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டன்சினேன் எஸ்டேட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்பிட்டிய தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pundaluoya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்பர் பிரதர்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}