{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84011/india-reports-its-first-monkeypox-death",
  "time_ut": 1659325980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India reports its first Monkeypox death",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India reports its first Monkeypox death",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As monkeypox cases continue to spread across the world, India has now reported its first death linked to the viral zoonotic infection.",
        "A 22-year-old youth with monkeypox symptoms passed away in Kerala’s Thrissur district after travelling from a middle eastern country. The state administration has announced its intention to undertake a high-level inquiry to look into the case.",
        "Following his death, the state health department had called a meeting in Punnayur and a contact list and route map of the deceased youth were prepared. The health department has traced and contacted people he had been in touch with after his arrival in India, to isolate and monitor them.",
        "The Kerala youth who died in Thrissur on Saturday had tested positive for monkeypox abroad, state Health Minister Veena George said on Sunday.",
        "The 22-year-old youth, a native of Punniyoor in Thrissur, died at a private hospital in Thrissur, days after he returned from the UAE.",
        "The state government said that while the results of the test done in the UAE confirmed the presence of the monkeypox virus, a probe would be conducted to ascertain the cause of death.",
        "“The youth had no symptoms of monkeypox. He had been admitted to a hospital with symptoms of encephalitis and fatigue. His relatives handed over the test result only on Saturday. A high-level probe would be held into the death as monkeypox has a very low fatality rate,’’ said the minister.",
        "The state health department has sent his samples to the National Institute of Virology’s Alappuzha unit in Kerala.",
        "Sources in the health department said the youth, who was employed at Ras al-Khaimah in the UAE, reached Kozhikode airport in Kerala on July 22. “He had been active after reaching home. He played football at a local ground. On July 26, he developed a fever and sought treatment at a local hospital, Later, he was shifted to another hospital, where he was put on life support. He said he had got tested in the UAE before boarding the flight to Kerala. After his death, we came to know that he was told to take rest after reaching home. Until Saturday, the family was not keen on taking up the matter with the health department or the local village panchayat,” sources said.",
        "After the youth died Saturday afternoon, his burial was held as per the protocol for the disease. All his primary contacts have been put under observation.",
        "India has so far had four confirmed monkeypox cases, three of them in Kerala. The patient who had the first reported case was discharge from hospital on Saturday.",
        "Spain on Saturday reported a second death from monkeypox in as many days. These are believed to be the first confirmed monkeypox fatalities in Europe since its recent spread beyond Africa.",
        "The monkeypox outbreak has seen more than 22,000 cases in nearly 80 countries since May. There have been 75 suspected deaths in Africa, mostly in Nigeria and Congo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Monkeypox",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thrissur",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the state health department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Punnayur",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thrissur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veena George",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thrissur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thrissur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Institute of Virology’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ras al-Khaimah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kozhikode",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Later",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "as many days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 22,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nigeria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව සිය පළමු වඳුරු මරණය වාර්තා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වඳුරු රෝග ලොව පුරා ව්‍යාප්ත වෙමින් පවතින අතර, ඉන්දියාව දැන් වෛරස් zoonotic ආසාදනයට සම්බන්ධ එහි පළමු මරණය වාර්තා කර ඇත.",
        "වඳුරු රෝග ලක්ෂණ සහිත 22 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකු මැද පෙරදිග රටක සිට සංචාරය කිරීමෙන් පසු කේරළයේ ත්‍රිසූර් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ දී මිය ගියේය. සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බැලීම සඳහා ඉහළ මට්ටමේ පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්වීමට රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලනය සිය අභිප්‍රාය ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහුගේ මරණයෙන් පසු ප්‍රාන්ත සෞඛ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පුන්නයුර් හි රැස්වීමක් කැඳවා ඇති අතර මියගිය තරුණයාගේ සම්බන්ධතා ලැයිස්තුවක් සහ මාර්ග සිතියමක් සකස් කර ඇත. ඔහු ඉන්දියාවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඔහු සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වී සිටි පුද්ගලයින් හුදකලා කිරීමට සහ නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීමට සෞඛ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් සොයා ගෙන ඔවුන් සම්බන්ධ කර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා ත්‍රිසූර්හිදී මියගිය කේරළ තරුණයා විදේශයන්හි වඳුරු රෝගයට ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කර ඇති බව ප්‍රාන්ත සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය වීනා ජෝර්ජ් ඉරිදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ත්‍රිසූර් හි පුන්නියූර් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 22 හැවිරිදි තරුණයා එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේ සිට ආපසු පැමිණ දින කිහිපයකට පසු ත්‍රිසූර් හි පෞද්ගලික රෝහලකදී මිය ගියේය.",
        "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේ සිදුකළ පරීක්ෂණයේ ප්‍රතිඵල අනුව වඳුරු වයිරසය පවතින බව තහවුරු වී ඇති අතර මරණයට හේතුව සොයා බැලීම සඳහා පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බව ප්‍රාන්ත රජය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“තරුණයන්ට වඳුරු රෝග ලක්ෂණ තිබුණේ නැහැ. එන්සෙෆලයිටිස් සහ තෙහෙට්ටුව වැනි රෝග ලක්ෂණ සහිතව ඔහු රෝහලකට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත. ඔහුගේ ඥාතීන් පරීක්ෂණ ප්‍රතිඵලය ලබා දුන්නේ සෙනසුරාදා දිනයේදීය. වඳුරු මරණ අනුපාතය ඉතා අඩු බැවින් මෙම මරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉහළ මට්ටමේ පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වනු ලබන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රාන්ත සෞඛ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඔහුගේ සාම්පල කේරළයේ ජාතික වෛරස් විද්‍යා ආයතනයේ ඇලප්පුසා ඒකකය වෙත යවා ඇත.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග පැවසුවේ එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේ රාස් අල්-කයිමා හි සේවයේ නියුතු තරුණයා ජූලි 22 වන දින කේරළයේ කොස්කෝඩ් ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත ළඟා වූ බවයි. ඔහු ප්‍රාදේශීය පිටියක පාපන්දු ක්‍රීඩා කළේය. ජූලි 26 වන දින ඔහුට උණ වැළඳී ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහලකින් ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා ගත් අතර පසුව ඔහු වෙනත් රෝහලකට ගෙන යන ලද අතර එහිදී ඔහුට ජීවිත ආධාරකයක් ලබා දෙන ලදී. කේරළයට යන ගුවන් යානයට ගොඩවීමට පෙර තමා එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේදී පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය. ඔහුගේ මරණයෙන් පසු නිවසට පැමිණි පසු විවේක ගන්නා ලෙස ඔහුට දැනුම් දුන් බව අපට දැනගන්නට ලැබිණි. සෙනසුරාදා වන තුරු, පවුලේ අය සෞඛ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හෝ ප්‍රාදේශීය ගම් පංචායතනය සමඟ ප්‍රශ්නය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට උනන්දු වූයේ නැත.",
        "තරුණයා සෙනසුරාදා පස්වරුවේ මිය ගිය පසු, ඔහුගේ භූමදානය රෝගය සඳහා වූ ප්‍රොටෝකෝලය අනුව සිදු කරන ලදී. ඔහුගේ ප්‍රාථමික සම්බන්ධතා සියල්ල නිරීක්ෂණයට ලක්කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දියාව මේ වන විට තහවුරු කර ඇති වඳුරු රෝග හතරක් වාර්තා වී ඇති අතර ඉන් තුනක් කේරළයේ වේ. පළමු නඩුව වාර්තා වූ රෝගියා සෙනසුරාදා රෝහලෙන් පිටව ගියේය.",
        "ස්පාඤ්ඤය සෙනසුරාදා දින කිහිපයක් තුළ වඳුරු උවදුරෙන් දෙවන මරණය වාර්තා කළේය. මෑතදී අප්‍රිකාවෙන් ඔබ්බට ව්‍යාප්ත වීමෙන් පසු යුරෝපයේ සිදු වූ පළමු වඳුරු මරණ සංඛ්‍යාව මෙය බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "වඳුරු වසංගතය මැයි මාසයේ සිට රටවල් 80 කට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක 22,000 කට වඩා වැඩි සංඛ්‍යාවක් දැක තිබේ. අප්‍රිකාවේ, වැඩි වශයෙන් නයිජීරියාවේ සහ කොංගෝවේ, සැක සහිත මරණ 75ක් වාර්තා වී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වඳුරු උවදුර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිසූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සෞඛ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුන්නයුර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිසූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීනා ජෝර්ජ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිසූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිසූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික වෛරස් විද්‍යා ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාස් අල්-කයිමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොසිකෝඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින ගණනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22,000 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයිජීරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංගෝව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவில் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலுக்கு முதல் மரணம் பதிவாகியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உலகம் முழுவதும் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலின் பாதிப்புகள் தொடர்ந்து பரவி வரும் நிலையில், இந்தியாவில் தற்போது வைரஸ் ஜூனோடிக் நோய்த்தொற்றுடன் தொடர்புடைய முதல் மரணம் பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "கேரளாவின் திருச்சூர் மாவட்டத்தில் மத்திய கிழக்கு நாட்டிலிருந்து பயணம் செய்த 22 வயது இளைஞர் குரங்கு பாக்ஸ் அறிகுறிகளுடன் காலமானார். இந்த வழக்கை விசாரிக்க உயர்மட்ட விசாரணையை மேற்கொள்ள உள்ளதாக மாநில நிர்வாகம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அவரது மரணத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, மாநில சுகாதாரத் துறை புன்னயூரில் கூட்டத்தை கூட்டி, இறந்த இளைஞரின் தொடர்பு பட்டியல் மற்றும் வழி வரைபடம் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டது. அவர் இந்தியா வந்த பிறகு அவர்களுடன் தொடர்பில் இருந்தவர்களை சுகாதாரத் துறை கண்டறிந்து தொடர்பு கொண்டு அவர்களை தனிமைப்படுத்தவும் கண்காணிக்கவும் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "திருச்சூரில் சனிக்கிழமை உயிரிழந்த கேரள இளைஞருக்கு வெளிநாட்டில் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் பாதிப்பு இருப்பது உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அம்மாநில சுகாதாரத்துறை அமைச்சர் வீனா ஜார்ஜ் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திருச்சூரில் உள்ள புண்ணியூரைச் சேர்ந்த 22 வயது இளைஞர், ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸில் இருந்து திரும்பிய சில நாட்களில் திருச்சூரில் உள்ள தனியார் மருத்துவமனையில் உயிரிழந்தார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸில் நடத்தப்பட்ட சோதனையின் முடிவுகள் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருப்பது உறுதிசெய்யப்பட்ட நிலையில், இறப்புக்கான காரணத்தைக் கண்டறிய விசாரணை நடத்தப்படும் என்று மாநில அரசு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“இளைஞருக்கு குரங்கு காய்ச்சலின் அறிகுறிகள் எதுவும் இல்லை. அவர் மூளைக்காய்ச்சல் மற்றும் சோர்வு அறிகுறிகளுடன் மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார். அவரது உறவினர்கள் பரிசோதனை முடிவை சனிக்கிழமை மட்டுமே அளித்தனர். குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் இறப்பு விகிதம் மிகக் குறைவு என்பதால், இந்த மரணம் குறித்து உயர்மட்ட விசாரணை நடத்தப்படும்,'' என்றார்.",
        "மாநில சுகாதாரத் துறை அவரது மாதிரிகளை கேரளாவில் உள்ள தேசிய வைராலஜி நிறுவனத்தின் ஆலப்புழா பிரிவுக்கு அனுப்பியுள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸில் உள்ள ராஸ் அல்-கைமாவில் பணிபுரியும் இளைஞர் ஜூலை 22 அன்று கேரளாவின் கோழிக்கோடு விமான நிலையத்தை அடைந்ததாக சுகாதாரத் துறை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. “அவர் வீட்டிற்கு வந்த பிறகு சுறுசுறுப்பாக இருந்தார். உள்ளூர் மைதானத்தில் கால்பந்து விளையாடினார். ஜூலை 26 அன்று, அவருக்கு காய்ச்சல் ஏற்பட்டது மற்றும் உள்ளூர் மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்றார், பின்னர், அவர் வேறு மருத்துவமனைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டார், அங்கு அவருக்கு உயிர் ஆதரவு வைக்கப்பட்டது. கேரளாவிற்கு விமானத்தில் ஏறுவதற்கு முன்பு ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸில் சோதனை செய்யப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார். அவர் இறந்த பிறகு, வீட்டிற்கு வந்த பிறகு ஓய்வெடுக்கச் சொன்னார்கள் என்று எங்களுக்குத் தெரியும். சனிக்கிழமை வரை, சுகாதாரத் துறையிலோ அல்லது உள்ளூர் கிராம பஞ்சாயத்திலோ இந்த விஷயத்தை எடுத்துச் செல்வதில் குடும்பத்தினர் ஆர்வம் காட்டவில்லை” என்று வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் இளைஞர் இறந்த பிறகு, நோய்க்கான நெறிமுறையின்படி அவரது அடக்கம் நடைபெற்றது. அவரது முக்கிய தொடர்புகள் அனைத்தும் கண்காணிப்பில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இந்தியாவில் இதுவரை நான்கு குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், அவற்றில் மூன்று கேரளாவில் உள்ளன. முதலில் பதிவாகிய நோயாளி சனிக்கிழமை மருத்துவமனையில் இருந்து டிஸ்சார்ஜ் செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஸ்பெயினில் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட சில நாட்களில் இரண்டாவது மரணம் சனிக்கிழமை பதிவாகியுள்ளது. சமீபத்தில் ஆப்பிரிக்காவிற்கு அப்பால் பரவியதில் இருந்து ஐரோப்பாவில் குரங்கு காய்ச்சலால் ஏற்பட்ட முதல் மரணங்கள் இவை என்று நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "குரங்கு பாக்ஸ் வெடிப்பு மே மாதத்திலிருந்து கிட்டத்தட்ட 80 நாடுகளில் 22,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வழக்குகளைக் கண்டுள்ளது. ஆப்பிரிக்காவில் 75 சந்தேக மரணங்கள் உள்ளன, பெரும்பாலும் நைஜீரியா மற்றும் காங்கோவில்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "குரங்கு நோய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில சுகாதார துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புன்னயூர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீணா ஜார்ஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய வைராலஜி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஸ் அல்-கைமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோழிக்கோடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பெயின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நைஜீரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}