{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Risk-of-new-COVID-variants-emerging-advised-to-get-4th-jab-Heath-experts/342-240403",
  "time_ut": 1657036158,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Risk of new COVID variants emerging; advised to get 4th jab Heath experts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Risk of new COVID variants emerging; advised to get 4th jab Heath experts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Emphasising that there is a risk of a new COVID-19 variant emerging among the people, Health Services Director aGeneral Dr. Asela Gunawardena said the best way to prevent infection from the virus is to get all four doses of the COVID-19 vaccine.",
        "Addressing the media at the Information Department today, he said the health ministry had requested the public to get the 4th COVID-19 jab after getting the first dose.",
        "At that time, the Ministry had provided the COVID-19 primary vaccine between 97% and 100% for people who were older than 20 years of age. The first dose of the vaccine was received by 7.9 million people. We have asked people to get the fourth vaccine as well.",
        "Obtaining all four vaccine doses will result in minimised risk of contracting the virus, the seriousness of the virus if contracted and will reduce the mortality rate.",
        "All individuals above 60 years of age and those who are seeking to travel overseas must obtain the vaccines. The vaccines can be obtained at all state hospitals, medical offices of health, and stipulated vaccination centres, Dr. Gunawardena said.",
        "Meanwhile, addressing the media, Chief Epidemiologist Dr. Samitha Ginige said the risk of the coronavirus is still prevalent across the world. There is an increase in cases that has been witnessed during the past three weeks. Our country currently records around 10 COVID-19 patients daily and one virus related death weekly.",
        "Dr. Ginige said while school children have been urged to obtain the second vaccine, only a limited number of children have obtained them, adding that one million children between the ages of 12 and 15 have not got the vaccine.",
        "Furthermore, the Immunology and Molecular Medicine Department of the University of Sri Jayewardenepura Prof. Neelika Malavige said the Omicron variant of the coronavirus spread rapidly in January and February, adding the seriousness of the variant was not felt as a majority of the public had obtained at least two vaccinations.",
        "Prof. Malavige said a successful vaccination drive led to a drop in the spread of coronavirus. She said new variants emerge in countries, adding that the variant doesn’t spread owing to the increased immunity levels among populations. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "COVID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Health Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "aGeneral",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asela Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 97% and 100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "older than 20 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samitha Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 COVID-19",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "between the ages of 12 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Molecular Medicine Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura Prof.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Neelika Malavige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "January",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malavige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව COVID ප්‍රභේද මතු වීමේ අවදානම; 4th jab Heath විශේෂඥයින් ලබා ගැනීමට උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව කොවිඩ්-19 ප්‍රභේදයක් ජනතාව අතර මතුවීමේ අවදානමක් පවතින බව අවධාරණය කළ සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් වෛද්‍ය අසේල ගුණවර්ධන කියා සිටියේ වෛරසය ආසාදනය වීම වැළැක්වීමට ඇති හොඳම ක්‍රමය කොවිඩ්-19 එන්නත් මාත්‍රා හතරම ලබා ගැනීම බවයි.",
        "අද ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය අමතමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ පළමු මාත්‍රාව ලබා ගැනීමෙන් පසු 4 වන COVID-19 ජබ් එක ලබා ගන්නා ලෙස සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඒ වන විට අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් වයස අවුරුදු 20 ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා COVID-19 ප්‍රාථමික එන්නත 97% ත් 100% ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබා දී ඇත. එන්නතෙහි පළමු මාත්‍රාව මිලියන 7.9 ක ජනතාවක් විසින් ලබා ගන්නා ලදී. හතරවැනි එන්නතත් ගන්න කියලා අපි ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබෙනවා.",
        "එන්නත් මාත්‍රා හතරම ලබා ගැනීමෙන් වෛරසය වැළඳීමේ අවදානම අවම වන අතර, වෛරසය වැළඳුනහොත් එහි බරපතලකම සහ මරණ අනුපාතය අඩු වේ.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 60 ට වැඩි සියලුම පුද්ගලයින් සහ විදේශගත වීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අය එන්නත් ලබා ගත යුතුය. සියලුම රජයේ රෝහල්වලින්, සෞඛ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය කාර්යාලවලින් සහ නියමිත එන්නත් මධ්‍යස්ථානවලින් එන්නත් ලබා ගත හැකි බව වෛද්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර, මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රධාන වසංගත රෝග විද්‍යාඥ වෛද්‍ය සමිත ගිනිගේ කියා සිටියේ කොරෝනා වෛරසයේ අවදානම තවමත් ලොව පුරා පවතින බවයි. පසුගිය සති තුනක කාලය තුළ වාර්තා වූ නඩු වැඩි වීමක් දක්නට ලැබේ. අපේ රටේ දැනට දිනකට COVID-19 රෝගීන් 10 ක් පමණ වාර්තා වන අතර සතිපතා එක් වෛරසයක් ආශ්‍රිත මරණයක් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "දෙවන එන්නත ලබා ගන්නා ලෙස පාසල් සිසුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියද එය ලබාගෙන ඇත්තේ සීමිත ළමුන් සංඛ්‍යාවක් පමණක් බවත්, වයස අවුරුදු 12ත් 15ත් අතර ළමුන් ලක්ෂ 10කට එම එන්නත ලබාගෙන නොමැති බවත් වෛද්‍ය ගිනිගේ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණ හා අණුක වෛද්‍ය අංශයේ මහාචාර්ය නීලිකා මලවිගේ මහත්මිය පැවසුවේ, ජනවාරි සහ පෙබරවාරි මාසවලදී කොරෝනා වෛරසයේ Omicron ප්‍රභේදය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් ව්‍යාප්ත වූ බවත්, එම ප්‍රභේදයේ බරපතලකම මහජනතාවගෙන් බහුතරයකට දැනී නොතිබූ බවත්ය. අවම වශයෙන් එන්නත් දෙකක්.",
        "මහාචාර්ය මලවිගේ පැවසුවේ සාර්ථක එන්නත් කිරීමේ ව්‍යාපාරයක් කොරෝනා වයිරසයේ ව්‍යාප්තිය අඩුවීමට හේතු වූ බවයි. රටවල් තුළ නව ප්‍රභේද මතු වන බව පැවසූ ඇය, ජනගහනය අතර ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණ මට්ටම ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් එම ප්‍රභේදය ව්‍යාප්ත නොවන බව පැවසුවාය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොවිඩ්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාමාන්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසේල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "97% සහ 100% අතර",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 20 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 7.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 60 කි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමිත ගිනිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සති තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 COVID-19",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 12 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අණුක වෛද්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ මහාචාර්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීලිකා මලවිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මලවිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய கோவிட் மாறுபாடுகள் உருவாகும் அபாயம்; 4 வது ஜப் ஹீத் நிபுணர்களைப் பெற அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்கள் மத்தியில் புதிய COVID-19 மாறுபாடு உருவாகும் அபாயம் உள்ளது என்பதை வலியுறுத்திய சுகாதார சேவைகள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் டாக்டர் அசேல குணவர்தன, வைரஸிலிருந்து தொற்றுநோயைத் தடுப்பதற்கான சிறந்த வழி COVID-19 தடுப்பூசியின் நான்கு டோஸ்களையும் பெறுவதே என்றார்.",
        "இன்று தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த அவர், முதல் டோஸைப் பெற்ற பின்னர் 4 வது கோவிட்-19 ஜப் பெறுமாறு சுகாதார அமைச்சு பொதுமக்களிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில், அமைச்சகம் 20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்களுக்கு 97% முதல் 100% வரை COVID-19 முதன்மை தடுப்பூசியை வழங்கியது. தடுப்பூசியின் முதல் டோஸ் 7.9 மில்லியன் மக்களால் பெறப்பட்டது. நான்காவது தடுப்பூசியையும் பெறுமாறு மக்களைக் கேட்டுள்ளோம்.",
        "நான்கு தடுப்பூசி டோஸ்களையும் பெறுவது, வைரஸ் தொற்றும் அபாயத்தைக் குறைக்கும், சுருங்கினால் வைரஸின் தீவிரத்தன்மை மற்றும் இறப்பு விகிதத்தைக் குறைக்கும்.",
        "60 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட அனைத்து நபர்களும், வெளிநாடு செல்ல விரும்புபவர்களும் தடுப்பூசிகளைப் பெற வேண்டும். தடுப்பூசிகளை அனைத்து அரச மருத்துவமனைகள், சுகாதார மருத்துவ அலுவலகங்கள் மற்றும் நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட தடுப்பூசி மையங்களில் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியும் என டாக்டர் குணவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த பிரதம தொற்றுநோயியல் நிபுணர் டாக்டர் சமித்த கினிகே, கொரோனா வைரஸின் ஆபத்து இன்னும் உலகம் முழுவதும் பரவலாக உள்ளது. கடந்த மூன்று வாரங்களில் வழக்குகள் அதிகரித்துள்ளன. நம் நாட்டில் தற்போது தினசரி சுமார் 10 கோவிட்-19 நோயாளிகள் மற்றும் ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு ஒரு வைரஸ் தொடர்பான இறப்பு பதிவு செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "இரண்டாவது தடுப்பூசியைப் பெற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறு பாடசாலை மாணவர்களிடம் வலியுறுத்தப்பட்ட நிலையில், குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையிலான சிறுவர்களே அவற்றைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ளதாகவும், 12 முதல் 15 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட ஒரு மில்லியன் குழந்தைகளுக்கு தடுப்பூசி போடப்படவில்லை எனவும் டாக்டர் கினிகே தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் நோயெதிர்ப்பு மற்றும் மூலக்கூறு மருத்துவத் துறை பேராசிரியர் நீலிகா மாளவிகே கூறுகையில், ஜனவரி மற்றும் பெப்ரவரி மாதங்களில் கொரோனா வைரஸின் ஓமிக்ரான் மாறுபாடு வேகமாகப் பரவியது. குறைந்தது இரண்டு தடுப்பூசிகள்.",
        "வெற்றிகரமான தடுப்பூசி இயக்கம் கொரோனா வைரஸின் பரவல் குறைவதற்கு வழிவகுத்தது என்று பேராசிரியர் மாளவிகே கூறினார். நாடுகளில் புதிய மாறுபாடுகள் தோன்றுவதாகவும், மக்களிடையே நோய் எதிர்ப்பு சக்தி அதிகரிப்பதால் இந்த மாறுபாடு பரவுவதில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோவிட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பொது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசேல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தகவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "97% மற்றும் 100% இடையே",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமிதா கினிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கோவிட்-19",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 முதல் 15 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூலக்கூறு மருத்துவம் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழக பேராசிரியர்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீலிகா மாளவிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமிக்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாளவிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}