{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Stop-arrests-suppression-of-protesters-AKD-urges-Govt/108-241829",
  "time_ut": 1658856040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Stop arrests, suppression of protesters: AKD urges Govt.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Stop arrests, suppression of protesters: AKD urges Govt.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) today urged the government to stop arrests and suppression of Galle Face protesters.",
        "JVP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake told this to the media after a discussion with the representatives of the Galle Face protesters at the JVP head office in Pelawatte today.",
        "He said President Ranil Wickremesinghe got the armed forces to unleash a vehement attack on the protesters even though they had assured to hand over the Presidential Secretariat at 2.00 pm on the following day.",
        "He said the attack was carried out to please the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna MPs who voted Ranil to presidency. \"Even after the barbaric attack, there is a move to arrest the protesters making various allegations. The government has not realised the cause of the public protest which emerged due to various hardships and shortage in essential goods and services. The government is trying to hamper reasonable demands of the people through suppression,\" he said.",
        "Mr. Dissanayake said President Wickremesinghe was attempting to use suppressive laws and regulations such as emergency regulations to quell public protests and urged the government to stop such moves. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AKD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pelawatte",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the following day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම්, විරෝධතාකරුවන් මර්දනය කිරීම නවත්වන්න: AKD රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සහ මර්දනය කිරීම නතර කරන ලෙස ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ (ජවිපෙ) අද රජයට බලකර සිටියි.",
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා මේ බව කියා සිටියේ ගාලුමුවදොර විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත නියෝජිතයින් සමඟ පැලවත්ත ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේ අද පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකින් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින්.",
        "පසුදා පස්වරු 2.00 ට ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය භාර දෙන බවට සහතික වූවත් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට දැඩි ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කිරීමට ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව ලවා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ කටයුතු කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු කියා සිටියේ රනිල්ට ඡන්දය දුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සතුටු කිරීමට මෙම ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල කළ බවයි. “ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් පසුවත් විවිධ චෝදනා නගමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ සූදානමක් තිබෙනවා.විවිධ දුෂ්කරතා සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ හා සේවා හිඟය නිසා මතුවූ මහජන විරෝධයට හේතුව රජය අවබෝධ කරගෙන නැහැ.ආණ්ඩුව අඩාල කරන්න හදනවා. මර්දනය හරහා ජනතාවගේ සාධාරණ ඉල්ලීම්,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මහජන විරෝධතා මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි වැනි මර්දනකාරී නීති සහ රෙගුලාසි භාවිතා කිරීමට ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ උත්සාහ කරන බව පැවසූ දිසානායක මහතා එවැනි පියවරයන් නතර කරන ලෙස රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AKD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கைதுகளை நிறுத்தவும், போராட்டக்காரர்களை ஒடுக்கவும்: AKD அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலிமுகத்திடல் போராட்டக்காரர்களை கைது செய்வதையும் ஒடுக்குவதையும் நிறுத்துமாறு மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி (ஜேவிபி) இன்று அரசாங்கத்திடம் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "காலி முகத்திடலில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் பெலவத்தையில் உள்ள ஜே.வி.பி தலைமை அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் பின்னர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த ஜே.வி.பி தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க இதனை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மறுநாள் பிற்பகல் 2.00 மணிக்கு ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தை கையளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்த போதிலும், போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது கடுமையான தாக்குதலை கட்டவிழ்த்துவிடுவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆயுதப்படைகளை பெற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "ரணிலை ஜனாதிபதி ஆக்குவதற்கு வாக்களித்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன எம்.பி.க்களை மகிழ்விப்பதற்காகவே இந்த தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார். \"காட்டுமிராண்டித்தனமான தாக்குதலுக்குப் பிறகும், பல்வேறு குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை முன்வைத்து போராட்டக்காரர்களை கைது செய்யும் நடவடிக்கை உள்ளது. பல்வேறு இன்னல்கள் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகள் பற்றாக்குறையால் உருவான பொதுமக்களின் போராட்டத்தின் காரணத்தை அரசாங்கம் உணரவில்லை. அரசாங்கம் தடுக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது. அடக்குமுறை மூலம் மக்களின் நியாயமான கோரிக்கைகள்,\" என்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, அடக்குமுறை சட்டங்கள் மற்றும் அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் போன்ற ஒழுங்குமுறைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி பொதுமக்களின் எதிர்ப்புக்களை அடக்குவதற்கு முயற்சிப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்த திரு. (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஏ.கே.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}