{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/fm-sabry-briefs-diplomatic-corps-on-key-developments/",
  "time_ut": 1659433380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "FM Sabry briefs Diplomatic Corps on Key Developments",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "FM Sabry briefs Diplomatic Corps on Key Developments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  The Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry briefed the Colombo-based Ambassadors and High Commissioners on key developments following the election of the new President and the formation of the new Government, at his first briefing of the diplomatic corps on Monday 1 August 2022 at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.",
        "The Minister outlined the recent political developments in Sri Lanka leading up to the election of President Ranil Wickremesinghe as well as the formation of the interim Government. The related processes had taken place within a democratic constitutional framework.",
        "The Foreign Minister reiterated the commitment of the President to speedily resolve the economic challenges faced by the country in discussion with all relevant partners in the international community as a matter of the highest priority.",
        "The Foreign Minister extended his deep appreciation to the international community for the assistance being extended to Sri Lanka to address issues of relevance in the current socio-economic context.",
        "Elaborating on the broad-based, consultative approach adopted by the President in addressing the current challenges, the Foreign Minister referred to ongoing discussions on forming an all-party Government.  Reference was also made to progressive legislative reforms being contemplated in the near term under the aspirations of the people.",
        "Concerning the policy priorities of the new Government which would be presented to Parliament by President Wickremesinghe when the Parliament reconvenes for its next session on Wednesday 3 August 2022, Minister Sabry reiterated Sri Lanka’s neutral and non-aligned foreign policy based on the principle of friendship towards all.",
        "The Foreign Minister highlighted the longstanding, democratic credentials of Sri Lanka, including the right to peaceful protest, freedom of assembly, and expression. These rights are constitutionally guaranteed and upheld by the Government.  He apprised the diplomatic community of action taken to restore normalcy in the country within the framework of the law, to ensure the effective functioning of Government.  The Minister observed that the emergency regulations enacted in July 2022 are subject to regular and periodic review.",
        "Members of the Diplomatic community congratulated the Foreign Minister warmly on the assumption of his new role and thanked him for the useful update.",
        "Secretary to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Aruni Wijewardane and senior officials of the Ministry were also present at the briefing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sabry",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Diplomatic Corps on Key Developments",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday 1 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday 3 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Diplomatic",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "FM Sabry ප්‍රධාන වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික බලකායට විස්තර කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි විසින් 2022 අගෝස්තු 1 වන සඳුදා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ පැවති රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික බළකාය පිළිබඳ සිය පළමු සාකච්ඡාවේදී නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමෙන් සහ නව රජය පිහිටුවීමෙන් පසු ප්‍රධාන වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව කොළඹ පිහිටි තානාපතිවරුන් සහ මහ කොමසාරිස්වරුන් දැනුවත් කළේය. විදේශ කටයුතු පිළිබඳ.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තේරී පත්වීම දක්වා මෙන්ම අන්තර්වාර රජය පිහිටුවීම දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෑතකාලීන දේශපාලන වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරයා කරුණු දැක්වීය. ඊට අදාළ ක්‍රියාදාමයන් සිදුවී තිබුණේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුවක් තුළ ය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවේ අදාළ සියලුම හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඉහළම ප්‍රමුඛතාවයක් ලෙස රට මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික අභියෝග කඩිනමින් විසඳීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ කැපවීම විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා යළිත් අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් සමාජ-ආර්ථික සන්දර්භය තුළ අදාළ ගැටළු විසඳීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දෙන සහය පිළිබඳව විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව වෙත සිය ගැඹුරු කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් අභියෝගවලට මුහුණදීමේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් අනුගමනය කරන ලද පුළුල් පදනමක් සහිත උපදේශනාත්මක ප්‍රවේශය පිළිබඳව විස්තර කළ විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිහිටුවීම පිළිබඳ දැනට පවතින සාකච්ඡා පිළිබඳව සඳහන් කළේය. ජනතාවගේ අභිලාෂයන් යටතේ නුදුරු කාලීනව සලකා බලනු ලබන ප්‍රගතිශීලී ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳව ද සඳහන් කරන ලදී.",
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 3 වැනි බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මීළඟ සැසිවාරය සඳහා යළි රැස්වන විට ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන නව රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රමුඛතා සම්බන්ධයෙන්, මිත්‍රත්වයේ මූලධර්මය මත පදනම් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මධ්‍යස්ථ සහ නොබැඳි විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය අමාත්‍ය සබ්රි යළි අවධාරණය කළේය. සෑම.",
        "සාමකාමී විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ අයිතිය, රැස්වීමේ නිදහස සහ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දීර්ඝ කාලීන, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අක්තපත්‍ර විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය. මෙම අයිතිවාසිකම් රජය විසින් ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව සහතික කර තහවුරු කර ඇත. රජයේ ඵලදායී ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය සහතික කිරීම සඳහා නීතියේ රාමුව තුළ රට සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව ඔහු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව දැනුවත් කළේය. 2022 ජූලි මස පනවන ලද හදිසි නීති රෙගුලාසි නිතිපතා සහ කාලානුරූපී සමාලෝචනයට යටත් වන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා නිරීක්ෂණය කළේය.",
        "රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ප්‍රජාවේ සාමාජිකයින් විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ නව භූමිකාව භාර ගැනීම පිළිබඳව උණුසුම් සුබපැතුම් පළ කළ අතර ප්‍රයෝජනවත් යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම සඳහා ඔහුට ස්තූති කළහ.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන මහත්මිය සහ එම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් ද මෙම දැනුවත් කිරීමේ අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සබ්රි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ප්රධාන වර්ධනයන් පිළිබඳ රාජ්යතාන්ත්රික බලකාය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 1 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 3 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්යතාන්ත්රික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முக்கிய முன்னேற்றங்கள் குறித்து எஃப்எம் சப்ரி இராஜதந்திரப் படையை விளக்குகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி, 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 1 திங்கட்கிழமை அமைச்சில் நடைபெற்ற இராஜதந்திரப் படையணியின் முதல் மாநாட்டில், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் தெரிவு மற்றும் புதிய அரசாங்கம் உருவானதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஏற்பட்ட முக்கிய முன்னேற்றங்கள் குறித்து கொழும்பில் உள்ள தூதுவர்கள் மற்றும் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர்களுக்கு விளக்கமளித்தார். வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தேர்தல் மற்றும் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் அமைப்பது வரை இலங்கையில் அண்மைக்காலமாக ஏற்பட்ட அரசியல் முன்னேற்றங்களை அமைச்சர் கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார். இது தொடர்பான செயல்முறைகள் ஜனநாயக அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் நடந்தன.",
        "நாடு எதிர்நோக்கும் பொருளாதார சவால்களை சர்வதேச சமூகத்திலுள்ள அனைத்து பங்குதாரர்களுடனும் மிக அதிக முன்னுரிமையுடன் கலந்துரையாடி விரைவாகத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் அர்ப்பணிப்பை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய சமூக-பொருளாதார சூழலில் பொருத்தமான பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டு வரும் உதவிகளுக்காக வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் சர்வதேச சமூகத்திற்கு தனது ஆழ்ந்த பாராட்டுக்களை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தற்போதைய சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் ஜனாதிபதியினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் பரந்த அடிப்படையிலான, கலந்தாலோசனை அணுகுமுறையை விரிவாகக் கூறிய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமொன்றை அமைப்பது தொடர்பாக நடைபெற்று வரும் கலந்துரையாடல்களை குறிப்பிட்டார். மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளின் கீழ், முற்போக்கான சட்டச் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் அண்மைக் காலத்தில் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுவதைப் பற்றியும் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 3 புதன்கிழமையன்று பாராளுமன்றம் அதன் அடுத்த அமர்வுக்கு மீண்டும் கூடும் போது ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்வைக்கப்படும் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் கொள்கை முன்னுரிமைகள் குறித்து அமைச்சர் சப்ரி இலங்கையின் நடுநிலை மற்றும் அணிசேரா வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கையை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினார். அனைத்து.",
        "அமைதியான போராட்டத்திற்கான உரிமை, ஒன்று கூடும் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் கருத்துச் சுதந்திரம் உள்ளிட்ட இலங்கையின் நீண்டகால ஜனநாயக நற்சான்றிதழ்களை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் எடுத்துரைத்தார். இந்த உரிமைகள் அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியில் அரசாங்கத்தால் உத்தரவாதம் அளிக்கப்பட்டு உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன. அரசாங்கம் திறம்பட செயல்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக, சட்டத்தின் கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் நாட்டில் இயல்பு நிலையை மீட்டெடுக்க எடுக்கப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து அவர் இராஜதந்திர சமூகத்திற்கு எடுத்துரைத்தார். ஜூலை 2022 இல் இயற்றப்பட்ட அவசரகாலச் சட்டங்கள் வழக்கமான மற்றும் அவ்வப்போது மறுஆய்வுக்கு உட்பட்டவை என்பதை அமைச்சர் கவனித்தார்.",
        "இராஜதந்திர சமூகத்தின் உறுப்பினர்கள் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சரின் புதிய பொறுப்பை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதற்கு அன்புடன் வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்தனர் மற்றும் பயனுள்ள புதுப்பித்தலுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் அருணி விஜேவர்தன மற்றும் அமைச்சின் உயர் அதிகாரிகளும் இந்த மாநாட்டில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சப்ரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "முக்கிய முன்னேற்றங்கள் பற்றிய இராஜதந்திர கார்ப்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1, 2022 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 3, 2022 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராஜதந்திரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}