{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/යුක්රේනය-මුල්-කරගෙන-සීතල-යුද-වෑයමක්---චීනය/3-395206",
  "time_ut": 1657216896,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යුක්රේනය මුල් කරගෙන සීතල යුද වෑයමක් - චීනය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A Cold War effort based on Ukraine - China",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi emphasized that he will stand against any attempt to create a new cold war.",
        "Regarding the Ukraine issue, the Chinese minister said:",
        "The two diplomats met in Bali, Indonesia on the sidelines of the G20 Foreign Ministers' Meeting.",
        "Raising China's concerns over the situation in Ukraine, Wang said China opposes the Cold War mentality and any attempt to use the crisis to fuel factional conflict and create a new Cold War.",
        "He said that facing complex and dire challenges, the world values ​​cooperation rather than division, and calls for dialogue, not conflict. The Chinese Foreign Minister added that China will continue to firmly stand on the right side of history and promote peace talks."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cold War",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ukraine",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese State Councilor and Foreign",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bali",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුක්රේනය මුල් කරගෙන සීතල යුද වෑයමක් - චීනය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව සීතල යුද්ධයක් ඇති කිරීමට දරන ඕනෑම උත්සාහයකට එරෙහිව නැගී සිටින බව චීන රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රී සහ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය වැන්ග් යී අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "යුක්රේන ප්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය සුබ්‍රමනියම් ජයශංකර් සමග අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගනිමින් චීන අමාත්‍යවරයා මෙසේ කීවේය.",
        "G20 විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරුන්ගේ රැස්වීමට සමගාමීව රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් දෙදෙනා ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ බාලිහිදී හමුවිය.",
        "යුක්රේනයේ තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනයේ කනස්සල්ල මතු කරමින්, වෑන්ග් පැවසුවේ, සීතල යුද මානසිකත්වය සහ කණ්ඩායම් ගැටුම අවුලුවාලීමට සහ නව සීතල යුද්ධයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීමට අර්බුදය භාවිත කිරීමට ගන්නා ඕනෑම උත්සාහයකට චීනය විරුද්ධ බවයි.",
        "සංකීර්ණ හා දරුණු අභියෝගවලට මුහුණදෙන ලෝකය බෙදීමට වඩා සහයෝගීතාව අගය කරන බවත්, ගැටුමක් නොව සංවාදයක් අවශ්‍ය බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. චීනය අඛණ්ඩව ඉතිහාසයේ දකුණු පැත්තේ ස්ථිරව සිට සාම සාකච්ඡා ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරන බව චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "යුක්රේනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රී සහ විදේශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බාලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உக்ரைனை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு பனிப்போர் முயற்சி - சீனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய பனிப்போரை உருவாக்கும் எந்த முயற்சிக்கும் எதிராக நிற்கப்போவதாக சீன அரசு கவுன்சிலரும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சருமான வாங் யி வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "உக்ரைன் விவகாரம் குறித்து சீன அமைச்சர் கூறியதாவது:",
        "இந்தோனேசியாவின் பாலியில் G20 வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர்கள் கூட்டத்தின் ஒருபுறம் இரு தூதர்களும் சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "உக்ரைனில் உள்ள நிலைமை குறித்து சீனாவின் கவலைகளை எழுப்பிய வாங், பனிப்போர் மனப்பான்மையை சீனா எதிர்ப்பதாகவும், நெருக்கடியை பயன்படுத்தி கோஷ்டி மோதலைத் தூண்டி புதிய பனிப்போரை உருவாக்கும் எந்த முயற்சியையும் எதிர்ப்பதாகவும் கூறினார்.",
        "சிக்கலான மற்றும் கடுமையான சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதால், உலகம் பிரிவினையை விட ஒத்துழைப்பை மதிக்கிறது, மேலும் மோதல் அல்ல, உரையாடலுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது என்று அவர் கூறினார். சீனா தொடர்ந்து வரலாற்றின் வலது பக்கத்தில் உறுதியாக நின்று சமாதானப் பேச்சுக்களை ஊக்குவிக்கும் என்று சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பனிப்போர்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "உக்ரைன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன மாநில கவுன்சிலர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}