{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-state-sector-to-go-full-electric-no-more-fuel-vehicles-president-99182/",
  "time_ut": 1661847540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s state sector to go full electric, no more fuel vehicles: president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s state sector to go full electric, no more fuel vehicles: president",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will exclusively purchase electric vehicles for use in the state sector, President Ranil Wickremesinghe s aid.",
        "Presenting an interim budget for the remainder of the year, Wickremesinghe told parliament on Tuesday August 30 that the purchase of fuel-run vehicles for state services will be stopped.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through an energy crisis in the midst of the country’s worst economic crisis since independence. Fuel queues, which had eased following the implementation of a digital quota system, have now returned, though the Power & Energy Ministry has assured the public that supply will continue as usual.",
        "Meanwhile, daily power cuts continue, though the duration of scheduled cuts have now reduced to two hours and 20 minutes. (Colombo/Aug30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Power & Energy Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two hours and 20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය අංශය සම්පුර්ණයෙන් විදුලියට, ​​ඉන්ධන වාහනවලට යන්න එපා: ජනපති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ භාවිතය සඳහා පමණක් විදුළි වාහන මිලදී ගන්නා බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ සහාය.",
        "වසරේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා අතුරු අයවැයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රාජ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා ඉන්ධන ධාවනය වන වාහන මිලදී ගැනීම නතර කරන බවයි.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු රට මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලශක්ති අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටී. ඩිජිටල් කෝටා ක්‍රමයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමෙන් පසු ලිහිල් වූ ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් මේ වන විට යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් වී ඇති නමුත් සැපයුම සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි සිදුවන බවට විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය ජනතාවට සහතික විය.",
        "මේ අතර, නියමිත විදුලි කප්පාදුවේ කාලය දැන් පැය දෙකයි විනාඩි 20 දක්වා අඩු වී ඇතත්, දෛනික විදුලි කප්පාදුව දිගටම පවතී. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය දෙකයි විනාඩි 20 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் அரச துறை முழுமையாக மின்சாரம், எரிபொருள் வாகனங்கள் வேண்டாம்: ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை அரச துறையில் பயன்படுத்துவதற்காக பிரத்தியேகமாக மின்சார வாகனங்களை கொள்வனவு செய்யும், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் உதவி.",
        "எஞ்சிய வருடத்திற்கான இடைக்கால வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டத்தை முன்வைத்த விக்கிரமசிங்க, அரச சேவைகளுக்காக எரிபொருளில் இயங்கும் வாகனங்களை கொள்வனவு செய்வது நிறுத்தப்படும் என்று ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் இலங்கை எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது. டிஜிட்டல் ஒதுக்கீடு முறை அமலுக்கு வந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து குறைந்திருந்த எரிபொருள் வரிசைகள் தற்போது திரும்பியுள்ளன, இருப்பினும் வழக்கம் போல் விநியோகம் தொடரும் என்று மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம் பொதுமக்களுக்கு உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், தினசரி மின்வெட்டு தொடர்கிறது, இருப்பினும் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வெட்டுகளின் காலம் இப்போது இரண்டு மணி நேரம் 20 நிமிடங்களாக குறைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மணி 20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}