{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-asks-Harin-to-resign-from-Parliament/108-241638",
  "time_ut": 1658511590,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB asks Harin to resign from Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB asks Harin to resign from Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "MP Harin Fernando should hand over the national list slot through which he came into Parliament back to Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) so that former MP Ranjan Ramanayake could be nominated to Parliament once he is out of prison, an SJB MP suggested today.",
        "SJB MP Nalin Bandara Jayamaha told a briefing that Mr. Fernandio should resign from the House and give the seat back to where it belongs.",
        "“Mr. Fernando can come through the UNP national list as it has fallen vacant after its leader Ranil Wickremesinghe was elected President. We can use the SJB national list slot to bring Ranjan Ramanayake into Parliament if Mr. Fernando hands over the national list slot to us,” he said.",
        "Mr. Fernando when inquired by Daily Mirror said SJB should ask MP Diana Gamage to resign and hand it over to SJB.",
        "“Mr, Jayamaha should request Ms. Gamage to resign first before asking me. If MP Jayamaha wants I can show him the amount of funds which are due to me for doing campaigns for the SJB and its leader,” he added. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Harin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Bandara Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernandio",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diana Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB හරීන්ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙන්න කියලා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වූ පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට නම් කළ හැකි වන පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීධුරය සමගි ජන බලවේගයට යළි ලබාදිය යුතු බව SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් අද යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා සභාවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී මන්ත්‍රී ආසනය අයිති තැනටම ලබාදිය යුතු බව SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නලින් බණ්ඩාර ජයමහ මහතා දැනුවත් කිරීමේ හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "\"මහතා. එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු පුරප්පාඩු වූ එජාප ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතාට පැමිණිය හැකිය. ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා අපට ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීධුරය ලබාදුන්නොත් අපට රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගෙන ඒමට SJB ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම භාවිත කළ හැකියි.",
        "ඩේලි මිරර් කළ විමසීමකදී ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසුවේ SJB මන්ත්‍රී ඩයනා ගමගේ මහත්මියට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා එය SJB වෙත භාරදිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "“මගෙන් අහන්න කලින් ගමගේ මහත්මියගෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙන්න කියලා ජයමහ මහතා ඉල්ලා සිටිය යුතුයි. ජයමහ මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට අවශ්‍ය නම් මට SJB සහ එහි නායකයා වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රචාරක කටයුතු සඳහා මට ලැබිය යුතු මුදල් ප්‍රමාණය ඔහුට පෙන්විය හැකියි. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හරීන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයනා ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஹரினை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு SJB கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ, அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்த தேசியப் பட்டியல் இடத்தை மீண்டும் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) விடம் ஒப்படைக்க வேண்டும், இதனால் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க சிறையிலிருந்து வெளியேறியதும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்கப்படுவார் என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் இன்று பரிந்துரைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "பெர்னாண்டியோ சபையில் இருந்து இராஜினாமா செய்துவிட்டு அந்த ஆசனத்தை மீண்டும் தனக்குரிய இடத்திற்கே வழங்க வேண்டும் என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நளின் பண்டார ஜயமஹா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"திரு. ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் ஊடாக பெர்னாண்டோ வரலாம். பெர்னாண்டோ எங்களிடம் தேசியப் பட்டியல் இடத்தை ஒப்படைத்தால், ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை நாடாளுமன்றத்துக்குக் கொண்டுவருவதற்கு எஸ்.ஜே.பி.யின் தேசியப் பட்டியலைப் பயன்படுத்திக் கொள்ளலாம்,” என்றார்.",
        "பெர்னாண்டோவிடம் டெய்லி மிரர் வினவியபோது, ​​SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டயானா கமகேவை பதவி விலகச் சொல்லி SJBயிடம் ஒப்படைக்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "“திரு, ஜெயமஹா என்னைக் கேட்பதற்கு முன் திருமதி கமகேவை ராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு கோர வேண்டும். பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜயமஹா விரும்பினால், நான் SJB மற்றும் அதன் தலைவருக்காக பிரச்சாரங்களை செய்ததற்காக எனக்கு செலுத்த வேண்டிய நிதியை அவருக்கு காட்ட முடியும், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹரின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பண்டார ஜயமஹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டியோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டயானா கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}