{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84602/4-killed-2-injured-after-shooter-sets-building-on-fire-in-houston",
  "time_ut": 1661749680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "4 killed, 2 injured after shooter sets building on fire in Houston",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "4 killed, 2 injured after shooter sets building on fire in Houston",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At least four people were killed and two people were injured on Sunday morning (local time) after a man set fire to a building and then shot at people fleeing in Houston, according to city Police chief Troy Finner.",
        "Speaking at a press conference, the police chief informed that among the four killed was the suspect, CNN reported. The suspect was later killed by a Houston police officer.",
        "According to Finner, victims were all men, and range in age from 40-60.",
        "“This suspect, unfortunately, and very sadly, and very evilly, set fire to several residents,” Finner said during the press conference as quoted by CNN.",
        "The suspect then “laid in wait for those residents to come out and fired upon them,” he said. The fire department arrived at the scene first to douse the fire, but had to retreat from the gunman upon arrival, as per the police official.",
        "“The suspect began to fire. I don’t know if he was firing in their direction, but they had to take cover,” Finner said.",
        "According to him, the suspect was a 40-year-old African American man who was dressed in all black.",
        "Last week, one person was killed and six others sustained injuries in an apparent targeted shooting in the US state of Maryland.",
        "Police said one victim succumbed to his injuries and was pronounced dead by medical personnel. All of the victims are adult males.",
        "Witnesses reported that the suspect vehicle is a 4-door silver Lexus sedan.",
        "“On August 24, 2022, at approximately 12:24 p.m., Northwest District officers were summoned to the intersection of Shirley Avenue and Park Heights Avenue to investigate a reported shooting,” the Baltimore police said in a statement posted on Facebook.",
        "Prior to that a man set his car on fire and drove into a US Capitol barricade late night, according to Fox News. The unidentified man reportedly fired a weapon indiscriminately and then shot himself."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Houston",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "At least four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Houston",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Troy Finner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Houston",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Finner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "African American",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maryland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lexus",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 24, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 12:24 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northwest District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shirley Avenue",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Park Heights Avenue",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baltimore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "late night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fox News",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හූස්ටන් හි ගොඩනැගිල්ලකට වෙඩි තැබීමකින් 4 දෙනෙකු මිය ගොස් දෙදෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නගර පොලිස් ප්‍රධානී ට්‍රෝයි ෆිනර් පවසන පරිදි, ඉරිදා උදෑසන (ප්‍රාදේශීය වේලාවෙන්) පුද්ගලයෙකු ගොඩනැගිල්ලකට ගිනි තබා පලා යමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයින්ට වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් සිව් දෙනෙකු මිය ගොස් දෙදෙනෙකු තුවාල ලැබීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් අමතමින් පොලිස් ප්‍රධානියා දන්වා සිටියේ මියගිය සිව්දෙනා අතර සැකකරුද සිටින බවයි. පසුව හූස්ටන් පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු විසින් සැකකරු ඝාතනය කර ඇත.",
        "ෆිනර්ට අනුව, වින්දිතයන් සියල්ලන්ම පිරිමින් වන අතර වයස අවුරුදු 40-60 අතර පරාසයක පවතී.",
        "\"මෙම සැකකරු, අවාසනාවන්ත ලෙස, ඉතා කණගාටුදායක ලෙස, සහ ඉතා නපුරු ලෙස, නිවැසියන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට ගිනි තැබුවේය,\" ෆිනර් CNN විසින් උපුටා දක්වන ලද මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "පසුව සැකකරු “එම නිවැසියන් එළියට එනතුරු බලා සිට ඔවුන්ට වෙඩි තැබුවා” යැයි ඔහු පැවසීය. ගිනි නිවන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ගින්න මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ප්‍රථමයෙන් එම ස්ථානයට පැමිණියද, පොලිස් නිලධාරියා පවසන පරිදි පැමිණීමත් සමඟ තුවක්කුකරුගෙන් පසුබැසීමට සිදුවිය.",
        "“සැකකරු වෙඩි තියන්න පටන් ගත්තා. ඔහු ඔවුන්ගේ දිශාවට වෙඩි තැබුවාද යන්න මම නොදනිමි, නමුත් ඔවුන්ට සැඟවීමට සිදු විය, ”ෆිනර් පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහුට අනුව, සැකකරු 40 හැවිරිදි අප්‍රිකානු ඇමරිකානුවෙක් වන අතර ඔහු සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම කළු ඇඳුමින් සැරසී සිටියේය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ, එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මේරිලන්ඩ් ප්‍රාන්තයේ පැහැදිලිවම ඉලක්කගත වෙඩි තැබීමකින් එක් පුද්ගලයෙකු මිය ගොස් තවත් හය දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇත.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, තුවාල ලැබූ එක් අයෙකු මිය ගොස් ඇති අතර, වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඔහු මිය ගිය බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. වින්දිතයන් සියල්ලෝම වැඩිහිටි පිරිමින්ය.",
        "සිද්ධිය ඇසින් දුටුවන් වාර්තා කළේ සැකකාර රථය දොරටු 4 කින් යුත් රිදී ලෙක්සස් සෙඩාන් රථයක් බවයි.",
        "“2022 අගෝස්තු 24 වන දින, ආසන්න වශයෙන් 12:24 ට, වාර්තා වූ වෙඩි තැබීමක් විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා වයඹ දිස්ත්‍රික් නිලධාරීන් ෂර්ලි මාවත සහ පාර්ක් හයිට්ස් මාවතේ මංසන්ධියට කැඳවන ලදී,” බැල්ටිමෝර් පොලිසිය ෆේස්බුක් හි පළ කළ ප්‍රකාශයක සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ඊට පෙර මිනිසෙක් තම මෝටර් රථයට ගිනි තබා රාත්‍රියේ එක්සත් ජනපද කැපිටල් බාධකයකට ඇතුළු වූ බව ෆොක්ස් නිව්ස් වාර්තා කරයි. නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයා අවි ආයුධයකින් වෙඩි තබාගෙන වෙඩි තබාගෙන සියදිවි හානිකරගෙන ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "හූස්ටන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් හතරක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හූස්ටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රෝයි ෆිනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හූස්ටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු ඇමරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේරිලන්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙක්සස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 12:24 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂර්ලි මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ක් හයිට්ස් මාවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැල්ටිමෝර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆොක්ස් නිව්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஹூஸ்டனில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியவர் கட்டிடத்திற்கு தீ வைத்ததில் 4 பேர் கொல்லப்பட்டனர், 2 பேர் காயமடைந்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை காலை (உள்ளூர் நேரம்) ஹூஸ்டனில் ஒரு நபர் ஒரு கட்டிடத்திற்கு தீ வைத்து பின்னர் தப்பியோடிய மக்கள் மீது சுட்டதில் குறைந்தது நான்கு பேர் கொல்லப்பட்டனர் மற்றும் இரண்டு பேர் காயமடைந்தனர் என்று நகர காவல்துறைத் தலைவர் ட்ராய் ஃபின்னர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் பேசிய பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர், கொல்லப்பட்ட நால்வரில் சந்தேக நபரும் அடங்குவதாக சிஎன்என் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. சந்தேக நபர் பின்னர் ஹூஸ்டன் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரியால் கொல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஃபின்னரின் கூற்றுப்படி, பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் அனைவரும் ஆண்கள் மற்றும் 40-60 வயதுடையவர்கள்.",
        "\"இந்த சந்தேக நபர், துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, மற்றும் மிகவும் துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, மற்றும் மிகவும் தீய முறையில், பல குடியிருப்பாளர்களுக்கு தீ வைத்துள்ளார்,\" என்று CNN மேற்கோள் காட்டிய செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது ஃபின்னர் கூறினார்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் பின்னர் \"அந்த குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் வெளியே வருவதற்கு காத்திருந்து அவர்கள் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தினார்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். தீயணைப்புத் துறையினர் முதலில் சம்பவ இடத்திற்கு வந்து தீயை அணைத்தனர், ஆனால் வந்தவுடன் துப்பாக்கி ஏந்தியவரிடம் இருந்து பின்வாங்க வேண்டியிருந்தது என்று காவல்துறை அதிகாரி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“சந்தேக நபர் சுட ஆரம்பித்தார். அவர் அவர்களின் திசையில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்துகிறாரா என்று எனக்குத் தெரியவில்லை, ஆனால் அவர்கள் மறைத்துக்கொள்ள வேண்டியிருந்தது\" என்று ஃபின்னர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவரது கூற்றுப்படி, சந்தேக நபர் 40 வயதான ஆப்பிரிக்க அமெரிக்கர் ஆவார், அவர் முழு கருப்பு உடையில் இருந்தார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம், அமெரிக்காவின் மேரிலாண்ட் மாநிலத்தில், இலக்கு வைக்கப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் கொல்லப்பட்டதுடன் மேலும் ஆறு பேர் காயமடைந்தனர்.",
        "காயமடைந்த ஒருவர் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாகவும், அவர் உயிரிழந்துவிட்டதாகவும் வைத்திய அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர். பாதிக்கப்பட்ட அனைவரும் வயது வந்த ஆண்கள்.",
        "சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வாகனம் 4 கதவுகள் கொண்ட சில்வர் லெக்ஸஸ் செடான் என்று சாட்சிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "\"ஆகஸ்ட் 24, 2022 அன்று, சுமார் மதியம் 12:24 மணிக்கு, வடமேற்கு மாவட்ட அதிகாரிகள் ஷெர்லி அவென்யூ மற்றும் பார்க் ஹைட்ஸ் அவென்யூ சந்திப்பிற்கு வரவழைக்கப்பட்டனர், துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு குறித்து விசாரிக்க,\" என்று பால்டிமோர் காவல்துறை பேஸ்புக்கில் வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதற்கு முன்னதாக, ஒரு நபர் தனது காரை தீ வைத்து, அமெரிக்க கேபிடல் தடுப்பணையில் நள்ளிரவில் ஓட்டிச் சென்றதாக ஃபாக்ஸ் நியூஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. அடையாளம் தெரியாத நபர் சரமாரியாக துப்பாக்கியால் சுட்டுவிட்டு தன்னைத்தானே சுட்டுக்கொண்டதாக கூறப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹூஸ்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூஸ்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிராய் ஃபின்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூஸ்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபின்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்க இனம் சேர்ந்த அமெரிக்கர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேரிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெக்ஸஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12:24 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெர்லி அவென்யூ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்க் ஹைட்ஸ் அவென்யூ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பால்டிமோர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாக்ஸ் நியூஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}