{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/வாக்கெடுப்பிலிருந்து-விலக-பலர்-தீர்மானம்/175-303444",
  "time_ut": 1662102834,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "வாக்கெடுப்பிலிருந்து விலக பலர் தீர்மானம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Many decided to withdraw from the referendum",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main opposition United People's Shakti has decided to stay out of the referendum as the referendum on the interim relief proposed by President Ranil Wickremesinghe is scheduled to take place today.",
        "Meanwhile, Member of Parliament G. L. said that 13 members of parliament, including himself, who had decided to work independently in the opposition party, had decided to withdraw from the vote on interim relief. Peiris said. (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United People's Shakti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බොහෝ දෙනෙක් ජනමත විචාරණයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කළහ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කර ඇති අතුරු සහන පිළිබඳ ජනමත විචාරණය අද පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බැවින් ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති ජනමත විචාරණයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර විපක්ෂයේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කිරීමට තීරණය කළ තමන් ඇතුළු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනෙකු අතුරු සහන පිළිබඳ ඡන්ද විමසීමෙන් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කළ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය. (ආ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வாக்கெடுப்பிலிருந்து விலக பலர் தீர்மானம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட இடைக்கால  பாதீடு மீதான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ள நிலையில், வாக்கெடுப்பிலிருந்து விலகியிருக்க, பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இணைந்து சுயாதீனமாக செயற்பட தீர்மானித்த தான் உட்பட 13 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் இடைக்கால பாதீடு மீதான வாக்கெடுப்பிலிருந்து விலகியிருக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜீ.எல். பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}