{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/30/sri-lanka-in-final-stages-of-imf-talks-president/",
  "time_ut": 1661865480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka in final stages of IMF talks – President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka in final stages of IMF talks – President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe told the Parliament that negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) have successfully reached its final stages.",
        "Speaking to Parliament on Tuesday (30), the President said that the discussions on debt restructuring will be held with the main countries that provide loan assistance to the country.",
        "\"The United Nations in collaboration with leading international organizations is launching a program to ensure food security. The process of providing daily needs like gas, electricity, and fuel without a shortage has been initiated. Schools have opened, and the universities are commencing their academic activities,\" he said.",
        "The President stressed that Sri Lanka should prepare a National Economic",
        "\"This Interim Budget forms the basic foundation for the National Economic Policy, which is envisaged to be established through the 2023 Budget,\" he added.",
        "The President noted that the Interim Budget speech, the IMF agreement and the Budget 2023 will set the framework for Economic Stabilization and Revival. \"Within it, we will set the Road Map.\"",
        "He also noted that once the discussions with the IMF are concluded, I expect to provide the information on the same to the Parliament.",
        "Suspect remanded for stealing liquor bottle from RWs private home"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This Interim Budget",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Economic Policy",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RWs private home",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡාවල අවසන් අදියරේ – ජනපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ පැවැත්වූ සාකච්ඡා සාර්ථකව අවසන් අදියරට පැමිණ ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා (30) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අමතමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ රටට ණය ආධාර ලබාදෙන ප්‍රධාන රටවල් සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වන බවයි.",
        "\"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන සමඟ එක්ව ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව තහවුරු කිරීමේ වැඩසටහනක් දියත් කරයි. ගෑස්, විදුලිය, ඉන්ධන වැනි දෛනික අවශ්‍යතා හිඟයකින් තොරව සැපයීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කර ඇත. පාසල් විවෘත කර විශ්ව විද්‍යාල අධ්‍යයන කටයුතු ආරම්භ කරයි. ක්රියාකාරකම්,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාතික ආර්ථිකයක් සකස් කළ යුතු බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය",
        "\"මෙම අතුරු අයවැය 2023 අයවැය හරහා ස්ථාපිත කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන ජාතික ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ මූලික පදනම සාදයි,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "අතුරු අයවැය කතාව, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ගිවිසුම සහ 2023 අයවැය මගින් ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ පුනර්ජීවනය සඳහා රාමුව සකස් කරන බව ජනාධිපතිතුමා සඳහන් කළේය. \"එය තුළ, අපි මාර්ග සිතියම සකස් කරමු.\"",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා අවසන් වූ පසු ඒ පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ලබාදීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "RWs පෞද්ගලික නිවසකින් මත්පැන් බෝතලයක් සොරකම් කළ සැකකරු රිමාන්ඩ්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ අතුරු අයවැය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RWs පෞද්ගලික නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தையின் இறுதி கட்டத்தில் இலங்கை – ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தை வெற்றிகரமாக இறுதிக்கட்டத்தை எட்டியுள்ளதாக இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டிற்கு கடன் உதவிகளை வழங்கும் பிரதான நாடுகளுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்தவுள்ளதாக செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (30) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உரையாற்றிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை முன்னணி சர்வதேச அமைப்புகளுடன் இணைந்து உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதற்கான திட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது. எரிவாயு, மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் போன்ற அன்றாட தேவைகளை பற்றாக்குறையின்றி வழங்கும் செயல்முறை தொடங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பள்ளிகள் திறக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, பல்கலைக்கழகங்கள் தங்கள் கல்வியைத் தொடங்குகின்றன. நடவடிக்கைகள், \"என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை தேசிய பொருளாதாரத்தை தயாரிக்க வேண்டும் என ஜனாதிபதி வலியுறுத்தினார்",
        "\"இந்த இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் தேசிய பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கைக்கான அடிப்படை அடித்தளத்தை உருவாக்குகிறது, இது 2023 பட்ஜெட் மூலம் நிறுவ திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரை, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதிய ஒப்பந்தம் மற்றும் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் 2023 ஆகியவை பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் மறுமலர்ச்சிக்கான கட்டமைப்பை அமைக்கும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி குறிப்பிட்டார். \"அதற்குள், நாங்கள் சாலை வரைபடத்தை அமைப்போம்.\"",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான கலந்துரையாடல்கள் முடிவடைந்தவுடன், அது தொடர்பான தகவல்களை நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு வழங்க எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன் என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "RWs தனியார் வீட்டில் மதுபாட்டில்களை திருடிய சந்தேகநபர் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RWs தனியார் வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}