{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/25/9th-may-military-lapses-committee-concludes-evidence-examination/",
  "time_ut": 1661405640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "9th May Military Lapses: Committee concludes evidence examination",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "9th May Military Lapses: Committee concludes evidence examination",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Committee appointed to investigate any failure on the part of the Military and State Intelligence to quell the May 09 incidents has concluded the examination of evidence.",
        "The three-member committee said it recorded evidence from 35 officers, including Former Army Commander & present Chief of Defence Staff, General Shavendra Silva, Inspector General of Police C. D. Wickramaratne, and Senior DIG in-charge of the Western Province Deshabandu Thennakoon.",
        "The three-member committee that probed the failure on the part of the then government to quell the May 09 incidents was planning to hand over its report to then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa when he was forced to flee the country on 13th July.",
        "The report will now be handed over to President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "The committee consisted of the Admiral of the Fleet (Retd.) Wasantha Karannagoda (Chairman), Marshal of the Air Force (Retd.) Roshan Gunatilleke and General (Retd.) Daya Ratnayake.",
        "Army Chief Hails ‘Commonwealth Games’ winners; Yupun Abeykoon to be promoted",
        "Generator One of Norochcholai back in operation from Monday (29)",
        "SL Police cites specific UN Security Council Resolution as relevant in PTA arrests"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "May Military Lapses:",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army Commander &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Admiral of the Fleet (Retd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Karannagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force (Retd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daya Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yupun Abeykoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN Security Council Resolution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැයි 9 මිලිටරි පසුබෑම්: කමිටුව සාක්ෂි විභාගය අවසන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මැයි 09 සිදුවීම් මැඩලීමට හමුදාවේ සහ රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශවල යම් අපොහොසත්කමක් තිබේදැයි සොයා බැලීමට පත් කළ කමිටුව සාක්ෂි විභාගය අවසන් කර තිබේ.",
        "හිටපු යුද හමුදාපති සහ වත්මන් ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා, පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී වික්‍රමරත්න, බස්නාහිර පළාත භාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන් ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් 35 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සාක්ෂි සටහන් කරගත් බව ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මැයි 09 වැනි දින සිදු වූ සිදුවීම් මැඩලීමට එවකට රජය අසමත් වීම පිළිබඳව සොයා බැලූ ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුව එහි වාර්තාව එවක ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත භාර දීමට සැලසුම් කරමින් සිටියේ ජූලි 13 වැනි දින ඔහුට රටින් පැන යාමට සිදු වූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "එම වාර්තාව දැන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මෙම කමිටුව සමන්විත වූයේ අද්මිරාල් ඔෆ් ද ෆ්ලීට් (විශ්‍රාමික) වසන්ත කරන්නාගොඩ (සභාපති), මාර්ෂල් ඔෆ් එයාර් ෆෝස් (විශ්‍රාමික) රොෂාන් ගුණතිලක සහ ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) දයා රත්නායක යන අයගෙනි.",
        "යුද හමුදාපති ‘පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා’ ජයග්‍රාහකයන්ට ප්‍රශංසා කරයි; යුපුන් අබේකෝන්ට උසස්වීම්",
        "නොරොච්චෝලේ ජෙනරේටරය සඳුදා (29) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මකයි",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය අදාළ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ නිශ්චිත යෝජනාව උපුටා දක්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලිටරි පසුබෑම:",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුධ හමුදාපති සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික හමුදාවේ අද්මිරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත කරන්නාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව (විශ්‍රාමික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයා රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුපුන් අබේකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලයේ යෝජනාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மே 9 இராணுவ தோல்விகள்: குழு சாட்சியங்களை பரிசோதித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மே 09 சம்பவங்களை அடக்குவதற்கு இராணுவம் மற்றும் அரச புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரின் தரப்பில் ஏதேனும் தவறினால் விசாரணை நடத்த நியமிக்கப்பட்ட குழு சாட்சியங்களை பரிசோதித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் இராணுவத் தளபதி மற்றும் தற்போதைய பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா, பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சி.டி. விக்கிரமரத்ன, மேல் மாகாணத்திற்குப் பொறுப்பான சிரேஷ்ட பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேசபந்து தென்னகோன் உள்ளிட்ட 35 அதிகாரிகளிடம் சாட்சியங்களைப் பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாக மூவரடங்கிய குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மே 09 சம்பவங்களை அடக்குவதற்கு அப்போதைய அரசாங்கம் தவறியமை குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்திய மூவரடங்கிய குழு, ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற நிர்ப்பந்திக்கப்பட்ட போது, ​​அதன் அறிக்கையை அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் ஒப்படைக்க திட்டமிட்டிருந்தது.",
        "இந்த அறிக்கை தற்போது ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கையளிக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவில் கடற்படையின் அட்மிரல் (ஓய்வு) வசந்த கரன்னாகொட (தலைவர்), விமானப்படையின் மார்ஷல் (ஓய்வு) ரொஷான் குணதிலக்க மற்றும் ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு) தயா ரத்நாயக்க ஆகியோர் அடங்கியிருந்தனர்.",
        "‘காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு’ வெற்றியாளர்களுக்கு ராணுவத் தலைவர் பாராட்டு; யுபுன் அபேகோன் பதவி உயர்வு",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (29) முதல் நரோச்சோலை ஜெனரேட்டர் ஒன்று மீண்டும் இயங்குகிறது.",
        "PTA கைதுகளில் தொடர்புடையது என குறிப்பிட்ட UN பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானத்தை SL போலீஸ் மேற்கோள் காட்டுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம் தோல்வியடையலாம்:",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ தளபதி &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படையின் அட்மிரல் (ஓய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த கரன்னாகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை (ஓய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயா ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூபுன் அபேகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}