{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/நடுக்கடலில்-தத்தளித்த-55-பேர்-மீட்பு/175-300293",
  "time_ut": 1657651386,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நடுக்கடலில் தத்தளித்த 55 பேர் மீட்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rescue of 55 people stranded in the middle of the sea",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lankan Navy has rescued 55 people aboard a fishing trawler that got stuck in strong winds about 390 nautical miles south-east of Ambandottai while trying to go abroad illegally.",
        "They were rescued yesterday (12) by the Sri Lankan Navy's Maritime Search and Rescue Coordination Center when the boat was in distress.",
        "The Navy has announced that 55 people, including 46 men, 3 women and 6 children, were traveling on the said boat, including 5 people who assisted in the illegal journey.",
        "The Navy mentioned that the boat they were traveling in was damaged due to strong winds and could not be brought ashore due to sea water ingress.",
        "People from Trincomalee, Mannar, Vavuniya, Kilinochchi, Mullaitivu, Jaffna and Puttalam have been rescued by the Navy. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "55",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambandottai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maritime Search and Rescue Coordination Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee, Mannar,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුහුද මැද අතරමං වූ 55 දෙනෙකු බේරා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස විදේශගත වීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී අඹන්තොටට නාවික සැතපුම් 390ක් පමණ ගිනිකොන දෙසින් ඇති වූ තද සුළඟට හසු වූ ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක සිටි පුද්ගලයින් 55 දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් බේරාගෙන තිබේ.",
        "බෝට්ටුව අනතුරට ලක්ව තිබියදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ සමුද්‍රීය සෝදිසි සහ මුදාගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඊයේ (12) ඔවුන් බේරාගෙන ඇත.",
        "එම යාත්‍රාවේ පිරිමින් 46 ක්, කාන්තාවන් 3 ක් සහ ළමුන් 6 දෙනෙකු ඇතුළු 55 දෙනෙකු ගමන් කර ඇති අතර, ඒ අතර නීතිවිරෝධී ගමනට සහය වූ පුද්ගලයින් 5 දෙනෙකු ද සිටින බවයි නාවික හමුදාව නිවේදනය කළේ.",
        "ඔවුන් ගමන් ගත් බෝට්ටුවට තද සුළං හේතුවෙන් අලාභ හානි සිදුවී ඇති අතර මුහුදු ජලය ඇතුළුවීම හේතුවෙන් ගොඩබිමට රැගෙන ඒමට නොහැකි වූ බවයි නාවික හමුදාව සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, මන්නාරම, වවුනියාව, කිලිනොච්චිය, මුලතිව්, යාපනය සහ පුත්තලම ප්‍රදේශවල පුද්ගලයින් නාවික හමුදාව විසින් බේරාගෙන ඇත. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "55",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්ඩොට්ටයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර සෙවීම් සහ මුදාගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, මන්නාරම,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நடுக்கடலில் தத்தளித்த 55 பேர் மீட்பு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டவிரோதமாக வெளிநாடு செல்ல முயற்சித்த போது அம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு தென்கிழக்கே சுமார் 390 கடல் மைல்  தொலைவில் கடும் காற்றில் சிக்கித் தவித்த மீன்பிடி இழுவைப் படகில் இருந்த 55 பேரை இலங்கை கடற்படை மீட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குறித்த படகு அனர்த்தத்தை எதிர்கொண்ட நிலையில், இலங்கை கடற்படையின் கடல்சார் தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மத்திய நிலையத்தினூடாக அவர்கள் நேற்று (12) மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சட்டவிரோத பயணத்துக்கு உதவிய 5 பேரும் 46 ஆண்களும் 3 பெண்களும் 6 சிறுவர்களும்  அடங்கலாக 55 பேர் குறித்த படகில் பயணித்ததாக கடற்படையினர் அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பலத்த காற்றினால் இவர்கள் பயணித்த படகு சேதமடைந்து கடல் நீர் உட்புகுந்தமையால், அதனை கரைக்கு எடுத்து வர முடியாது போயுள்ளதாக கடற்படை குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "திருகோணமலை, மன்னார், வவுனியா, கிளிநொச்சி, முல்லைத்தீவு, யாழ்ப்பாணம் மற்றும் புத்தளத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்களே கடற்படையினால் மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.  (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "55",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை, மன்னார்,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}