{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78318",
  "time_ut": 1656702360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF team in Colombo  Recommends  Taxes on  those earning  above Rs. 40,000 per month  but Prime Minister  Wickremesinghe immediately expressed concern saying it could not be done as it would further increase the socio-economic crisis faced by the people",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF team in Colombo  Recommends  Taxes on  those earning  above Rs. 40,000 per month  but Prime Minister  Wickremesinghe immediately expressed concern saying it could not be done as it would further increase the socio-economic crisis faced by the people",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Excerpted from the “Sunday Morning” Political Column “The Black Box” by “Capt.Vasaba)",
        "The IMF team that was in Colombo met with Prime Minister Wickremesinghe on Monday (27 June) for another round of meetings.",
        "During the meeting, the IMF team had expressed concerns over the delay in reaching an agreement with China on debt restructuring. The IMF has maintained that China’s agreement on debt restructuring was important since it would help Sri Lanka’s overall debt rescheduling programme.",
        "The IMF team had also discussed some of its observations and proposals during the meeting. Some of the proposals put forward by the IMF team had been turned down by Prime Minister Wickremesinghe, who had pointed out that the people would not be able to bear them given the crisis situation in the country.",
        "One of the main proposals that had drawn the Prime Minister’s attention was increasing the country’s tax revenue by further reducing the taxable income threshold to a level that would cover a majority of low income earners. The IMF team had noted the need to include those earning Rs. 40,000 per month into the tax net. Wickremesinghe, it is learnt, immediately expressed concern, saying it could not be done as it would further increase the socio-economic crisis faced by the people.",
        "The Premier had also explained that it would be counterproductive to look at increasing tax revenue by burdening a majority of the low income earners as the Government would have to increase the social welfare coverage, thereby increasing public expenditure. He had added that increasing the tax burden would also increase the level of corruption in the country.",
        "Prime Minister Wickremesinghe had therefore called on the IMF team to also look at the practical side of implementing proposals amidst a time of crisis. He underscored the importance of introducing proposals that would not be counterproductive once implemented.",
        "Meanwhile, the US State Department and Treasury officials who were in Sri Lanka last week had also informed Prime Minister Wickremesinghe of their desire to meet with the IMF team that was in Sri Lanka. It is learnt that the US Government delegation had met with the IMF delegation on Tuesday (28 June).",
        "The IMF team on Wednesday (29 June) met with the SJB Leader, SLFP Leader and former President Maithripala Sirisena, and a group of SLFP seniors as well.",
        "The IMF team concluded its consultations with Sri Lanka on Thursday.",
        "Meanwhile the finalisation of the Government’s economic recovery plan, it is learnt, is also dependent on the decisions taken during the staff-level meeting with the International Monetary Fund (IMF).",
        "These meetings concluded on Thursday (30 June), with the IMF issuing a press release.",
        "The IMF stated that talks had progressed satisfactorily and it would continue virtual discussions with the aim of “reaching a staff-level agreement on the EFF (Extended Fund Facility) in the near term”.",
        "However, reading between the lines in the IMF message, it seems like the Fund will take a little more time than initially anticipated by the Sri Lankan authorities."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday Morning” Political Column “The Black Box",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasaba",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the US State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF කොළඹ කණ්ඩායම රු. මසකට 40,000 ක් ගෙවන නමුත් අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ වහාම කනස්සල්ල පළ කළේ එය ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන සමාජ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය තවත් වැඩි කරන බැවින් එය කළ නොහැකි බවයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(උපුටා ගැනීම \"ඉරිදා උදෑසන\" දේශපාලන තීරුව \"කප්ටන් වසබාගේ කළු පෙට්ටියෙන්\")",
        "කොළඹට පැමිණ සිටි IMF කණ්ඩායම තවත් රැස්වීම් වටයක් සඳහා සඳුදා (ජූනි 27) අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවිය.",
        "මෙම හමුවේදී, ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනය සමඟ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීම ප්‍රමාද වීම පිළිබඳව IMF කණ්ඩායම කනස්සල්ල පළ කර තිබේ. ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ චීනයේ එකඟතාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමස්ත ණය ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කිරීමේ වැඩසටහනට උපකාරී වන බැවින් එය වැදගත් බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ අදහස වී තිබේ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කණ්ඩායම සිය නිරීක්ෂණ සහ යෝජනා කිහිපයක් ද රැස්වීමේදී සාකච්ඡා කර ඇත. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කණ්ඩායම ඉදිරිපත් කළ ඇතැම් යෝජනා අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර තිබූ අතර රටේ පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය හමුවේ ඒවා ජනතාවට දරාගත නොහැකි බව පෙන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ අවධානයට ලක්ව තිබූ එක් ප්‍රධාන යෝජනාවක් වූයේ අඩු ආදායම්ලාභීන් බහුතරයක් ආවරණය වන මට්ටමට බදු අය කළ හැකි ආදායම් සීමාව තවදුරටත් අඩු කර රටේ බදු ආදායම ඉහළ නැංවීමයි. IMF කණ්ඩායම සටහන් කර තිබුණේ රු. බදු ජාලයට මසකට 40,000. වික්‍රමසිංහ වහාම කනස්සල්ල පළ කළේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන සමාජ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය තවත් වැඩි කරන බැවින් එය කළ නොහැකි බව පවසමිනි.",
        "රජයට සමාජ සුබසාධන ආවරණය වැඩිකර රාජ්‍ය වියදම් ඉහළ දැමීමට සිදුවන බැවින් අඩු ආදායම්ලාභීන්ගෙන් බහුතරයකට බර පටවා බදු ආදායම ඉහළ නැංවීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කිරීම ප්‍රතිපලදායක බව ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැහැදිලි කර ඇත. බදු බර වැඩි කිරීමෙන් රටේ දූෂණ මට්ටම ද ඉහළ යනු ඇතැයි ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පවසා තිබිණි.",
        "එබැවින් අර්බුදකාරී කාලයක් මධ්‍යයේ යෝජනා ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ ප්‍රායෝගික පැත්ත ද සොයා බලන ලෙස අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ IMF කණ්ඩායමෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබුණි. වරක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ පසු ප්‍රතිපලදායක නොවන යෝජනා හඳුන්වාදීමේ වැදගත්කම ඔහු අවධාරනය කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර පසුගිය සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ සිටි ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර නිලධාරීන් ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ සිටි IMF කණ්ඩායම හමුවීමට ඇති කැමැත්ත අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට දන්වා තිබුණි. අඟහරුවාදා (ජුනි 28) එක්සත් ජනපද රජයේ නියෝජිත පිරිස IMF නියෝජිත පිරිස හමුවී ඇති බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "IMF කණ්ඩායම බදාදා (ජුනි 29) SJB නායක, ශ්‍රීලනිප නායක සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සහ ශ්‍රීලනිප ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයින් පිරිසක් ද හමුවිය.",
        "IMF කණ්ඩායම බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සිය උපදේශන අවසන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, රජයේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසාධන සැලැස්ම අවසන් කිරීම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ පැවති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ රැස්වීමේදී ගන්නා ලද තීරණ මත ද රඳා පවතින බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "IMF මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් මෙම රැස්වීම් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (ජූනි 30) අවසන් විය.",
        "IMF ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සාකච්ඡා සතුටුදායක ලෙස ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇති අතර එය “නුදුරු කාලීනව EFF (පුළුල් කරන ලද අරමුදල් පහසුකම) පිළිබඳ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීමේ අරමුණින් අතථ්‍ය සාකච්ඡා දිගටම කරගෙන යනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ පණිවිඩයේ පේළි අතර කියවීමෙන්, අරමුදලට ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් මුලින් බලාපොරොත්තු වූවාට වඩා ටිකක් වැඩි කාලයක් ගතවනු ඇති බව පෙනේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා උදෑසන\" දේශපාලන තීරුව \"කළු පෙට්ටිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසබා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழு, 2000 ரூபாய்க்கு மேல் வருமானம் பெறுபவர்களுக்கு வரிகளை பரிந்துரைக்கிறது. மாதாந்தம் 40,000 ஆனால் அது மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் சமூக-பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை மேலும் அதிகரிக்கும் என்பதால் அதைச் செய்ய முடியாது என்று பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்க உடனடியாக கவலை தெரிவித்தார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(\"சண்டே மார்னிங்\" அரசியல் பத்தியில் இருந்து எடுக்கப்பட்டது \"கருப்பு பெட்டி\" \"கேப்டன். வசாபா)",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழு, திங்கட்கிழமை (ஜூன் 27) மற்றுமொரு சுற்றுச் சந்திப்புக்காக பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்கவைச் சந்தித்தது.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பாக சீனாவுடன் உடன்பாட்டை எட்டுவதில் ஏற்பட்ட தாமதம் குறித்து IMF குழு கவலை தெரிவித்திருந்தது. கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான சீனாவின் ஒப்பந்தம் இலங்கையின் ஒட்டுமொத்த கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு திட்டத்திற்கு உதவும் என்பதால், அது முக்கியமானது என்று IMF பராமரித்து வருகிறது.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்பின் போது IMF குழு அதன் சில அவதானிப்புகள் மற்றும் முன்மொழிவுகளையும் விவாதித்தது. சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் குழு முன்வைத்த சில முன்மொழிவுகளை பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்க நிராகரித்திருந்தார், நாட்டில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் அவற்றை மக்கள் தாங்க முடியாது என சுட்டிக்காட்டியிருந்தார்.",
        "பிரதமரின் கவனத்தை ஈர்த்துள்ள முக்கிய திட்டங்களில் ஒன்று, குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் பெரும்பான்மையினரை உள்ளடக்கும் அளவிற்கு வரி விதிக்கக்கூடிய வருமான வரம்பை மேலும் குறைப்பதன் மூலம் நாட்டின் வரி வருவாயை அதிகரிப்பதாகும். IMF குழு ரூ. வருமானம் ஈட்டுபவர்களை சேர்க்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை குறிப்பிட்டது. வரி வலையில் மாதம் 40,000. விக்கிரமசிங்க, உடனடியாக கவலை வெளியிட்டார், இது மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் சமூக-பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை மேலும் அதிகரிக்கும் என்பதால் அதைச் செய்ய முடியாது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறுபவர்களில் பெரும்பான்மையினரைச் சுமையாக ஏற்றி வரி வருவாயை அதிகரிப்பது எதிர்விளைவாக இருக்கும் என்றும், சமூக நலத் தொகையை அரசாங்கம் அதிகரிக்க வேண்டும், அதன் மூலம் பொதுச் செலவினங்களை அதிகரிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் பிரதமர் விளக்கினார். வரிச்சுமையை அதிகரிப்பதன் மூலம் நாட்டில் ஊழலின் அளவு அதிகரிக்கும் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எனவே நெருக்கடியான காலப்பகுதியில் பிரேரணைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கான நடைமுறை பக்கத்தையும் ஆராயுமாறு பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்க சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழுவிற்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்திருந்தார். ஒருமுறை செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டால் எதிர்விளையாத திட்டங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை அவர் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, கடந்த வாரம் இலங்கை வந்திருந்த அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்க திணைக்களம் மற்றும் திறைசேரி அதிகாரிகள் இலங்கை வந்திருந்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழுவைச் சந்திக்க விருப்பம் இருப்பதாக பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவிடம் தெரிவித்திருந்தனர். செவ்வாய்கிழமை (ஜூன் 28) அமெரிக்க அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளை சந்தித்ததாக அறியப்படுகிறது.",
        "IMF குழு புதன்கிழமை (ஜூன் 29) SJB தலைவர், SLFP தலைவர் மற்றும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் SLFP மூத்தவர்கள் குழுவையும் சந்தித்தது.",
        "IMF குழு இலங்கையுடனான தனது ஆலோசனைகளை வியாழன் அன்று நிறைவு செய்தது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், அரசாங்கத்தின் பொருளாதார மீட்புத் திட்டத்தை இறுதி செய்வது, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) ஊழியர்கள் மட்ட சந்திப்பின் போது எடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவுகளைப் பொறுத்தது என்று அறியப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்புகள் வியாழக்கிழமை (ஜூன் 30) ​​முடிவடைந்தது, IMF ஒரு செய்திக்குறிப்பை வெளியிட்டது.",
        "பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் திருப்திகரமாக முன்னேறிவிட்டதாகவும், \"எதிர்காலத்தில் EFF (விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி) குறித்த பணியாளர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவதற்கான\" நோக்கத்துடன் மெய்நிகர் விவாதங்களைத் தொடரும் என்றும் IMF கூறியது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், IMF செய்தியில் உள்ள வரிகளுக்கு இடையில் படிக்கும்போது, ​​இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் ஆரம்பத்தில் எதிர்பார்த்ததை விட இந்த நிதி இன்னும் சிறிது நேரம் எடுக்கும் என்று தெரிகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு காலை” அரசியல் நெடுவரிசை “கருப்புப் பெட்டி",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}