{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Sri-Lanka-rerun-Iraq-protestors-storm-presidential-palace-take-dip-in-pool/108-243993",
  "time_ut": 1661837643,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka rerun, Iraq protestors storm presidential palace, take dip in pool",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka rerun, Iraq protestors storm presidential palace, take dip in pool",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two months after the unprecedented Sri Lankan political turmoil wherein thousands of protestors stormed the presidential palace in Colombo, similar sights were visible in Baghdad city in Iraq. Following the announcement by Iraq's influential Shi'ite Muslim cleric Moqtada al-Sadr to quit politics, his supporters took to the streets in protest and skirmishes between the rival-backed groups and his loyalists ensued.",
        "As per news agency AFP, not less than eight protestors have died in the clashes in Baghdad and security forces resorted to tear gas to disperse an angry crowd.",
        "In videos which are being widely circulated, protestors can be seen storming the presidential palace, akin to visuals from Sri Lanka after President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's ouster from office and exit from the island nation.",
        "At a time when Iraq is witnessing a political deadlock, Sadr's supporters or his rivals' supporters were seen availing luxuries at the president's residence.",
        "Reports suggest that shots were fired by guns and weapons while Sadr's supporters and Tehran-backed units hurled stones at each other. The incident took place in Baghdad's Green Zone, an area where ministries and embassies are situated. The Iraqi military imposed a curfew at 3:30 pm and urged protestors to vacate the Zone.",
        "The country is reeling under a political deadlock since Sadr's party secured the largest majority in October parliamentary elections but did not secure enough seats to form a government. The poll results were followed by his refusal to form a coalition government with his rivals, including the Iran-back Shi'ite. Now, his decision to quit politics has triggered uncertainty for a country of more than four crore population."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Iraq",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baghdad",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iraq",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iraq",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi'ite Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moqtada al-Sadr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baghdad",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Iraq",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sadr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sadr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tehran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baghdad",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Green Zone",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iraqi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sadr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "October",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi'ite",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යළි ක්‍රියාත්මකයි, ඉරාක විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී, තටාකයේ ගිල්වා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දහස් ගණන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී පෙර නොවූ විරූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන කැලඹීමෙන් මාස දෙකකට පසු, ඉරාකයේ බැග්ඩෑඩ් නගරයේ ද එවැනිම දර්ශන දැකගත හැකි විය. ඉරාකයේ බලගතු ෂියා මුස්ලිම් පූජක මොක්තාඩා අල්-සදර් විසින් දේශපාලනයෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස නිවේදනය කිරීමෙන් පසුව, ඔහුගේ ආධාරකරුවන් විරෝධතාවයෙන් වීදි බැස ප්‍රතිවාදී පිටුබලය ලත් කණ්ඩායම් සහ ඔහුගේ හිතවත් පිරිස් අතර ගැටුම් ඇති විය.",
        "AFP පුවත් ඒජන්සියට අනුව, බැග්ඩෑඩ් හි ඇති වූ ගැටුම්වලින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් අට දෙනෙකුට නොඅඩු සංඛ්‍යාවක් මිය ගොස් ඇති අතර කෝපයට පත් පිරිසක් විසුරුවා හැරීමට ආරක්ෂක හමුදා කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළහ.",
        "පුළුල් ලෙස බෙදා හරින වීඩියෝවල, විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී සිටිනු දැකිය හැකිය, එය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ධුරයෙන් නෙරපා හැරීම සහ දිවයිනෙන් පිටවීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දර්ශනවලට සමාන ය.",
        "ඉරාකය දේශපාලන අර්බුදයක් අත්විඳින මොහොතක, සදර්ගේ ආධාරකරුවන් හෝ ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිවාදීන්ගේ ආධාරකරුවන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවසේ සුඛෝපභෝගී භාණ්ඩ ලබා ගන්නා ආකාරය දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "සදර්ගේ ආධාරකරුවන් සහ ටෙහෙරානයේ පිටුබලය ලත් ඒකක එකිනෙකාට ගල් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කරද්දී තුවක්කු සහ ආයුධවලින් වෙඩි තැබූ බව වාර්තා පෙන්වා දෙයි. මෙම සිදුවීම සිදුව ඇත්තේ අමාත්‍යාංශ සහ තානාපති කාර්යාල පිහිටි ප්‍රදේශයක් වන බැග්ඩෑඩ් හි හරිත කලාපයේ ය. ඉරාක හමුදාව සවස 3:30 ට ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවූ අතර කලාපයෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ඔක්තෝබර් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයෙන් සදර්ගේ පක්ෂය විශාලතම බහුතරය ලබා ගත් නමුත් රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් ආසන සංඛ්‍යාවක් ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ හෙයින් රට දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට ලක්ව ඇත. ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිඵලවලින් පසුව ඉරානයට පිටුපා සිටින ෂියාවරුන් ඇතුළු ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිවාදීන් සමඟ සභාග ආන්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම ඔහු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. දැන්, ඔහු දේශපාලනයෙන් සමුගැනීමට ගත් තීරණය කෝටි හතරකට වැඩි ජනගහනයක් සිටින රටක අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයක් ඇති කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉරාකය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැග්ඩෑඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාකය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාකය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂියා මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොක්තාඩා අල්-සදර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටට වඩා අඩුය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැග්ඩෑඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරාකය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සදර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සදර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙහෙරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැග්ඩෑඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාක",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:30 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සදර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi'ite",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மீண்டும், ஈராக் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்டு, குளத்தில் நீராடுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை ஆயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்ட முன்னோடியில்லாத இலங்கை அரசியல் கொந்தளிப்புக்கு இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, ஈராக்கில் உள்ள பாக்தாத் நகரிலும் இதே போன்ற காட்சிகள் காணப்பட்டன. ஈராக்கின் செல்வாக்குமிக்க ஷியைட் முஸ்லிம் மதகுரு மொக்தாதா அல்-சதர் அரசியலில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக அறிவித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, அவரது ஆதரவாளர்கள் எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்து தெருக்களில் இறங்கி போட்டி ஆதரவு குழுக்களுக்கும் அவரது விசுவாசிகளுக்கும் இடையே மோதல் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "செய்தி நிறுவனமான AFP இன் படி, பாக்தாத்தில் நடந்த மோதல்களில் குறைந்தது எட்டு எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் இறந்துள்ளனர் மற்றும் கோபமான கூட்டத்தை கலைக்க பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை நாடினர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச பதவியில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்டு தீவு நாட்டிலிருந்து வெளியேறிய பின்னர், இலங்கையில் இருந்து வரும் காட்சிகளைப் போலவே, பரவலாகப் பரப்பப்படும் வீடியோக்களில், எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிடுவதைக் காணலாம்.",
        "ஈராக் ஒரு அரசியல் முட்டுக்கட்டைக்கு சாட்சியாக இருக்கும் நேரத்தில், சதரின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் அல்லது அவரது போட்டியாளர்களின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்தில் ஆடம்பரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைக் காண முடிந்தது.",
        "சதரின் ஆதரவாளர்களும் தெஹ்ரான் ஆதரவுப் பிரிவினரும் ஒருவரையொருவர் கற்களை வீசிக்கொண்டபோது துப்பாக்கிகள் மற்றும் ஆயுதங்களால் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. பாக்தாத்தின் பசுமை மண்டலத்தில், அமைச்சகங்கள் மற்றும் தூதரகங்கள் அமைந்துள்ள பகுதியில் இந்த சம்பவம் நடந்துள்ளது. ஈராக் இராணுவம் மாலை 3:30 மணிக்கு ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவை விதித்தது மற்றும் போராட்டக்காரர்களை மண்டலத்தை காலி செய்யும்படி வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "அக்டோபர் நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் சதரின் கட்சி மிகப்பெரிய பெரும்பான்மையைப் பெற்றது, ஆனால் அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு போதுமான இடங்களைப் பெறாததால் நாடு ஒரு அரசியல் முட்டுக்கட்டைக்குள் தள்ளாடிக்கொண்டிருக்கிறது. வாக்கெடுப்பு முடிவுகளைத் தொடர்ந்து அவர் ஈரானில் இருந்து பின்வாங்கிய ஷியைட் உட்பட தனது போட்டியாளர்களுடன் கூட்டணி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க மறுத்தார். இப்போது, ​​​​அரசியலில் இருந்து விலகுவதற்கான அவரது முடிவு நான்கு கோடிக்கும் அதிகமான மக்கள்தொகை கொண்ட நாட்டில் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மையைத் தூண்டியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஈராக்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்தாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈராக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈராக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷியா முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொக்தாதா அல்-சதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டுக்கும் குறைவானது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்தாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈராக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்தாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசுமை மண்டலம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈராக்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 3:30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈரான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi'ite",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்குக்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}