{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/බෙලාරුස්--රුසියාව-සමග-න්‍යෂ්ටික-සාකච්ඡාවක/3-395090",
  "time_ut": 1656930163,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බෙලාරුස්, රුසියාව සමග න්‍යෂ්ටික සාකච්ඡාවක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Belarus in nuclear talks with Russia",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko emphasizes that the idea of ​​getting back nuclear weapons to Belarus was caused by Poland's willingness to deploy nuclear weapons from the United States on its territory.",
        "\"The topic came up with the president of Russia after the Poles turned to the Americans and asked them to bring nuclear weapons to Poland. Then I said to President Putin, 'Why are we pretending that nothing is happening?'\" Lukashenko said in his Independence Day speech in the nation's capital, Minsk. said.",
        "On June 25, Lukashenko asked Russian leader Putin to help Belarus adapt to Su-35 aircraft capable of carrying nuclear warheads.",
        "Accordingly, Putin gave the green light to modernize these warplanes and promised that Russia would send tactical missile systems to its ally in the coming months."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Belarusian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alexander Lukashenko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belarus",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poles",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Americans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lukashenko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Minsk",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lukashenko",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belarus",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බෙලාරුස්, රුසියාව සමග න්‍යෂ්ටික සාකච්ඡාවක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බෙලාරුස් වෙත න්‍යෂ්ටික අවි නැවත ලබාගැනීමේ අදහස, පෝලන්තය විසින් එක්සත් ජනපදයෙන් පරමාණුක අවි තම භූමියේ යෙදවීමට ඇති කැමැත්ත නිසා ඇති වූවක් බව බෙලාරුසියානු ජනාධිපති ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ලුකෂෙන්කෝ අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "\"රුසියාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමග මෙම මාතෘකාව මතු වූයේ පෝලන්ත ජාතිකයන් ඇමරිකානුවන් වෙත හැරී පෝලන්තයට න්‍යෂ්ටික අවි ගෙන එන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටීමෙන් පසුවයි. එවිට මම ජනාධිපති පූටින්ට කිව්වේ, ‘අපි කිසිවක් සිදු නොවන බව මවාපාන්නේ ඇයි?’කියායි\" ලුකෂෙන්කෝ ජාතියේ අගනුවර වන මින්ස්ක්හි සිය නිදහස් දින කතාවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "ජූනි 25දා, ලුකෂෙන්කෝ රුසියානු නායක පූටින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ, න්‍යෂ්ටික යුද හිස් රැගෙන යා හැකි Su-35 ගුවන් යානා වෙත අනුවර්තනය වීමට බෙලරුසියාවට උදව් කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම යුද ගුවන් යානා නවීකරණය කිරීමට පූටින් හරිත එළියක් ලබා දුන් අතර ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය තුළ රුසියාව තම මිත්‍ර රට වෙත උපායශීලී මිසයිල පද්ධති යවන බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙලරුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ලුකෂෙන්කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලාරුස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුකෂෙන්කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මින්ස්ක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුකෂෙන්කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලාරුස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்யாவுடன் அணுசக்தி பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் பெலாரஸ்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெலாரஸ் ஜனாதிபதி அலெக்சாண்டர் லுகாஷென்கோ, பெலாரஸுக்கு அணு ஆயுதங்களைத் திரும்பப் பெறுவதற்கான யோசனை அமெரிக்காவிலிருந்து அணு ஆயுதங்களை அதன் பிரதேசத்தில் நிலைநிறுத்த போலந்தின் விருப்பத்தால் ஏற்பட்டது என்று வலியுறுத்துகிறார்.",
        "\"துருவங்கள் அமெரிக்கர்களிடம் திரும்பி, போலந்திற்கு அணு ஆயுதங்களைக் கொண்டுவரச் சொன்னதைத் தொடர்ந்து ரஷ்யாவின் ஜனாதிபதியுடன் தலைப்பு வந்தது. பின்னர் நான் ஜனாதிபதி புட்டினிடம், 'ஏன் எதுவும் நடக்கவில்லை என்று பாசாங்கு செய்கிறோம்?' நாட்டின் தலைநகரான மின்ஸ்கில் நடந்த சுதந்திர தின உரையில் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூன் 25 அன்று, லுகாஷென்கோ, அணு ஆயுதங்களை சுமந்து செல்லும் திறன் கொண்ட Su-35 விமானங்களுக்கு ஏற்ப பெலாரஸ் உதவுமாறு ரஷ்ய தலைவர் புட்டினைக் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "அதன்படி, இந்த போர் விமானங்களை நவீனமயமாக்குவதற்கு பச்சைக்கொடி காட்டிய புதின், வரும் மாதங்களில் ரஷ்யா தனது நட்பு நாடுகளுக்கு தந்திரோபாய ஏவுகணை அமைப்புகளை அனுப்பும் என்று உறுதியளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பெலாரசியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலெக்சாண்டர் லுகாஷென்கோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலாரஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருவங்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லுகாஷென்கோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்ஸ்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லுகாஷென்கோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலாரஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}