{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Singhagiri-celebrates-Golden-Jubilee/34-737573",
  "time_ut": 1657911729,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Singhagiri celebrates Golden Jubilee",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Singhagiri celebrates Golden Jubilee",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "With the completion of 50 successful years of outstanding achievements, that established Singhagiri as the trusted electronics and home appliances partner of every Sri Lankan household, comes the perfect opportunity to congratulate the combined efforts of every Singhagiri employee.",
        "Singhagiri would also like to offer its heartfelt gratitude to its valued consumers for their continued patronage and unwavering trust, which enabled the company to celebrate yet another significant milestone. The company wishes to extend its thanks to its esteemed partners whose sustained cooperation was vital to its progress.",
        "In 1930, Singhagiri General Stores was founded by the late Sugathadasa Marasinghe and was incorporated as a private limited liability company in 1972, resulting in the inception of Singhagiri Ltd.",
        "Singhagiri, now a leading Consumer Electronic Retailer in Sri Lanka, boasts long years of hard work, determination, patience and dedication. From humble beginnings, to have built an empire with a widespread network of showrooms, numerous subsidiaries under the Singhagiri umbrella, and a wealth of employees sharing one vision is indeed admirable.",
        "Singhagiri at its inception dealt with textiles and saw numerous prospects in the electronic boom of 1977 and embraced the opportunity to offer its Sri Lankan clientele premium consumer electronics.",
        "Being the first company to have proudly introduced the acclaimed brand Samsung to the Sri Lankan market, Singhagiri’s product portfolio consists of many more world-renowned brands.",
        "With the prime objective of offering premium brands at affordable prices and thereby empowering Sri Lankans, Singhagiri persists in its unstoppable and steady stride, partnering with dominant brands such as Hisense, an affordable luxury brand that enhances the Sri Lankan lifestyle by adding class and comfort.",
        "The company owns 100 retail showrooms, 12 flagship plaza showrooms and an outlet at the Bandaranaike International Airport’s duty-free terminal. Singhagiri is also represented in 200+ dealer points islandwide.",
        "Backed by engineers and technicians who have mastered their skills with overseas training, Singhagiri offers its loyal customers genuine after-sales services with quality maintenance and repair solutions.",
        "Relentless in its endeavour to serve the Sri Lankan masses with nothing but the best and contribute further to the nation’s economy, Singhagiri has a superior product line-up branded ‘SGL’, consisting of refrigerators and kitchen and home appliances. Moreover, Singhagiri now manufactures SGL branded TVs, a first in the history of Sri Lanka and no doubt a boon to the Sri Lankan economy.",
        "In order to achieve their corporate objective of offering Sri Lankans dependable products and services, Singhagiri supplies Sri Lankan households with Solar and related services as well.",
        "The success of Singhagiri Ltd was acknowledged by the LMD Magazine, nominating Singhagiri as one of the 100 most respected companies in Sri Lanka for the year 2022."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Singhagiri",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Golden Jubilee",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "every Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1930",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri General Stores",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sugathadasa Marasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Consumer Electronic Retailer in Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samsung",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hisense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport’s",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Solar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the LMD Magazine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singhagiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිංහගිරි ස්වර්ණ ජයන්තිය සමරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෑම ශ්‍රී ලාංකික නිවසකම විශ්වාසනීය ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උපකරණ සහ ගෘහ උපකරණ සහකරු ලෙස සිංහගිරි ස්ථාපිත කළ විශිෂ්ට ජයග්‍රහණ වසර 50 සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමත් සමඟම, සෑම සිංහගිරි සේවකයකුගේම ඒකාබද්ධ ප්‍රයත්නයට සුබ පැතීමට කදිම අවස්ථාවක් උදා වේ.",
        "තවත් සුවිශේෂී සන්ධිස්ථානයක් සැමරීමට සමාගමට හැකි වූ ඔවුන්ගේ අඛණ්ඩ අනුග්‍රහය සහ නොසැලෙන විශ්වාසය වෙනුවෙන් සිංහගිරි සිය වටිනා පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට හෘදයාංගම කෘතඥතාව පිරිනැමීමට කැමැත්තෙන් සිටී. සමාගම තම ප්‍රගතියට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වූ තිරසාර සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් යුතු ගෞරවනීය හවුල්කරුවන්ට ස්තුතිය පුද කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "1930 දී, සිංහගිරි ජෙනරල් ස්ටෝර්ස් දිවංගත සුගතදාස මාරසිංහ විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලද අතර 1972 දී පුද්ගලික සීමිත වගකීම් සමාගමක් ලෙස සංස්ථාගත කරන ලද අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස සිංහගිරි ලිමිටඩ් ආරම්භ විය.",
        "සිංහගිරි, දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දෙකු වන අතර, වසර ගණනාවක වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කිරීම, අධිෂ්ඨානය, ඉවසීම සහ කැපවීම ගැන පුරසාරම් දොඩයි. නිහතමානී ආරම්භයේ සිටම, පුළුල් ප්‍රදර්ශනාගාර ජාලයක්, සිංහගිරි කුඩය යටතේ බොහෝ අනුබද්ධ ආයතන සහ එක් දැක්මක් බෙදා හදා ගන්නා සේවක ධනයක් සහිත අධිරාජ්‍යයක් ගොඩ නැගීම ඇත්තෙන්ම ප්‍රශංසනීයයි.",
        "සිංහගිරි එහි ආරම්භයේ දී රෙදිපිළි සමඟ කටයුතු කළ අතර 1977 ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උත්පාතය තුළ බොහෝ අපේක්ෂාවන් දුටු අතර එහි ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට වාරික පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උපකරණ පිරිනැමීමේ අවස්ථාව වැළඳ ගත්තේය.",
        "ප්‍රශංසනීය සන්නාමය වන Samsung ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය වෙළෙඳපොළට සාඩම්බරයෙන් හඳුන්වා දුන් පළමු සමාගම වන සිංහගිරි නිෂ්පාදන පෙළ තවත් ලෝක ප්‍රකට සන්නාම රැසකින් සමන්විත වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සවිබල ගැන්වීමේ ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ ඇතිව, දැරිය හැකි මිලකට, ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සවිබල ගැන්වීමේ ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ ඇතිව, සිංහගිරි සිය නොනවතින සහ ස්ථාවර ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගනිමින්, පන්තිය සහ සුවපහසුව එක් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය ජීවන රටාව වැඩිදියුණු කරන දැරිය හැකි මිලකට සුඛෝපභෝගී සන්නාමයක් වන Hisense වැනි ප්‍රමුඛ සන්නාම සමඟ හවුල් වේ.",
        "සමාගම සතුව සිල්ලර ප්‍රදර්ශනාගාර 100 ක්, ප්‍රධාන ප්ලාසා ප්‍රදර්ශනාගාර 12 ක් සහ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළේ තීරුබදු රහිත පර්යන්තයේ අලෙවිසැලක් ඇත. සිංහගිරි ද දිවයින පුරා අලෙවි නියෝජිත ස්ථාන 200+ නියෝජනය කරයි.",
        "විදේශීය පුහුණුව සමඟින් ඔවුන්ගේ කුසලතා ප්‍රගුණ කළ ඉංජිනේරුවන් සහ කාර්මික ශිල්පීන්ගේ සහාය ඇතිව, සිංහගිරි සිය විශ්වාසවන්ත පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ගුණාත්මක නඩත්තු සහ අලුත්වැඩියා විසඳුම් සමඟ අව්‍යාජ අලෙවියෙන් පසු සේවාවන් ලබා දෙයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට හොඳම දේ හැර අන් කිසිවක් නොමැතිව සේවය කිරීමට සහ ජාතියේ ආර්ථිකයට තවදුරටත් දායක වීමට දරන උත්සාහයේ නොපසුබට උත්සාහයේ, සිංහගිරි සතුව ශීතකරණ සහ මුළුතැන්ගෙයි සහ ගෘහ උපකරණවලින් සමන්විත ‘SGL’ සන්නාමය සහිත උසස් නිෂ්පාදන පෙළක් ඇත. එපමණක් නොව, සිංහගිරි දැන් SGL සන්නාමය සහිත රූපවාහිනී නිෂ්පාදනය කරයි, එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉතිහාසයේ පළමුවැන්න වන අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකයට මහත් ආශිර්වාදයක් වනවාට සැක නැත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට විශ්වාසනීය නිෂ්පාදන සහ සේවා ලබා දීමේ ඔවුන්ගේ ආයතනික අරමුණ සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා, සිංහගිරි ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය නිවාසවලට සූර්ය බලය සහ ඒ ආශ්‍රිත සේවාවන් ද සපයයි.",
        "LMD සඟරාව විසින් සිංහගිරි Ltd හි සාර්ථකත්වය පිළිගෙන ඇති අතර, 2022 වසර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ගෞරවනීය සමාගම් 100 න් එකක් ලෙස සිංහගිරි නම් කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිංහගිරි",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ස්වර්ණ ජුබිලිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෙක්ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1930",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි පොදු වෙළඳසැල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුගතදාස මාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාරිභෝගික ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික සිල්ලර වෙළෙන්දා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්සුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිස්සෙන්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සූර්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LMD සඟරාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහගිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிங்ககிரியில் பொன்விழா கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "50 ஆண்டுகால சிறந்த சாதனைகளை நிறைவு செய்ததன் மூலம், சிங்ககிரியை இலங்கையின் ஒவ்வொரு குடும்பத்திற்கும் நம்பகமான மின்னணுவியல் மற்றும் வீட்டு உபயோகப் பங்குதாரராக நிலைநிறுத்தியதன் மூலம், ஒவ்வொரு சிங்ககிரி ஊழியரின் ஒருங்கிணைந்த முயற்சிகளையும் வாழ்த்துவதற்கான சரியான வாய்ப்பு கிடைத்துள்ளது.",
        "மற்றொரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க மைல்கல்லைக் கொண்டாட நிறுவனத்திற்கு உதவிய அதன் மதிப்புமிக்க நுகர்வோரின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஆதரவு மற்றும் அசைக்க முடியாத நம்பிக்கைக்கு சிங்ககிரி தனது மனமார்ந்த நன்றியைத் தெரிவிக்க விரும்புகிறது. நிறுவனம் அதன் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கு இன்றியமையாத ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்கிய அதன் மதிப்புமிக்க கூட்டாளர்களுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிக்க விரும்புகிறது.",
        "1930 இல், சிங்ககிரி ஜெனரல் ஸ்டோர்ஸ் மறைந்த சுகததாச மாரசிங்கவால் நிறுவப்பட்டது மற்றும் 1972 இல் ஒரு தனியார் வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட பொறுப்பு நிறுவனமாக இணைக்கப்பட்டது, இதன் விளைவாக சிங்ககிரி லிமிடெட் தொடங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது முன்னணி நுகர்வோர் மின்னணு சில்லறை விற்பனையாளராக உள்ள சிங்ககிரி, நீண்ட வருட கடின உழைப்பு, உறுதிப்பாடு, பொறுமை மற்றும் அர்ப்பணிப்பு ஆகியவற்றைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. எளிமையான தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து, பரந்த ஷோரூம்கள், சிங்ககிரி குடையின் கீழ் ஏராளமான துணை நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் ஒரு பார்வையைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ளும் ஊழியர்களின் செல்வம் ஆகியவற்றைக் கொண்ட ஒரு சாம்ராஜ்யத்தை உருவாக்கியது உண்மையில் பாராட்டத்தக்கது.",
        "சிங்ககிரி அதன் தொடக்கத்தில் ஜவுளிகளைக் கையாண்டது மற்றும் 1977 ஆம் ஆண்டின் மின்னணு ஏற்றத்தில் பல வாய்ப்புகளைக் கண்டது மற்றும் அதன் இலங்கை வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு பிரீமியம் நுகர்வோர் மின்னணு சாதனங்களை வழங்கும் வாய்ப்பைத் தழுவியது.",
        "இலங்கை சந்தையில் புகழ்பெற்ற பிராண்டான Samsung ஐ பெருமையுடன் அறிமுகப்படுத்திய முதல் நிறுவனம், சிங்ககிரியின் தயாரிப்பு போர்ட்ஃபோலியோ இன்னும் பல உலகப் புகழ்பெற்ற வர்த்தக நாமங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரீமியம் பிராண்டுகளை மலிவு விலையில் வழங்குதல் மற்றும் அதன் மூலம் இலங்கையர்களை வலுவூட்டுதல் ஆகியவற்றின் பிரதான நோக்கத்துடன், சிங்ககிரி தனது தடையற்ற மற்றும் நிலையான முன்னேற்றத்தில் நிலைத்து நிற்கிறது, உயர்தர வர்த்தக நாமங்களான Hisense போன்றவற்றுடன் கூட்டுசேர்கிறது, இது இலங்கையின் வாழ்க்கை முறையை மேம்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "நிறுவனம் 100 சில்லறை காட்சியறைகள், 12 ஃபிளாக்ஷிப் பிளாசா காட்சியறைகள் மற்றும் பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் கடமையற்ற முனையத்தில் ஒரு விற்பனை நிலையத்தை கொண்டுள்ளது. நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் 200+ டீலர் புள்ளிகளிலும் சிங்ககிரி பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொறியாளர்கள் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்களின் ஆதரவுடன், வெளிநாட்டுப் பயிற்சியின் மூலம் தங்கள் திறன்களை தேர்ச்சி பெற்ற சிங்ககிரி, அதன் விசுவாசமான வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு தரமான பராமரிப்பு மற்றும் பழுதுபார்ப்பு தீர்வுகளுடன் உண்மையான விற்பனைக்குப் பிந்தைய சேவைகளை வழங்குகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு சிறந்த சேவையைத் தவிர வேறெதுவும் இல்லாமல், நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு மேலும் பங்களிக்கும் முயற்சியில் இடைவிடாது, சிங்ககிரியில் குளிர்சாதனப் பெட்டிகள் மற்றும் சமையலறை மற்றும் வீட்டு உபயோகப் பொருட்கள் அடங்கிய 'SGL' என்ற சிறந்த தயாரிப்பு வரிசை உள்ளது. மேலும், சிங்ககிரி இப்போது SGL பிராண்டட் தொலைக்காட்சிகளை உற்பத்தி செய்கிறது, இது இலங்கையின் வரலாற்றில் முதன்முறையாக மற்றும் இலங்கை பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு ஒரு வரப்பிரசாதம் என்பதில் சந்தேகமில்லை.",
        "இலங்கையர்களுக்கு நம்பகமான தயாரிப்புகள் மற்றும் சேவைகளை வழங்குவதற்கான அவர்களின் நிறுவன நோக்கத்தை அடைவதற்காக, சிங்ககிரி இலங்கையின் குடும்பங்களுக்கு சோலார் மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய சேவைகளையும் வழங்குகிறது.",
        "சிங்ககிரி லிமிடெட்டின் வெற்றியை LMD சஞ்சிகை அங்கீகரித்து, 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான இலங்கையில் மிகவும் மதிக்கப்படும் 100 நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றாக சிங்ககிரியை பரிந்துரைத்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பொன்விழா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு இலங்கையர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1930",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி ஜெனரல் ஸ்டோர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகததாச மாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையில் நுகர்வோர் மின்னணு சில்லறை விற்பனையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாம்சங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிசென்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூரிய ஒளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LMD இதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்ககிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}