{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Protest-near-Maldives-Presidents-house-urging-to-send-GR-back/108-240971",
  "time_ut": 1657690195,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protest near Maldives President’s house urging to send GR back",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protest near Maldives President’s house urging to send GR back",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Maldivians and Sri Lankan expatriates are protesting near Maldives President's house urging the authorities to send ousted Sri Lankan President expel from that country, the head of the Maldivian TV Channel told Daily Mirror.  (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldivians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maldivian TV Channel told",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජීආර් ආපසු එවන්නැයි බලකරමින් මාලදිවයිනේ ජනපතිගේ නිවස අසල උද්ඝෝෂණයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නෙරපා හරින ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා එරටින් පිටුවහල් කරන ලෙස බලධාරීන්ට බලකරමින් මාලදිවයින් සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික විදේශිකයන් මාලදිවයින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවස අසල විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වන බව මාලදිවයින් රූපවාහිනී නාලිකාවේ ප්‍රධානියා ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසීය. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින් රූපවාහිනී නාලිකාව පැවසීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜிஆரை திருப்பி அனுப்ப வலியுறுத்தி மாலத்தீவு அதிபர் மாளிகை அருகே போராட்டம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மாலைதீவில் இருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட சிறிலங்கா அதிபரை வெளியேற்றுமாறு அதிகாரிகளை வலியுறுத்தி மாலைதீவு ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்திற்கு அருகில் மாலைதீவு மக்களும் வெளிநாட்டவர்களும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளதாக மாலைதீவு தொலைக்காட்சி சேனலின் தலைவர் டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு தொலைக்காட்சி சேனல் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}