{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-signs-conditional-pardon-for-ex-mp-ranjan-ramanayake-99051/",
  "time_ut": 1661494800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka president signs conditional pardon for ex MP Ranjan Ramanayake",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka president signs conditional pardon for ex MP Ranjan Ramanayake",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka president Ranil Wickremesinghe has signed a document pardoning former opposition MP Ranjan Ramanayake who was imprisoned over charges of contempt of court.",
        "The president’s media division said on Friday August 26 that the presidential pardon was granted to Ramanayake on the condition that he would not make any statement critical or derogatory of the judiciary in the future.",
        "MP Ramanayake apologised to the court’s on Thursday for a remark he had made in August 2017 that led to his imprisonment and a subsequent remark made to the media that he would not retract his original statement.",
        "Tourism Minister Harin Fernando tweeted Thursday evening that his former colleague in the main opposition the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) would be released either on Friday or Monday August 29.",
        "Sri Lanka imprisoned ex MP likely to be released Aug 26 or 29: tourism minister",
        "Since his appointment as president, Wickremesinghe had publicly declared that a pardon for Ramanayake, who has been serving a four-year rigorous imprisonment sentence for contempt of court, would be considered.",
        "Justice Minister Rajapakshe said earlier in August that Ramanayake must first submit an affidavit apologising for the charges against him.",
        "On August 13, Ramanayake signed an affidavit apologising for the charges against him and the process of granting him a presidential pardon was expected to be finalised in under a month, according to his lawyers.",
        "The Supreme Court sentenced the former main opposition Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) parliamentarian to four years’ rigorous imprisonment on January 12, 2021, over contempt of court charges, in connection with disparaging remarks he had allegedly made about the judiciary in August 2017.",
        "Opposition and SJB leader Sajith Premadasa had previously written to former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appealing for a presidential pardon for Ramanayake. The pardon never came, though Rajapaksa controversially pardoned murder-convict and former MP Duminda Silva, drawing criticism from the the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) and others. (Colombo/Aug26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday August 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday or",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday August 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "under a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duminda Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the the Office of the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug26/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් අත්සන් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත සිරගත කර සිටින හිටපු විපක්ෂ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට සමාව දෙන ලියවිල්ලකට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අත්සන් තබා තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දුන්නේ මින් ඉදිරියට අධිකරණය විවේචනය කරන හෝ අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදු නොකිරීමේ කොන්දේසිය මත බවයි.",
        "2017 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී තමා සිරගත කිරීමට හේතු වූ ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් රාමනායක මන්ත්‍රීවරයා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව අයැද සිටි අතර පසුව මාධ්‍යයට කළ ප්‍රකාශය නිසා තමාගේ මුල් ප්‍රකාශය ඉල්ලා අස්කර නොගන්නා බවට.",
        "සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සවස ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ තම හිටපු සගයා සමඟි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) අගෝස්තු 29 සිකුරාදා හෝ සඳුදා නිදහස් කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිරගතව සිටින හිටපු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අගෝස්තු 26 හෝ 29 නිදහස් කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇත: සංචාරක ඇමති",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වසර හතරක බරපතල සිරදඬුවමක් විඳිමින් සිටින රාමනායකට සමාවක් ලබා දීම ගැන සලකා බලන බව වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් වූ දා සිට ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණි.",
        "අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය රාජපක්ෂ අගෝස්තු මස මුලදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රාමනායක ප්‍රථමයෙන් ඔහුට එරෙහි චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව අයැද දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 13 වැනි දින රාමනායක ඔහුට එරෙහි චෝදනාවලට සමාව අයැද දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් අත්සන් කළ අතර ඔහුට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය මාසයකට අඩු කාලයකින් අවසන් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වූ බව ඔහුගේ නීතීඥයෝ පවසති.",
        "2017 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බව කියන ප්‍රකාශ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් 2021 ජනවාරි 12 වැනි දින හිටපු ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට වසර 4ක බරපතළ වැඩ සහිත සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කළේය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මීට පෙර හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ලිඛිතව ලිඛිතව ඉල්ලා සිටියේ රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙසයි. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ (OHCHR) සහ අනෙකුත් අයගේ විවේචනයට ලක්ව රාජපක්ෂ විසින් මිනීමැරුම් වරදකරු සහ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දුමින්ද සිල්වාට මතභේදාත්මක ලෙස සමාව ලබා දුන්නද සමාව කිසිදා නොලැබුණි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා හෝ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරාතුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් යටතේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 26/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள முன்னாள் எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்பி ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு மன்னிப்பு வழங்கும் ஆவணத்தில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் நீதித்துறையை விமர்சிக்கவோ அல்லது இழிவுபடுத்தும் வகையிலான எந்தவொரு அறிக்கையையும் வெளியிடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனையின் பேரில் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தது.",
        "2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் தாம் சிறைத்தண்டனைக்கு இட்டுச் சென்ற கருத்துக்காகவும் அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து தனது அசல் அறிக்கையை மீளப்பெறப் போவதில்லை என ஊடகங்களுக்கு தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்காகவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ராமநாயக்க வியாழக்கிழமை நீதிமன்றில் மன்னிப்புக் கோரினார்.",
        "சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ வியாழன் மாலை தனது ட்விட்டர் பக்கத்தில், பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) ஆகஸ்டு 29 வெள்ளி அல்லது திங்கட்கிழமைகளில் விடுதலை செய்யப்படுவார் என்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை சிறையில் இருக்கும் முன்னாள் எம்.பி., ஆகஸ்ட் 26 அல்லது 29ல் விடுவிக்கப்படுவார்: சுற்றுலா அமைச்சர்",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து, நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததற்காக நான்கு வருட கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனையை அனுபவித்து வரும் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவது பரிசீலிக்கப்படும் என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க பகிரங்கமாக அறிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "நீதி அமைச்சர் ராஜபக்ஷ, தமக்கு எதிரான குற்றச்சாட்டுகளுக்கு முதலில் மன்னிப்புக் கோரும் பிரமாணப் பத்திரத்தை ராமநாயக்க சமர்பிக்க வேண்டும் என்று ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் முன்னதாக கூறினார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 13 அன்று, ராமநாயக்க தமக்கு எதிரான குற்றச்சாட்டுகளுக்கு மன்னிப்பு கோரும் பிரமாணப் பத்திரத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டார், மேலும் அவருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவதற்கான செயல்முறை ஒரு மாதத்திற்குள் இறுதி செய்யப்படும் என்று அவரது வழக்கறிஞர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருக்கு, ஆகஸ்ட் 2017 இல் நீதித்துறையை அவமதித்ததாகக் கூறப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்புக் குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில், உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் 2021 ஜனவரி 12 அன்று நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதித்தது.",
        "ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் SJB தலைவரான சஜித் பிரேமதாச முன்னர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியிருந்தார். கொலைக் குற்றவாளியும் முன்னாள் எம்.பி.யுமான துமிந்த சில்வாவை ராஜபக்ச சர்ச்சைக்குரிய வகையில் மன்னித்தாலும், ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைகளுக்கான உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் அலுவலகம் (OHCHR) மற்றும் பிறரிடமிருந்து விமர்சனங்களுக்கு ஆளான போதிலும், மன்னிப்பு ஒருபோதும் வரவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை அல்லது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதத்திற்குள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்26/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}