{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Tense-situ-at-Kandakadu-Rehab-Centre-One-inmate-killed/108-240029",
  "time_ut": 1656485808,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tense situ at Kandakadu Rehab Centre: One inmate killed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tense situ at Kandakadu Rehab Centre: One inmate killed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An inmate at the Kandakadu Treatment and Rehabilitation Centre in Polonnaruwa was killed following a tense situation between two groups.",
        "Around a thousand detainees were staying at the Kandakadu rehabilitation Centre which is under the Bureau of Commissioner General Rehabilitation.",
        "It was reported that more than 500 inmates have escaped the Centre amidst the clash.",
        "The Police and the Army have taken steps to control the situation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kandakadu Rehab Centre",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kandakadu Treatment and Rehabilitation Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousand",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bureau of Commissioner General Rehabilitation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක්: එක් රැඳවියෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොළොන්නරුව කන්දකාඩු ප්‍රතිකාර හා පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ දෙපිරිසක් අතර ඇති වූ උණුසුම්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් එහි රැඳවියෙකු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් පුනරුත්ථාපන කාර්යාංශය යටතේ පවතින කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ රැඳවියන් දහසක් පමණ රැඳී සිටියහ.",
        "ගැටුම මධ්‍යයේ රැඳවියන් 500 කට වැඩි පිරිසක් මධ්‍යස්ථානයෙන් පැන ගොස් ඇති බව වාර්තා විය.",
        "තත්ත්වය පාලනය කිරීමට පොලිසිය සහ යුද හමුදාව පියවර ගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කන්දකාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්දකාඩු ප්‍රතිකාර හා පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහසක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් පුනරුත්ථාපන කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கந்தகாடு புனர்வாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் பதற்றமான சூழல்: கைதி ஒருவர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொலன்னறுவை கந்தகாடு சிகிச்சை மற்றும் புனர்வாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் இரு குழுக்களுக்கிடையில் ஏற்பட்ட முறுகல் நிலை காரணமாக கைதி ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் புனர்வாழ்வு பணியகத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள கந்தகாடு புனர்வாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் சுமார் ஆயிரம் கைதிகள் தங்க வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த மோதலுக்கு மத்தியில் 500க்கும் மேற்பட்ட கைதிகள் மையத்தில் இருந்து தப்பிச் சென்றதாக தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளது.",
        "நிலைமையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த பொலிஸாரும் இராணுவத்தினரும் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கந்தகாடு மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கந்தகாடு சிகிச்சை மற்றும் மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆணையர் பொது மறுவாழ்வு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}