{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78881",
  "time_ut": 1659726900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB Leader and Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa  Keeps Away from the  Tea Party Given by President Ranil Wickremesinghe after his policy speech in Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB Leader and Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa  Keeps Away from the  Tea Party Given by President Ranil Wickremesinghe after his policy speech in Parliament",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "(excerpt from the  “Ceylon Politics” Column titled “Sajith boycotts Ranil’s Tea Party  in  the  “Ceylon Today” of August 6th 2022)",
        "After the President’s Policy Statement, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa got SJB MPs together and started to discuss about the speech.",
        "At that time, Chief Opposition Whip Lakshman Kiriella asked Premadasa whether they were going to attend the traditional Tea Party. Rajitha Senaratne said the SJB should attend the occasion.",
        "A majority of the SJB MPs had said the party should attend the tea party, except a few who were listening to Premadasa’s speech. MPs Harsha de Silva and Eran Wickramaratne also said they should attend the occasion.",
        "Then Kiriella left saying he was going to the tea party and others can join if a decision is reached.  After that Harsha de Silva, Mayantha Dissanayake, Gayantha Karunatileka, Eran Wickramaratne and Mano Ganesan also left. Only a handful MPs including Ranjith Maddumabandara, Thalatha Atukorale and Rohini Wijeratne remained with Premadasa.",
        "It is reported that Thalatha Atukorale stressed that the party should attend the tea party despite political differences and Premadasa should not behave like a child. Both Atukorale and Rohini Wijeratne left after that."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Keeps Away",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tea Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith boycotts Ranil’s Tea Party",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 6th 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Policy Statement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tea Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mayantha Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayantha Karunatileka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalatha Atukorale",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohini Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thalatha Atukorale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Atukorale",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohini Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB නායක සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති කතාවෙන් පසු ලබාදුන් තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහයෙන් ඈත් වෙයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "(උපුටා ගැනීම 2022 අගෝස්තු 06 වැනිදා \"සිලෝන් ටුඩේ\" පුවත්පතේ \"සජිත් රනිල්ගේ තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහය වර්ජනය කරයි\" යන \"සිලෝන් පොලිටික්ස්\" තීරුවෙන්)",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රකාශයෙන් පසුව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රැස්කරගෙන කතාව ගැන සාකච්ඡා කරන්නට විය.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවේදී විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල ප්‍රේමදාසගෙන් විමසා සිටියේ සාම්ප්‍රදායික තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහයට යන්නද යන්නයි. රාජිත සේනාරත්න කියා සිටියේ මෙම අවස්ථාවට SJB සහභාගී විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාසගේ කතාවට සවන් දෙමින් සිටි කිහිප දෙනෙකු හැර SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් බහුතරයක් පක්ෂය තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහයට සහභාගී විය යුතු බව පවසා තිබුණි. පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා සහ ඉරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට පැමිණිය යුතු බව කියා සිටියා.",
        "එවිට කිරිඇල්ල තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහයට යන බවත් තීරණයකට පැමිණියහොත් තවත් පිරිසකට එක්විය හැකි බවත් පවසා පිටත්ව ගියේය. ඉන් පසුව හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා, මයන්ත දිසානායක, ගයන්ත කරුණාතිලක, එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න, මනෝ ගනේෂන් යන මහත්වරුද පිටව ගියහ. ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සමඟ රැඳී සිටියේ රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර, තලතා අතුකෝරළ, රෝහිණී විජේරත්න ඇතුළු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතළොස්සකි.",
        "දේශපාලන මතභේද නොතකා තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහයට සහභාගි විය යුතු බවත් ප්‍රේමදාස කුඩා දරුවෙකු මෙන් නොහැසිරෙන ලෙසත් තලතා අතුකෝරළ අවධාරණය කළ බව වාර්තා වේ. අතුකෝරළ සහ රෝහිණී විජේරත්න යන දෙදෙනාම ගියේ ඉන් පසුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඈත් කරයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "තේ සාදය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් රනිල්ගේ තේ පැන් සංග්‍රහය වර්ජනය කරයි",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රතිපත්ති ප්රකාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේ සාදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයන්ත දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයන්ත කරුණාතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලතා අතුකෝරළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිණී විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තලතා අතුකෝරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුකෝරලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිණී විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தனது கொள்கை உரையின் பின்னர் வழங்கிய தேனீர் விருந்தில் கலந்துகொள்ளாமல் தவித்த SJB தலைவரும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவருமான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ஆகஸ்ட் 6, 2022 இன் “சிலோன் டுடே” ரணிலின் தேநீர் விருந்தை சஜித் புறக்கணிக்கிறார் என்ற தலைப்பில் “சிலோன் பாலிடிக்ஸ்” பத்தியில் இருந்து ஒரு பகுதி)",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் கொள்கைப் பிரகடனத்தின் பின்னர், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, SJB எம்.பி.க்களை ஒன்று திரட்டி, பேச்சு குறித்து விவாதிக்கத் தொடங்கினார்.",
        "அப்போது, ​​பாரம்பரியமான தேநீர் விருந்தில் கலந்து கொள்ளப் போகிறீர்களா என்று எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல பிரேமதாசவிடம் வினவினார். இந்த நிகழ்வில் SJB கலந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என ராஜித சேனாரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரேமதாசவின் உரையை செவிமடுத்த ஒரு சிலரைத் தவிர, பெரும்பான்மையான SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தேநீர் விருந்தில் பங்கேற்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறியிருந்தனர். பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா மற்றும் எரான் விக்ரமரத்ன ஆகியோரும் இந்த நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பின்னர் கிரியெல்ல தேநீர் விருந்துக்கு செல்வதாகவும், தீர்மானம் எட்டப்பட்டால் ஏனையோர் இணைந்து கொள்ளலாம் எனவும் கூறிவிட்டு சென்றுள்ளார். அதன் பின்னர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, மயந்த திஸாநாயக்க, கயந்த கருணாதிலக, எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன, மனோ கணேசன் ஆகியோரும் வெளியேறினர். ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார, தலதா அத்துகோரள, ரோஹினி விஜேரத்ன உள்ளிட்ட சில பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களே பிரேமதாசவுடன் எஞ்சியிருந்தனர்.",
        "அரசியல் வேறுபாடுகள் இருந்தாலும் தேநீர் விருந்தில் கலந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் எனவும் பிரேமதாச சிறுபிள்ளை போன்று நடந்து கொள்ளக் கூடாது எனவும் தலதா அதுகோரள வலியுறுத்தியதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. அதன் பின்னர் அதுகோரள மற்றும் ரோஹினி விஜேரத்ன இருவரும் வெளியேறினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விலகி வைக்கிறது",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேநீர் விருந்து",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணிலின் தேநீர் விருந்தை சஜித் புறக்கணித்தார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 6, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காப்புறுதி அறிக்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேநீர் விருந்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மயந்த திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயந்த கருணாதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலதா அதுகோரளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹினி விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலதா அதுகோரளே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுகோரலே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹினி விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}