{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78561",
  "time_ut": 1657780920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Saudi Arabian Airlines flight 788  from Maldives to Singapore believed to be carrying Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was the world’s most-tracked flight on Thursday July 14",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Saudi Arabian Airlines flight 788  from Maldives to Singapore believed to be carrying Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was the world’s most-tracked flight on Thursday July 14",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Saudi Arabian Airlines flight from Maldives to Singapore believed to be carrying Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was the world’s most-tracked flight on Thursday (July 14), underscoring massive global interest in the troubled island nation’s political affairs.",
        "Saudia flight 788 from Male was being tracked by almost 5,000 users as of 7.43am GMT (3.43pm Singapore time), according to data from Flightradar24.com, more than three times the number of people tracking a French Air Force plane flying in Europe.",
        "Rajapaksa is taking a Saudi Arabian Airlines plane to Singapore and then Saudi Arabia, the Associated Press reported earlier Thursday, citing a Maldivian official it didn’t name.",
        "The plane, a Boeing 787 Dreamliner is scheduled to land in Singapore at about 7.12pm local time, according to Flightradar24 data.",
        "Rajapaksa fled Sri Lanka for the Maldives on Wednesday, amid widespread protests against his government.",
        "He is expected to tender his resignation letter once at his destination, after missing a self-declared deadline Wednesday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Saudi Arabian Airlines",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "788",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thursday July 14",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabian Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "almost 5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.43pm",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flightradar24.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabian Airlines",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Associated Press",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boeing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "787 Dreamliner",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flightradar24",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෞදි අරාබියානු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් 788 දරන ගුවන් යානය මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රැගෙන යන බවට විශ්වාස කෙරෙන අතර එය ජූලි 14 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ලොව වැඩිපුරම ලුහුබැඳ ගිය ගුවන් යානය විය.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා ගිය සෞදි අරාබියානු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයක් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (ජූලි 14) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රැගෙන යන බවට විශ්වාස කෙරෙන, ලෝකයේ වඩාත්ම ලුහුබැඳ ගිය ගුවන් යානය වූ අතර, අවුල් සහගත දිවයිනේ දේශපාලන කටයුතු පිළිබඳ දැවැන්ත ගෝලීය උනන්දුව අවධාරනය කරයි.",
        "Flightradar24.com හි දත්ත වලට අනුව GMT උදෑසන 7.43 (සිංගප්පූරු වේලාවෙන් සවස 3.43) වන විට Male සිට Saudia 788 ගුවන් යානය භාවිතා කරන්නන් 5,000 කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් විසින් නිරීක්ෂණය කරන ලදී, යුරෝපයේ පියාසර කරන ප්‍රංශ ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයක් නිරීක්ෂණය කරන පුද්ගලයින් සංඛ්‍යාව මෙන් තුන් ගුණයකට වඩා වැඩිය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ සෞදි අරාබියානු ගුවන් සේවයේ ගුවන් යානයක් සිංගප්පූරුවට සහ පසුව සෞදි අරාබියට රැගෙන යන බව මාලදිවයින් නිලධාරියෙකු උපුටා දක්වමින් ඇසෝසියේටඩ් ප්‍රෙස් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා කලින් වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "Flightradar24 දත්ත වලට අනුව, Boeing 787 Dreamliner වර්ගයේ යානය එරට වේලාවෙන් පස්වරු 7.12 ට පමණ සිංගප්පූරුවට ගොඩබෑමට නියමිතයි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ බදාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගියේ ඔහුගේ රජයට එරෙහි පුලුල් විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ය.",
        "බදාදා ස්වයං-ප්‍රකාශිත කාල සීමාවක් මග හැරීමෙන් පසු, ඔහු තම ගමනාන්තයට එක් වරක් සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය භාර දීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෞදි අරාබි ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "788",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 14 බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞදි අරාබි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5,000ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.43 ප.ව",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flightradar24.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි අරාබි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇසෝසියේටඩ් ප්‍රෙස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලින් බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෝයිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "787 ඩ්‍රීම්ලයිනර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flightradar24",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சவூதி அரேபியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானம் 788 மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூருக்கு இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை ஏற்றிச் சென்றதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது, இது ஜூலை 14 வியாழன் அன்று உலகில் அதிகம் கண்காணிக்கப்பட்ட விமானமாகும்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "வியாழன் அன்று (ஜூலை 14) இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை ஏற்றிச் சென்றதாக நம்பப்படும் சவூதி அரேபிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானம் மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "Flightradar24.com இன் தரவுகளின்படி, Male-ல் இருந்து சவுதியா விமானம் 788 ஐ 7.43 GMT (சிங்கப்பூர் நேரப்படி மாலை 3.43 மணி) வரை கிட்டத்தட்ட 5,000 பயனர்களால் கண்காணிக்கப்பட்டது, ஐரோப்பாவில் பறக்கும் பிரெஞ்சு விமானப்படை விமானத்தை கண்காணிக்கும் நபர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை விட மூன்று மடங்கு அதிகம்.",
        "ராஜபக்சே சவூதி அரேபியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தை சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் பின்னர் சவுதி அரேபியாவுக்கும் அழைத்துச் செல்கிறார் என்று அசோசியேட்டட் பிரஸ் வியாழன் முன்னதாக அறிவித்தது, மாலத்தீவு அதிகாரி ஒருவரை மேற்கோள் காட்டி.",
        "விமானம், போயிங் 787 ட்ரீம்லைனர் உள்ளூர் நேரப்படி இரவு 7.12 மணிக்கு சிங்கப்பூரில் தரையிறங்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது என்று Flightradar24 தரவுகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "தனது அரசுக்கு எதிரான பரவலான எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு மத்தியில், ராஜபக்சே புதன்கிழமை இலங்கையிலிருந்து மாலைத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றார்.",
        "புதன் கிழமை தானே அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட காலக்கெடுவை தவறவிட்ட பிறகு, அவர் சேருமிடத்திற்கு ஒருமுறை ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை அனுப்புவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சவுதி அரேபிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "788",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 14 வியாழன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சவுதி அரேபிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 3.43 மணி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flightradar24.com",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றுக்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி அரேபிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசோசியேட்டட் பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக வியாழக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போயிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "787 ட்ரீம்லைனர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flightradar24",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}