{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78173",
  "time_ut": 1655924220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Second  Ship  with 14,712 tonnes rice, 250 tonnes of milk powder and 38 tonnes of medicines  Valued at 670 Million Indian Rupees sent as Gift from Tamil Nadu State to Sri Lanka Leaves Thoothukkudy Port",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Second  Ship  with 14,712 tonnes rice, 250 tonnes of milk powder and 38 tonnes of medicines  Valued at 670 Million Indian Rupees sent as Gift from Tamil Nadu State to Sri Lanka Leaves Thoothukkudy Port",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The second ship, carrying over 15,000 tonnes of relief materials donated by the Tamil Nadu government, sailed from the VOC Port here to Colombo Harbour on Wednesday.",
        "Minister for the Welfare of Minorities and Non-Resident Tamils Gingee K.S. Masthan; Food Minister R. Sakkarapani; Minister for Fisheries and Animal Husbandry Anita R. Radhakrishnan; and Minister for Social Welfare P. Geetha Jeevan flagged off the merchant vessel VTC Sun that carried relief materials worth ₹67.70 crore.",
        "After Chief Minister M.K. Stalin announced that Tamil Nadu would donate 40,000 tonnes of rice, 500 tonnes of milk powder and medicines worth ₹28 crore to the Sri Lankans in view of the economic crisis in the neighbouring country, the first ship with 9,045 tonnes of rice, 50 tonnes of ‘Aavin’ milk powder and 8 tonnes of medicines left Chennai for Colombo on May 18.",
        "The second ship carried 14,712 tonnes rice, 250 tonnes of ‘Aavin’ milk powder and 38 tonnes of medicines. “We have stocked up on more essential commodities to be sent to Sri Lanka. They will be sent once we receive the request from the Sri Lankan government,” Mr. Masthan said.",
        "Commissioner for Welfare of Non-Resident Tamils Jacinta Lazurus, Collector K. Senthil Raj, VOC Port Chairman T.K. Ramachandran, Thoothukudi Mayor Jegan Periyasamy, MLAs G.V. Markandeyan of Vilaathikulam and M.C. Shanmugaiah of Ottapidaaram and officials were present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,712 tonnes",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "250 tonnes",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "38 tonnes",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "670 Million Indian Rupees",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gift",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu State",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Leaves Thoothukkudy Port",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 15,000 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the VOC Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Welfare of Minorities and Non-Resident Tamils Gingee K.S. Masthan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Sakkarapani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anita R. Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67.70",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "M.K. Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,045 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,712 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "K. Senthil Raj",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VOC Port",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "T.K. Ramachandran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoothukudi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jegan Periyasamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.V. Markandeyan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.C. Shanmugaiah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සහල් ටොන් 14,712 ක්, කිරිපිටි ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ ටොන් 38 ක් සමඟ තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්තයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තෑග්ගක් ලෙස එවන ලද ඉන්දීය රුපියල් මිලියන 670 ක් වටිනා දෙවන නෞකාව තුත්තුකුඩි වරායෙන් පිටත් වේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහන ද්‍රව්‍ය ටොන් 15,000කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් රැගත් දෙවන නෞකාව බදාදා VOC වරායේ සිට කොළඹ වරායට යාත්‍රා කළේය.",
        "සුළු ජාතීන්ගේ සහ අනේවාසික දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ සුබසාධන අමාත්‍ය ජින්ගී කේ. මස්තාන්; ආහාර ඇමැති ආර්.සක්කරපානි; ධීවර හා සත්ව පාලන අමාත්‍ය අනීටා ආර්. රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්; සහ සමාජ සුබසාධන අමාත්‍ය පී. ගීතා ජීවන් විසින් රුපියල් කෝටි 67.70ක් වටිනා සහන ද්‍රව්‍ය රැගෙන ගිය VTC සන් වෙළඳ නෞකාව ධජය විවෘත කරන ලදී.",
        "මහ ඇමැති එම්.කේ. අසල්වැසි රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් තමිල්නාඩුව සහල් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි ටොන් 500 ක් සහ රුපියල් කෝටි 28 ක් වටිනා ඖෂධ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට පරිත්‍යාග කරන බව ස්ටාලින් නිවේදනය කළේය, සහල් ටොන් 9,045 ක් සහිත පළමු නෞකාව, ටොන් 50 ‘ආවින්’ කිරිපිටි සහ ඖෂධ ටොන් 8 ක් චෙන්නායි සිට කොළඹ බලා පිටත් වූයේ මැයි 18 වැනිදාය.",
        "දෙවන නෞකාව සහල් ටොන් 14,712 ක්, ‘ආවින්’ කිරිපිටි ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ ටොන් 38 ක් රැගෙන ගොස් ඇත. “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එවීමට අවශ්‍ය තවත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ අපි ගබඩා කර තිබෙනවා. ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලීම ලැබුණු පසු ඒවා එවනවා,” මස්තාන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අනේවාසික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන්ගේ සුබසාධන කොමසාරිස් ජසින්ටා ලාසුරස්, අයකැමි කේ. සෙන්තිල් රාජ්, වීඕසී වරාය සභාපති ටී. රාමචන්ද්‍රන්, තූතුකුඩි නගරාධිපති ජෙගන් පෙරියසාමි, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ජී.වී. විලාතිකුලමේ මාර්කන්දේයන් සහ එම්.සී. ඔට්ටපිඩාරමේ ෂන්මුගයියා ඇතුළු නිලධාරීහු සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටොන් 14,712 කි",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටොන් 250 යි",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටොන් 38 යි",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය රුපියල් මිලියන 670 කි",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "තෑගි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්තය",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තූත්තුකුඩි වරායෙන් පිටත් වේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 15,000 කට වඩා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VOC වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුළු ජාතීන්ගේ සහ අනේවාසික දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ සුබසාධනය Gingee K.S. මස්තාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් සක්කරපානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anita R. Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67.70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්.කේ. ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 500 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 9,045 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 50 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 8 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 14,712 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 250 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 38 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මස්තාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේ. සෙන්තිල් රාජ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VOC වරාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.කේ. රාමචන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූතුකුඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙගන් පෙරියසාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.වී. මාර්කන්දේයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.සී. ෂන්මුගයියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "670 மில்லியன் இந்திய ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள 14,712 டன் அரிசி, 250 டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 டன் மருந்துகளுடன் தமிழ்நாடு மாநிலத்திலிருந்து இலங்கைக்கு பரிசாக அனுப்பப்பட்ட இரண்டாவது கப்பல் தூத்துக்குடி துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து புறப்பட்டது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழக அரசால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 15,000 டன் நிவாரணப் பொருட்களை ஏற்றிக்கொண்டு இரண்டாவது கப்பல் புதன்கிழமை இங்குள்ள VOC துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்திற்கு புறப்பட்டது.",
        "சிறுபான்மையினர் மற்றும் வெளிநாடு வாழ் தமிழர்கள் நலத்துறை அமைச்சர் செஞ்சி கே.எஸ். மஸ்தான்; உணவுத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஆர்.சக்கரபாணி; மீன்பிடி மற்றும் கால்நடை பராமரிப்புத்துறை அமைச்சர் அனிதா ஆர்.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்; 67.70 கோடி மதிப்பிலான நிவாரணப் பொருட்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற VTC சன் என்ற வணிகக் கப்பலை சமூக நலத்துறை அமைச்சர் ப.கீதா ஜீவன் கொடியசைத்து துவக்கி வைத்தார்.",
        "முதலமைச்சருக்குப் பிறகு மு.க. அண்டை நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, தமிழகம் 40,000 டன் அரிசி, 500 டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் ₹28 கோடி மதிப்பிலான மருந்துகளை இலங்கையர்களுக்கு நன்கொடையாக அளிப்பதாக ஸ்டாலின் அறிவித்துள்ளார். 'ஆவின்' பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 8 டன் மருந்துகளுடன் கடந்த மே 18ம் தேதி சென்னையில் இருந்து கொழும்புக்கு புறப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இரண்டாவது கப்பலில் 14,712 டன் அரிசி, 250 டன் ‘ஆவின்’ பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 டன் மருந்துகள் இருந்தன. “இலங்கைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட வேண்டிய அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களை நாங்கள் சேமித்து வைத்துள்ளோம். இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திடம் இருந்து கோரிக்கை கிடைத்தவுடன் அவர்கள் அனுப்பப்படுவார்கள்” என்று திரு மஸ்தான் கூறினார்.",
        "வெளிநாடு வாழ் தமிழர்கள் நல ஆணையர் ஜெசிந்தா லாசரஸ், ஆட்சியர் கே.செந்தில் ராஜ், வ.உ.சி துறைமுக தலைவர் டி.கே. ராமச்சந்திரன், தூத்துக்குடி மேயர் ஜெகன் பெரியசாமி, எம்எல்ஏக்கள் ஜி.வி. விளாத்திகுளத்தைச் சேர்ந்த மார்க்கண்டேயன் மற்றும் எம்.சி. ஓட்டப்பிடாரம் சண்முகையா மற்றும் அதிகாரிகள் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "14,712 டன்கள்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "250 டன்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "38 டன்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "670 மில்லியன் இந்திய ரூபாய்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "பரிசு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு மாநிலம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை தூத்துக்குடி துறைமுகத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறுகிறது",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 டன்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VOC போர்ட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறுபான்மையினர் மற்றும் வெளிநாடு வாழ் தமிழர்கள் நலன் செஞ்சி கே.எஸ். மஸ்தான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.சக்கரபாணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனிதா ஆர். ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "67.70",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.கே. ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,045 டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,712 டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஸ்தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கே.செந்தில் ராஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "VOC போர்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.க. ராமச்சந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெகன் பெரியசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.வி. மார்க்கண்டேயன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.சி. சண்முகையா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}