{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-dmc-warns-of-floods-landslides-after-heavy-rains-99281/",
  "time_ut": 1661934900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka DMC warns of floods, landslides after heavy rains",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka DMC warns of floods, landslides after heavy rains",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s Disaster Management Centre (DMC) has issued warning of possible floods and landslides after the most parts of the island recorded over 150mm rainfall.",
        "People living in the hill country and near river basins are requested to be vigilant with showers or thundershowers expected in the Western, Sabaragamuwa, Central, North-western and Northern provinces as well as in Galle, Matara and Anuradhapura districts.",
        "General public is advised to take precautionary measures against strong winds and lightning. People living in hilly areas (particularly landslide-prone areas) and low-lying areas in river basins are requested to be vigilant, while drivers using hilly roads are advised to be careful as there could be the risk of fallen trees and power cords.",
        "“There is a low-level atmospheric disturbance in the vicinity of Sri Lanka. Therefore, cloudy skies will prevail over the island,” the DMC said in a statement.",
        "Heavy showers above 100 mm are expected in Western, Sabaragamuwa, Central and North-western provinces, while showers above 75 mm may occur at some places in Northern province and in Galle and Matara districts, the DMC said.",
        "Between 0630 hours to 0830 hours on Wednesday, Yakkalamulla in Galle district has recorded 195.0mm rainfall, Boossa in Galle district has recorded 148.5mm rain, Palindanuwara in Kaluthara district has recorded 122.0mm rain while Hiyare in Galle district has recorded 119.0mm rain.",
        "“On the apparent southward relative motion of the sun, it is going to be directly over the latitudes of Sri Lanka during 28th of August to 07th of September in this year,” DMC said.",
        "The nearest towns where the sun will be overhead tomorrow (01) are Kalpitiya, Dunupotagama (Anuradhapura District), Uttimaduwa, Nikawewa (Polonnaruwa District), Vellai (Trincomalee District) and Verugal (Trincomalee District) about 12.10 noon. (Colombo/Aug31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Disaster Management Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Between 0630 hours to 0830 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yakkalamulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "195.0mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boossa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "148.5mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palindanuwara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaluthara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "122.0mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "119.0mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28th of August to 07th of September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dunupotagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uttimaduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vellai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Verugal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 12.10 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අධික වර්ෂාවෙන් පසු ගංවතුර, නායයෑම් ගැන Sri Lanka DMC අනතුරු අඟවයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය (DMC) දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ට වැඩි වර්ෂාපතනයක් වාර්තා වීමෙන් පසු ඇතිවිය හැකි ගංවතුර සහ නායයෑම් පිළිබඳ අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, වයඹ සහ උතුරු පළාත්වල මෙන්ම ගාල්ල, මාතර සහ අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි අපේක්ෂා කරන බැවින් කඳුකරයේ සහ ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිතව ජීවත් වන ජනතාව විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස දන්වා සිටී.",
        "තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් ආරක්ෂාකාරී පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවට දන්වා සිටී. කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල (විශේෂයෙන් නාය යාම් අවදානම් සහිත ප්‍රදේශවල) සහ ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම්වල වෙසෙන ජනතාව අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර කඳුකර මාර්ග භාවිත කරන රියදුරන්ට ගස් කඩා වැටීමේ අවදානමක් පවතින බැවින් ඒ පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙස දන්වා සිටී.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසන්නයේ පහළ මට්ටමේ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹීමක් පවතී. එබැවින් දිවයින පුරා අහස වළාකුලින් බරව පවතිනු ඇත,” DMC නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ වයඹ පළාත්වල මිලිමීටර් 100 ට වැඩි තද වැසි අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර උතුරු පළාතේ සහ ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 75 ට වැඩි වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව DMC පවසයි.",
        "බදාදා පැය 0630 සිට පැය 0830 දක්වා කාලය තුළ ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ යක්කලමුල්ලට මිලිමීටර් 195.0ක වර්ෂාපතනයක් ද, ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ බූස්සෙන් මිලිමීටර් 148.5ක වර්ෂාපතනයක් ද, කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පාලින්දනුවරට මිලිමීටර් 122.0ක වර්ෂාපතනයක් ද, ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ හියාරේට මිලිමීටර් 11.0ක වර්ෂාපතනයක් ද වාර්තා වී තිබේ.",
        "\"පැහැදිලි ලෙස සූර්යයාගේ දකුණට සාපේක්ෂ චලිතය මත, එය මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු 28 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 07 දක්වා කාලය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අක්ෂාංශ වලට සෘජුවම ඉහළින් පවතිනු ඇත,\" DMC පවසයි.",
        "හෙට (01) දහවල් 12.10 ට පමණ කල්පිටිය, දුනුපොටගම (අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය), උට්ටිමඩුව, නිකවැව (පොළොන්නරුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කය), වෙල්ලෙයි (ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දිස්ත්‍රික්කය) සහ වෙරුගල් (ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දිස්ත්‍රික්කය) යන නගරවලට ආසන්නතම නගර වේ. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීඑම්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය 0630 සිට පැය 0830 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යක්කලමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "195.0 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බූස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "148.5 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලින්දනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "122.0 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "119.0 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 28 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 07 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුනුපොටගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උත්තිමඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ලයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙරුගල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12.10ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கனமழைக்கு பிறகு வெள்ளம், நிலச்சரிவு ஏற்படும் என இலங்கை டிஎம்சி எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அனர்த்த முகாமைத்துவ நிலையம் (DMC) தீவின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகளில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றர் மழைவீழ்ச்சி பதிவானதை அடுத்து, வெள்ளம் மற்றும் மண்சரிவு ஏற்படக்கூடிய அபாய எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமேல் மற்றும் வடமாகாணங்களிலும் காலி, மாத்தறை மற்றும் அனுராதபுரம் மாவட்டங்களிலும் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுவதால் மலையகத்தில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் அவதானத்துடன் இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கத்திலிருந்து முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகிறார்கள். மலைப்பாங்கான பகுதிகளில் (குறிப்பாக மண்சரிவு அபாயம் உள்ள பகுதிகள்) மற்றும் ஆற்றங்கரையில் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் விழிப்புடன் இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள், அதே நேரத்தில் மலைப்பாங்கான சாலைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தும் சாரதிகள் மரங்கள் மற்றும் மின் கம்பிகள் முறிந்து விழும் அபாயம் இருப்பதால் கவனமாக இருக்குமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "“இலங்கையை அண்மித்த பகுதியில் குறைந்த அளவிலான வளிமண்டலக் குழப்பம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. எனவே, தீவு முழுவதும் வானம் மேகமூட்டத்துடன் காணப்படும்” என்று டிஎம்சி அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழைவீழ்ச்சி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் அதேவேளை, வடமாகாணத்திலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என தி.மு.க.",
        "புதன்கிழமை 0630 மணி முதல் 0830 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்கு இடையில் காலி மாவட்டத்தின் யக்கலமுல்லையில் 195.0 மி.மீ மழையும், காலி மாவட்டத்தின் பூஸ்ஸ 148.5 மி.மீ மழையும், களுத்துறை மாவட்டத்தின் பாலிந்தநுவரவில் 122.0 மி.மீ மழையும், காலி மாவட்டத்தின் ஹியாரே.1.0 மி.மீ மழையும் பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "\"சூரியனின் தெற்கு நோக்கிய ஒப்பீட்டு இயக்கத்தில், அது இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 28 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 07 வரை இலங்கையின் அட்சரேகைகளுக்கு மேல் நேரடியாக இருக்கும்\" என்று DMC தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாளை (01) நண்பகல் 12.10 மணியளவில் கல்பிட்டி, துனுபோதகம (அநுராதபுரம் மாவட்டம்), உத்திமடுவ, நிகவெவ (பொலன்னறுவை மாவட்டம்), வெள்ளை (திருகோணமலை மாவட்டம்) மற்றும் வெருகல் (திருகோணமலை மாவட்டம்) ஆகியவை சூரியன் தலைக்கு மேல் இருக்கும் அருகிலுள்ள நகரங்களாகும். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஎம்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "0630 மணி முதல் 0830 மணி வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யக்கலமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "195.0மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "148.5மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலிந்தநுவர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "122.0மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "119.0மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 28 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 07 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துனுபோதகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உத்திமடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெருகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12.10 மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}