{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/එක්ස්ප්‍රස්-පර්ල්-නැවේ-ගින්නෙන්--කෝටි-නවයක්-වතුරේ/101-618641",
  "time_ut": 1661263227,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් නැවේ ගින්නෙන්  කෝටි නවයක් වතුරේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Nine crores in the fire of Express Pearl ship",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The chairman of the Maritime Environment Protection Authority, lawyer Darshanee Lahandapura, said that nine million thirty-eight million fifty-seven thousand two hundred and ninety-three rupees have been spent so far to clean the coastline from Mannar to Hambantota Kirinda by removing the plastic and waste released by the ship M.V Express Pearl, which caught fire in Sri Lanka's waters. Mrs. said.",
        "Mrs. Lahandapura also said that it will take several more years to remove the plastic and chemicals released from the ship's containers and completely clean the coastline.",
        "She mentioned that 1600 metric tons of plastic beads and chemicals released from the ship have been deposited in warehouses acquired on rental basis in Pamunugama area and further steps will be taken based on legal advice.",
        "The container ship MV Express Pearl, which was carrying goods under the flag of Singapore, caught fire and sank 9 nautical miles from the port of Colombo on June 02 last year.",
        "The Chairperson of the Marine Environment Protection Authority said this in a discussion held at the Urban Development and Housing Ministry Auditorium in Setsiripa, Battaramulla."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nine",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Express Pearl",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Maritime Environment Protection Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshanee Lahandapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Kirinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Express Pearl",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lahandapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "several more years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1600 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pamunugama area",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Express Pearl",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 nautical miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 02 last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Marine Environment Protection Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Urban Development and Housing Ministry Auditorium",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Setsiripa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් නැවේ ගින්නෙන්  කෝටි නවයක් වතුරේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙරට මුහුදු සීමාවේදී ගිනිබත් වූ එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් ( M.V Express Pearl ) නෞකාවෙන් නිකුත්වූ ප්ලාස්ටික් හා අපද්‍රව්‍ය ඉවත්කොට මන්නාරම සිට හම්බන්තොට කිරින්ද දක්වා වූ වෙරළ තීරය පිරිසිදු කිරීමට මෙතෙක්  රුපියල් නව කෝටි තිස් අටලක්ෂ පනස්හත් දහස් දෙසීය අනූ තුනක්  වැයවී ඇති බව සමුද්‍රීය පරිසර ආරක්ෂණ අධිකාරියේ සභාපතිනී නීතීඥ දර්ශනී ළහඳපුර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "එම නෞකාවේ බහාලුම් වලින් නිකුත්වන ප්ලාස්ටික් හා රසායන ද්‍රව්‍යයන් ඉවත්කොට මුහුදු තීරය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පිරිසිදු කිරීමට තවත් වසර කිහිපයක්ම ගතවනු ඇතැයි ද ළහඳපුර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "මේ වනවිට නෞකාවෙන් නිකුත්වූ ප්ලාස්ටික් පබළු හා රසායන ද්‍රව්‍යයන් මෙට්ට්‍ර්ක් ටොන් 1600 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් පමුණුගම ප්‍රදේශයේ කුලී පදනම මත ලබාගත් ගබඩාවල තැන්පත් කර තිබෙන බවත් නීති උපදෙස් මත ඒවා සම්බන්ධ ඉදිරි පියවර ගන්නා බවත් ඇය  සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "සිංගප්පූරු ධජය යටතේ භාණ්ඩ රැගෙන යාත්‍ර කරමින් තිබූ එම්.වී එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් බහාලුම් ප්‍රවාහන නෞකාව කොළඹ වරායට නාවික සැතපුම් 9ක් දුරින් ගිනි ගෙන මුහුදුබත් වූයේ පසුගිය වසරේ ජුනි මස 02 වැනිදාය.",
        "බත්තරමුල්ල, සෙත්සිරිපායේ පිහිටි නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යංශ ශ්‍රවණාගාරයේදී  පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවකදී සමුද්‍රීය පරිසර ආරක්ෂණ අධිකාරියේ සභාපතිනිය මෙි බව කීවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නවය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්ස්ප්රස් පර්ල්",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍රීය පරිසර ආරක්ෂණ අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශනී ලහඳපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන නවයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට කිරින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්ප්රස් පර්ල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලහඳපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් වසර කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1600 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පමුණුගම ප්‍රදේශයේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්ප්රස් පර්ල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික සැතපුම් 9 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ ජූනි 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර පරිසර ආරක්ෂණ අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශ ශ්‍රවණාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙට්සිරිපා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் கப்பலில் ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் ஒன்பது கோடி!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மன்னார் முதல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை கிரிந்த வரையிலான கடற்கரையை பிளாஸ்டிக் அகற்றி சுத்தப்படுத்துவதற்கு இதுவரை ஒன்பது இலட்சத்து முப்பத்தெட்டு இலட்சத்து ஐம்பத்தேழாயிரத்து இருநூற்று தொண்ணூற்று மூன்று ரூபா செலவிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கடல்சார் சுற்றாடல் பாதுகாப்பு அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் சட்டத்தரணி தர்ஷனி லஹந்தபுர தெரிவித்தார். மற்றும் இலங்கையின் கடற்பரப்பில் தீப்பிடித்த M.V Express Pearl என்ற கப்பலால் வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட கழிவுகள் என திருமதி.",
        "கப்பலின் கொள்கலன்களில் இருந்து வெளியாகும் பிளாஸ்டிக் மற்றும் இரசாயனங்களை அகற்றி கரையோரத்தை முழுமையாக சுத்தப்படுத்த இன்னும் பல வருடங்கள் ஆகும் என்றும் திருமதி லஹந்தபுர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கப்பலில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட 1600 மெற்றிக் தொன் பிளாஸ்டிக் மணிகள் மற்றும் இரசாயனங்கள் பமுனுகம பிரதேசத்தில் வாடகை அடிப்படையில் பெறப்பட்ட களஞ்சியசாலைகளில் வைப்புச் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் சட்ட ஆலோசனையின் அடிப்படையில் மேலதிக நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சிங்கப்பூரின் கொடியுடன் பொருட்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற MV Express Pearl என்ற கொள்கலன் கப்பல் கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 02 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து 9 கடல் மைல் தொலைவில் தீப்பிடித்து மூழ்கியது.",
        "பத்தரமுல்லை செத்சிறிபாவில் உள்ள நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சின் கேட்போர் கூடத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் கடல் சுற்றாடல் பாதுகாப்பு அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்பது",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷநீ லஹந்தபுரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை கிரிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லஹந்தபுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் பல ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1600 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பமுனுகம பிரதேசம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 கடல் மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு ஜூன் 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடல் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சக ஆடிட்டோரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செட்சிரிபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}