{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62233213",
  "time_ut": 1658271446,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: ජනපති අසුන සඳහා වන තරගය සුළු මොහොතකින්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: The race for the presidential seat in a few moments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliamentarians of Sri Lanka are scheduled to vote for a new president today due to former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa fleeing the country and resigning amid public protests held due to the country's economic crisis.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, nominated by the ruling party for that role, is considered to be the leading candidate in this race.",
        "But the protesters want to see Wickremesinghe also resign.",
        "Wickramasinghe faces a serious challenge from Dallas Alahapperuma, a member of the ruling party who has the support of the main opposition.",
        "Whoever is elected by Parliament will be tasked with serving the remainder of Gotabaya's term, which ends in November 2024.",
        "Currently, Sri Lanka is a bankrupt state and is facing acute shortages of food, fuel and other basic supplies.",
        "The country needs a stable government in order to start new negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to recover the country from the crisis.",
        "225 Members of Parliament have qualified to vote today (July 20). The candidate who gets more than half of the votes wins the contest.",
        "It is a three-way contest between Wickramasinghe, Alahaperuma, and National People's Power leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "a few moments",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahaperuma",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: ජනපති අසුන සඳහා වන තරගය සුළු මොහොතකින්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය නිසාවෙන් පැවැත්වූ මහජන විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ රටින් පළාගොස් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සඳහා අද ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට නියමිත ය.",
        "එම භූමිකාව සඳහා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය විසින් නම්කෙරුණු වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මෙම තරගයේ ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටින අපේක්ෂකයා ලෙස සැලකේ.",
        "එහෙත් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට අවශ්‍ය වී ඇත්තේ වික්‍රමසිංහ ද ඉල්ලා අස්වනු දැකීම යි.",
        "ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සහාය ඇති ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුමගෙන් වික්‍රමසිංහට බරපතල අභියෝගයක් එල්ලවේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් තේරී පත්වන්නේ කවුරුන් වුව ද, 2024 නොවැම්බරයෙන් අවසන් වන ගෝඨාභයගේ ඉතිරි ධුරකාලයේ දී සේවය කිරීමේ වගකීම ඔහුට හිමිවනු ඇත.",
        "මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංකොලොත් රාජ්‍යයක් වන අතර ආහාර, ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් මූලික සැපයුම්වල උග්‍ර හිඟයකට මුහුණදී සිටියි.",
        "රට පත්ව ඇති අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩගැනීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමග නව සාකච්ඡා ඇරඹීමට නම් ස්ථාවර රජයක් රටට අවශ්‍ය ය.",
        "අද (ජුලි 20) ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකු සුදුසුකම් ලබා ඇත. මනාපවලින් අඩකට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබන අපේක්ෂකයා මෙම තරගය ජයගනියි.",
        "එය වික්‍රමසිංහ, අලහපෙරුම, සහ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක අතර තුන්කොන් තරගයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සුළු මොහොතක්",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩකටත් වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahaperuma",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජන බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: இன்னும் சில நிமிடங்களில் அதிபர் பதவிக்கான போட்டி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக மக்கள் போராட்டத்திற்கு மத்தியில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி இராஜினாமா செய்ததன் காரணமாக புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "அந்த பதவிக்காக ஆளும் கட்சியால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவே இந்தப் போட்டியில் முன்னணி வேட்பாளராகக் கருதப்படுகிறார்.",
        "ஆனால் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்று விரும்புகிறார்கள்.",
        "பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்றுள்ள ஆளும் கட்சி உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவிடமிருந்து விக்கிரமசிங்க கடும் சவாலை எதிர்கொள்கிறார்.",
        "2024 நவம்பரில் முடிவடையும் கோட்டாபயவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக்காலம் வரை பாராளுமன்றத்தால் தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டவர் பணிக்கப்படுவார்.",
        "தற்போது, ​​இலங்கை ஒரு திவாலான மாநிலமாக உள்ளது மற்றும் உணவு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பிற அடிப்படைப் பொருட்களின் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்கிறது.",
        "நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்பதற்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) புதிய பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை தொடங்க நாட்டிற்கு நிலையான அரசாங்கம் தேவை.",
        "225 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்று (ஜூலை 20) வாக்களிக்க தகுதி பெற்றுள்ளனர். பாதிக்கு மேல் வாக்குகள் பெறும் வேட்பாளர் போட்டியில் வெற்றி பெறுவார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க, அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் மும்முனைப் போட்டி நிலவுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சில கணங்கள்",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதிக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alahaperuma",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}