{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/விசாரிக்குமாறு-காஞ்சன-கோரிக்கை/175-299954",
  "time_ut": 1657259611,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "விசாரிக்குமாறு காஞ்சன கோரிக்கை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kanchan requests to investigate",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Power and Energy Kanjana Wijesekara has asked COB Committee Chairman Saritha Herath to inquire into the allegations leveled by the Chairman of the Public Utilities Commission.",
        "Sri Lanka Public Utilities Commission Chairman Janaka Ratnayaka, who was present at the COPE committee yesterday, mentioned that petrol and diesel can be sold in the country at a price of less than 250 rupees.",
        "In this situation, Minister Kanchana Wijesekara has also requested that an investigation should be conducted in a Twitter post.",
        "I would like to kindly request @charith9 to call CPC & myself to the CPOE to inquire into the allegations made by PUCSL Chairman on FuelPricing & Procurement. Inquiry should be held on if the COPE & the Public was misled by PUCSL Chairman or CPC on fuel pricing & any other matter"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "COB Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saritha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than 250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPOE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FuelPricing & Procurement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the COPE & the Public",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පරීක්ෂණයක් කරන ලෙස කාංචන් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා විසින් එල්ල කර ඇති චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බලන ලෙස විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංජන විජේසේකර මහතා COB කමිටු සභාපති සාරිතා හේරත් මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "ඊයේ කෝප් කමිටුවට පැමිණි ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක සඳහන් කළේ රුපියල් 250ට අඩු මිලකට රට තුළ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් අලෙවි කළ හැකි බවයි.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය මත අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා ද ට්විටර් සටහනක් තබමින් මේ පිළිබඳව පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්විය යුතු බව ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "ඉන්ධන මිල සහ ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් PUCSL සභාපතිවරයා විසින් කරන ලද චෝදනා පිළිබඳව විමසීම සඳහා CPC සහ මා CPOE වෙත කැඳවන ලෙස මම @charith9 ගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටිමි. PUCSL සභාපති හෝ CPC විසින් ඉන්ධන මිල සහ වෙනත් යම් කරුණක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෝප් කමිටුව සහ මහජනතාව නොමඟ යවා තිබේද යන්න පිළිබඳව පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්විය යුතුය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "COB කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරිතා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 ට අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPOE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන මිලකරණය සහ ප්‍රසම්පාදනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව සහ මහජනතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விசாரிக்குமாறு காஞ்சன கோரிக்கை",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் முன்வைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் குறித்து, விசாரிக்குமாறு மின்சக்தி மற்றும் வலுசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர,  கோப் குழுத் தலைவர் சரித்த ஹேரத்திடம் கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று முன்தினம் கோப் குழுவில் முன்னிலையான இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்னாயக்க, பெற்றோல் மற்றும் டீசலை ஏறத்தாழ 250 ரூபாயை விட குறைவான விலையில் நாட்டில் விற்பனை செய்ய முடியும் என குறிப்பிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில், ட்விட்டர் பதிவொன்றில் அது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "I would like to kindly request @charith9 to call CPC & myself to the CPOE to inquire into the allegations made by PUCSL Chairman on FuelPricing & Procurement. Inquiry should be held on if the COPE & the Public was misled by PUCSL Chairman or CPC on fuel pricing & any other matter"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "COB குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPOE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் விலை மற்றும் கொள்முதல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப் மற்றும் பொதுமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}