{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79197",
  "time_ut": 1661540760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian High Commission in Colombo  Responds Strongly to Chinese Envoy’s Article in Sri Lankan Media Saying “His violation of basic diplomatic etiquette may be a personal trait or reflecting a larger national attitude”",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian High Commission in Colombo  Responds Strongly to Chinese Envoy’s Article in Sri Lankan Media Saying “His violation of basic diplomatic etiquette may be a personal trait or reflecting a larger national attitude”",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sharply reacting to recent remarks of the Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka, on the controversial visit of a Chinese military vessel from August 16 to 22, the Indian mission in Colombo said they “violated basic diplomatic etiquette” and “gave away” the purpose of the vessel’s visit.",
        "In a strongly worded Twitter thread late on Saturday, the Indian High Commission said it had noted the remarks of the Chinese Ambassador. “His violation of basic diplomatic etiquette may be a personal trait or reflecting a larger national attitude,” the Indian mission said.",
        "“His view of Sri Lanka’s northern neighbour may be coloured by how his own country behaves. India, we assure him, is very different. His imputing a geopolitical context to the visit of a purported scientific research vessel is a giveaway,” it said.",
        "India’s uncharacteristically direct response referring to the diplomat and China came a day after Chinese Ambassador Qi Zhenhong wrote in Sri Lanka media about countries “far or near bullying Sri Lanka”. The Ambassador had also observed that Sri Lanka overcame “aggression from its northern neighbour 17 times”.",
        "He had also connected U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s visit to Taiwan with the “successful” docking of Chinese satellite-tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 in the southern Hambantota port, and argued for China and Sri Lanka “jointly safeguarding each other’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity”.",
        "The ship, which deferred its arrival by a few days on Sri Lanka’s request, after India and the U.S. raised concern, left on August 22 after a week.",
        "The Indian High Commission further said: “Opaqueness and debt driven agendas are now a major challenge, especially for smaller nations. Recent developments are a caution. Sri Lanka needs support, not unwanted pressure or unnecessary controversies to serve another country’s agenda.”",
        "Sri Lanka’s Chinese debt is in focus in the context of the island nation’s attempts to restructure its foreign loans to qualify for IMF support."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian High Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16 to 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S. House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nancy Pelosi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 22 after a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "\"ඔහුගේ මූලික රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආචාර විධි උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම පුද්ගලික ලක්ෂණයක් හෝ විශාල ජාතික ආකල්පයක් පිළිබිඹු කිරීමක් විය හැකිය\" යනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මාධ්‍යවල චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ ලිපියට කොළඹ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය දැඩි ලෙස ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගෝස්තු 16 සිට 22 දක්වා චීන හමුදා යාත්‍රාවක ආන්දෝලනාත්මක සංචාරය පිළිබඳ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ මෑත ප්‍රකාශයන්ට තියුණු ලෙස ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින්, කොළඹ ඉන්දීය දූත පිරිස “මූලික රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආචාර විධි කඩ කර” සහ “ඉවත් දුන්” බව පැවසීය. යාත්රාවේ සංචාරය.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා අගභාගයේදී දැඩි වචන සහිත ට්විටර් ත්‍රෙඩ් එකක ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය කියා සිටියේ චීන තානාපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශය තමන් විසින් සටහන් කර ඇති බවයි. \"ඔහුගේ මූලික රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ආචාර විධි උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම පුද්ගලික ලක්ෂණයක් හෝ විශාල ජාතික ආකල්පයක් පිළිබිඹු කිරීමක් විය හැකිය\" යනුවෙන් ඉන්දීය දූත මණ්ඩලය පවසයි.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උතුරු අසල්වැසියා පිළිබඳ ඔහුගේ දැක්ම ඔහුගේම රට හැසිරෙන ආකාරය අනුව වර්ණවත් විය හැකිය. ඉන්දියාව, අපි ඔහුට සහතික වෙනවා, එය බෙහෙවින් වෙනස් ය. ඔහු විසින් කියනු ලබන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක සංචාරයට භූ දේශපාලනික සන්දර්භයක් ආරෝපණය කිරීම පරිත්‍යාගයකි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයා සහ චීනය ගැන සඳහන් කරමින් ඉන්දියාවේ අසාමාන්‍ය ලෙස සෘජු ප්‍රතිචාරය පැමිණියේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හිරිහැර කරන දුර හෝ ආසන්න\" රටවල් ගැන ශ්‍රී ලංකා මාධ්‍යවල ලිවීමෙන් දිනකට පසුවය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “17 වතාවක් උතුරු අසල්වැසියාගේ ආක්‍රමණ” ජයගත් බව තානාපතිවරයා නිරීක්ෂණය කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහු එක්සත් ජනපද සභානායක නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ තායිවාන සංචාරය දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායේ යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 චීන චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව “සාර්ථක” නැව්ගත කිරීම සමඟ සම්බන්ධ කර ඇති අතර, චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “එකිනෙකාගේ ස්වෛරීත්වය, ස්වාධීනත්වය සහ ඒකාබද්ධව ආරක්ෂා කිරීම” සඳහා තර්ක කළේය. භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාව\".",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය කනස්සල්ලෙන් පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉල්ලීම මත එහි පැමිණීම දින කිහිපයකින් කල් දැමූ නෞකාව සතියකට පසු අගෝස්තු 22 දින පිටත් විය.",
        "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය තවදුරටත් මෙසේ පැවසීය: “පාර විනිවිදභාවය සහ ණය මත පදනම් වූ න්‍යාය පත්‍ර දැන් ප්‍රධාන අභියෝගයක්, විශේෂයෙන් කුඩා ජාතීන්ට. මෑත වර්ධනයන් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමකි. වෙනත් රටක න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට සේවය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය අවශ්‍ය මිස අනවශ්‍ය බලපෑම් හෝ අනවශ්‍ය මතභේද නොවේ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහය සඳහා සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමට තම විදේශ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට දිවයින ජාතිය දරන උත්සාහයේ සන්දර්භය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන නය අවධානය යොමු වී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16 සිට 22 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට පසු අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் இலங்கை ஊடகங்களில் சீனத் தூதுவரின் கட்டுரைக்கு கடுமையாகப் பதிலளித்துள்ளது, \"அவரது அடிப்படை இராஜதந்திர ஆசாரங்களை மீறுவது தனிப்பட்ட பண்பாக இருக்கலாம் அல்லது ஒரு பெரிய தேசிய அணுகுமுறையை பிரதிபலிக்கும்\"",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 16 முதல் 22 வரை சீன இராணுவக் கப்பலின் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய பயணம் குறித்து இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவரின் சமீபத்திய கருத்துக்களுக்கு கடுமையாக பதிலளித்து, கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய தூதரகம், அவர்கள் \"அடிப்படை இராஜதந்திர நெறிமுறைகளை மீறி\" மற்றும் \"வழங்கியது\" என்று கூறியது. கப்பல் வருகை.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை பிற்பகுதியில் கடுமையாகச் சொல்லப்பட்ட ட்விட்டர் நூலில், இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் சீனத் தூதரின் கருத்துக்களைக் குறிப்பிட்டதாகக் கூறியது. \"அடிப்படை இராஜதந்திர ஆசாரங்களை அவர் மீறுவது தனிப்பட்ட பண்பாக இருக்கலாம் அல்லது ஒரு பெரிய தேசிய அணுகுமுறையை பிரதிபலிக்கும்\" என்று இந்திய தூதரகம் கூறியது.",
        "“இலங்கையின் வடக்கு அண்டை நாடு பற்றிய அவரது பார்வை அவரது சொந்த நாடு எவ்வாறு நடந்து கொள்கிறது என்பதன் வண்ணமாக இருக்கலாம். இந்தியா மிகவும் வித்தியாசமானது என்று நாங்கள் அவருக்கு உறுதியளிக்கிறோம். விஞ்ஞான ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலின் வருகைக்கு அவர் புவிசார் அரசியல் சூழலைக் கூறுவது ஒரு பரிசாக இருக்கிறது,” என்று அது கூறியது.",
        "சீனத் தூதுவர் குய் ஜென்ஹோங் இலங்கை ஊடகங்களில் \"இலங்கையை அச்சுறுத்தும் தூரத்தில் அல்லது அருகில் உள்ள\" நாடுகளைப் பற்றி எழுதிய ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு, இராஜதந்திரி மற்றும் சீனாவைக் குறிப்பிடும் இந்தியாவின் இயல்பற்ற நேரடியான பதில் வந்தது. இலங்கை \"அதன் வடக்கு அண்டை நாடுகளின் ஆக்கிரமிப்பை 17 தடவைகள்\" முறியடித்ததையும் தூதுவர் அவதானித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் யு.எஸ். ஹவுஸ் சபாநாயகர் நான்சி பெலோசியின் தைவான் விஜயத்தை தெற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் சீன செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 \"வெற்றிகரமான\" கப்பல்துறையுடன் இணைத்திருந்தார். பிராந்திய ஒருமைப்பாடு\".",
        "இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் கவலை தெரிவித்ததையடுத்து, இலங்கையின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் சில நாட்களுக்கு அதன் வருகையை ஒத்திவைத்த கப்பல், ஒரு வாரத்திற்குப் பிறகு ஆகஸ்ட் 22 அன்று புறப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் மேலும் கூறியது: “ஒளிவுமறைவு மற்றும் கடன் உந்துதல் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரல் இப்போது ஒரு பெரிய சவாலாக உள்ளது, குறிப்பாக சிறிய நாடுகளுக்கு. சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்கள் ஒரு எச்சரிக்கை. வேறொரு நாட்டின் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலுக்கு சேவை செய்ய இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவு தேவை, தேவையற்ற அழுத்தங்கள் அல்லது தேவையற்ற சர்ச்சைகள் அல்ல.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவிற்குத் தகுதிபெறும் வகையில் தனது வெளிநாட்டுக் கடன்களை மறுசீரமைக்க தீவு நாடு முயற்சிக்கும் சூழலில் இலங்கையின் சீனக் கடன் கவனம் செலுத்துகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16 முதல் 22 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்சி பெலோசியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம் கழித்து ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}