{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83738/independent-mps-including-wimal-gammanpila-to-back-dullas",
  "time_ut": 1658222700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Independent MPs including Wimal, Gammanpila to back Dullas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Independent MPs including Wimal, Gammanpila to back Dullas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Union of Independent Parties led by MPs Wimal Weerawansa, Udaya Gammanpila and Vasudeva Nanayakkara has decided to back SLPP MP Dullas Alahapperuma in the election in parliament to elect a new President tomorrow (July 20).",
        "This was announced in a media briefing held in Colombo this afternoon.",
        "A parliamentary vote is scheduled at 10.00 a.m. tomorrow to elect a Member of Parliament, who is qualified to be elected as the Head of State, to hold office for the unexpired period of the term of office of the President vacating office.",
        "The names of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, MP Alahapperuma and NPP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake were officially nominated for the presidency at today’s parliamentary session.",
        "MP Alahapperuma’s name was proposed by Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa and it was seconded by Foreign Minister Prof. G.L. Peiris.",
        "Before the nominations were called this morning, the Opposition Leader withdrew his candidacy, announcing support for MP Alahapperuma in the vote.",
        "Meanwhile, the names of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe and National People’s Power (NPP) leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake were also nominated for the post of President."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wimal",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gammanpila",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Union of Independent Parties",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්ට සහායට විමල්, ගම්මන්පිල ඇතුළු ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන විමල් වීරවංශ, උදය ගම්මන්පිල සහ වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ප්‍රමුඛ නිදහස් පක්ෂ එකමුතුව හෙට (ජූලි 20) නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පැවැත්වෙන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දැක්වීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "අද පස්වරුවේ කොළඹ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ධූර කාලය අවසන් නොවන කාලසීමාව සඳහා ධූර දැරීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වීමට සුදුසුකම් ඇති මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමක් හෙට පෙරවරු 10.00 ට පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අලහප්පෙරුම සහ එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් සන්ධානයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් අද පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයේදී නිල වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නම් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ නම විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කළ අතර විදේශ අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් විසින් එය ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "අද පෙරවරුවේ නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීමට පෙර විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට සහය පළ කරමින් සිය අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත්තා.",
        "මේ අතර, වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ සහ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකගේ නම් ද ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා යෝජනා වී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විමල්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගම්මන්පිල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டலஸுக்கு ஆதரவாக விமல், கம்மன்பில உள்ளிட்ட சுயேச்சை எம்.பி.க்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான விமல் வீரவன்ச, உதய கம்மன்பில மற்றும் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தலைமையிலான சுயேட்சை கட்சிகளின் ஒன்றியம் நாளை (ஜூலை 20) புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தலில் SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று பிற்பகல் இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பிலேயே இவ்வாறு தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பதவியை விட்டு வெளியேறும் ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவிக் காலம் முடிவடையாத காலத்திற்கு பதவி வகிப்பதற்கு, அரச தலைவராக தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவதற்கு தகுதியான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பு நாளை காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இன்றைய பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் NPP தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயர் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸவினால் முன்மொழியப்பட்டதுடன், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸினால் அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று காலை வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர், வாக்கெடுப்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக அறிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தனது வேட்புமனுவை வாபஸ் பெற்றார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்களும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விமல்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கம்மன்பில",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சிகளின் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}