{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84389/susil-doesnt-think-gotabaya-will-return-to-politics-again",
  "time_ut": 1660840260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Susil doesn’t think Gotabaya will return to politics again",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Susil doesn’t think Gotabaya will return to politics again",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister Susil Premajayantha says he does not believe that former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will get involved in politics again after returning to Sri Lanka.",
        "Responding to a question from journalists on whether he is expecting the former President to engage in politics again after returning from overseas, he said: “No. Never. I don’t think.”",
        "The Minister of Education made these comments while speaking to reporters following an event held in Jaffna today (18).",
        "In response to another question, the minister denied that the government recently lifted the ban on several Tamil diaspora groups due to the upcoming UN Human Rights Council session in Geneva.",
        "Asked about the forming of an all-party government, he said that most of the political parties have expressed their views positively towards a common programme, but some of them have made their statements towards joining the government and forming a national government.",
        "“You can’t expect to get all the political parties for a national government, but if they agree for a minimum programme that is enough for the moment,” Premajayantha said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය ආයෙත් දේශපාලනයට එයි කියලා සුසිල් හිතන්නේ නැහැ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු යළිත් දේශපාලනයට සම්බන්ධ වනු ඇතැයි තමන් විශ්වාස නොකරන බව අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත පවසනවා.",
        "විදේශගතව සිට මෙරටට පැමිණි හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා යළිත් දේශපාලනයේ නියැලීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන්නේ දැයි මාධ්‍යවේදීන් නැගූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඔහු මෙසේ පැවසීය. කවදාවත් නැහැ. මම හිතන්නේ නැහැ.\"",
        "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයා මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ යාපනයේ අද (18) පැවති උත්සවයකින් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින්.",
        "ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත සැසිවාරය හේතුවෙන් දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරා කණ්ඩායම් කිහිපයකට පනවා තිබූ තහනම රජය විසින් පසුගියදා ඉවත් කළ බව තවත් ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කළ විමසීමකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ බොහෝ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ පොදු වැඩපිළිවෙළකට සුබවාදී අදහස් පළ කර ඇති නමුත් ඇතැමුන් ආණ්ඩුවට එක්වී ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"ඔබට ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ ලබා ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂා කළ නොහැක, නමුත් ඔවුන් අවම වැඩපිළිවෙලකට එකඟ වුවහොත් එය මේ මොහොතේ ප්‍රමාණවත් වේ,\" ප්‍රේමජයන්ත පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய மீண்டும் அரசியலுக்கு வருவார் என சுசில் நினைக்கவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கை திரும்பிய பின்னர் மீண்டும் அரசியலில் ஈடுபடுவார் என தாம் நம்பவில்லை என அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டில் இருந்து நாடு திரும்பிய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மீண்டும் அரசியலில் ஈடுபடுவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கிறீர்களா என ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த அவர், “இல்லை. ஒருபோதும் இல்லை. நான் நினைக்கவில்லை.\"",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இன்று (18) இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வொன்றின் பின்னர் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசும் போதே கல்வி அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மற்றுமொரு கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த அமைச்சர், ஜெனிவாவில் நடைபெறவுள்ள ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை அமர்வு காரணமாக, பல புலம்பெயர் தமிழ் குழுக்களுக்கான தடையை அரசாங்கம் அண்மையில் நீக்கியதை அமைச்சர் மறுத்தார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி ஆட்சி அமைப்பது குறித்து கேட்டதற்கு, பெரும்பாலான அரசியல் கட்சிகள் பொது வேலைத்திட்டம் குறித்து சாதகமாக கருத்து தெரிவித்துள்ளதாகவும், ஆனால் சில கட்சிகள் அரசுடன் இணைந்து தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்து வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளையும் ஒரு தேசிய அரசாங்கத்திற்குப் பெறுவீர்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்க முடியாது, ஆனால் அவர்கள் குறைந்தபட்ச வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு இணங்கினால் அதுவே போதுமானது” என்று பிரேமஜயந்த கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}