{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Pathum-Nissanka-out-of-second-test-with-Covid/342-240829",
  "time_ut": 1657515789,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pathum Nissanka out of second test with Covid",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pathum Nissanka out of second test with Covid",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka have been hit with another Covid-19 case after opener Pathum Nissanka tested positive, taking the number of players since the start of the Australia series to six.",
        "\"He was found to be positive during an Antigen test conducted on the player yesterday morning, following the player complaining of feeling unwell,\" an SLC statement said.",
        "\"A PCR test carried out later in the day confirmed the result. Nissanaka was immediately isolated in a different hotel upon identification and will undergo Covid-19 protocols.\" For the second time in two matches, Oshada Fernando has been brought in as the Covid substitute after he replaced Angelo Mathews, the first player to test positive, during the opening game in Galle.",
        "Since then Praveen Jayawickrama, Dhananjaya de Silva, Asitha Fernando and Jeffrey Vandersay have also been positive with the quartet ruled out of the second Test.",
        "Mathews was able to take his place in the side for this game having completed his five-day isolation period. With two days of the series remaining, Australia have managed to avoid any Covid cases within their squad.",
        "Andrew McDonald, the head coach, arrived late for the tour last month after testing positive before leaving.",
        "Sri Lanka have a short turnaround to their next Test with the opening match against Pakistan getting underway in Galle on June 16.",
        "Pathum NissankaOshada FernandoSri LankaSri Lanka vs AustraliaAustralia in Sri LankaICC World Test Championship."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pathum Nissanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathum Nissanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Antigen",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nissanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angelo Mathews",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Praveen Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhananjaya de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asitha Fernando",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeffrey Vandersay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Andrew McDonald",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pathum NissankaOshada FernandoSri LankaSri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AustraliaAustralia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Test Championship",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක කොවිඩ් දෙවන පරීක්ෂණයෙන් ඉවතට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආරම්භක පිතිකරු පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තවත් Covid-19 රෝගයක් වැළඳී ඇත, එය ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු තරගාවලිය ආරම්භයේ සිට ක්‍රීඩකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව 6 දක්වා ගෙන ගියේය.",
        "\"ඊයේ උදෑසන ක්‍රීඩකයා අසනීප වී ඇති බවට පැමිණිලි කිරීමෙන් පසු ක්‍රීඩකයාට සිදු කරන ලද ප්‍රතිදේහජනක පරීක්ෂණයකදී ඔහු ධනාත්මක බව සොයා ගන්නා ලදී,\" ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් නිවේදනයක දැක්වේ.",
        "\"පසුව දවසේ සිදු කරන ලද PCR පරීක්ෂණයකින් ප්‍රතිඵලය තහවුරු විය. හඳුනාගැනීමෙන් පසු නිශ්ශනක වහාම වෙනත් හෝටලයක හුදකලා කරන ලද අතර Covid-19 ප්‍රොටෝකෝලවලට භාජනය වනු ඇත.\" ගාල්ලේ පැවති ආරම්භක තරගයේදී ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කළ පළමු ක්‍රීඩකයා වූ ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස් වෙනුවට ඕෂද ප්‍රනාන්දු තරග දෙකකදී දෙවැනි වරටත් කොවිඩ් ආදේශක ලෙස ගෙන්වා ඇත.",
        "එතැන් පටන් ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම, ධනංජය ද සිල්වා, අසිත ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ ජෙෆ්රි වැන්ඩර්සේ යන ක්‍රීඩකයින්ද දෙවන ටෙස්ට් තරඟයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමත් සමඟින් සිව්වන කණ්ඩායමට ධනාත්මකව පෙනී සිටියහ.",
        "දින පහක හුදකලා කාලය සම්පූර්ණ කළ මැතිව්ස් මෙම තරගය සඳහා ඔහුගේ ස්ථානය ලබා ගැනීමට සමත් විය. තරඟාවලියේ දින දෙකක් ඉතිරිව තිබියදී, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ඔවුන්ගේ සංචිතය තුළ කිසිදු Covid ආසාදිතයෙකු වළක්වා ගැනීමට සමත් වී තිබේ.",
        "ප්‍රධාන පුහුණුකරු ඇන්ඩෘ මැක්ඩොනල්ඩ් පිටත්ව යාමට පෙර ධනාත්මක බව පරීක්‍ෂා කිරීමෙන් පසු පසුගිය මාසයේ සංචාරය සඳහා ප්‍රමාද විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිලට ඔවුන්ගේ මීළඟ ටෙස්ට් තරගයට කෙටි පෙරළියක් උදාවී ඇත්තේ පාකිස්තානයට එරෙහි ආරම්භක තරගය ජුනි 16 වැනිදා ගාල්ලේදී ආරම්භ වීමත් සමඟය.",
        "Pathum NissankaOshada Fernando Sri LankaSri Lanka vs AustraliaAustralia Sri LankaICC World Test Championship."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රතිදේහජනක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිශ්ශනක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනංජය ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසිත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙෆ්රි වැන්ඩර්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ඩෲ මැක්ඩොනල්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් නිශ්ශංක ඕෂද ප්‍රනාන්දුSri LankaSri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ටෙස්ට් ශූරතාවලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோவிட் உடனான இரண்டாவது சோதனையிலிருந்து பதும் நிஸ்ஸங்க வெளியேறினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆஸ்திரேலிய தொடரின் தொடக்கத்திலிருந்து வீரர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை ஆறாகக் கொண்டு சென்ற தொடக்க ஆட்டக்காரர் பாத்தும் நிசாங்க நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்ததை அடுத்து இலங்கை மற்றொரு கோவிட் -19 நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"நேற்று காலை வீரர் உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருப்பதாக புகார் தெரிவித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, நேற்று காலை வீரருக்கு நடத்தப்பட்ட ஆன்டிஜென் சோதனையின் போது அவர் நேர்மறையாக இருப்பது கண்டறியப்பட்டது\" என்று SLC அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"பின்னர் நடத்தப்பட்ட பிசிஆர் சோதனை முடிவை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது. அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டவுடன் நிசானகா உடனடியாக வேறு ஹோட்டலில் தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டார் மற்றும் கோவிட்-19 நெறிமுறைகளுக்கு உட்படுவார்.\" இரண்டு போட்டிகளில் இரண்டாவது தடவையாக, காலியில் ஆரம்பமான ஆட்டத்தின் போது நேர்மறையை பரிசோதித்த முதல் வீரரான ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸுக்குப் பதிலாக ஓஷத பெர்னாண்டோ கோவிட் மாற்று வீரராகக் கொண்டுவரப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் பிரவீன் ஜயவிக்ரம, தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா, அசித்த பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் ஜெஃப்ரி வான்டர்சே ஆகியோரும் இரண்டாவது டெஸ்டில் இருந்து நால்வர் அணியை நீக்கியதில் சாதகமாக இருந்தனர்.",
        "மேத்யூஸ் தனது ஐந்து நாள் தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட காலத்தை முடித்ததன் மூலம் இந்த ஆட்டத்தில் தனது இடத்தைப் பிடிக்க முடிந்தது. தொடரின் இரண்டு நாட்கள் மீதமுள்ள நிலையில், ஆஸ்திரேலியா தனது அணிக்குள் எந்த கோவிட் வழக்குகளையும் தவிர்க்க முடிந்தது.",
        "தலைமைப் பயிற்சியாளரான ஆண்ட்ரூ மெக்டொனால்ட், புறப்படுவதற்கு முன் நேர்மறை சோதனைக்குப் பிறகு கடந்த மாதம் சுற்றுப்பயணத்திற்கு தாமதமாக வந்தார்.",
        "ஜூன் 16ஆம் தேதி காலியில் பாகிஸ்தானுக்கு எதிரான தொடக்கப் போட்டி தொடங்கவுள்ள நிலையில், இலங்கை அணி தனது அடுத்த டெஸ்ட் போட்டிக்கு குறுகிய திருப்பத்தை பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை ஐசிசி உலக டெஸ்ட் சாம்பியன்ஷிப் போட்டியில் பாத்தும் நிஸ்ஸங்க ஓஷதா பெர்னாண்டோ இலங்கை இலங்கை vs ஆஸ்திரேலியா ஆஸ்திரேலியா."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாத்தும் நிஸ்ஸங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் நிஸ்ஸங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆன்டிஜென்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஸ்ஸனகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசித்த பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஃப்ரி வாண்டர்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்ட்ரூ மெக்டொனால்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதம் நிஸ்ஸங்க ஓஷதா பெர்னாண்டோ இலங்கை இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக டெஸ்ட் சாம்பியன்ஷிப்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}