{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131582",
  "time_ut": 1657952080,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "என் தாய் நாட்டுக்காக தொடர்ந்தும் சேவையாற்றுவேன் - முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டா உறுதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "I will continue to serve my motherland - former President Kota assured",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has said that he will continue to serve the motherland after resigning from the presidency.",
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa mentioned this in his resignation letter which was read today in Parliament.",
        "Parliamentary Secretary General Thammika Dasanayake read the resignation letter sent to the Speaker when the Parliament met today.",
        "In that letter, within 3 months of my inauguration as President, the Covid-19 pandemic had affected the entire world.",
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa expressed his satisfaction with the efforts made to protect Sri Lanka from the pandemic at that time.",
        "In his resignation letter, he noted that the implementation of the lockdowns in 2020 and 2021 has caused the country to lose foreign exchange and continue to hurt an already battered economy.",
        "I called on all parties in Parliament to form an all-party government to address this volatile economy."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kota",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මම දිගටම මගේ මව්බිමට සේවය කරනවා - හිටපු ජනාධිපති කොටා සහතික වෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු මාතෘ භූමියට තවදුරටත් සේවය කරන බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කියවන ලද ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වූ අවස්ථාවේදී කථානායකවරයා වෙත යවන ලද ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් තම්මික දසනායක විසින් කියවා තිබේ.",
        "එම ලිපියේ, මා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත්වී මාස 3ක් ඇතුළත Covid-19 වසංගතය මුළු ලෝකයටම බලපෑවා.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වසංගතයෙන් ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීමට ගත් උත්සාහය පිළිබඳව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය සතුට පළ කළේය.",
        "2020 සහ 2021 වසරවල අගුලු දැමීම් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම නිසා රටට විදේශ විනිමය අහිමි වී දැනටමත් බැට කෑ ආර්ථිකයට දිගින් දිගටම හානියක් සිදු වී ඇති බව ඔහු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියේ සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අස්ථාවර ආර්ථිකයට පිළියම් යෙදීම සඳහා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන ලෙස මම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලුම පක්ෂවලට කතා කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොටා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස 3 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "என் தாய் நாட்டுக்காக தொடர்ந்தும் சேவையாற்றுவேன் - முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டா உறுதி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்ததன் பின்னர் தொடர்ந்தும் தாய் நாட்டுக்காக சேவையாற்றுவேன் என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இன்று வாசிக்கப்பட்ட அவரது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்திலேயே இதனை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று பாராளுமன்றம் கூடிய போது சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்ட இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க வாசித்தார்.",
        "அந்தக் கடிதத்தில், நான் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற 3 மாதங்களுக்குள் கொவிட் தொற்று உலகம் முழுவதையும் பாதித்தது.",
        "அந்த நேரத்தில் இலங்கையை தொற்றுநோயிலிருந்து பாதுகாக்க எடுக்கப்பட்ட முயற்சிகள் குறித்து திருப்தியடைவதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "2020 மற்றும் 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டுகளில் பொது முடக்கங்களை அமுல்படுத்தியதன் மூலம், நாடு அந்நியச் செலாவணியை இழந்ததாகவும், ஏற்கனவே பாதிக்கப்பட்ட பொருளாதாரம் தொடர்ந்து பாதிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் தனது இராஜிநாமா கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த நிலையற்ற பொருளாதார தன்மைக்கு தீர்வுகாணும் நோக்கில் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளுக்கும் பாராளுமன்றில் நான் அழைப்பு விடுத்தேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}