{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Disciplinary-action-against-missing-Beach-VB-players/108-243388",
  "time_ut": 1660929031,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Disciplinary action against missing Beach VB players",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Disciplinary action against missing Beach VB players",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Volleyball Federation (SLVB) has appointed a three-member disciplinary committee to investigate the decamping of the Sri Lanka Men’s Beach Volleyball Team during the 22nd Commonwealth Games in Birmingham, England.",
        "Retired DIG Priyantha Jayakody (Chairman), DIG Nimal Perera and Secretary SLV Tournament Committee Dhanapala Jayapathma will form the three-member disciplinary committee.",
        "The Sri Lanka Men’s Beach Volleyball Team composed of Ashan Rashmika and Malintha Yapa went missing soon after they had lost their matches at the Commonwealth Games.",
        "The two missing players are from Sri Lanka Air Force (SLAF) and the SLV has officially informed the Commander of SLAF about their disappearance."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Beach VB",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Volleyball Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Men’s Beach Volleyball Team",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth Games",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Birmingham",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLV Tournament Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanapala Jayapathma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ashan Rashmika",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malintha Yapa",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commonwealth Games",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අතුරුදන් වූ Beach VB ක්‍රීඩකයන්ට එරෙහිව විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එංගලන්තයේ බර්මින්හැම් හි පැවැත්වෙන 22 වැනි පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිරිමි බීච් වොලිබෝල් කණ්ඩායම ඉවත් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා වොලිබෝල් සම්මේලනය (SLVB) ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විනය කමිටුවක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "විශ්‍රාමික නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති ප්‍රියන්ත ජයකොඩි (සභාපති), නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති නිමල් පෙරේරා සහ SLV තරඟාවලි කමිටුවේ ලේකම් ධනපාල ජයපත්ම යන මහත්වරුන් විසින් ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විනය කමිටුව පිහිටුවනු ඇත.",
        "අශාන් රශ්මික සහ මලින්ත යාපාගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිරිමි බීච් වොලිබෝල් කණ්ඩායම පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේ තරග පරාජය වීමත් සමඟම අතුරුදන් විය.",
        "අතුරුදන් වූ ක්‍රීඩකයින් දෙදෙනා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවේ (ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවේ) ක්‍රීඩකයින් වන අතර ඔවුන්ගේ අතුරුදහන් වීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාපතිවරයාට නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බීච් වී.බී",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වොලිබෝල් සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිරිමි වෙරළ වොලිබෝල් කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බර්මින්හැම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLV තරඟාවලි කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනපාල ජයපත්ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අශාන් රශ්මික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලින්ත යාපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காணாமல் போன பீச் விபி வீரர்கள் மீது ஒழுங்கு நடவடிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இங்கிலாந்தின் பர்மிங்ஹாமில் நடைபெற்ற 22வது பொதுநலவாய விளையாட்டுப் போட்டியின் போது இலங்கை ஆண்கள் பீச் கைப்பந்து அணியினர் களமிறங்கியது குறித்து விசாரிப்பதற்காக இலங்கை கைப்பந்து சம்மேளனம் (SLVB) மூன்று பேர் கொண்ட ஒழுக்காற்றுக் குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் பிரியந்த ஜயக்கொடி (தலைவர்), பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் நிமல் பெரேரா மற்றும் செயலாளர் எஸ்.எல்.வி போட்டிக் குழுவின் செயலாளர் தனபால ஜயபத்ம ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய மூவரடங்கிய ஒழுக்காற்றுக் குழு அமைக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "அஷான் ரஷ்மிகா மற்றும் மலிந்த யாப்பா ஆகியோரைக் கொண்ட இலங்கை ஆடவர் பீச் வாலிபால் அணி, பொதுநலவாய விளையாட்டுப் போட்டிகளில் தோல்வியடைந்ததை அடுத்து காணாமல் போனது.",
        "காணாமல் போன இரண்டு வீரர்களும் இலங்கை விமானப் படையைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்கள் காணாமல் போனது குறித்து SLV உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக விமானப்படைத் தளபதிக்கு அறிவித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்கரை வி.பி",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கைப்பந்து சம்மேளனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஆண்கள் பீச் வாலிபால் அணி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பர்மிங்காம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLV போட்டிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனபால ஜயபத்ம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஷான் ரஷ்மிகா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலிந்த யாப்பா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}