{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/15/sri-lanka-president-gotabaya-has-officially-stepped-down/",
  "time_ut": 1657857300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka: President Gotabaya has officially stepped down",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: President Gotabaya has officially stepped down",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has officially stepped down, said Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena on Friday (15).",
        "Speaking to reporters at the Official Residence of the Speaker, Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena said as per Article 38 (1) of the constitution he received the letter of resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "“Gotabaya Rajapaksa has stepped down legally from his post from the 14th of July 2022,” he said adding that the constitutional process to elect a new President will commence from this moment.",
        "Until the process is complete, the duties and functions of the President will be discharged by the Prime Minister as per the provisions of the constitution.",
        "The Speaker said the election of the new President will take place as per the provisions of the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act (No. 2 of 1981) and Article 40 of the constitution of Sri Lanka.",
        "He said the process will be completed expeditiously, and the process will take place in complete transparency complying with all democratic norms.",
        "The Speaker has appealed to all party leaders, state officials, and security forces to support this process.",
        "He also appealed to the general public to allow all MPs to function independently and create a peaceful environment to do so so that they can follow the proper democratic parliamentary procedure.",
        "He said within seven days all responsible officials will be involved in completing the process, and Parliament will convene on 16th July 2022.",
        "Sri Lanka President’s resignation received, official announcement on Friday (15)",
        "Dayasiri requests CJ to consider that President fled the country"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 38",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th of July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇති බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන සිකුරාදා (15) ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 38 (1) වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය තමන්ට ලැබුණු බව කථානායක නිල නිවසේ දී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා 2022 ජුලි 14 වැනිදා සිට නීත්‍යානුකූලව සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇති බවත්, නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ක්‍රියාවලිය මේ මොහොතේ සිට ආරම්භ කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එම ක්‍රියාවලිය අවසන් වන තුරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ රාජකාරි සහ කාර්යයන් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධාන අනුව අගමැතිවරයා විසින් ඉටු කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත (1981 අංක 2) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධාන අනුව නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සිදුවනු ඇතැයි කථානායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "එම ක්‍රියාවලිය කඩිනමින් අවසන් කරන බවත්, සියලු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සම්මතයන්ට අනුකූලව සම්පූර්ණ විනිවිදභාවයකින් එම ක්‍රියාවලිය සිදුවන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම ක්‍රියාවලියට සහාය දෙන ලෙස කථානායකවරයා සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින්, රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කිරීමට ඉඩ ලබා දෙන ලෙසත්, නිසි ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය අනුගමනය කළ හැකි පරිදි සාමකාමී පරිසරයක් නිර්මාණය කරන ලෙසත් ඔහු සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "දින හතක් ඇතුළත සියලුම වගකිවයුතු නිලධාරීන් මෙම ක්‍රියාවලිය සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට සම්බන්ධ කර ගන්නා බවත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව 2022 ජූලි 16 වැනි දින රැස්වන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සිකුරාදා (15) නිල නිවේදනය ලැබී ඇත.",
        "ජනපති රටින් පැන ගිය බව සලකන්නැයි දයාසිරි අගවිනිසුරුවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 14 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: அதிபர் கோத்தபய அதிகாரபூர்வமாக பதவி விலகியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பதவி விலகியுள்ளார் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (15) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சபாநாயகரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, அரசியலமைப்பின் 38 (1) சரத்தின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமா கடிதம் தமக்கு கிடைத்ததாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ 2022 ஜூலை 14 முதல் தனது பதவியில் இருந்து சட்டப்பூர்வமாக விலகியுள்ளார்,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான அரசியலமைப்பு செயல்முறை இந்த தருணத்திலிருந்து தொடங்கும்.",
        "செயல்முறை முடியும் வரை, அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளின்படி, ஜனாதிபதியின் கடமைகள் மற்றும் செயல்பாடுகள் பிரதமரால் நிறைவேற்றப்படும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம் (1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலக்கம் 2) மற்றும் இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 வது சரத்தின் விதிகளின்படி புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் நடைபெறும் என்று சபாநாயகர் கூறினார்.",
        "செயல்முறை விரைவாக முடிக்கப்படும் என்றும், அனைத்து ஜனநாயக விதிமுறைகளுக்கும் இணங்க முழு வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையுடன் செயல்முறை நடைபெறும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கு ஆதரவளிக்குமாறு அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள், அரச அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரிடம் சபாநாயகர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அனைத்து எம்.பி.க்களும் சுதந்திரமாக செயல்பட அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும், அமைதியான சூழலை உருவாக்கி, முறையான ஜனநாயக நாடாளுமன்ற நடைமுறையை பின்பற்ற வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் பொதுமக்களிடம் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஏழு நாட்களுக்குள் அனைத்து பொறுப்புள்ள அதிகாரிகளும் செயல்முறையை முடிப்பதில் ஈடுபடுவார்கள் என்றும், 2022 ஜூலை 16 ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றம் கூடும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சிறிலங்கா அதிபரின் இராஜினாமா, வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (15) உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிவிப்பு கிடைத்தது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதை கருத்தில் கொள்ளுமாறு தயாசிறி தலைமை நீதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 38",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}