{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/mfa-sabry-meets-with-undp-deputy-regional-director/",
  "time_ut": 1660621560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "MFA Sabry meets with UNDP Deputy Regional Director",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "MFA Sabry meets with UNDP Deputy Regional Director",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  The Deputy Regional Director for Asia and the Pacific of the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) Christophe Bahuet who is presently on a visit to Sri Lanka, called on the Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry recently.",
        "Foreign Minister Ali Sabry appreciated the consistent support extended by the UNDP to Sri Lanka for over five decades and in particular, during difficult times.",
        "Sri Lanka is keen to continue its close cooperation with the UNDP and Deputy Regional Director Bahuet affirmed the continued support and cooperation of the UNDP to Sri Lanka, particularly in the priority areas identified and recovery measures being taken by the Government to overcome the current challenges.",
        "The Foreign Minister and the Deputy Regional Director also discussed ways to enhance cooperation between the UNDP and the Government of Sri Lanka to support social protection measures for the vulnerable communities and ensure sustainable recovery from the current challenges.",
        "Chinese Research / Survey Vessel Yuan Wang 5 reaches Sri Lanka’s Hambantota"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "MFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sabry",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "UNDP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pacific of the United Nations Development Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahuet",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese Research / Survey Vessel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "MFA Sabry UNDP නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ දිනවල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරතව සිටින එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහනේ (UNDP) ආසියා සහ පැසිෆික් කලාපයේ නියෝජ්‍ය කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ Christophe Bahuet මහතා පසුගියදා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි දශක පහකට වැඩි කාලයක් සහ විශේෂයෙන් දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී UNDP විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් ස්ථාවර සහයෝගය අගය කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව UNDP සමඟ සමීප සහයෝගීතාව දිගටම පවත්වා ගෙන යාමට උනන්දු වන අතර නියෝජ්‍ය කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ Bahuet ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට UNDP හි අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය සහ සහයෝගීතාව තහවුරු කළේය, විශේෂයෙන් හඳුනාගෙන ඇති ප්‍රමුඛතා ක්ෂේත්‍ර සහ වත්මන් අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා රජය විසින් ගනු ලබන ප්‍රතිසාධන ක්‍රියාමාර්ග.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ නියෝජ්‍ය කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ප්‍රජාවන් සඳහා සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ ක්‍රියාමාර්ගවලට සහාය වීම සහ වත්මන් අභියෝගවලින් තිරසාර ප්‍රකෘතිමත් වීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා UNDP සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අතර සහයෝගීතාව වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව ද සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "චීන පර්යේෂණ / සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොටට ළඟා වේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "MFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සබ්රි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "UNDP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහනේ පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහුඑට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන පර්යේෂණ / සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UNDP துணை பிராந்திய இயக்குனரை MFA சப்ரி சந்திக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தற்போது இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ள ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டத்தின் (UNDP) ஆசிய மற்றும் பசுபிக் பிராந்தியத்திற்கான பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் கிறிஸ்டோப் பஹூட் அண்மையில் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியை சந்தித்தார்.",
        "ஐந்து தசாப்தங்களுக்கும் மேலாக மற்றும் குறிப்பாக கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு UNDP வழங்கிய நிலையான ஆதரவை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி பாராட்டினார்.",
        "UNDP உடனான தனது நெருக்கமான ஒத்துழைப்பைத் தொடர இலங்கை ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது மற்றும் UNDP யின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஆதரவையும் ஒத்துழைப்பையும், குறிப்பாக அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட முன்னுரிமைப் பகுதிகள் மற்றும் தற்போதைய சவால்களை சமாளிக்க அரசாங்கத்தால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் மீட்பு நடவடிக்கைகளில் துணைப் பிராந்தியப் பணிப்பாளர் Bahuet உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய சமூகங்களுக்கான சமூக பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கும் தற்போதைய சவால்களில் இருந்து நிலையான மீட்சியை உறுதி செய்வதற்கும் UNDP மற்றும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிகள் குறித்தும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் மற்றும் பிரதி பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "சீன ஆராய்ச்சி / ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கையின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை சென்றடைந்தது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "MFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சப்ரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சித் திட்டத்தின் பசிபிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahuet",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சி / ஆய்வுக் கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}