{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132456",
  "time_ut": 1659076505,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் 3 ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடர் ஆகஸ்ட் 3 இல் ஆரம்பம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The 3rd Session of the Ninth Parliament begins on 3 August",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "The third session of the Ninth Parliament will be inaugurated by President Ranil Wickramawasinghe on the 3rd of August. The 2nd session was adjourned on 28th midnight.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe issued a special gazette announcement on the 28th regarding the completion of the 2nd session and the commencement of the 3rd session.",
        "The 2nd session of Parliament was adjourned with effect from midnight on the 28th in accordance with Article 70 of the Constitution.",
        "The 3rd session of the Parliament will be formally opened on the 3rd of the next month with a special speech by the President.",
        "Following the adjournment of the parliamentary session, the parliamentary committees including the COP committee, the COP committee and the finance committee will be dissolved as usual and new committees will be appointed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The 3rd Session",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramawasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 3rd of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28th midnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 28th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight on",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 70 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 3 වැනි සැසිවාරය අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා ආරම්භ වේ",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තුන්වැනි සැසිවාරය අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ආරම්භ කෙරේ. 2 වැනි සැසිවාරය 28 මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ කල් තැබිණි.",
        "2 වැනි සැසිවාරය අවසන් කර 3 වැනි සැසිවාරය ආරම්භ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් පසුගිය 28 වැනිදා නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 වැනි වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 2 වැනි සැසිවාරය 28 වැනි දින මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි කල් තැබිණි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 3 වැනි සැසිවාරය ලබන මස 3 වැනිදා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විශේෂ කතාවකින් විධිමත් ලෙස විවෘත කෙරේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය කල් තැබීමෙන් පසු සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි COP කමිටුව, COP කමිටුව, මූල්‍ය කමිටුව ඇතුළු පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා විසුරුවා හැර නව කමිටු පත් කිරීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 වන සැසිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 3 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 70 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் 3 ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடர் ஆகஸ்ட் 3 இல் ஆரம்பம்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றாவது கூட்டத்தொடர் எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 03ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமவசிங்கவினால் ஆரம்பித்து வைக்கப்படும். 2ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடர் 28 ஆம் திகதி நள்ளிரவுடன் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடர் நிறைவு, 3ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடர் ஆரம்பம் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 28 ஆம் திகதி விசேட வர்த்மானி அறிவித்தலை வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 70ஆவது உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரத்திற்கமைய 28 ஆம் திகதி நள்ளிரவு முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் 2அவது பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடர் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் 3ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடர் எதிர்வரும் மாதம் 3ஆம் திகதி சம்பிரதாய பூர்வமாக ஜனாதிபதியின் விசேட உரையினை தொடர்ந்து ஆரம்பித்து வைக்கப்படும்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடர் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து கோப் குழு, கோபா குழு,நிதிக்குழு உட்பட பாராளுமன்ற குழுக்கள் இயல்வாகவே கலைக்கப்பட்டு,புதிய குழுக்கள் நியமிக்கப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3வது அமர்வு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமவசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 3 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 70",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}