{
  "newspaper_id": "colombo-telegraph-com",
  "url": "https://www.colombotelegraph.com/index.php/gtf-welcomes-the-delisting-of-diaspora-entities-calls-for-a-well-targeted-unhrc-resolution-on-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1660963505,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GTF Welcomes The Delisting Of Diaspora Entities & Calls For A Well-Targeted UNHRC Resolution On Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GTF Welcomes The Delisting Of Diaspora Entities & Calls For A Well-Targeted UNHRC Resolution On Sri Lanka",
      "author": "COLOMBO TELEGRAPH",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Global Tamil Forum (GTF) welcomes the delisting of various Tamil diaspora organisations and individuals as an important step towards achieving improved ethnic relations and economic outcomes in Sri Lanka. However, it is disappointing that many Tamil and Muslim organisations and individuals are still on the updated list, gazetted on August 1, 2022. GTF calls on the Sri Lankan government to discontinue this shambolic process of listing and delisting entities to suit the political agenda of the time.",
        "The entire process of publishing a list of designated entities and individuals by the Sri Lankan government is arbitrary, irrational, and an outright abuse of the United Nations Regulation (Regulation 4(7) of the UN Regulations No. 1 of 2012). From 2014, it was misused by the government to suppress freedom of speech and dissent and intimidate human rights defenders – not just within Sri Lanka but also overseas.",
        "This is best illustrated with GTF – an organisation formed after the end of war in 2009 to play a constructive role in promoting peace, justice, equality, and reconciliation in Sri Lanka. While promoting wartime accountability including at the UNHRC, GTF has maintained high level engagement with all stakeholders in Sri Lanka, including politicians, civil society activists and media personnel, with the intention of working towards a durable political solution acceptable to all communities. GTF was also involved in targeted activities related to rehabilitation, medical emergencies and development initiatives in many regions and communities across Sri Lanka.",
        "Despite its notable openness, transparency, and international recognition, and remaining unchanged in its philosophy and approach, GTF found itself in and out of the ‘list’ twice – listed in 2014, delisted in 2015, re-listed in 2021 and delisted in 2022.",
        "GTF is grateful that the international community and many Sri Lankan stakeholders (including the media) ignored this listing for what it truly is. In fact, our diplomatic engagements, including the crucial meetings in the US in November 2021 and March 2022, also meeting with the Minister of State for the Commonwealth and United Nations, and South Asia at the Foreign, Commonwealth & Development Office (FCDO) and various other important engagements including the United Nations (UN) were not affected by the listing, but the ban’s impact on reconciliation, rehabilitation and economic progress in Sri Lanka was significant.",
        "There is no doubt the timing of the recent delisting is to bolster Sri Lanka’s credentials as its human rights record is about to be reviewed at the UNHRC next month for the eighth time since the war ended in 2009. This action only confirms the time-tested pattern of Sri Lanka doing the bare minimum just in time for the next UNHRC session – and presents an eloquent argument for increased international scrutiny over Sri Lanka’s human rights and governance record.",
        "UNHRC session of September 2022 is hugely important for the Tamil people and indeed for the entire country to move forward. Sri Lanka’s record on implementing the key aspects of the UNHRC resolutions since 2012 (the last one passed in March 2021) is truly appalling. Despite few token initiatives, such as the establishment of the Office of the Missing Persons and the Office for Reparations, the country is yet to make any meaningful progress that would provide effective relief, justice, and closure for those directly impacted by the war. Further, some of the high handed measures being taken against the protesters who agitated for progressive changes are deeply concerning. All of these call for increased international oversight of the human rights situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "The nascent transformation Sri Lanka presently undergoing is significant. The successful protests that deposed Gotabaya Rajapaksa presidency has created an environment where an unaccountable government will be under increased scrutiny. In addition to wartime accountability, legal, financial, and other governance accountabilities are also under intense focus. This emerging trend needs to be conscientiously promoted by the international community, which is possible only with the adoption of a well-targeted UNHRC resolution. The new resolution needs to build on the key aspects of the March 2021 UNHRC resolution (A/HRC/RES/46/1) which empowered the High Commissioner’s Office to further advance wartime accountability.",
        "Any argument Sri Lanka may put forward leveraging its economic difficulties for lowering the international scrutiny of its human rights record – as attempted by Sri Lanka during the UNHRC session in March 2022 – has no legal, moral, or political basis. The struggle for justice, rule of law, human rights and accountability could be strengthened by the UNHRC taking a principled stance at the Council’s upcoming 51st Session."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Global Tamil Forum",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Regulation (Regulation 4(7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Regulations No",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2021 and March 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign, Commonwealth & Development Office",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Office of the Missing Persons and the Office for Reparations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "A/HRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Session",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "GTF ඩයස්පෝරා ආයතන ඉවත් කිරීම සාදරයෙන් පිළිගනී සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් හොඳින් ඉලක්ක කරගත් UNHRC යෝජනාවක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "COLOMBO Telegraph",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෝලීය දෙමළ සංසදය (GTF) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනවාර්ගික සබඳතා සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිඵල වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා වැදගත් පියවරක් ලෙස විවිධ දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයන් ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කිරීම සාදරයෙන් පිළිගනී. කෙසේ වෙතත්, 2022 අගෝස්තු 1 වැනි දින ගැසට් කරන ලද යාවත්කාලීන කරන ලද ලැයිස්තුවේ බොහෝ දෙමළ සහ මුස්ලිම් සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයන් තවමත් සිටීම බලාපොරොත්තු සුන් කරවන්නකි. දේශපාලන න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට ගැළපෙන පරිදි ආයතන ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීමේ සහ ඉවත් කිරීමේ මෙම සාහසික ක්‍රියාවලිය නතර කරන ලෙස GTF ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී. කාලය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් නම් කරන ලද ආයතන සහ පුද්ගලයන්ගේ ලැයිස්තුවක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමේ සමස්ත ක්‍රියාවලියම අත්තනෝමතික, අතාර්කික සහ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි (2012 අංක 1 දරණ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසිවල රෙගුලාසි 4(7)) සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම අපයෝජනය කිරීමකි. 2014 සිට, එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ පමණක් නොව විදේශයන්හි ද - භාෂණයේ සහ විසම්මුතියේ නිදහස යටපත් කිරීමට සහ මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්ෂකයින් බිය ගැන්වීමට රජය විසින් වැරදි ලෙස භාවිතා කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සාමය, යුක්තිය, සමානාත්මතාවය සහ ප්‍රතිසන්ධානය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා සාධනීය කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කිරීම සඳහා 2009 යුද්ධය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු පිහිටුවන ලද GTF - සංවිධානය සමඟ මෙය වඩාත් හොඳින් නිරූපණය වේ. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය ඇතුළු යුද කාලීන වගවීම ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරන අතරම, ජීටීඑෆ්, සියලුම ප්‍රජාවන්ට පිළිගත හැකි කල්පවත්නා දේශපාලන විසඳුමක් සඳහා ක්‍රියා කිරීමේ අරමුණින්, දේශපාලඥයින්, සිවිල් සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සහ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම පාර්ශ්වකරුවන් සමඟ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ සම්බන්ධතාවක් පවත්වා ගෙන යයි. GTF පුනරුත්ථාපනය, වෛද්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා බොහෝ කලාපවල සහ ප්‍රජාවන්හි සංවර්ධන මුලපිරීම් සම්බන්ධ ඉලක්කගත ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල ද සම්බන්ධ විය.",
        "එහි කැපී පෙනෙන විවෘතභාවය, විනිවිදභාවය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර පිළිගැනීම සහ එහි දර්ශනයේ සහ ප්‍රවේශයේ නොවෙනස්ව පැවතීම තිබියදීත්, GTF දෙවරක් 'ලැයිස්තුව' තුළට සහ ඉන් පිටතට පැමිණියා - 2014 දී ලැයිස්තුගත කර, 2015 දී ලැයිස්තුගත කර, 2021 දී නැවත ලැයිස්තුගත කර 2022 දී ඉවත් කරන ලදී. .",
        "GTF ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව සහ බොහෝ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පාර්ශවකරුවන් (මාධ්‍ය ඇතුළුව) මෙම ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීම සත්‍ය වශයෙන්ම නොසලකා හැරීම ගැන කෘතඥ වෙනවා. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, 2021 නොවැම්බර් සහ 2022 මාර්තු මාසයේදී එක්සත් ජනපදයේ තීරනාත්මක රැස්වීම් ඇතුළුව අපගේ රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික කටයුතු, විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලයේදී (FCDO) පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සහ දකුණු ආසියාව සඳහා රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවීමට සහ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය (එජාස) ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් විවිධ වැදගත් ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට මෙම ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීම බලපෑවේ නැත, නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංහිඳියාව, පුනරුත්ථාපනය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රගතිය කෙරෙහි තහනමේ බලපෑම සැලකිය යුතු විය.",
        "2009 වසරේ යුද්ධය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව හිමිකම් වාර්තාව අටවැනි වරටත් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ දී සමාලෝචනයට ලක් කිරීමට නියමිත බැවින් මෑතකාලීන ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අක්තපත්‍ර ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා වූ කාලසීමාව බවට සැකයක් නැත. මීළඟ UNHRC සැසිවාරය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවම වශයෙන් ක්‍රියා කරන රටාව - සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව හිමිකම් සහ පාලන වාර්තාව පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර පරීක්ෂාව වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා වාචික තර්කයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ 2022 සැසිවාරය දෙමළ ජනතාවට සහ ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම මුළු රටම ඉදිරියට යාමට ඉතා වැදගත් වේ. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ යෝජනාවල ප්‍රධාන කරුණු 2012 සිට (අවසාන වරට සම්මත වූයේ 2021 මාර්තු මාසයේදී) ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වාර්තාව සැබවින්ම භයානක ය. අතුරුදහන් වූවන්ගේ කාර්යාලය සහ වන්දි ගෙවීමේ කාර්යාලය පිහිටුවීම වැනි සංකේතාත්මක මුලපිරීම් කිහිපයක් තිබියදීත්, යුද්ධයෙන් සෘජුවම බලපෑමට ලක්වූවන් සඳහා ඵලදායී සහන, යුක්තිය සහ වසා දැමීම සඳහා රට තවමත් අර්ථවත් ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා නැත. තවද, ප්‍රගතිශීලී වෙනස්කම් සඳහා උද්ඝෝෂණ කළ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ගනු ලබන සමහර ඉහළ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැඹුරින් සැලකිලිමත් වේ. මේ සියල්ල ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව හිමිකම් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර අධීක්ෂණය වැඩි කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වර්තමානයේ සිදුවෙමින් පවතින නව පරිවර්තනය ඉතා වැදගත් ය. ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් නෙරපා හරින ලද සාර්ථක විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් වගකීම් විරහිත ආණ්ඩුවක් වැඩි අවධානයට ලක්වන පරිසරයක් නිර්මාණය වී තිබේ. යුධ කාලීන වගකීම් වලට අමතරව, නීතිමය, මූල්‍ය සහ අනෙකුත් පාලන වගකීම් ද දැඩි අවධානයට ලක්ව ඇත. මෙම නැගී එන ප්‍රවණතාවය ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව විසින් හෘද සාක්ෂියට එකඟව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කළ යුතු අතර, එය කළ හැක්කේ හොඳින් ඉලක්ක කරගත් UNHRC යෝජනාවක් සම්මත කර ගැනීමෙන් පමණි. යුධ කාලීන වගවීම තවදුරටත් ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයට බලය ලබා දුන් 2021 මාර්තු UNHRC යෝජනාවේ (A/HRC/RES/46/1) ප්‍රධාන අංගයන් මත නව යෝජනාව ගොඩනැගීමට අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "2022 මාර්තු මාසයේ UNHRC සැසියේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උත්සාහ කළ පරිදි - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය මානව හිමිකම් වාර්තාව පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර පරීක්ෂාව පහත හෙළීම සඳහා ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා උපයෝගී කර ගනිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකි ඕනෑම තර්කයකට නෛතික, සදාචාරාත්මක හෝ දේශපාලන පදනමක් නොමැත. යුක්තිය, නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය, මානව හිමිකම් සහ වගවීම සඳහා වන අරගලය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ ඉදිරි 51 වැනි සැසිවාරයේදී ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය ස්ථාවරයක් ගැනීම මගින් ශක්තිමත් කළ හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය දෙමළ සංසදය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි (නියාමනය 4(7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ රෙගුලාසි අංක",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 නොවැම්බර් සහ 2022 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරුදහන් වූවන්ගේ කාර්යාලය සහ වන්දි ගෙවීමේ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "A/HRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புலம்பெயர் நிறுவனங்களின் பட்டியலிடுதலை GTF வரவேற்கிறது மற்றும் இலங்கை தொடர்பான UNHRC தீர்மானத்தை நன்கு இலக்காகக் கொண்டது",
      "author": "கொழும்பு டெலிகிராப்",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் மேம்பட்ட இன உறவுகள் மற்றும் பொருளாதார விளைவுகளை அடைவதற்கான முக்கிய படியாக பல்வேறு புலம்பெயர்ந்த தமிழ் அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களின் பட்டியலில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்டதை Global Tamil Forum (GTF) வரவேற்கிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், ஆகஸ்ட் 1, 2022 அன்று வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட புதுப்பிக்கப்பட்ட பட்டியலில் பல தமிழ் மற்றும் முஸ்லிம் அமைப்புக்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்கள் இன்னும் இருப்பது ஏமாற்றமளிக்கிறது. அரசியல் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலுக்கு ஏற்ற வகையில் பட்டியலிடுதல் மற்றும் நீக்குதல் போன்ற இந்த குழப்பமான செயல்முறையை நிறுத்துமாறு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை GTF கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது. நேரம்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்களின் பட்டியலை வெளியிடுவதற்கான முழு செயல்முறையும் தன்னிச்சையானது, பகுத்தறிவற்றது மற்றும் ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் ஒழுங்குமுறையை (2012 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஐ.நா. ஒழுங்குமுறை எண். 1 இன் ஒழுங்குமுறை 4(7)) முற்றிலும் துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்வதாகும். 2014 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல், பேச்சு சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை நசுக்குவதற்கும், மனித உரிமைப் பாதுகாவலர்களை அச்சுறுத்துவதற்கும் அரசாங்கத்தால் தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டது - இலங்கைக்குள் மட்டுமல்ல, வெளிநாடுகளிலும்.",
        "இலங்கையில் சமாதானம், நீதி, சமத்துவம் மற்றும் நல்லிணக்கத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதில் ஆக்கப்பூர்வமான பங்கை வகிப்பதற்காக 2009 இல் போர் முடிவடைந்த பின்னர் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட GTF - அமைப்பில் இது சிறப்பாக விளக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. UNHRC உட்பட போர்க்கால பொறுப்புக்கூறலை ஊக்குவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், அனைத்து சமூகங்களும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய நீடித்த அரசியல் தீர்வை நோக்கி செயல்படும் நோக்கத்துடன், அரசியல்வாதிகள், சிவில் சமூக ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் உட்பட இலங்கையிலுள்ள அனைத்து பங்குதாரர்களுடனும் GTF உயர் மட்ட ஈடுபாட்டைப் பேணி வருகின்றது. இலங்கை முழுவதும் பல பிராந்தியங்கள் மற்றும் சமூகங்களில் புனர்வாழ்வு, மருத்துவ அவசரநிலைகள் மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி முயற்சிகள் தொடர்பான இலக்கு நடவடிக்கைகளிலும் GTF ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை, வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை மற்றும் சர்வதேச அங்கீகாரம் மற்றும் அதன் தத்துவம் மற்றும் அணுகுமுறையில் மாறாமல் இருந்த போதிலும், GTF இரண்டு முறை 'பட்டியலுக்கு' உள்ளேயும் வெளியேயும் தன்னைக் கண்டறிந்தது - 2014 இல் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டது, 2015 இல் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டது, 2021 இல் மீண்டும் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டது மற்றும் 2022 இல் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டது. .",
        "சர்வதேச சமூகம் மற்றும் பல இலங்கை பங்குதாரர்கள் (ஊடகங்கள் உட்பட) இந்தப் பட்டியலைப் புறக்கணித்ததற்கு GTF நன்றி தெரிவிக்கிறது. உண்மையில், நவம்பர் 2021 மற்றும் மார்ச் 2022 இல் அமெரிக்காவில் நடந்த முக்கியமான சந்திப்புகள் உட்பட எங்களின் இராஜதந்திர ஈடுபாடுகள், காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மற்றும் தெற்காசியாவின் வெளியுறவுத்துறை, காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு அலுவலகத்தில் (FCDO) மற்றும் தெற்காசியாவிற்கான ராஜாங்க அமைச்சருடன் சந்திப்பு மற்றும் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை (ஐ.நா.) உட்பட பல்வேறு முக்கிய ஈடுபாடுகள் இந்த பட்டியலினால் பாதிக்கப்படவில்லை, ஆனால் இலங்கையில் நல்லிணக்கம், புனர்வாழ்வு மற்றும் பொருளாதார முன்னேற்றம் ஆகியவற்றில் தடையின் தாக்கம் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கதாக இருந்தது.",
        "2009 இல் யுத்தம் முடிவடைந்ததன் பின்னர் எட்டாவது தடவையாக அடுத்த மாதம் UNHRC இல் இலங்கையின் மனித உரிமைகள் பதிவு மீளாய்வு செய்யப்படவுள்ள நிலையில், இலங்கையின் நற்சான்றிதழ்களை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்காகவே சமீபத்திய பட்டியலில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்ட நேரம் என்பதில் சந்தேகமில்லை. அடுத்த UNHRC அமர்விற்கான நேரத்தில் இலங்கையின் குறைந்தபட்ச செயல்பாட்டின் முறை - மற்றும் இலங்கையின் மனித உரிமைகள் மற்றும் நிர்வாகப் பதிவுகள் மீதான சர்வதேச ஆய்வுக்கு ஒரு சொற்பொழிவு வாதத்தை முன்வைக்கிறது.",
        "செப்டம்பர் 2022 UNHRC அமர்வு தமிழ் மக்களுக்கும் உண்மையில் முழு நாடும் முன்னேறுவதற்கும் மிகவும் முக்கியமானது. UNHRC தீர்மானங்களின் முக்கிய அம்சங்களை 2012 முதல் (கடைசியாக 2021 மார்ச்சில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது) நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதில் இலங்கையின் சாதனை உண்மையிலேயே பயங்கரமானது. காணாமல் போனோர் அலுவலகம் மற்றும் இழப்பீடுகளுக்கான அலுவலகம் போன்ற சில டோக்கன் முன்முயற்சிகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், போரினால் நேரடியாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு பயனுள்ள நிவாரணம், நீதி மற்றும் மூடல் ஆகியவற்றை வழங்கும் எந்தவொரு அர்த்தமுள்ள முன்னேற்றத்தையும் நாடு இன்னும் அடையவில்லை. மேலும், முற்போக்கான மாற்றங்களுக்காக கிளர்ந்தெழுந்த போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக எடுக்கப்படும் சில உயர்தர நடவடிக்கைகள் ஆழ்ந்த கவலையளிக்கின்றன. இவையனைத்தும் இலங்கையின் மனித உரிமைகள் நிலைமையை சர்வதேச கண்காணிப்பை அதிகரிக்க வேண்டும் என்று கோருகின்றன.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது ஏற்பட்டுள்ள புதிய மாற்றம் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கதாகும். கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை அகற்றிய வெற்றிகரமான போராட்டங்கள், பொறுப்புக் கூற முடியாத அரசாங்கத்தின் மீது அதிக ஆய்வுக்கு உட்படுத்தப்படும் சூழலை உருவாக்கியுள்ளது. போர்க்கால பொறுப்புக்கூறலுக்கு கூடுதலாக, சட்ட, நிதி மற்றும் பிற நிர்வாக பொறுப்புக்கூறல்களும் தீவிர கவனம் செலுத்துகின்றன. இந்த வளர்ந்து வரும் போக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகத்தால் மனசாட்சியுடன் ஊக்குவிக்கப்பட வேண்டும், இது நன்கு இலக்காகக் கொண்ட UNHRC தீர்மானத்தை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதன் மூலம் மட்டுமே சாத்தியமாகும். புதிய தீர்மானம் மார்ச் 2021 UNHRC தீர்மானத்தின் (A/HRC/RES/46/1) முக்கிய அம்சங்களில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும், இது போர்க்கால பொறுப்புக்கூறலை மேலும் முன்னெடுக்க உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு அதிகாரம் அளித்தது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் மாதம் UNHRC அமர்வின் போது இலங்கை மேற்கொண்ட முயற்சியின்படி - மனித உரிமைகள் பதிவின் சர்வதேச ஆய்வை குறைப்பதற்காக இலங்கை தனது பொருளாதார சிக்கல்களை முன்வைக்கும் எந்தவொரு வாதமும் சட்ட, தார்மீக அல்லது அரசியல் அடிப்படையை கொண்டிருக்கவில்லை. நீதி, சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி, மனித உரிமைகள் மற்றும் பொறுப்புக்கூறல் ஆகியவற்றுக்கான போராட்டமானது, சபையின் எதிர்வரும் 51வது அமர்வில் UNHRC ஒரு கொள்கை ரீதியான நிலைப்பாட்டை எடுப்பதன் மூலம் பலப்படுத்தப்படலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குளோபல் தமிழ் மன்றம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் ஒழுங்குமுறை (ஒழுங்குமுறை 4(7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா. விதிமுறைகள் எண்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GTF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2021 மற்றும் மார்ச் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு, காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காணாமல் போனோர் அலுவலகம் மற்றும் இழப்பீடுகளுக்கான அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "A/HRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமர்வு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}