{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Biden-announces-20-Million-in-additional-assistance-to-feed-over-800-000-Sri-Lankan-children/108-239965",
  "time_ut": 1656413253,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Biden announces $20 Million in additional assistance to feed over 800,000 Sri Lankan children",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Biden announces $20 Million in additional assistance to feed over 800,000 Sri Lankan children",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At the G7 Summit today, President of the United States Joe Biden announced $20 million in additional assistance to strengthen food security in Sri Lanka.",
        "Building on other recent funding announcements from the United States, this newly posted assistance will target Sri Lankans most in need during the current economic crisis.  The funding aims to support a school nutrition program that will feed over 800,000 Sri Lankan children and provide food vouchers for over 27,000 pregnant and lactating women over the next 15 months.  The effort also plans to support approximately 30,000 farmers through the contribution of agricultural assistance and cash in order to increase food production in vulnerable Sri Lankan communities.",
        "“President Biden’s announcement of $20 million in additional assistance to Sri Lanka demonstrates the United States’ ongoing commitment to food security, public health, and the economic well-being of all Sri Lankan people,” said U.S. Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung.  “The United States will continue to support Sri Lankan efforts to promote economic stability and will ensure this assistance reaches the communities – and children – who need it most.”",
        "The $20 million of humanitarian assistance announced today builds on nearly $12 million in recent U.S. commitments in economic and humanitarian assistance, totaling $32 million in U.S. support for the Sri Lankan people since June 16, 2022.  Funding is provided through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and will be awarded to partners that adhere to globally recognized monitoring and evaluation standards.  This ensures that funding is accounted for and assistance reaches those identified as most vulnerable to food insecurity, the US Embassy in Sri Lanka said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "$20 Million",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "800,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the G7 Summit",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 27,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 15 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly $12 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$32 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 16, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Agency for International Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිඩෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දරුවන් 800,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක අමතර ආධාරයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද පැවති G7 සමුළුවේදී අමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා අතිරේක ආධාර වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 20ක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපදයේ අනෙකුත් මෑතකාලීන අරමුදල් නිවේදන මත පදනම්ව, මෙම අලුතින් පළ කරන ලද ආධාර වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය තුළ වඩාත්ම අවශ්‍යතා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ඉලක්ක කරනු ඇත. ඉදිරි මාස 15 තුළ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දරුවන් 800,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට පෝෂණය සහ 27,000 කට අධික ගැබිණි සහ කිරි දෙන කාන්තාවන් සඳහා ආහාර වවුචර ලබා දෙන පාසල් පෝෂණ වැඩසටහනකට සහාය වීම මෙම අරමුදල්වල අරමුණයි. අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ප්‍රජාවන්ගේ ආහාර නිෂ්පාදනය ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා කෘෂිකාර්මික ආධාර සහ මුදල් දායකත්වය තුළින් දළ වශයෙන් ගොවීන් 30,000 කට ආධාර කිරීමට ද මෙම ප්‍රයත්නය සැලසුම් කරයි.",
        "\"ජනාධිපති බිඩෙන් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක අතිරේක ආධාරයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීම, ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව, මහජන සෞඛ්‍යය සහ සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවගේ ආර්ථික යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ අඛණ්ඩ කැපවීම පෙන්නුම් කරයි\" යනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති ජූලි චුන්ග් පැවසීය. \"ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට එක්සත් ජනපදය අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දක්වන අතර මෙම ආධාර වඩාත් අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රජාවන්ට සහ ළමයින්ට - ළඟා වීම සහතික කරනු ඇත.\"",
        "අද ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 මානුෂීය ආධාර, 2022 ජූනි 16 සිට ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාව සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඩොලර් මිලියන 32 ක ආධාරයක් වන ආර්ථික සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර සඳහා මෑත කාලීන එක්සත් ජනපද කැපවීම් තුළ ඩොලර් මිලියන 12 කට ආසන්න මුදලක් මත ගොඩනැගී ඇත.  අරමුදල් සපයනු ලබන්නේ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ එක්සත් ජනපද නියෝජිතායතනය හරහා ය. (USAID) සහ ගෝලීය වශයෙන් පිළිගත් අධීක්ෂණ සහ ඇගයීම් ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුගත වන හවුල්කරුවන්ට ප්‍රදානය කෙරේ. ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත භාවයට වඩාත්ම අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි අය ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති අයට අරමුදල් සම්පාදනය කිරීම සහ ආධාර ලබා දීම මෙමගින් සහතික වන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "800,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "G7 සමුළුව",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "27,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 12 කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 32 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ එක්සත් ජනපද නියෝජිතායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "800,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட இலங்கை குழந்தைகளுக்கு உணவளிக்க 20 மில்லியன் டாலர் கூடுதல் உதவியை பிடென் அறிவித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று நடைபெற்ற G7 உச்சிமாநாட்டில், இலங்கையின் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்த 20 மில்லியன் டாலர் கூடுதல் உதவியாக அமெரிக்க அதிபர் ஜோ பிடன் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "அமெரிக்காவின் பிற சமீபத்திய நிதி அறிவிப்புகளின் அடிப்படையில், புதிதாக வெளியிடப்பட்ட இந்த உதவி தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் போது மிகவும் தேவைப்படும் இலங்கையர்களை குறிவைக்கும். இந்த நிதியுதவியானது 800,000 இலங்கைச் சிறுவர்களுக்கு உணவளிக்கும் பாடசாலை போசாக்கு திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் அடுத்த 15 மாதங்களில் 27,000 கர்ப்பிணி மற்றும் பாலூட்டும் பெண்களுக்கு உணவு வவுச்சர்களை வழங்குகின்றது. பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய இலங்கை சமூகங்களில் உணவு உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிப்பதற்காக விவசாய உதவிகள் மற்றும் பணத்தின் பங்களிப்பு மூலம் சுமார் 30,000 விவசாயிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கவும் இந்த முயற்சி திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"இலங்கைக்கு 20 மில்லியன் டாலர் கூடுதல் உதவி வழங்குவதாக ஜனாதிபதி பிடென் அறிவித்திருப்பது, உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு, பொது சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் அனைத்து இலங்கை மக்களின் பொருளாதார நல்வாழ்வுக்கான அமெரிக்காவின் தொடர்ச்சியான அர்ப்பணிப்பை நிரூபிக்கிறது\" என்று இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் கூறினார். \"பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான இலங்கை முயற்சிகளுக்கு அமெரிக்கா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும், மேலும் இந்த உதவி மிகவும் தேவைப்படும் சமூகங்களுக்கும் - குழந்தைகளுக்கும் சென்றடைவதை உறுதி செய்யும்.\"",
        "இன்று அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட $20 மில்லியன் மனிதாபிமான உதவியானது, பொருளாதார மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகளில் அமெரிக்காவின் சமீபத்திய அர்ப்பணிப்புகளில் ஏறக்குறைய $12 மில்லியனைக் கட்டியெழுப்பியுள்ளது, இது ஜூன் 16, 2022 முதல் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு $32 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க ஆதரவாக உள்ளது.  சர்வதேச அபிவிருத்திக்கான அமெரிக்க நிறுவனம் மூலம் நிதி வழங்கப்படுகிறது. (USAID) மற்றும் உலகளவில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட கண்காணிப்பு மற்றும் மதிப்பீட்டுத் தரங்களைக் கடைப்பிடிக்கும் கூட்டாளர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும். உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையால் மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடியவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட நிதியுதவி கணக்கிடப்படுவதையும், உதவிகள் சென்றடைவதையும் இது உறுதி செய்கிறது என்று இலங்கையில் உள்ள அமெரிக்கத் தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "$20 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "800,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "G7 உச்சி மாநாடு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "800,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "27,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 15 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 30,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $12 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$32 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 16, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வளர்ச்சிக்கான யு.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}