{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/රුසියාවෙන්-ගූගල්-සමාගමට-ඩො-මිලියන-366ක-දඩයක්/3-395535",
  "time_ut": 1658210905,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රුසියාවෙන් ගූගල් සමාගමට ඩො.මිලියන 366ක දඩයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A fine of USD 366 million was imposed on Google from Russia",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Russian court has fined Google 21 billion rubles (US$366 million) for failing to delete banned information about the conflict in Ukraine, according to foreign reports.",
        "Moscow's Tagansky District Court has fined the IT company a turnover-based fine for repeatedly refusing to delete information prohibited by Russian law.",
        "Roskommandoza, the national internet and media watchdog, previously ordered the company to remove \"misleading information\" from YouTube about Russia's military offensive in Ukraine."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Google 21 billion rubles",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$366 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tagansky District Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Roskommandoza",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTube",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියාවෙන් ගූගල් සමාගමට ඩො.මිලියන 366ක දඩයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුක්රේනයේ ගැටුම පිළිබඳ තහනම් තොරතුරු මකා දැමීමට අපොහොසත් වීම නිසා රුසියානු අධිකරණයක් ගූගල් සමාගම වෙත රුබල් බිලියන 21 (ඇ.ඩො.මිලියන 366) දඩයක් නියම කර ඇති බව විදෙස් වාර්තා පවසයි.",
        "රුසියානු නීතියෙන් තහනම් කර ඇති තොරතුරු මකා දැමීම නැවත නැවතත් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම හේතුවෙන් මොස්කව්හි ටගන්ස්කි දිස්ත්‍රික් උසාවිය තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ සමාගමට පිරිවැටුම මත පදනම් වූ දඩයක් නියම කර ඇත.",
        "ජාතික අන්තර්ජාල සහ මාධ්‍ය නිරීක්ෂකයා වන රොස්කොමන්ඩ්සෝර්, යුක්‍රේනයේ රුසියාවේ හමුදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් \"නොමඟ යවන සුළු තොරතුරු\" යූටියුබ් වෙතින් ඉවත් කරන ලෙස සමාගමට මීට පෙර දක්වා තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගූගල් රූබල් බිලියන 21",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 366 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tagansky දිසා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොස්කොමන්ඩෝසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTube",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்யாவில் இருந்து கூகுளுக்கு 366 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் அபராதம் விதிக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உக்ரைனில் நிலவும் மோதல்கள் குறித்த தடை செய்யப்பட்ட தகவல்களை நீக்கத் தவறியதற்காக ரஷ்ய நீதிமன்றம் கூகுள் நிறுவனத்திற்கு 21 பில்லியன் ரூபிள் (366 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்) அபராதம் விதித்துள்ளது.",
        "ரஷ்ய சட்டத்தால் தடைசெய்யப்பட்ட தகவல்களை நீக்கத் திரும்பத் திரும்ப மறுத்த ஐடி நிறுவனத்திற்கு மாஸ்கோவின் தாகன்ஸ்கி மாவட்ட நீதிமன்றம் விற்றுமுதல் அடிப்படையிலான அபராதம் விதித்துள்ளது.",
        "தேசிய இணையம் மற்றும் ஊடக கண்காணிப்பு அமைப்பான Roskommandoza, உக்ரைனில் ரஷ்யாவின் இராணுவத் தாக்குதல் பற்றிய \"தவறான தகவல்களை\" YouTubeல் இருந்து நீக்குமாறு நிறுவனத்திற்கு முன்னர் உத்தரவிட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூகுள் 21 பில்லியன் ரூபிள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$366 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாகன்ஸ்கி மாவட்ட நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஸ்கோமன்டோசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலைஒளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}