{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132229",
  "time_ut": 1658737150,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ் சாலை பணியாளர்கள் பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Transport Board's Jaffna Road Workers strike",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Transport Board's Jaffna road workers and private bus drivers (25) went on strike on Monday.",
        "Last Friday at 9:00 pm, the driver and the guard of the 57-route EPO bus that left Jaffna for Colombo were attacked by the employees of the Kalkamuwa Road EPO Road in Thaladagama, the Sri Lanka Transport Board said that appropriate action should be taken against the employees who carried out the attack. The road workers have been boycotting for the past two days.",
        "Meanwhile, Jaffna district private buses are not in local and out-of-town service due to problems in getting fuel.",
        "Due to lack of fuel to run the service, all private transport has come to a standstill and long distance bus services have not operated.",
        "Sri Lankan Transport Board buses and private buses were involved in boycotting services, and commuters faced a lot of difficulties.",
        "Especially when schools have started after a long time, students and teachers faced difficulties in going to schools."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board's",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaffna Road Workers",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9:00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalkamuwa Road EPO Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thaladagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ යාපනය මාර්ග සේවක වර්ජනය",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ යාපනය මාර්ග සේවකයින් සහ පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ රියදුරන් (25) සඳුදා වැඩ වර්ජනයක නිරත විය.",
        "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා රාත්‍රී 9.00 ට යාපනයේ සිට කොළඹ බලා ධාවනය වූ මාර්ග 57 EPO බස් රථයේ රියදුරුට සහ මුරකරුට තලදාගම කල්කමූව පාර EPO පාරේ සේවකයන් විසින් පහර දුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල කළ සේවකයන්ට එරෙහිව ගෙන ඇත.මාර්ග සේවකයෝ පසුගිය දින දෙකේ සිට වර්ජනයේ නිරත වූහ.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමේ ගැටළු හේතුවෙන් යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික් පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ දේශීය සහ නගරයෙන් පිටත ධාවනය නොවේ.",
        "ධාවනයට අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන නොමැතිවීම හේතුවෙන් සියලුම පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රවාහනය ඇනහිට ඇති අතර දුරගමන් සේවා බස් සේවා ක්‍රියාත්මක නොවීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ බස් රථ සහ පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ සේවා වර්ජනයක නිරත වූ අතර මගී ජනතාව දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ දුන්හ.",
        "විශේෂයෙන් දිගු කාලයකට පසු පාසල් ආරම්භ වී ඇති බැවින් පාසල් යාමට සිසුන් හා ගුරුවරුන් දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුණ පෑහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපනය මාර්ග සේවකයෝ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වරු 9:00",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්කමූව පාර EPO පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලදාගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ் சாலை பணியாளர்கள் பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பு",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ் சாலை பணியாளர்கள், மற்றும் தனியார் பேருந்து சாரதிகள் (25) திங்கட்கிழமை பணிப்பகிஷ்கரிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இரவு 9 மணியளவில் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இருந்து கொழும்பு நோக்கி புறப்பட்ட 57 வழித்தட இ.போ.ச பேருந்தின் சாரதி மற்றும் காப்பாளர் இருவரும் கல்கமுவ சாலை இ.போ.ச சாலை ஊழியர்களினால் தலாதகம எனும் பகுதியில் தாக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில் இந்த தாக்குதலை நடாத்திய ஊழியர்களுக்கு எதிராக உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் யாழ் சாலை ஊழியர்கள் கடந்த இரண்டு தினங்களாக பகிஷ்கரிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "அதேவேளை எரிபொருள் பெறுவதில் உள்ள சிக்கல்கள் காரணமாக யாழ்ப்பாண மாவட்ட தனியார் பேருந்துகள் உள்ளூர் மற்றும் வெளியூரில் சேவையில் ஈடுபடவில்லை.",
        "சேவையில் ஈடுபட எரிபொருள் இல்லாததால் முழு தனியார் போக்குவரத்தும் ஸ்தம்பிதமடைந்து, தூர பேருந்து சேவையும் இடம்பெறவில்லை.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை பேருந்துக்கள் மற்றும் தனியார் பேருந்துகள் சேவை புறக்கணிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டமையால் , பயணிகள் பெரும் சிரமங்களை எதிர்கொண்டனர்.",
        "குறிப்பாக நீண்டகாலத்திற்கு பின்னர்  பாடசாலைகள் ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ள நிலையில் மாணவர்கள் ஆசிரியர்கள் பாடசாலைகளுக்கு செல்ல சிரமங்களை எதிர்கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் வீதிப் பணியாளர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9:00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "57",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கமுவ வீதி EPO வீதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலடகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}