{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-forced-to-walk-out-of-parliament-amid-opposition-protest-96951/",
  "time_ut": 1657007820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka president forced to walk out of parliament amid opposition protest",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka president forced to walk out of parliament amid opposition protest",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was in for a rude shock when he made an appearance in parliament where he was greeted by opposition MPs who loudly protested his presence, a day after they asked where he was hiding.",
        "The president was seen walking out as opposition MPs heckled Prime Minister Ranil Wickreemesinghe during a speech.",
        "Wickremesinghe, who was explaining a roadmap for a way out of Sri Lanka’s ongoing economic crisis, said he was ready to step down if opposition National People’s Power (NPP) leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake could present a viable six-month recovery plan.",
        "This prompted a chorus of “Go home, Gota” from the opposition benches, with the main opposition Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) leading the chant, co-opting a popular slogan from Sri Lanka’s youth protest movement against the government.",
        "“When I said I am ready to go home, they are shouting at the president,” said Wickremesinghe sarcastically, openly laughing at the MPs across the aisle.",
        "Before his departure, President Rajapaksa was also seen laughing along with Wickremesinghe at the opposition’s angry protestations.",
        "“If Anura Dissanayaka’s plan is a success, I will resign and with that the cabinet will resign and Anura Kumara will be given the Prime Minister’s position,” said Wickremesinghe.",
        "Wickremesinghe said Dissanayake’s plan can be taken up for debate on July 07 and 08.",
        "“I am certainly not ready to lie to the public. I must tell the truth and if someone has a better plan than us, we must give power to that person, which can only be done through parliament. If we can’t do it, then there will be no future for this country,” he said.",
        "As the protests intensified, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena adjourned the session for 10 minutes, during which President Rajapaksa had vacated the chamber. (Colombo/Jul05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickreemesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayaka’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 07 and 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විපක්ෂයේ විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටව යාමට සිදුවිය",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පෙනී සිටි විට, ඔහු සැඟවී සිටින්නේ කොහේදැයි ඇසීමෙන් දිනකට පසුව, ඔහුගේ පැමිණීමට දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කළ විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබූ විට, ඔහු දැඩි කම්පනයකට පත් විය.",
        "විපක්‍ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට බනින විට ජනාධිපතිවරයා පිටව යන අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා මාර්ග සිතියමක් පැහැදිලි කරමින් සිටි වික්‍රමසිංහ, විපක්ෂ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (එන්පීපී) නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායකට මාස හයක ශක්‍ය ප්‍රකෘති සැලැස්මක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකි නම් තමන් ඉවත් වීමට සූදානම් බව පැවසීය.",
        "මෙය ආන්ඩුවට එරෙහි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තරුණ විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයේ ජනප්‍රිය සටන් පාඨයක් සමඟින් ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) ප්‍රමුඛ විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සමඟ \"ගොඨා ගෙදර යන්න\" යන ගායනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "“මම ගෙදර යන්න ලෑස්තියි කිව්වම ජනාධිපතිතුමාට කෑ ගහනවා” යැයි වික්‍රමසිංහ උපහාසාත්මක ලෙස කීවේ පාරේ සිටි මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට විවෘතව සිනාසෙමිනි.",
        "ඔහු පිටත්ව යාමට පෙර, විපක්ෂයේ කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාවලට වික්‍රමසිංහ සමඟ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ ද සිනාසෙනු දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "“අනුර දිසානායකගේ සැලැස්ම සාර්ථක වුවහොත් මම ඉල්ලා අස්වෙනවා, ඒ සමඟම කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඉල්ලා අස්වෙලා අනුර කුමාරට අගමැතිකම දෙනවා,” වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසීය.",
        "දිසානායකගේ සැලැස්ම ජූලි 07 සහ 08 යන දිනවල විවාදයට ගත හැකි බව වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසීය.",
        "“මම මහජනතාවට බොරු කියන්න සූදානම් නැහැ. මම ඇත්ත කියන්න ඕන අපිට වඩා හොඳ සැලසුමක් කාට හරි තියෙනවා නම් අපි ඒ පුද්ගලයාට බලය දිය යුතුයි, ඒක කරන්න පුළුවන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන්. අපිට ඒක කරන්න බැරි නම් මේ රටට අනාගතයක් නැහැ.” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "විරෝධතා උත්සන්න වීමත් සමඟ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් සභාව විනාඩි 10කට කල් තැබූ අතර, එම අවස්ථාවේදී ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සභා ගර්භයෙන් ඉවත්ව ගියේය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායකගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 07 සහ 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 10 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் எதிர்ப்புக்கு மத்தியில் இலங்கை அதிபர் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து வெளிநடப்பு செய்தார்",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தோன்றியபோது முரட்டுத்தனமான அதிர்ச்சிக்கு உள்ளானார், அங்கு எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் அவரை வரவேற்றனர், அவர் எங்கு மறைந்திருக்கிறார் என்று அவர்கள் கேட்டதற்கு ஒரு நாள் கழித்து அவர் முன்னிலையில் சத்தமாக எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உரையின் போது பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் கடிந்து கொண்டதையடுத்து ஜனாதிபதி வெளிநடப்பு செய்ததை காணமுடிந்தது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீள்வதற்கான பாதை வரைபடத்தை விளக்கிய விக்கிரமசிங்க, எதிர்க்கட்சியான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் (NPP) தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆறுமாத கால மீட்பு திட்டத்தை முன்வைத்தால் பதவி விலகத் தயார் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இது எதிரணி பெஞ்சுகளில் இருந்து \"வீட்டிற்குச் செல்லுங்கள், கோதா\" என்ற கோரஸைத் தூண்டியது, பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) கோஷத்தை வழிநடத்தியது, அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான இலங்கையின் இளைஞர் எதிர்ப்பு இயக்கத்தின் ஒரு பிரபலமான கோஷத்தை ஒருங்கிணைத்தது.",
        "\"நான் வீட்டிற்குச் செல்லத் தயார் என்று நான் சொன்னபோது, ​​அவர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியைக் கூச்சலிடுகிறார்கள்,\" என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கிண்டலாகக் கூறினார், இடைகழி முழுவதும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைப் பார்த்து வெளிப்படையாக சிரித்தார்.",
        "அவர் புறப்படுவதற்கு முன், ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் கோபமான எதிர்ப்புக்களைப் பார்த்து விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் சேர்ந்து சிரித்துக் கொண்டிருந்தார்.",
        "அநுர திஸாநாயக்கவின் திட்டம் வெற்றியடையும் பட்சத்தில் நான் இராஜினாமா செய்வேன், அதன் மூலம் அமைச்சரவை இராஜினாமா செய்து அநுரகுமாரவுக்கு பிரதமர் பதவி வழங்கப்படும் என விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "திஸாநாயக்கவின் திட்டம் ஜூலை 07 மற்றும் 08 ஆம் திகதிகளில் விவாதத்திற்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படலாம் என விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“பொதுமக்களிடம் பொய் சொல்ல நான் தயாராக இல்லை. நான் உண்மையைச் சொல்ல வேண்டும், எங்களை விட சிறந்த திட்டம் யாரிடமாவது இருந்தால், அந்த நபருக்கு அதிகாரத்தை வழங்க வேண்டும், அது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூலம் மட்டுமே செய்ய முடியும். நம்மால் அதைச் செய்ய முடியாவிட்டால், இந்த நாட்டிற்கு எதிர்காலம் இருக்காது, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எதிர்ப்பு வலுத்ததையடுத்து, சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன அவையை 10 நிமிடங்களுக்கு ஒத்திவைத்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 07 மற்றும் 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}