{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/IMF-chief-pleased-over-SL-reaching-staff-level-pact-for-US-2-9bn/108-244267",
  "time_ut": 1662267262,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF chief pleased over SL reaching staff-level pact for US $ 2.9bn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF chief pleased over SL reaching staff-level pact for US $ 2.9bn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "International Monetary Fund chief Kristalina Georgieva said today that she is very pleased that IMF staff and Sri Lankan government officials have reached a staff-level agreement to support the country’s economic policies with a 48-month Extended Fund Facility of about US$2.9 billion.",
        "The IMF on Thursday announced that it has reached a staff-level agreement with Sri Lanka, in a first step before extending a $2.9 billion loan package that the Fund has made contingent on assurances from the island nation’s creditors.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2.9bn",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kristalina Georgieva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US$2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීම ගැන IMF ප්‍රධානියා සතුටු විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රධානී Kristalina Georgieva අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ නිලධාරීන්, ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9ක පමණ විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමකින් රටේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීම පිළිබඳව තමන් ඉතා සතුටට පත්වන බවයි.",
        "IMF බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා නිවේදනය කළේ, දිවයිනේ ණය හිමියන්ගේ සහතික කිරීම් මත අරමුදල විසින් සිදු කර ඇති ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක ණය පැකේජයක් දීර්ඝ කිරීමට පෙර පළමු පියවර ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹ ඇති බවයි.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බිලියන 2.9 ක්",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර්ජිවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு SL ஊழியர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியதில் IMF தலைவர் மகிழ்ச்சி அடைந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் தலைவர் கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜோர்ஜீவா, 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியுடன் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கு IMF ஊழியர்களும் இலங்கை அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகளும் ஊழியர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டியிருப்பது மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சியளிப்பதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வியாழனன்று IMF, இலங்கையுடன் பணியாளர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியுள்ளதாக அறிவித்தது, இது தீவு நாட்டின் கடனாளிகளின் உறுதிமொழியின் பேரில் நிதியமானது 2.9 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் பொதியை வழங்குவதற்கு முன் முதல் படியாக உள்ளது.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2.9 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜார்ஜீவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}