{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නුගේගොඩ-පොලිසිවල-මේ-මාසේ-පඩි-කොළේ-කරනමක්-ගහලා/1-618756",
  "time_ut": 1661433883,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නුගේගොඩ පොලිසිවල මේ මාසේ පඩි කොළේ කරනමක් ගහලා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Nugegoda Police have done a job in this month's pay slip",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to police sources, the police officers of Nugegoda Police Division have been in a lot of trouble due to the fact that some of them have received less salary and others have not received any salary.",
        "This was revealed yesterday (25) after an inspection was conducted after the salaries were banked for those officials.",
        "The sources state that most of the paid people have received the salary they received in January 2021 and the police officers who came for duty in Nugegoda Police Division from February till now have not received any salary in the bank.",
        "Thousands of officers as well as special officers from 17 police stations belonging to Nugegoda Police Superintendent's jurisdiction, namely Mirihana, Maharagama, Kaduwela, Homagama, Hanwella, Meegoda, Wellampitiya, Athurigiriya, Malambe, Boralasgamuwa, Navagamuwa, Thalangama, Mulleriya, Malabe, Kottawa, Welikada, and Padukka. The officers working in the departments were also in a lot of trouble due to this.",
        "In the meantime, some police officers who have been suspended have also received their salaries from other sources.",
        "Police Media Spokesperson Senior Superintendent of Police Advocate Mr. Nihal Talduwa said that he would look into this matter and give an answer. But tried to connect to the phone on several occasions but could not"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The Nugegoda Police",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "month",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda Police Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda Police Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda Police Superintendent's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaduwela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hanwella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meegoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellampitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athurigiriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malambe, Boralasgamuwa, Navagamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalangama, Mulleriya, Malabe, Kottawa, Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Padukka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nihal Talduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නුගේගොඩ පොලිසිවල මේ මාසේ පඩි කොළේ කරනමක් ගහලා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නුගේගොඩ පොලිස් කොට්ඨාසයේ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට මෙවර වැටුප් ලබා දීමේදී ඇතැම්  පිරිස්වලට වැටුප අඩු වීමත් තවත් පිරිසකට කිසිදු වැටුපක් නොලැබීමත් හේතුවෙන් ඔහුන් දැඩි අපහසුතාවයකට  පත්ව  ඇතැයි පොලිස් ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "මේ බව අනාවරණය වී ඇත්තේ ඊයේ (25) දින  එම නිලධාරීන් සඳහා වූ වැටුප් බැංකු ගත කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව  සිදුකරන ලද පරීක්ෂාවකින් අනතුරුවය",
        "වැටුප් ලද පිරිසෙන් බොහෝ පිරිසකට ලැබී ඇත්තේ 2021 ජනවාරි  මස දී ඔවුන් ලබාගත් වැටුප බවත් පෙබරවාරි මස සිට මේ දක්වා   නුගේගොඩ පොලිස් කොට්ඨාසයේ  රාජකාරි සඳහා පැමිණි පොලිස්  නිලධාරීන්ට කිසිදු වැටුපක් බැංකු ගත වී නැති බවද එම ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "නුගේගොඩ පොලිස් අධිකාරී බල ප්‍රදේශයට අයත් මිරිහාන, මහරගම , කඩුවෙල , හෝමාගම, හංවැල්ල, මීගොඩ, වැල්ලම්පිටිය, අතුරුගිරිය, මාලඹේ , බොරලැස්ගමුව, නවගමුව, තලන්ගම, මුල්ලේරියාව, මාලබේ, කොට්ටාව,  වැලිකඩ,හා පාදුක්ක යන පොලිස් ස්ථාන 17 ක නිලධාරීන් දහස්  ගණනක් මෙන්ම විශේෂ අංශවල සේවය කරන  නිලධාරීහු  ද මේ හේතුවෙන් දැඩි අපහසුතාවයට පත්වූහ.",
        "මේ අතර වැඩතහනමට ලක්වූ ඇතැම් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට ද වැටුප් බැංකු ගතවී ඇතැයි ද වැඩිදුර ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳ පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නීතීඥ නිහාල් තල්දුව මහතාගෙන් විමසීමකදී කියා සිටියේ මේ පිලිබදව  සොයා බලා පිලිතුරක් ලබා දෙන බවය. එහෙත් අවස්ථා කීපයකදීම දුරකථනයට සම්බන්ධ වීමට උත්සාහ කළත් නොහැකි විය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නුගේගොඩ පොලිසිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මස",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ පොලිස් වසමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ පොලිස් වසමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ පොලිස් අධිකාරීගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩුවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හංවැල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලම්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරුගිරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලඹේ, බොරලස්ගමුව, නවගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලංගම, මුල්ලේරිය, මාලඹේ, කොට්ටාව, වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාදුක්ක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த மாத சம்பள சீட்டில் நுகேகொடை போலீசார் ஒரு வேலையை செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நுகேகொடை பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களில் சிலர் குறைந்த சம்பளம் பெற்றுள்ளமையாலும், ஏனையவர்கள் சம்பளம் பெறாததாலும் மிகுந்த சிரமத்திற்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "நேற்று (25) அந்த உத்தியோகத்தர்களுக்கு சம்பளம் நிர்ணயம் செய்யப்பட்டதையடுத்து மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சோதனையின் போதே இது தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "பணம் பெற்றவர்களில் பெரும்பாலானோர் 2021 ஜனவரியில் பெற்ற சம்பளத்தை பெற்றுள்ளதாகவும், பெப்ரவரி மாதம் முதல் இதுவரை நுகேகொட பொலிஸ் பிரிவில் கடமைக்கு வந்த பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் வங்கியில் சம்பளம் பெறவில்லை எனவும் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "நுகேகொடை பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகரின் அதிகார எல்லைக்குட்பட்ட 17 பொலிஸ் நிலையங்களான மிரிஹான, மஹரகம, கடுவெல, ஹோமாகம, ஹன்வெல்ல, மீகொட, வெல்லம்பிட்டிய, அத்துரிகிரிய, மலம்பே, பொரலஸ்கமுவ, நவகமுவ, கொட்டாரியம், மலபெல், மலபெல், தலங்கம, மலபெல், என ஆயிரக்கணக்கான உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் மற்றும் விசேட அதிகாரிகள். வெலிக்கடை, பாதுக்க ஆகிய திணைக்களங்களில் பணிபுரியும் உத்தியோகத்தர்களும் இதனால் மிகவும் சிரமத்திற்குள்ளாகினர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில் சஸ்பெண்ட் செய்யப்பட்ட சில காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகளும் வேறு வழிகளில் சம்பளம் பெற்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் ஆராய்ந்து பதில் அளிப்பதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் சட்டத்தரணி திரு.நிஹால் தல்துவா தெரிவித்தார். ஆனால் பலமுறை போனை இணைக்க முயன்றும் முடியவில்லை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நுகேகொட பொலிஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாதம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட பொலிஸ் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட பொலிஸ் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹன்வெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுரிகிரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலம்பே, பொரலஸ்கமுவ, நவகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலங்கம, முல்லேரியா, மாலபே, கொட்டாவ, வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}