{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-flees-to-maldives-97308/",
  "time_ut": 1657675920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President flees to Maldives",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President flees to Maldives",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa had fled to the Maldives in a military aircraft, reports said as his resignation is expected later in the day amid the worst currency crisis in the history of the island’s intermediate regime central bank.",
        "Sri Lanka’s Derana Television quoted Air Force Spokesman Group Dushan Wijesinghe as saying that on a of the existing government request President Rajapaksa, his wife and two body guards had left the country in an Air Force aircraft.",
        "The French News Agency reported that President Rajapaksa had left in a Antonov 32 aircraft to the Maldives.",
        "Sri Lanka President Rajapaksa is expected to give his resignation today, according to an earlier statement by the speaker."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Derana Television",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The French News Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Antonov",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති මාලදිවයිනට පලා යයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගොස් ඇති බව වාර්තා වන පරිදි, දිවයිනේ අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම පසු දින බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙරණ රූපවාහිනිය උපුටා දක්වමින් ගුවන් හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක සමූහ දුෂාන් විජේසිංහ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පවතින රජයේ ඉල්ලීමක් මත ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු ගුවන් හමුදාවේ ගුවන් යානයකින් රට හැර ගිය බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රංශ පුවත් ඒජන්සිය වාර්තා කළේ, ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඇන්ටනොව් 32 ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගිය බවයි.",
        "කථානායකවරයාගේ කලින් ප්‍රකාශයකට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ අද සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ලබා දෙනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙරණ රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කණ්ඩායම දුෂාන් විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශ පුවත් ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ටනොව්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அதிபர் மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இராணுவ விமானத்தில் மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளார், தீவின் இடைநிலை ஆட்சியின் மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் அவர் பதவி விலகுவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது என தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு மெய்க்காவலர்கள் விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதாக விமானப்படை பேச்சாளர் குழு துஷான் விஜேசிங்கவை மேற்கோள்காட்டி இலங்கையின் தெரண தொலைக்காட்சி தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மாலத்தீவுக்கு அன்டோனோவ் 32 ரக விமானத்தில் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே புறப்பட்டதாக பிரான்ஸ் செய்தி நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சபாநாயகரின் முந்தைய அறிக்கையின்படி, இலங்கை அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே இன்று ராஜினாமா செய்வார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெரனா தொலைக்காட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு துஷான் விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரெஞ்சு செய்தி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்டோனோவ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}