{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/sri-lankas-popular-brand-hemas-set-to-enter-omani-market/",
  "time_ut": 1657452180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s popular brand ‘Hemas’ set to enter Omani market",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s popular brand ‘Hemas’ set to enter Omani market",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s 72 year old leading public quoted company Hemas Holding PLC is set to enter the Omani market.Ambassador of Sri Lanka to the Sultanate of Oman Ameer Ajwad together with Hemas Senior Manager for International Business Promotion Kavindra Kasun Sigera met the Chairman of the Oman Chamber of Commerce and Industry (OCCI), Engr. Redha Juma Al Saleh, the sole representative of the entire Oman private sector, and introduced the Hemas brand. They also discussed ways and means to present Hemas products into the Omani market and the future scope for establishing a Hemas manufacturing facility in the Sultanate.",
        "The Embassy of Sri Lanka in Muscat facilitated a series of B2B meetings between Hemas Senior Manager for International Business and their potential counterparts in Oman, including Muscat Pharmacy (FMCG Division), Concordia Group, Future Well Trading, LuLu Hypermarket, SPAR Supermarkets, etc. to establish business links.",
        "The Senior Business Consultant of MS Holding (pvt) Ltd Dineshkumar Karthigesu, who coordinated the visit by Hemas Consumer Good to the Sultanate of Oman, accompanied the delegation.",
        "DIMO unveils Pela Batta, paddy transplanting machine in Sri Lanka",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Omani",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemas Holding PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sultanate of Oman Ameer Ajwad",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Business Promotion Kavindra Kasun Sigera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Oman Chamber of Commerce and Industry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Engr",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Redha Juma Al Saleh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sultanate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Embassy of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muscat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muscat Pharmacy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Concordia Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LuLu Hypermarket",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MS Holding",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dineshkumar Karthigesu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pela Batta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනප්‍රිය සන්නාමය වන ‘හේමාස්’ ඕමාන වෙළඳපොළට පිවිසීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර 72ක් පැරණි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ මහජන උපුටාගත් සමාගමක් වන Hemas Holding PLC ඕමාන වෙළඳපොළට පිවිසීමට නියමිතය. ඕමානයේ සුල්තාන් රාජ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති අමීර් අජ්වාඩ් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ව්‍යාපාර ප්‍රවර්ධන හේමාස් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාර කවින්ද්‍ර කසුන් සිගේරා ඕමාන් වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපතිවරයා හමුවිය. වාණිජ හා කර්මාන්ත (OCCI), ඉංජිනේරු. සමස්ත ඕමාන් පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ එකම නියෝජිතයා වන Redha Juma Al Saleh විසින් Hemas සන්නාමය හඳුන්වා දෙන ලදී. හේමාස් නිෂ්පාදන ඕමාන වෙළඳපොළට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමේ ක්‍රම සහ විධි සහ සුල්තාන් රාජ්‍යයේ හේමාස් නිෂ්පාදන මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් පිහිටුවීමේ අනාගත විෂය පථය පිළිබඳව ද ඔවුහු සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "මස්කට් හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය විසින් ජාත්‍යන්තර ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා හේමාස් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකරු සහ මස්කට් ෆාමසි (FMCG අංශය), Concordia Group, Future Well Trading, LuLu Hypermarket, SPAR සුපිරි වෙළඳසැල් ඇතුළු ඕමානයේ ඔවුන්ගේ අනාගත සගයන් අතර B2B රැස්වීම් මාලාවකට පහසුකම් සපයන ලදී. ව්‍යාපාරික සම්බන්ධතා ඇති කර ගැනීමට.",
        "හේමාස් පාරිභෝගික භාණ්ඩ ඕමානයේ සුල්තාන් රාජ්‍යයේ සංචාරය සම්බන්ධීකරණය කළ MS Holding (pvt) Ltd හි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ව්‍යාපාරික උපදේශක දිනේෂ්කුමාර් කාර්තිගේසු මහතා ද නියෝජිත පිරිස සමඟ එක්ව සිටියේය.",
        "ඩීමෝ විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වී බද්ධ කිරීමේ යන්ත්‍රය පැල බට්ටා එළිදක්වයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඕමාන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමාස් හෝල්ඩින් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් සුල්තාන් අමීර් අජ්වාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර ව්‍යාපාර ප්‍රවර්ධනය කවින්ද්‍ර කසුන් සිගේරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් වාණිජ හා කර්මාන්ත මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංජිනේරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙධා ජුමා අල් සලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුල්තාන් රාජ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මස්කට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර ව්යාපාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මස්කට් ෆාමසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්කෝඩියා සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LuLu අධි වෙළඳසැල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MS Holding",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ්කුමාර් කාර්තිගේසු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැල බට්ටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பிரபல வர்த்தக நாமமான ‘ஹேமாஸ்’ ஓமானி சந்தையில் பிரவேசிக்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 72 வயதான முன்னணி பொது மேற்கோள் நிறுவனமான ஹேமாஸ் ஹோல்டிங் பிஎல்சி ஓமானி சந்தையில் நுழைய உள்ளது. ஓமானுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் அமீர் அஜ்வாத் மற்றும் சர்வதேச வர்த்தக ஊக்குவிப்புக்கான ஹேமாஸ் சிரேஷ்ட முகாமையாளர் கவீந்திர கசுன் சிகேரா ஆகியோர் ஓமன் சேம்பர் தலைவரை சந்தித்தனர். வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை (OCCI), இன்ஜி. முழு ஓமன் தனியார் துறையின் ஒரே பிரதிநிதியான ரெதா ஜுமா அல் சலே மற்றும் ஹேமாஸ் பிராண்ட் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. ஹேமாஸ் தயாரிப்புகளை ஓமானி சந்தையில் வழங்குவதற்கான வழிகள் மற்றும் வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் சுல்தானகத்தில் ஹேமாஸ் உற்பத்தி நிலையத்தை நிறுவுவதற்கான எதிர்கால நோக்கம் குறித்தும் அவர்கள் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "மஸ்கட்டில் உள்ள இலங்கைத் தூதரகம், சர்வதேச வணிகத்திற்கான ஹேமாஸ் மூத்த மேலாளர் மற்றும் மஸ்கட் பார்மசி (FMCG பிரிவு), கான்கார்டியா குழுமம், ஃபியூச்சர் வெல் டிரேடிங், லுலு ஹைப்பர் மார்க்கெட், SPAR பல்பொருள் அங்காடிகள், முதலியன உட்பட ஓமானில் உள்ள அவர்களது சாத்தியமான சகாக்களுக்கு இடையே தொடர்ச்சியான B2B சந்திப்புகளுக்கு உதவியது. வணிக இணைப்புகளை நிறுவ.",
        "MS Holding (pvt) Ltd இன் மூத்த வணிக ஆலோசகர் தினேஷ்குமார் கார்த்திகேசு, ஓமான் சுல்தானகத்திற்கான ஹேமாஸ் நுகர்வோர் குட் நிறுவனத்தின் வருகையை ஒருங்கிணைத்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் நெல் நடவு இயந்திரமான பேல பட்டாவை DIMO அறிமுகம் செய்துள்ளது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஓமானி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமாஸ் ஹோல்டிங் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் சுல்தான் அமீர் அஜ்வாத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வர்த்தக ஊக்குவிப்பு கவீந்திர கசுன் சிகேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெதா ஜுமா அல் சலே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுல்தானகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஸ்கட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய வர்த்தகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஸ்கட் மருந்தகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கான்கார்டியா குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லுலு ஹைப்பர் மார்க்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SPAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.எஸ் ஹோல்டிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ்குமார் கார்த்திகேசு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேலா பட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}