{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/යුද-සමයේ-ඉන්දියාවට-ගිය-ලාංකිකයන්-කඩිනමින්-ගෙන්වා-ගන්න--කමිටුවක්/101-619330",
  "time_ut": 1662372708,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යුද සමයේ ඉන්දියාවට ගිය ලාංකිකයන් කඩිනමින් ගෙන්වා ගන්න  කමිටුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A committee to quickly bring back the Sri Lankans who went to India during the war",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A committee has been appointed by President's Secretary Mr. Saman Ekanayake to facilitate the repatriation of Sri Lankans who have gone to India as refugees due to the war.",
        "This committee has been appointed under the chairmanship of Miss Chandima Wickramasinghe, Additional Secretary to the President.",
        "The committee comprises senior officials from the Comptroller General of Immigration, Ministry of External Affairs, Registrar General's Department and Ministry of Justice.",
        "This decision was reached in the discussion held today (05) at the President's Office under the chairmanship of President's Secretary Mr. Saman Ekanayake at the request of the \"Organization for the Rehabilitation of Eelam Refugees\" (OFERR) to repatriate Sri Lankans who have gone to India as refugees due to the war.",
        "It was stated that about 58,000 Sri Lankans living in Tamil Nadu state of India are currently staying as refugees and about 3800 of them are ready to return to Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandima Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Comptroller General of Immigration, Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Registrar General's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department and Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the \"Organization for the Rehabilitation of Eelam Refugees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OFERR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 58,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 3800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුද සමයේ ඉන්දියාවට ගිය ලාංකිකයන් කඩිනමින් ගෙන්වා ගන්න  කමිටුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුද්ධය හේතුවෙන් සරණාගතයින් ලෙස ඉන්දියාවට ගොස් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් නැවත ගෙන්වා ගැනීම කාර්යක්ෂම කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා විසින් කමිටුවක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම කමිටුව ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් චන්දිමා වික්‍රමසිංහ මෙනවියගේ  ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ආගමන  විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය, රෙජිස්ටර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ  අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් කමිටුව  සමන්විත වේ.",
        "යුද්ධය හේතුවෙන් සරණාගතයින් ලෙස ඉන්දියාවට ගොස් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් නැවත ගෙන්වා ගැනීම සඳහා “ඊළාම් සරණාගතයින් පුනරුත්ථාපනය සඳහා වූ සංවිධානයේ” (OFERR) ඉල්ලීම පරිදි ජනාධිපති  ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී  අද (05) පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවේ දී මෙම තීරණයට එළැඹිණි.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්තයේ වෙසෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් 58,000ක් පමණ මේ වන විට සරණාගතයින් ලෙස රැඳී  සිටින අතර එම පිරිස අතරින් 3800ක් පමණ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නැවත පැමිණීමට සූදානමින් සිටින බවත් එහිදී සඳහන් විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"ඊලාම් සරණාගතයින් පුනරුත්ථාපනය කිරීම සඳහා වූ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිනැමීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3800 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போரின் போது இந்தியாவுக்குச் சென்ற இலங்கையர்களை விரைவாக அழைத்து வர குழு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யுத்தம் காரணமாக இந்தியாவிற்கு அகதிகளாகச் சென்ற இலங்கையர்களை நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதியாக ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் திரு.சமன் ஏகநாயக்கவினால் குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் மிஸ் சந்திமா விக்ரமசிங்க தலைமையில் இந்தக் குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் குழுவில் குடிவரவுக் கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரல், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு, பதிவாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் நீதி அமைச்சு ஆகியவற்றின் உயர் அதிகாரிகள் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "“ஈழ அகதிகள் புனர்வாழ்விற்கான அமைப்பு” (OFERR) விடுத்த வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் திரு.சமன் ஏகநாயக்க தலைமையில் இன்று (05) ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் இந்த முடிவு எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது. போர் காரணமாக அகதிகளாக இந்தியாவிற்கு.",
        "இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாடு மாநிலத்தில் வசிக்கும் சுமார் 58,000 இலங்கையர்கள் தற்போது அகதிகளாக தங்கியிருப்பதாகவும் அவர்களில் சுமார் 3800 பேர் இலங்கை திரும்புவதற்கு தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திம விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு, குடிவரவுக் கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை மற்றும் நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"ஈழ அகதிகளின் மறுவாழ்வுக்கான அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OFERR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 58,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}