{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SLNSS-members-of-SriLankan-Airlines-also-to-withdraw-from-service-from-noon/342-240914",
  "time_ut": 1657612385,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLNSS members of SriLankan Airlines also to withdraw from service from noon",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLNSS members of SriLankan Airlines also to withdraw from service from noon",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan Nidahas Sewaka Sangamaya (SLNSS) of the SriLankan airlines also decided to withdraw from services, in order to prevent responsible officials who are involved in the country's present crisis from leaving.",
        "Therefore, considering all aspects, the SLNSS has decided to withdraw from their duties from noon today and has also decided to stay away from passenger handling on the Silk Route/CIP."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLNSS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "noon",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sewaka Sangamaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNSS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Silk Route/CIP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ SLNSS සාමාජිකයින් ද දහවල් සිට සේවයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකන් නිදහස් සේවක සංගමය (SLNSS) ද සේවාවලින් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කළේ රටේ වත්මන් අර්බුදයට සම්බන්ධ වගකිවයුතු නිලධාරීන් පිටව යාම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා ය.",
        "එබැවින්, සියලු අංශ සලකා බලමින්, SLNSS අද දහවල් සිට සිය රාජකාරිවලින් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කර ඇති අතර සේද මාර්ගය/සීඅයිපී හි මගීන් හැසිරවීමෙන් ඈත් වීමට ද තීරණය කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLNSS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දහවල්",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේවක සංගමය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNSS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේද මාර්ගය/CIP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் SLNSS உறுப்பினர்களும் நண்பகல் முதல் சேவையிலிருந்து விலக வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள பொறுப்பான அதிகாரிகள் வெளியேறுவதைத் தடுப்பதற்காக, ஸ்ரீலங்கன் விமான சேவையின் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் நிதாஹஸ் சேவக சங்கமயாவும் (SLNSS) சேவைகளில் இருந்து விலகத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, அனைத்து அம்சங்களையும் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, SLNSS இன்று நண்பகல் முதல் தங்கள் பணிகளில் இருந்து விலக முடிவு செய்துள்ளது மற்றும் சில்க் ரூட்/சிஐபியில் பயணிகளைக் கையாள்வதில் இருந்து விலகி இருக்கவும் முடிவு செய்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்.எஸ்.எஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நண்பகல்",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேவக சங்கமய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்.எஸ்.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நண்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டு பாதை/சிஐபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}