{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/යුවාන්-වැංග්-5-කිසිඳු-රටක-බලපෑමකට-ලක්-නොවිය-යුතුයි/11-396350",
  "time_ut": 1660673165,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යුවාන් වැංග් 5 කිසිඳු රටක බලපෑමකට ලක් නොවිය යුතුයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Yuan Wang 5 should not be influenced by any country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China maintains that the Yuan Wang-5 Chinese scientific research vessel will not affect the security and economic interests of any country and should not be interfered with by a third party.",
        "Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Mr. Wang Wenbin said this while answering a question raised by a journalist at a press conference held today (16) in Beijing.",
        "Mr. Wang Wenbin said here that the Chinese scientific research ship Yuan Wang-5 successfully docked at Hambantota Port with the active cooperation of the Sri Lankan side on the afternoon of the 16th Beijing time.",
        "China and Sri Lanka, as two traditional friendly countries, have maintained close cooperation in the field of marine science research for a long time.",
        "He also said that the marine science research activities carried out by the Yuan Wang-5 scientific research ship are in accordance with international rules and regulations and will not affect the security and economic benefits of any country, and should not be interfered with by third parties."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang-5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the afternoon of the 16th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුවාන් වැංග් 5 කිසිඳු රටක බලපෑමකට ලක් නොවිය යුතුයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් - 5 චීන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ නෞකාව කිසිදු රටක ආරක්ෂක හා ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිලාභයට බලපෑම් එල්ල නොකරන බවත්, එය තුන්වන පාර්ශ්වයක බාධාවන්ට ලක් නොවිය යුතු බවත් චීනය කියාසිටී.",
        "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යංශ ප්‍රකාශක වං වෙන්බින් මහතා මේ බව පැවසුවේ, බෙයිජිංහි අද (16) පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු  නැගූ  ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමිනි.",
        "බෙයිජිං වේලාවෙන් 16වනදා දහවල් කාලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ශ්වයේ සක්‍රිය සහයෝගතාව ඇතිව යුවාන් වැන්ග් - 5 චීන විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ නෞකාව හම්බන්තොට වරායේ සාර්ථකව නැංගුරම් ලූ බව වං වෙන්බින් මහතා මෙහිදී පැවසීය.",
        "චීනය හා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍රශීලි රටවල් දෙකක් වශයෙන් දිගු කලක් පුරා සමුද්‍රීය විද්‍යා පර්යේෂණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ  සමීප සහයෝගතා පවත්වා ඇත.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් - 5 විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ නෞකාව සිදු කරන සමුද්‍රීය විද්‍යා පර්යේෂණ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ජගත් නීතිරීති හා ජගත් රෙගුලාසීන්වලට අනුකූල බවත් එය කිසිදු රටක ආරක්ෂක හා ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිලාභයන්ට බලපෑම් එල්ල නොකරන අතර, තුන්වන පාර්ශ්වයේ බාධාවකට ලක් නොවිය යුතු බව ද ඔහු කියා සිටි‍යේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang-5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 වැනිදා පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யுவான் வாங் 5 எந்த நாட்டினாலும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடாது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யுவான் வாங்-5 சீன அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல் எந்த நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களைப் பாதிக்காது என்றும் மூன்றாம் தரப்பினரால் தலையிடக் கூடாது என்றும் சீனா கூறுகிறது.",
        "பீஜிங்கில் இன்று (16) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவர் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் திரு.வாங் வென்பின் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சீன விஞ்ஞான ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலான யுவான் வாங்-5 இலங்கைத் தரப்பின் தீவிர ஒத்துழைப்புடன் 16ஆம் நாள் பெய்ஜிங் நேரப்படி பிற்பகல் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் வெற்றிகரமாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டதாக திரு.வாங் வென்பின் இங்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சீனாவும் இலங்கையும் இரண்டு பாரம்பரிய நட்பு நாடுகளாக, கடல்சார் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சித் துறையில் நீண்ட காலமாக நெருக்கமான ஒத்துழைப்பைப் பேணி வருகின்றன.",
        "யுவான் வாங்-5 அறிவியல் ஆய்வுக் கப்பலால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் கடல் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகள் சர்வதேச விதிகள் மற்றும் விதிமுறைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு எந்த நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நன்மைகளையும் பாதிக்காது என்றும், மூன்றாம் தரப்பினரால் தலையிடக் கூடாது என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang-5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "16ஆம் தேதி மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}