{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/petrol-shipment-further-delayed-kanchana/",
  "time_ut": 1656075720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Petrol shipment further delayed – Kanchana",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petrol shipment further delayed – Kanchana",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekara says that health services were allocated 85 filling statins on Friday (24).",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) communicated to the owners that 6,600L of petrol and 6,600L diesel were distributed to the locations each, tweeted the Minister.",
        "Also, Minister Wijesekara said that they communicated the quantities that they will be able to distribute to the Health Authorities.",
        "However, he said the unfortunately CPC has been informed a further delay of a petrol shipment and a new date of arrival will be confirmed later today (24).",
        "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "later today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල් යැවීම තවත් ප්‍රමාදයි – කාංචනා",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සිකුරාදා (24) සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පිරවුම් ස්ටැටින් 85 ක් වෙන් කළ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 6,600 ක් සහ ඩීසල් ලීටර් 6,600 බැගින් එම ස්ථානවලට බෙදා හැර ඇති බව ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) හිමිකරුවන්ට දන්වා ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම තමන්ට බෙදා හැරිය හැකි ප්‍රමාණයන් සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන්ට දැනුම් දුන් බවද අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අවාසනාවන්ත ලෙස පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බව ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට දන්වා ඇති බවත්, පැමිණෙන දිනය අද (24) පසුව තහවුරු කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගියදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී සිදුවීම් සොයා බලන කමිටුව Fmr යුධ හමුදාපතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதம் - காஞ்சனா",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (24) சுகாதார சேவைகளுக்கு 85 நிரப்பு ஸ்டேடின்கள் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) ஒவ்வொரு இடங்களுக்கும் 6,600L பெற்றோல் மற்றும் 6,600L டீசல் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக உரிமையாளர்களுக்குத் தெரிவித்ததாக அமைச்சர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், தாங்கள் விநியோகிக்கக்கூடிய அளவுகளை சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளுக்கு தெரிவித்ததாக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், துரதிருஷ்டவசமாக CPC க்கு பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியில் மேலும் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், புதிய வருகை தேதி இன்று (24) பின்னர் உறுதி செய்யப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சமீபத்திய கலவரங்களை விசாரிக்கும் குழு எஃப்எம்ஆர் இராணுவத் தளபதியிடம் இருந்து அறிக்கையைப் பெறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600லி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600லி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Petrol shipment further delayed – Kanchana",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekara says that health services were allocated 85 filling statins on Friday (24).",
    "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) communicated to the owners that 6,600L of petrol and 6,600L diesel were distributed to the locations each, tweeted the Minister.",
    "Also, Minister Wijesekara said that they communicated the quantities that they will be able to distribute to the Health Authorities.",
    "However, he said the unfortunately CPC has been informed a further delay of a petrol shipment and a new date of arrival will be confirmed later today (24).",
    "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petrol shipment further delayed – Kanchana",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekara says that health services were allocated 85 filling statins on Friday (24).",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) communicated to the owners that 6,600L of petrol and 6,600L diesel were distributed to the locations each, tweeted the Minister.",
        "Also, Minister Wijesekara said that they communicated the quantities that they will be able to distribute to the Health Authorities.",
        "However, he said the unfortunately CPC has been informed a further delay of a petrol shipment and a new date of arrival will be confirmed later today (24).",
        "Committee probing recent riots obtains statement from fmr Army Commander"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "later today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල් යැවීම තවත් ප්‍රමාදයි – කාංචනා",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සිකුරාදා (24) සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පිරවුම් ස්ටැටින් 85 ක් වෙන් කළ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් ලීටර් 6,600 ක් සහ ඩීසල් ලීටර් 6,600 බැගින් එම ස්ථානවලට බෙදා හැර ඇති බව ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) හිමිකරුවන්ට දන්වා ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම තමන්ට බෙදා හැරිය හැකි ප්‍රමාණයන් සෞඛ්‍ය බලධාරීන්ට දැනුම් දුන් බවද අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අවාසනාවන්ත ලෙස පෙට්‍රල් තොගයක් තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බව ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට දන්වා ඇති බවත්, පැමිණෙන දිනය අද (24) පසුව තහවුරු කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගියදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී සිදුවීම් සොයා බලන කමිටුව Fmr යුධ හමුදාපතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600L",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதம் - காஞ்சனா",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (24) சுகாதார சேவைகளுக்கு 85 நிரப்பு ஸ்டேடின்கள் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) ஒவ்வொரு இடங்களுக்கும் 6,600L பெற்றோல் மற்றும் 6,600L டீசல் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக உரிமையாளர்களுக்குத் தெரிவித்ததாக அமைச்சர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், தாங்கள் விநியோகிக்கக்கூடிய அளவுகளை சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளுக்கு தெரிவித்ததாக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், துரதிருஷ்டவசமாக CPC க்கு பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதியில் மேலும் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், புதிய வருகை தேதி இன்று (24) பின்னர் உறுதி செய்யப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சமீபத்திய கலவரங்களை விசாரிக்கும் குழு எஃப்எம்ஆர் இராணுவத் தளபதியிடம் இருந்து அறிக்கையைப் பெறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600லி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,600லி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}