{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Agriculture-Department-begins-to-distribute-urea-fertiliser-countywide/56-737691",
  "time_ut": 1658260249,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Agriculture Department begins to distribute urea fertiliser countywide",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Agriculture Department begins to distribute urea fertiliser countywide",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Says 3,000 tons of urea distributed among Agrarian Service Centres countrywide within three days",
        "Rice yield in 2021/22 Maha season drops by 50% to 1.6 m tons due to non-availability of urea fertiliser",
        "SL expects another shipment of 21,000 tons of urea to arrive within the next two weeks",
        "The Department of Agriculture has distributed 3,000 tons of urea fertiliser to Agrarian Service Centres across the country within three days.",
        "The stock was from the first batch of 44,000 tons from the total of 65,000 tons of urea fertiliser received under the Indian Credit Line commenced after it was stored at warehouses belonging to the State-owned Ceylon Fertiliser Company Ltd., and the Colombo Commercial Fertiliser Ltd.",
        "It was reported that the paddy yield decreased rapidly due to the decision to not provide urea fertiliser during the last three seasons.",
        "During the 2021/2022 Maha season, as farmers had to cultivate without urea fertiliser, the rice yield dropped significantly by about 50% to 1.6 million tons. Sri Lanka produces around three million tons of rice during the Maha harvesting season annually.",
        "However, former Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said due to the decision to provide urea fertiliser from the current Yala season, more paddy fields have been cultivated than any other season.",
        "Former Minister Amaraweera said another ship carrying 21,000 tons of urea is scheduled to arrive in Sri Lanka within the next two weeks."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Agriculture Department",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agrarian Service Centres",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021/22 Maha season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 m tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agrarian Service Centres",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Credit Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Fertiliser Company Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Commercial Fertiliser Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last three seasons",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 million tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around three million tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දිවයින පුරා යූරියා පොහොර බෙදා හැරීම අරඹයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දින තුනක් ඇතුළත යූරියා ටොන් 3000ක් රටපුරා ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථාන අතර බෙදාහරින බව කියයි",
        "යූරියා පොහොර නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් 2021/22 මහ කන්නයේ සහල් අස්වැන්න 50% සිට ටොන් මීටර් 1.6 දක්වා පහත වැටේ.",
        "ඉදිරි සති දෙක ඇතුළත යූරියා ටොන් 21,000ක තවත් නැව්ගත කිරීමක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත දින තුනක් ඇතුළත යූරියා පොහොර ටොන් 3000ක් බෙදා දී ඇත.",
        "මෙම තොගය ඉන්දියානු ණය රේඛාව යටතේ ලැබුණු යූරියා පොහොර ටොන් 65,000 න් පළමු කාණ්ඩයේ ටොන් 44,000 කින් සමන්විත වූ අතර එය රජයට අයත් සීමාසහිත ලංකා පොහොර සමාගමට සහ කොළඹ කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගමට අයත් ගබඩාවල ගබඩා කිරීමෙන් පසුව ආරම්භ විය. .",
        "පසුගිය කන්න තුනේදී යූරියා පොහොර ලබා නොදීමට තීරණය කිරීම නිසා වී අස්වැන්න ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් අඩු වූ බව වාර්තා විය.",
        "2021/2022 මහ කන්නයේ දී ගොවීන්ට යූරියා පොහොර නොමැතිව වගා කිරීමට සිදු වූ බැවින් සහල් අස්වැන්න ටොන් මිලියන 1.6 සිට 50% කින් පමණ සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස පහත වැටුණි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වාර්ෂිකව මහ අස්වනු නෙලන සමයේදී සහල් ටොන් මිලියන තුනක් පමණ නිෂ්පාදනය කරයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, හිටපු කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසුවේ මෙවර යල කන්නයේ සිට යූරියා පොහොර ලබාදීමට තීරණය කිරීම හේතුවෙන් අනෙකුත් කන්නයකට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් කුඹුරු වගා කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "යූරියා ටොන් 21,000ක් රැගත් තවත් නෞකාවක් ඉදිරි සති දෙක තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව හිටපු අමාත්‍ය අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021/22 මහ කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 1.6 m",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 21,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 44,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 65,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ණය රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත Colombo Commercial Fertilizer.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වාර තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50% පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් මිලියන 1.6 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් මිලියන තුනක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 21,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யூரியா உரத்தை மாவட்டம் முழுவதும் வினியோகம் செய்யும் பணியை வேளாண் துறை தொடங்கியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள கமநல சேவை மையங்களுக்கு மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் 3,000 டன் யூரியா விநியோகம்",
        "யூரியா உரம் கிடைக்காததால் 2021/22 மஹா பருவத்தில் நெல் விளைச்சல் 50% குறைந்து 1.6 மீ டன்னாக உள்ளது.",
        "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் 21,000 டன் யூரியா ஏற்றுமதி வரும் என்று SL எதிர்பார்க்கிறது",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள கமநல சேவை நிலையங்களுக்கு மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் 3,000 தொன் யூரியா உரத்தை விவசாய திணைக்களம் விநியோகித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியக் கடன் வரியின் கீழ் பெறப்பட்ட மொத்த யூரியா உரமான 65,000 டன்களில் முதல் தொகுதி 44,000 டன்கள் கையிருப்பு, அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான சிலோன் பெர்டிலைசர் கம்பெனி லிமிடெட் மற்றும் கொழும்பு கொமர்ஷல் பெர்டிலைசர் லிமிடெட் ஆகியவற்றின் கிடங்குகளில் சேமித்து வைக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் தொடங்கியது. .",
        "கடந்த மூன்று பருவங்களில் யூரியா உரம் வழங்கப்படுவதில்லை என்ற முடிவினால் நெல் விளைச்சல் வேகமாக குறைந்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2021/2022 மஹா பருவத்தில், விவசாயிகள் யூரியா உரம் இல்லாமல் பயிரிட வேண்டியிருந்ததால், நெல் விளைச்சல் கணிசமாக 50% குறைந்து 1.6 மில்லியன் டன்கள் வரை குறைந்தது. இலங்கை வருடாந்தம் மகா அறுவடைக் காலத்தில் சுமார் மூன்று மில்லியன் தொன் அரிசியை உற்பத்தி செய்கிறது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நடப்பு யால பருவத்தில் இருந்து யூரியா உரத்தை வழங்க தீர்மானித்ததன் காரணமாக, ஏனைய பருவங்களை விட அதிகளவு நெற்செய்கை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் 21,000 தொன் யூரியாவை ஏற்றிக்கொண்டு மற்றுமொரு கப்பல் இலங்கைக்கு வரவுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய சேவை மையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021/22 மகா சீசன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 மீ டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய சேவை மையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடன் வரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் பெர்டிலைசர் கம்பெனி லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கமர்ஷியல் பெர்டிலைசர் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மூன்று பருவங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.6 மில்லியன் டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் மூன்று மில்லியன் டன்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}