{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/11/no-indian-troop-deployment-to-sri-lanka-high-commission/",
  "time_ut": 1657511100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NO Indian troop deployment to Sri Lanka – High Commission",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NO Indian troop deployment to Sri Lanka – High Commission",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Indian High Commission in Colombo had categorically denied speculative reports in sections of media and social media about India sending her troops to Sri Lanka.",
        "These reports and such views are also not in keeping with the position of the Government of India, tweeted the High Commission.",
        "The Spokesperson of Ministry of External Affairs of India clearly stated that India stands with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realize their aspirations for prosperity & progress through democratic means & values, established institutions & constitutional framework.",
        "The Indian Ministry of External Affairs’ official spokesperson Arindam Bagchi said, “India is Sri Lanka’s closest neighbour and our two countries share deep civilizational bonds.”",
        "“We continue to closely follow the recent developments in Sri Lanka. India stands with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realize their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values, established institutions and constitutional framework,” Bagchi said.",
        "Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday said the Indian government has always been supportive of Sri Lanka and it was “trying to help” the neighbouring country through its present economic crisis and made it clear that there was “no refugee crisis right now”.",
        "Speaking to reporters outside the Thiruvananthapuram airport after arriving in the state capital on a three-day visit, Jaishankar said, “We have been very supportive of Sri Lanka. We are trying to help and we are always very helpful where they are concerned."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka –",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Spokesperson of Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්දීය හමුදා යෙදවීමක් නෑ - මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්දියාව සිය හමුදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එවීම පිළිබඳව මාධ්‍ය සහ සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල ඇතැම් සමපේක්ෂන වාර්තා කොළඹ පිහිටි ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර තිබුණි.",
        "මෙම වාර්තා සහ එවැනි අදහස් ඉන්දීය රජයේ ස්ථාවරයට නොගැළපෙන බව මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමෘද්ධිය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා වූ ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන විට ඉන්දියාව ඔවුන් සමඟ සිටින බව ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක පැහැදිලිව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිල ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi පැවසුවේ, \"ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමීපතම අසල්වැසියා වන අතර අප දෙරට ගැඹුරු ශිෂ්ටාචාරීය බැඳීම් බෙදා හදා ගන්නා\" බවයි.",
        "“අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෑත කාලීන වර්ධනයන් සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටිමු. ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා සමෘද්ධිය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන විට ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ සිටී, ”බග්චි පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය එස් ජයශංකර් ඉරිදා කියා සිටියේ ඉන්දීය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සැමවිටම සහය දක්වන බවත් වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හරහා අසල්වැසි රටට උදව් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බවත් “දැන් සරණාගත අර්බුදයක්” නොමැති බවත් පැහැදිලි කරමිනි.",
        "තෙදින සංචාරයක් සඳහා ප්‍රාන්ත අගනුවරට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් ජයිශංකර් පැවසුවේ, “අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විශාල සහයෝගයක් ලබා දුන්නා. අපි උදව් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන අතර ඔවුන් සැලකිලිමත් වන විට අපි සැමවිටම ඉතා ප්‍රයෝජනවත් වෙමු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව -",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியப் படைகளை அனுப்பவில்லை - உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், இந்தியா தனது படைகளை இலங்கைக்கு அனுப்புவது குறித்து ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் ஊகச் செய்திகளை திட்டவட்டமாக மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த அறிக்கைகள் மற்றும் இதுபோன்ற கருத்துக்கள் இந்திய அரசின் நிலைப்பாட்டுடன் ஒத்துப்போகவில்லை என்று உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள், நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க முயலும் இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியா நிற்கிறது என்று இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் தெளிவாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி, “இலங்கையின் நெருங்கிய அண்டை நாடு இந்தியா, எங்கள் இரு நாடுகளும் ஆழமான நாகரீக பிணைப்புகளைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்கின்றன” என்றார்.",
        "“இலங்கையில் அண்மைய முன்னேற்றங்களை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருகிறோம். ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள், நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க முற்படுகையில், இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியா நிற்கிறது\" என்று பாக்சி கூறினார்.",
        "இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை, இந்திய அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு எப்போதும் ஆதரவாக இருப்பதாகவும், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் மூலம் அண்டை நாட்டிற்கு \"உதவி செய்ய\" முயற்சிப்பதாகவும், \"தற்போது அகதிகள் நெருக்கடி இல்லை\" என்றும் தெளிவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "மூன்று நாள் பயணமாக மாநில தலைநகருக்கு வந்த பிறகு திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையத்திற்கு வெளியே செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய ஜெய்சங்கர், “நாங்கள் இலங்கைக்கு மிகவும் ஆதரவாக இருந்தோம். நாங்கள் உதவ முயற்சி செய்கிறோம், அவர்கள் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட இடங்களில் நாங்கள் எப்போதும் மிகவும் உதவியாக இருக்கிறோம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை -",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}