{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘විදෙස්-ගත-වන්නට-පෙර-මැලේරියාවට-බෙහෙත්-ගන්න‘‘/101-619160",
  "time_ut": 1662074706,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘විදෙස් ගත වන්නට පෙර මැලේරියාවට බෙහෙත් ගන්න‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Take Malaria Medicine Before Traveling Abroad\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The National Malaria Headquarters urges all Sri Lankans traveling abroad to use anti-malarial drugs and to carry a certain amount of those drugs with them.",
        "Sri Lankans traveling abroad should pay close attention to the fact that malaria has been reported in many countries including Africa, India, Thailand and Sudan, said Dr. Naveen De Soysa, senior registrar of community medicine at the headquarters.",
        "He said that when the malaria parasite enters the body, the mosquito spreads the disease.",
        "Malaria was completely eradicated from the country by 2016 and twenty seven cases have been reported this year. In 1963, 12 cases were reported and during 1965-67, although the number of cases was more than thousands, Sri Lanka was completely free of malaria, said Dr. Soysa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Take Malaria Medicine Before Traveling Abroad",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Malaria Headquarters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naveen De Soysa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malaria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "twenty seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1963",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1965-67",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soysa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘විදෙස් ගත වන්නට පෙර මැලේරියාවට බෙහෙත් ගන්න‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශගතවන සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මැලේරියා රෝගයට දෙනු ලබන ඖෂධ පාවිච්චි කරන ලෙසත් හා එම ඖෂධ යම් ප්‍රමාණයක් රැගෙන යන ලෙසත් ජාතික මැලේරියා මර්දන මූලස්ථානය ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "අප්‍රිකාව, ඉන්දියාව, තායිලන්තය, සුඩානය ඇතුළු රටවල් ගණනාවක මැලේරියා රෝගය පවතින බව වාර්තා වී ඇති බැවින් විදේශගත වන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැඩි අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතුව ඇතැයි එම මූලස්ථානය ප්‍රජා වෛද්‍ය වේදය පිළිබඳ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ලේඛකාධිකාරි වෛද්‍ය නවීන් ද සොයිසා මහතා කීය.",
        "මැලේරියා රෝගය බෝකරන පරපෝෂිතයා සිරුරට ඇතුල් වූ විට මදුරුවා එම රෝගය ප්‍රචලිත කරන බවද ඔහු කීය.",
        "මැලේරියා රෝගය 2016 වන විට මුළුමනින්ම මෙරටින් තුරන් වී තිබූ අතර මේ වසරේ රෝගීන් විසි හත් දෙනෙක් වාර්තා වී ඇත. 1963 දී රෝගීන්ගේ 12ක් වාර්තා වූ අතර 1965 - 67 කාලය තුළ රෝගීන් දහස් ගණනින් වැඩි වුවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුළුමනින්ම මැලේරියාවෙන් තොර රටක් වූ බවද වෛද්‍ය සොයිසා මහතා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විදේශගත වීමට පෙර මැලේරියා ඖෂධ ගන්න",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැලේරියා මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුඩානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවීන් ද සොයිසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැලේරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසි හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1963",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1965-67",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස් ගණනකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සොයිසා ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"வெளிநாடு செல்வதற்கு முன் மலேரியா மருந்து எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளிநாடுகளுக்குச் செல்லும் அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களையும் மலேரியா எதிர்ப்பு மருந்துகளைப் பயன்படுத்துமாறும், குறிப்பிட்ட அளவு அந்த மருந்துகளை தம்முடன் எடுத்துச் செல்லுமாறும் தேசிய மலேரியா தலைமையகம் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது.",
        "ஆபிரிக்கா, இந்தியா, தாய்லாந்து, சூடான் உள்ளிட்ட பல நாடுகளில் மலேரியா நோய் பதிவாகியுள்ளமை தொடர்பில் வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு பயணிக்கும் இலங்கையர்கள் அவதானம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் என தலைமையக சமூக வைத்திய பிரிவின் சிரேஷ்ட பதிவாளர் டொக்டர் நவீன் டி சொய்சா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மலேரியா ஒட்டுண்ணி உடலில் நுழையும் போது, ​​கொசுவால் நோய் பரவுகிறது என்றார்.",
        "2016 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் மலேரியா நாட்டிலிருந்து முற்றாக ஒழிக்கப்பட்டதுடன், இந்த ஆண்டு இருபத்தி ஏழு வழக்குகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன. 1963 இல் 12 வழக்குகள் பதிவாகியிருந்ததாகவும், 1965-67 ஆம் ஆண்டு காலப்பகுதியில் ஆயிரத்திற்கும் மேற்பட்ட நோயாளிகள் இருந்த போதிலும், இலங்கை மலேரியாவிலிருந்து முற்றாக விடுபட்டுள்ளதாகவும் டாக்டர் சொய்சா தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெளிநாடு செல்வதற்கு முன் மலேரியா மருந்து எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மலேரியா தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூடான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவீன் டி சொய்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மலேரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபத்தி ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1963",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1965-67",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரத்திற்கும் மேற்பட்டவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சொய்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}