{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය-වෙනුවට-අද-ඇත්තේ-රාජ්‍ය-ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයයි/1-617065",
  "time_ut": 1658823591,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය වෙනුවට අද ඇත්තේ රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Today, instead of democracy, there is state violence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition leader Mr. Sajith Premadasa said in Colombo that instead of democracy, there is state violence.",
        "The opposition leader also mentioned that the first attack on the democratic struggle of the people of the country was launched on the 9th of May by launching state violence.",
        "He said this while attending a special meeting of the National Reform Movement held at the opposition leader's office in Colombo with the participation of political party leaders, parliamentary public representatives and professionals.",
        "He said that today the state violence is working seriously and instead of a new journey, there is the same old violent journey.",
        "The opposition leader also said that in a situation where a president who became the ruler of the country with a majority of 69 lakhs has been expelled from the country by a public struggle, he cannot do anything arbitrarily.",
        "Mr. Premadasa further said that an appointed dictatorship should not be allowed to practice brutality because of the country's democracy and the rulers should set an example of unity and fairness.",
        "Members of Parliament M. that. Mr. Sumanthiran, Rajitha Senaratne, Tissa Attanayake, P. Digambaram, Harsha de Silva, Dylan Perera, Mujibur Rahman and others were present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Reform Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Attanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. Digambaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dylan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujibur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය වෙනුවට අද ඇත්තේ රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය වෙනුවට අද ඇත්තේ රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා කොළඹදී පැවසීය.",
        "රටේ ජනතාව කරනු ලැබූ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අරගලයට මුල්ම ප්‍රහාරය පහුගිය මැයි මාස නව වෙනිදා රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය දියත් කරමින් එල්ල කළ බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහජන නියෝජිතයින් සහ වෘත්තිකයින් පිරිසකගේ සහභාගිත්වයෙන් කොළඹ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේ දී පැවති ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ව්‍යාපාරයේ විශේෂ හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "අද වන විට රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය බරපතළ ලෙස  ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත් අලුත් ගමනක් වෙනුවට ඇත්තේ පරණ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ගමනම බවත් හෙතෙම පැවසීය.",
        "හැටනව ලක්ෂයක බහුතරයකින් රටේ පාලකයා බවට පත්වූ ජනාධිපති වරයෙකු මහජන අරගලයක් විසින් රටෙනුත් නෙරපා හැරි තත්ත්වයක් තුළ කිසිවක් කොට අත්තනෝමතික ලෙස හැසිරෙනු නොහැකි බව ද විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා කීවේය.",
        "පත්කරගත් ඒකාධිපතිත්වයකට රටේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය වනසා මිලේච්ඡත්වය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ඉඩ නොදිය යුතුබවත් පාලකයින් එකමුතු බවේත් සාධාරණත්වයේත් ආදර්ශය ලබා දියයුතු බවත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා තවදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාව සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වරුන් වන එම්. ඒ. සුමන්තිරන්, රාජිත සේනාරත්න, තිස්ස අත්තනායක,  පී දිගම්බරම්, හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා, ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා, මුජිබර් රහුමාන් යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.දිගම්බරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று ஜனநாயகத்துக்குப் பதிலாக அரச வன்முறையே அரங்கேறி வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு பதிலாக அரச வன்முறையே இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி அரச வன்முறையை முன்னெடுத்ததன் மூலம் நாட்டு மக்களின் ஜனநாயகப் போராட்டத்தின் மீதான முதலாவது தாக்குதல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள், நாடாளுமன்ற மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் தொழில் வல்லுநர்கள் கலந்துகொண்ட தேசிய சீர்திருத்த இயக்கத்தின் விசேட கூட்டத்தில் கொழும்பிலுள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்துத் தெரிவிக்கையிலேயே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று அரசு வன்முறை தீவிரமாக செயல்பட்டு வருவதாகவும், புதிய பயணத்திற்கு பதிலாக, பழைய வன்முறை பயணம் தான் உள்ளது என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "69 இலட்சம் பெரும்பான்மையுடன் ஆட்சியமைத்த ஜனாதிபதியொருவர், பொதுப் போராட்டத்தின் மூலம் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட சூழ்நிலையில், தன்னிச்சையாக எதையும் செய்ய முடியாது எனவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் ஜனநாயகம் காரணமாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட சர்வாதிகாரம் மிருகத்தனத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்த இடமளிக்கக் கூடாது என்றும், ஆட்சியாளர்கள் ஒற்றுமைக்கும் நேர்மைக்கும் முன்மாதிரியாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் திரு.பிரேமதாச மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான எம். அந்த. திரு.சுமந்திரன், ராஜித சேனாரத்ன, திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க, பி.திகாம்பரம், ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, டிலான் பெரேரா, முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான் மற்றும் பலர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சீர்திருத்த இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.திகாம்பரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}