{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/உலக-செய்திகள்/உக்ரேன்-ஜனாதிபதியின்-சர்ச்சை-புகைப்படம்/50-301342",
  "time_ut": 1659145297,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "உக்ரேன் ஜனாதிபதியின் சர்ச்சை புகைப்படம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Controversial photo of the President of Ukraine",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The way Ukrainian President Zelensky and his wife Olana appeared in a photo in a popular American magazine has caused controversy.",
        "Russia's war on Ukraine has left thousands dead and around 10 million people have fled the country and sought refuge in neighboring countries.",
        "In this situation, President of Ukraine Zelensky and his wife Olana have given an interview to the famous American monthly magazine 'Vogue'.",
        "This interview will be published in the upcoming October issue of 'Vogue'.",
        "In the photographs published by 'Vogue' magazine, there are pictures of Olana standing in war-affected places, and pictures of Zelensky and Olana as a couple.",
        "Controversy has also arisen as to whether it is necessary to take such photographs and publish them on the Internet at the time of war. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ukraine",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukrainian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zelensky",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Olana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 10 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukraine Zelensky",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Olana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "October",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vogue",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Olana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zelensky",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Olana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුක්රේන ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ආන්දෝලනාත්මක ඡායාරූපය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුක්රේන ජනාධිපති සෙලෙන්ස්කි සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ඔලානා ඇමරිකානු ජනප්‍රිය සඟරාවක ඡායාරූපයකට පෙනී සිටි ආකාරය ආන්දෝලනයට තුඩු දී තිබෙනවා.",
        "යුක්රේනයට එරෙහි රුසියාවේ යුද්ධයෙන් දහස් ගණනක් මිය ගිය අතර මිලියන 10 ක පමණ ජනතාවක් රට හැර ගොස් අසල්වැසි රටවල රැකවරණය පතා ඇත.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ යුක්රේන ජනාධිපති සෙලෙන්ස්කි සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ඔලානා ඇමරිකාවේ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ මාසික සඟරාවක් වන ‘වෝග්’ වෙත සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවක් ලබාදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "මෙම සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාව එළඹෙන ඔක්තෝබර් මාසයේ ‘වෝග්’ සඟරාවේ පළ කෙරේ.",
        "‘වෝග්’ සඟරාව විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද ඡායාරූපවල ඔලනා යුද්ධයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් ස්ථානවල සිටගෙන සිටින ඡායාරූප සහ සෙලෙන්ස්කි සහ ඔලානා යුවළක් ලෙස සිටින ඡායාරූප තිබේ.",
        "යුද්ධය පවතින අවස්ථාවක මෙවැනි ඡායාරූප ගෙන අන්තර්ජාලයට මුදා හැරීම අවශ්‍යද යන්න පිළිබඳවද මතභේදයක් මතුව තිබේ. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යුක්රේනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලෙන්ස්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලානා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 10 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය සෙලෙන්ස්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලානා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෝග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලානා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලෙන්ස්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලානා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உக்ரேன் ஜனாதிபதியின் சர்ச்சை புகைப்படம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவின் பிரபல பத்திரிகையில் உக்ரேன் ஜனாதிபதி ஜெலன்ஸ்கியும், அவரது மனைவி ஒலனாவும் புகைப்படத்தில் தோன்றிய விதம் சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "உக்ரேன் மீதான ரஷ்யாவின் போரில் ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன், சுமார் 1 கோடி பேர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி அண்டை நாடுகளில் அகதிகளாக தஞ்சம் புகுந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்தநிலையில் அமெரிக்காவின் பிரபல மாதாந்த இதழான 'வோக்' இதழுக்கு உக்ரேன் அதிபர் ஜெலன்ஸ்கியும், அவரது மனைவி ஒலனாவும் நேர்காணல் அளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் ஒக்டோபர் மாதம் வெளியாகும் 'வோக்' இதழில் இந்த நேர்காணல் இடம் பெறுகிறது.",
        "இதுதொடர்பில் 'வோக்' இதழ் வெளியிட்டுள்ள புகைப்படங்களில், ஒலனா போரினால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட இடங்களில் நிற்கும் படங்களும், ஜெலன்ஸ்கியும், ஒலனாவும் ஜோடியாக இருக்கும் படங்களும் உள்ளன.",
        "போர் இடம்பெறும் நேரத்தில் இப்படி புகைப்படம் எடுத்து இணையத்தில் வெளியிடுவது அவசியமா என்ற சர்ச்சையும் எழுந்துள்ளது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உக்ரைன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெலென்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒலனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன் ஜெலென்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒலனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வோக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒலனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெலென்ஸ்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒலனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}