{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132119",
  "time_ut": 1658641549,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பாக்கிஸ்தானில் இலங்கை போன்று மக்கள் வீதியில் இறங்கும் நாள் வெகுதொலைவில் இல்லை - இம்ரான்கான்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The day is not far when people will take to the streets in Pakistan like in Sri Lanka - Imran Khan",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Prime Minister Imran Khan has said that a moment like Sri Lanka will happen in Pakistan.",
        "He said that the day is not far when people will fill the streets for Haqqi Azadi in Pakistan like in Sri Lanka.",
        "He stated this on Twitter and mentioned that the Asivzardari Sharif family mafia has weakened the country in political economy in three months.",
        "Imran Khan questioned that they have saved the wealth accumulated for 30 years after looting Pakistan, how long will the government agencies allow this?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pakistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Imran Khan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haqqi Azadi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Imran Khan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාවේ වගේ පකිස්ථානයේ මිනිස්සු පාරට බහින දවස වැඩි ඈතක නෙවෙයි - ඉම්රාන් ඛාන්",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි මොහොතක් පාකිස්ථානයේදී සිදුවනු ඇති බව හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ඉම්රාන් ඛාන් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙන් පාකිස්ථානයේ හකී අසාදි වෙනුවෙන් ජනතාව පාරවල් පුරවන දිනය වැඩි ඈතක නොවන බවද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව ට්විටර් ගිණුමේ සටහනක් තබමින් සඳහන් කළේ අසිව්සර්දාරි ෂරීෆ් පවුලේ මාෆියාව මාස තුනකින් රට දේශපාලන ආර්ථිකයෙන් දුර්වල කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "පාකිස්ථානය කොල්ලකා වසර 30ක් පුරා රැස් කරගත් ධනය ඔවුන් ඉතිරි කර ගෙන ඇති බවත්, රජයේ ආයතන කොපමණ කාලයක් මෙයට ඉඩ දෙන්නේදැයි ඉම්රාන් ඛාන් ප්‍රශ්න කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉම්රාන් ඛාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හකී අසාදි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉම්රාන් ඛාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 30 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாக்கிஸ்தானில் இலங்கை போன்று மக்கள் வீதியில் இறங்கும் நாள் வெகுதொலைவில் இல்லை - இம்ரான்கான்",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போன்ற ஒரு தருணம் பாக்கிஸ்தானில் ஏற்படும் காலம் வெகுதூரத்தில் இல்லை என முன்னாள் பிரதமர் இம்ரான்கான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை போன்று பாக்கிஸ்தானில் ஹக்கீகி ஆசாதிக்காக மக்களை வீதிகளை நிரப்பும் நாள் வெகுதொலைவில் இல்லை என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "டுவிட்டரில் இதனை தெரிவித்துள்ள அவர் அசீவ்ஜர்தாரி ஷெரீப் குடும்ப மாபியா மூன்று மாதத்தில் நாட்டை அரசியல் பொருளாதாரத்தில் பலவீனப்படுத்தியுள்ளது என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாக்கிஸ்தானை சூறையாடி 30 வருடகாலமாக குவித்த சொத்துக்களை அவர்கள் சேமித்துள்ளனர்,அரச நிறுவனங்கள் எவ்வளவு காலம் இதனை அனுமதிக்கும் என்பதே எனது கேள்வி என இம்ரான்கன் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இம்ரான் கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹக்கி ஆசாதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இம்ரான் கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}