{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/dmc-issues-landslide-alert-for-several-areas/",
  "time_ut": 1661942880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "DMC issues Landslide alert for several areas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "DMC issues Landslide alert for several areas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Disaster Management Center (DMC) had issued a landslide alert for several areas, active for the next 24 hours.",
        "Accordingly, the landslide alert has been issued for Baddegama and Yakkalamulla Divisional Secretariats of Galle, Bulathsinhala and Palindanuwara Divisional Secretariats of Kalutara and fr Ratnapura, Elapatha and Kuruwita Divisional Secretariats of Ratnapura.",
        "The Department also issued a Red alert for heavy rains, citing a  low-level atmospheric disturbance in the vicinity of Sri Lanka.",
        "Accordingly, very heavy showers above 150mm may occur at some places in Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces on Wednesday (31), while heavy showers about",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Landslide",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Disaster Management Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Baddegama and Yakkalamulla Divisional Secretariats of Galle",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bulathsinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elapatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuruwita Divisional Secretariats of Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "DMC ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට නායයෑම් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉදිරි පැය 24 සඳහා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට නායයාමේ අවදානමක් ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය විසින් නිකුත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, ගාල්ල බද්දේගම සහ යක්කලමුල්ල ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශ, කළුතර බුලත්සිංහල සහ පාලින්දනුවර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශවලට සහ රත්නපුර රත්නපුර, ඇලපාත සහ කුරුවිට ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශවලට මෙම නායයෑමේ අවදානම් නිවේදනය නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආශ්‍රිතව පහත් මට්ටමේ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹීමක් ඇති බව සඳහන් කරමින්, අධික වර්ෂාව සඳහා රතු අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් ද දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව බදාදා (31) බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ඉක්මවූ ඉතා තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි අතර, ආසන්න වශයෙන් තද වැසි",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාය යෑම",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල බද්දේගම සහ යක්කලමුල්ල ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුලත්සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලපාත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර කුරුවිට ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "DMC பல பகுதிகளுக்கு நிலச்சரிவு எச்சரிக்கையை வெளியிடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையம் (டிஎம்சி) அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரத்திற்கு பல பகுதிகளில் நிலச்சரிவு எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, காலியின் பத்தேகம மற்றும் யக்கலமுல்ல பிரதேச செயலகங்களுக்கும், களுத்துறையின் புலத்சிங்கள மற்றும் பாலிந்தநுவர பிரதேச செயலகங்களுக்கும், இரத்தினபுரி, எலபாத மற்றும் குருவிட்ட பிரதேச செயலகங்களுக்கும் மண்சரிவு அபாய எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையை அண்மித்த பகுதியில் குறைந்த அளவிலான வளிமண்டலத் தொந்தரவை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, அதிக மழைக்கான சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கையையும் திணைக்களம் வெளியிட்டது.",
        "அதன்படி, புதன்கிழமை (31) மேற்கு, தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான கடும் மழை பெய்யக் கூடும் அதே வேளையில் சுமார் பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிலச்சரிவு",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி பத்தேகம மற்றும் யக்கலமுல்ல பிரதேச செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலத்சிங்கள",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலபத",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரியின் குருவிட்ட பிரதேச செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}