{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130839",
  "time_ut": 1657015806,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன் உள்ளிட்ட 10 பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது :  பிரதிவாதிகள் சார்பில் அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Case against 10 defendants including Arjuna Mahendran cannot proceed : Basic Objection on behalf of defendants",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Regarding the central bank bond fraud (2015), the defense attorney has submitted written arguments against the case filed against 10 defendants, including the former central bank governor Arjuna Mahendran, who cannot proceed on behalf of the defendants.",
        "When the said case came up for hearing on July 4, the government's senior lawyer Uthara Karunathilaka submitted the relevant arguments in the court.",
        "The Attorney General filed 23 charges against 10 defendants, including former Central Bank Governor Arjuna Mahendran, owner of Perpetual Treasuries, Arjun Aloysius, chairman of Perpetual Treasuries, in connection with the Central Bank's bond auction on September 27, 2015, which cost the government 688 million rupees. The case filed separately (04) came up for hearing on Monday.",
        "First, the case was taken up for hearing in the Special High Court before the permanent three-member Special High Court Judges Samba Janaki Rajaratne, Tamit Towawatta and Namal Palalle.",
        "During this, the first respondent, former Central Bank Governor Arjuna Mahendran, and the 10th respondent, Ajahn Bunjihewa, who served as the Director of Personal Treasuries, were present in the court.",
        "Meanwhile, on April 29, the main objection raised by the President's lawyer Anil Silva that the case could not be proceeded with, and written submissions were made on behalf of the suspects, the senior state lawyer Udara Karunathilaka, on behalf of the Attorney General, presented the counterarguments on behalf of the said objection. 4) submitted.",
        "In this situation, if there are any responses regarding the arguments of the Attorney General, the judges ordered to put them before the court during the upcoming term of the case and adjourned the case till the upcoming July 21.",
        "The First Permanent Triumvirate High Court of Western Province has already allowed the investigation of this case to proceed without the former Central Bank Governor Arjuna Mahendran and the tenth defendant, Ajahn Guardia Punjihewa.",
        "It is noteworthy that the court has decided to hear the allegations against the defendants Arjuna Mahendran and Ajahn Guardia Punjihewa in their absence while they are neglecting to appear in court on behalf of the Attorney General under Chapter 450 (8) of the Criminal Code."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uthara Karunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perpetual Treasuries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjun Aloysius",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perpetual Treasuries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 27, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "688 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Special High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samba Janaki Rajaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamit Towawatta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Palalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajahn Bunjihewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anil Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udara Karunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guardia Punjihewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Mahendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajahn",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chapter 450 (8) of the Criminal Code",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් ඇතුළු විත්තිකරුවන් 10 දෙනෙකුට එරෙහි නඩුව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැක : විත්තිකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් මූලික විරෝධය",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහ බැංකු බැඳුම්කර වංචාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් (2015) හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් ඇතුළු විත්තිකරුවන් 10 දෙනෙකුට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති නඩුව විත්තිකරුවන්ට ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බවට මූලික විරෝධතාවක් ලෙස විත්තිකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "එම නඩුව ජූලි 4 වැනිදා විභාගයට ගත් අවස්ථාවේදී රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥ උත්තරා කරුණාතිලක මහත්මිය අදාළ තර්ක අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළාය.",
        "2015 සැප්තැම්බර් 27 වැනිදා රජයට රුපියල් 688ක පාඩුවක් සිදු කළ මහ බැංකුවේ බැඳුම්කර වෙන්දේසිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පර්පෙචුවල් ට්‍රෙෂරීස් සමාගමේ හිමිකරු අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්, පර්පෙචුවල් ට්‍රෙෂරීස් සමාගමේ සභාපති අර්ජුන් ඇලෝසියස් ඇතුළු විත්තිකරුවන් 10 දෙනකුට එරෙහිව නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් චෝදනා 23ක් ගොනු කළේය. මිලියනයක් වෙන් වෙන් වශයෙන් පවරා ඇති නඩුව (04) සඳුදා විභාගයට ගැනිණි.",
        "පළමුව මෙම නඩුව විශේෂ මහාධිකරණයේ ස්ථීර ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විශේෂ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන් වන සම්බා ජානකී රාජරත්න, ටමිත් තොවාවත්ත සහ නාමල් පලාල්ලේ යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් හමුවේ විභාගයට ගැනිණි.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවේදී පළමු වගඋත්තරකරු හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් සහ 10 වැනි වගඋත්තරකරු වන පුද්ගලික භාණ්ඩාගාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ලෙස කටයුතු කළ අජාන් බන්ජිහේවා යන මහත්වරු අධිකරණයට පැමිණ සිටියහ.",
        "මේ අතර අප්‍රේල් 29 වැනිදා නඩුව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බවට ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ අනිල් සිල්වා මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතාවය සහ සැකකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥ උදාර කරුණාතිලක මහතා ලිඛිත දේශන ඉදිරිපත් කළේය. එකී විරෝධය වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රතිතර්ක ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී. 4) ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ නීතිපතිවරයාගේ තර්ක සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රතිචාර ඇත්නම් ඒවා ඉදිරි නඩු වාරයේදී අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස නියෝග කළ විනිසුරුවරු නඩුව ලබන ජූලි 21 වැනිදාට කල් තැබූහ.",
        "හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් සහ දසවැනි විත්තිකරු වන අජාන් ගාඩියා පුන්ජිහේවා නොමැතිව මෙම නඩුවේ විමර්ශන කටයුතු කරගෙන යාමට බස්නාහිර පළාතේ පළමු ස්ථිර ත්‍රිපුද්ගල මහාධිකරණය දැනටමත් අවසර ලබාදී තිබේ.",
        "විත්තිකරුවන් වන අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන් සහ අජාන් ගාඩියා පුන්ජිහේවා යන විත්තිකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව අපරාධ සංග්‍රහයේ 450 (8) පරිච්ෙඡ්දය යටතේ නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටීම පැහැර හරිමින් සිටියදී ඔවුන් නොමැති අවස්ථාවලදී ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව චෝදනා විභාග කිරීමට අධිකරණය තීරණය කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උත්තර කරුණාතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පර්පෙචුවල් ට්‍රෙෂරීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන් ඇලෝසියස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පර්පෙචුවල් ට්‍රෙෂරීස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 සැප්තැම්බර් 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 688 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්බා ජානකී රාජරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටැමිත් තොවාවත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් පලාල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජාන් බන්ජිහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනිල් සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදාර කරුණාතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාඩියා පුන්ජිහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන මහේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ නීති සංග්‍රහයේ 450 (8) පරිච්ඡේදය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன் உள்ளிட்ட 10 பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது :  பிரதிவாதிகள் சார்பில் அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனம்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "மத்திய வங்கி பிணை மோசடி தொடர்பில் ( 2015) மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அர்ஜூன மஹேந்திரன் உள்ளிட்ட பிரதிவாதிகள் 10 பேருக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது என பிரதிவாதிகள் சார்பில் அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனம் முன் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், அது குறித்த சட்ட மா அதிபரின் பதில் வாதங்கள் எழுத்து மூலம்  சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "குறித்த வழக்கு ஜூலை 4 ஆம் திகதி விசாரணைக்கு வந்த போது அரசின் சிரேஷ்ட சட்டவாதி உதார கருணாதிலக, குறித்த வாதங்களை நீதிமன்றில் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "2015 ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் 27 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற மத்திய வங்கியின் பிணை முறிகள் ஏலத்தின் மூலம் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு 688 மில்லியன் ரூபா நட்டம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளமை தொடர்பில் மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன், பேர்ப்பச்சுவல் ட்ரஷரீஸ் நிறுவனத்தின் உரிமையாளர் அர்ஜுன் அலோசியஸ், பேர்ப்பச்சுவல் ட்ரஷரீஸ் நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் ஜெப்ரி அலோசியஸ் உள்ளிட்ட 10 பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு எதிராக 23 குற்றச்சாட்டுகளின் கீழ் சட்டமா அதிபர் விஷேட  தாக்கல் செய்துள்ள வழக்கு  (04) திங்கட்கிழமை விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது.",
        "முதலாவது நிரந்தர மூவரடங்கிய விஷேட மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகளான சம்பா ஜானகி ராஜரத்ன, தமித் தொடவத்த மற்றும் நாமல் பலல்லே ஆகியோர் முன்னிலையில் விசேட மேல் நீதிமன்றத்தில் குறித்த வழக்கு  விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்போது முதல் பிரதிவாதி மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன் மற்றும்  10 ஆம் பிரதிவாதி பேர்ப்பச்சுவல் ட்ரஷரீஸ் நிறுவனத்தின் பணிப்பாளராக பணியாற்றிய அஜான் புஞ்சிஹேவா தவிற ஏனையோர் மன்றில் ஆஜராகியிருந்தனர்.",
        "இதன்போது, கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 29 ஆம் திகதி,  இந்த வழக்கினை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது எனக் கூறி  ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி அனில் சில்வா முன் வைத்த  அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனத்தை  மையபப்டுத்தி  சந்தேக நபர்கள் சார்பிலும் எழுத்து மூல சமர்ப்பணம் முன் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த நிலையில்,  குறித்த ஆட்சேபனம் தொடர்பில் பதில் வாதங்களை  சட்ட மா அதிபர் சார்பில் சிரேஷ்ட அரச சட்டவாதி உதார கருணாதிலக மன்றில் (4) சமர்ப்பித்தார்.",
        "இந் நிலையில் சட்ட மா அதிபரின் வாதங்கள் குறித்து ஏதும் பதிலளிப்புக்கள் இருப்பின் அவற்றை  எதிர்வரும் வழக்குத் தவணையின் போது நீதிமன்றில் முன் வைக்க உத்தரவிட்ட நீதிபதிகள் வழக்கை எதிர்வரும்  ஜூலை 21 வரை ஒத்தி வைத்தனர்.",
        "ஏற்கனவே இந்த வழக்கின் விசாரணையை மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அர்ஜூன மகேந்திரன் மற்றும் பத்தாவது பிரதிவாதியான அஜான் கார்டியா புஞ்சிஹேவா ஆகியோர் இன்றி முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல மேல் மாகாண முதலாவது நிரந்தர மூவரடங்கிய மேல் நீதிமன்றம்   அனுமதியளித்துள்லது.",
        "குற்றவியல் சட்டத்தின் 450 (8) ஆம் அத்தியாயத்துக்கு அமைய சட்ட மா அதிபர் சார்பில்,  முன் வைக்கப்பட்ட கோரிக்கைகளை ஏற்று, அர்ஜுன மகேந்ரன், அஜான் கார்டியா புஞ்சிஹேவா  ஆகிய பிரதிவாதிகள்   மன்றினைல் ஆஜராவதை புறக்கணிக்கும் நிலையில், அவர்கள் இல்லாமலேயே அவர்களுக்கு எதிரான குற்ரச்சாட்டுக்களை விசாரணைக்கு எடுக்க  நீதிமன்றம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உத்தர கருணாதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்பெச்சுவல் ட்ரஷரீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன் அலோசியஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்பெச்சுவல் ட்ரஷரீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 27, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "688 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பா ஜானகி ராஜரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமித் தோவாவத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் பலல்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜான் புஞ்சிஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனில் சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதார கருணாதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்டியா புஞ்சிஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன மகேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றவியல் சட்டத்தின் 450 (8) அத்தியாயம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}