{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Informative-webinar-on-opportunities-in-Israeli-market/34-738532",
  "time_ut": 1660176288,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Informative webinar on opportunities in Israeli market",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Informative webinar on opportunities in Israeli market",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Embassy of Sri Lanka in Tel Aviv and the Sri Lanka Export Development Board (SLEDB) jointly organised a webinar on opportunities in the Israeli market on 3 August, in collaboration with the Federation of Israeli Chamber of Commerce (FICC) and the Israel-Sri Lanka Chamber of Commerce.",
        "The aim of the webinar was to create awareness on the opportunities available in the Israeli market and share the latest Israeli trade related information for the benefit of the Sri Lankan exporters. Over 130 Sri Lankan exporters participated in the webinar representing several export sectors such as diamond, fisheries, tea, apparel, food and beverages, pneumatic and retreated rubber tyres and tubes, coco peat and fibre pith, spices, electrical and electronic components, and IT-BPM on the invitation of the SLEDB.",
        "In his opening remarks SLEDB Chairman and Chief Executive Suresh D. de Mel gave an overview of the Sri Lanka-Israel bilateral trade. The Ambassador of Sri Lanka to Israel Waruna Wilpatha during his remarks pointed out the importance of showcasing the products and services by the Sri Lankan exporters on regular basis at various trade fairs/exhibitions held in Israel to enable them to penetrate into the Israeli market while highlighting that the tea, apparel, fish and seafood, spices, food and beverages, rubber products, electrical and electronic components, IT-BPM and PPE as the potential areas to increase the volume of Sri Lankan exports into the Israeli market.",
        "Presentations on an overview of the Israel market, macroeconomic data on Israel, public on-line resources for identifying partners in Israel, the Israeli business culture, sectors of collaboration, ease of doing business in Israel, trade opportunities, requirements standards and barriers to access the Israeli market were made by Federation of Israeli Chamber of Commerce (FICC) Business Development Executive International Relations Or Nehushtan and Israel-Sri Lanka Chamber of Commerce Chairperson Dr. Anat Bernstein-Reich. SLEDB Deputy Director Market Development  Prasanna Jayasinghe moderated the webinar."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Israeli",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Embassy of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tel Aviv",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Export Development Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Federation of Israeli Chamber of Commerce (FICC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Israel-Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Over 130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLEDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLEDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka-Israel",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waruna Wilpatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israeli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Federation of Israeli Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamber of Commerce Chairperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anat Bernstein-Reich",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Market Development",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Jayasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳපොලේ ඇති අවස්ථා පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු සපයන webinar",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ටෙල් අවිව් හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලය (SLEDB) එක්ව ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළෙඳ පොළේ අවස්ථා පිළිබඳ webinar එකක් ඊශ්‍රායල වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ (FICC) සහ ඊශ්‍රායල ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංගමයේ සහයෝගයෙන් සංවිධානය කරන ලදී. ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය.",
        "මෙම webinar හි අරමුණ වූයේ ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳපොලේ ඇති අවස්ථා පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කිරීම සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික අපනයනකරුවන්ගේ ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳාම සම්බන්ධ නවතම තොරතුරු බෙදා ගැනීමයි. දියමන්ති, ධීවර කර්මාන්තය, තේ, ඇඟලුම්, ආහාර පාන, වායුමය සහ පසුබැසුණු රබර් ටයර් සහ ටියුබ්, කොකෝ පීට් සහ ෆයිබර් පිත්, කුළුබඩු, විදුලි හා ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උපාංග සහ තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ වැනි අපනයන ක්ෂේත්‍ර කිහිපයක් නියෝජනය කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික අපනයනකරුවන් 130 කට අධික පිරිසක් මෙම වෙබ් අඩවියට සහභාගි වූහ. -ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලයේ ආරාධනය මත බී.පී.එම්.",
        "සිය ආරම්භක අදහස් දැක්වීමේදී SLEDB සභාපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක සුරේෂ් ඩී ද මෙල් ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ඊශ්‍රායල් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම පිළිබඳ දළ විශ්ලේෂණයක් කළේය. ඊශ්‍රායලයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති වරුණ විල්පත මහතා සිය අදහස් දැක්වීමේදී ඊශ්‍රායලයේ පැවැත්වෙන විවිධ වෙළෙඳ ප්‍රදර්ශන/ප්‍රදර්ශනවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයනකරුවන් විසින් ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳපොළට විනිවිද යාමට හැකිවන පරිදි ඔවුන්ගේ නිෂ්පාදන හා සේවා නිතිපතා ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. තේ, ඇඟලුම්, මාළු සහ මුහුදු ආහාර, කුළුබඩු, ආහාර සහ පාන වර්ග, රබර් නිෂ්පාදන, විදුලි සහ ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික උපාංග, IT-BPM සහ PPE ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳපොළට ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන පරිමාව ඉහළ නැංවීමේ විභව ක්ෂේත්‍ර ලෙස.",
        "ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳපොළ පිළිබඳ දළ විශ්ලේෂණයක්, ඊශ්‍රායලයේ සාර්ව ආර්ථික දත්ත, ඊශ්‍රායලයේ හවුල්කරුවන් හඳුනා ගැනීම සඳහා පොදු මාර්ගගත සම්පත්, ඊශ්‍රායල ව්‍යාපාරික සංස්කෘතිය, සහයෝගීතා අංශ, ඊශ්‍රායලයේ ව්‍යාපාර කිරීමේ පහසුව, වෙළඳ අවස්ථා, අවශ්‍යතා ප්‍රමිතීන් සහ ප්‍රවේශ වීමට ඇති බාධක පිළිබඳ ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම් ඊශ්‍රායල වෙළඳපොළ සාදන ලද්දේ ඊශ්‍රායල වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ (FICC) ව්‍යාපාර සංවර්ධන විධායක ජාත්‍යන්තර සබඳතා හෙවත් නෙහුෂ්තාන් සහ ඊශ්‍රායල-ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපති ආචාර්ය ඇනට් බර්න්ස්ටයින්-රීච් විසිනි. SLEDB නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෙළඳපළ සංවර්ධන  ප්‍රසන්න ජයසිංහ වෙබ් නාලිකාව මෙහෙයවන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙල් අවිව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අපනයන සංවර්ධන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්‍රායල වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ සම්මේලනය (FICC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්‍රායලය-ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ විද්යා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "130 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLEDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLEDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ඊශ්‍රායලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරුණ විල්පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්‍රායල වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anat Bernstein-Reich",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳපල සංවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இஸ்ரேலிய சந்தையில் உள்ள வாய்ப்புகள் பற்றிய தகவல் வலையமைப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "டெல் அவிவில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகம் மற்றும் இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி மேம்பாட்டு வாரியம் (SLEDB) இணைந்து இஸ்ரேலிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம் (FICC) மற்றும் இஸ்ரேல்-ஸ்ரீ ஆகியவற்றுடன் இணைந்து ஆகஸ்ட் 3 ஆம் தேதி இஸ்ரேலிய சந்தையில் வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்த வலைநாடொன்றை ஏற்பாடு செய்தன. லங்கா வர்த்தக சபை.",
        "இஸ்ரேலிய சந்தையில் கிடைக்கும் வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்து விழிப்புணர்வை ஏற்படுத்துவதும், இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களின் நலனுக்காக இஸ்ரேலிய வர்த்தகம் தொடர்பான சமீபத்திய தகவல்களைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்வதும் வலையரங்கின் நோக்கமாகும். வைரம், மீன்பிடி, தேயிலை, ஆடைகள், உணவு மற்றும் குளிர்பானங்கள், வாயு மற்றும் பின்வாங்கப்பட்ட ரப்பர் டயர்கள் மற்றும் குழாய்கள், கொக்கோ பீட் மற்றும் ஃபைபர் பித், மசாலா பொருட்கள், மின்சாரம் மற்றும் இலத்திரனியல் பாகங்கள், மற்றும் ஐ.டி. - SLEDB இன் அழைப்பின் பேரில் BPM.",
        "SLEDB தலைவரும் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரியுமான சுரேஷ் டி.டி மெல் தனது ஆரம்ப உரையில் இலங்கை-இஸ்ரேல் இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் பற்றிய கண்ணோட்டத்தை வழங்கினார். இஸ்ரேலுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் வருண வில்பத தனது உரையின் போது இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்கள் இஸ்ரேலில் நடைபெறும் பல்வேறு வர்த்தக கண்காட்சிகள்/கண்காட்சிகளில் தொடர்ச்சியாக அவர்களின் தயாரிப்புகள் மற்றும் சேவைகளை காட்சிப்படுத்துவதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். தேயிலை, ஆடைகள், மீன் மற்றும் கடல் உணவுகள், மசாலாப் பொருட்கள், உணவு மற்றும் பானங்கள், இறப்பர் பொருட்கள், மின் மற்றும் இலத்திரனியல் பாகங்கள், IT-BPM மற்றும் PPE ஆகியவை இஸ்ரேலிய சந்தையில் இலங்கையின் ஏற்றுமதியின் அளவை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான சாத்தியமான பகுதிகளாகும்.",
        "இஸ்ரேல் சந்தையின் கண்ணோட்டம், இஸ்ரேல் பற்றிய மேக்ரோ பொருளாதார தரவு, இஸ்ரேலில் பங்குதாரர்களை அடையாளம் காண்பதற்கான பொது ஆன்லைன் ஆதாரங்கள், இஸ்ரேலிய வணிக கலாச்சாரம், ஒத்துழைப்புத் துறைகள், இஸ்ரேலில் எளிதாக வணிகம், வர்த்தக வாய்ப்புகள், தேவைகள் தரநிலைகள் மற்றும் அணுகுவதற்கான தடைகள் பற்றிய விளக்கக்காட்சிகள் இஸ்ரேலிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம் (FICC) வர்த்தக அபிவிருத்தி நிறைவேற்று சர்வதேச உறவுகள் அல்லது Nehushtan மற்றும் இஸ்ரேல்-இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் தலைவர் Dr. Anat Bernstein-Reich ஆகியோரால் இஸ்ரேலிய சந்தை உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. SLEDB பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் சந்தை அபிவிருத்தி  பிரசன்ன ஜயசிங்க வலையரங்கை நெறிப்படுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல் அவிவ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி அபிவிருத்தி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம் (FICC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்-இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "130க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLEDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLEDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருண வில்பத",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT-BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேலிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தக சபையின் தலைவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனாட் பெர்ன்ஸ்டீன்-ரீச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தை மேம்பாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ஜயசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}