{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/SLASSCOM-appoints-new-Chairman-Board-to-support-its-next-era-of-growth-and-transformation/34-738776",
  "time_ut": 1660688349,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLASSCOM appoints new Chairman, Board to support its next era of growth and transformation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLASSCOM appoints new Chairman, Board to support its next era of growth and transformation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLASSCOM Chairman Ashique Ali with office-bearers and Board of Directors for year 2022/23",
        "The Sri Lanka Association for Software Services Companies (SLASSCOM) recently appointed their new office-bearers for 2022/23, at the Annual General Meeting held recently. Ashique Ali was appointed as Chairman of SLASSCOM for the year 2022/2023.",
        "He is the Managing Director of Talliance, and is a veteran in the industry with over 30 years of experience. As a founding member of SLASSCOM, he has played an integral role in supporting the chamber’s initiatives, helping to guide and steer it to its current position as the leading association in the country for the IT/BPM industry. He also represents SLASSCOM in several key committees in Government and State institutions in policy, export promotion, FDI, capacity initiatives.",
        "Sharing his thoughts on this appointment, Chairman Ashique Ali stated: “This is a demanding and difficult time for our industry, where the needs of the IT/BPM organisations, its people and stakeholders are severely challenged due to the volatile and rapidly changing economic situation in our country.",
        "“Despite the many challenges our member companies have shown remarkable resilience in delivering on their commitments to foreign clients and investors and looking after the wellbeing of their employees.",
        "“These times call for strategic and innovative ways to successfully navigate the future to drive greater growth for our industry and country. I’m privileged to work alongside our Board and General Council Members who bring together unrivalled tenacity and industry expertise, which will be a great strength to help position the industry for its next phase of growth.”",
        "SLASSCOM Outgoing Chairperson Sandra De Zoysa, offering her congratulations to the newly elected Chairman and the Board said: “Ashique’s long history of leadership and experience in the industry as being a founding member of SLASSCOM actively guiding the SLASSCOM team to launch many value-driven initiatives for the industry, makes him an ideal person for this role. I look forward to supporting him to make a positive impact for all the industry’s stakeholders, including IT/BPM organisations and its people.”",
        "The other main office-bearers appointed included, Jehan Perinpanayagam as first Vice Chairman and Nishan Mendis as second Vice Chairman, Shehani Seneviratne as the Director of Operations and Feroze Carder as the Director of Finance.",
        "SLASSCOM First Vice Chairman Jehan Perinpanayagam, is the CEO of Informate Ltd., and the Vice President of the John Keells Holdings. Counting over 25 years of experience in the BPM industry, he was instrumental in setting up the first shared services centre in Sri Lanka and pioneered the country’s first rural BPM.",
        "SLASSCOM’s Second Vice Chairman Nishan Mendis, is the Executive Director and the Technology Consulting Leader and Chief Information Officer (CIO) for PwC Sri Lanka. He has a legacy of extensive experience counting more than 23 years, where he has successfully spearheaded various projects of national importance.",
        "Shehani Seneviratne, appointed to the position of Director Operations, is the Chief Operating Officer at 99X Technology, heads the SLASSCOM HR Forum and the Women’s Tech (Wtech) Forum. Shehani is also a Board Member of the Women’s Chamber for Digital and actively promotes the participation of more women in the IT industry.",
        "Feroze Cader, appointed to the position of Director Finance, is the Director, Head of Market Services Shared Operations at the London Stock Exchange Group. He has also been a member of SLASSCOM’s Strategy Council which advices the board.",
        "SLASSCOM’s new illustrious Board of Directors include hSenid  Business Solution CEO Sampath Jayasundara; GTN Group CEO and Head of Shared Services Arjuna Nanayakkara; VitalHub Innovations Lab Managing Director Dilan Rajapakse; WNS Global Services DGM Shanaka Fernando; SAKS Global CEO Rohith Pradeep; Loops Founder Shehan Selvanayagam; and Inqbaytor Co-Founder Harshani Perera.",
        "Backed by its newly elected Board that brings diversified leadership and industry expertise, the chamber today is well poised to accelerate the industry’s future growth and transformation in meeting its vision of generating $ 5.0 billion of revenue, creating 200,000 jobs and catalysing 1000 startups."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLASSCOM",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "next era",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashique Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "year 2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Association for Software Services Companies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Annual General Meeting",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashique Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2022/2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Talliance",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sharing",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ashique Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Board and General Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM Outgoing Chairperson Sandra De Zoysa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jehan Perinpanayagam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishan Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Operations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jehan Perinpanayagam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Informate Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the John Keells Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishan Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 23 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shehani Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wtech) Forum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehani",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Women’s Chamber for Digital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Feroze Cader",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the London Stock Exchange Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM’s Strategy Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "hSenid  Business Solution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GTN Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shared Services Arjuna Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VitalHub Innovations Lab",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilan Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WNS Global Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanaka Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAKS Global",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Loops",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehan Selvanayagam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshani Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 5.0 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SLASSCOM එහි මීළඟ වර්ධනයේ සහ පරිවර්තනයේ යුගයට සහාය වීම සඳහා නව සභාපති, මණ්ඩලය පත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLASSCOM සභාපති Ashique Ali 2022/23 වසර සඳහා නිලධාරී මණ්ඩලය සහ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සමඟ",
        "මෘදුකාංග සේවා සමාගම් සඳහා වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංගමය (SLASSCOM) පසුගියදා පැවති වාර්ෂික මහා සභා රැස්වීමේදී 2022/23 වසර සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ නව නිලධාරී මණ්ඩලය පත් කරන ලදී. 2022/2023 වසර සඳහා SLASSCOM හි සභාපති ලෙස Ashique Ali පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ඔහු Talliance හි කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා වන අතර වසර 30කට වැඩි පළපුරුද්දක් ඇති ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රවීණයෙකි. SLASSCOM හි ආරම්භක සාමාජිකයෙකු ලෙස, ඔහු IT/BPM කර්මාන්තය සඳහා දිවයිනේ ප්‍රමුඛතම සංගමය ලෙස එහි වත්මන් තත්ත්වයට මඟ පෙන්වීමට සහ මෙහෙයවීමට සහාය වෙමින්, වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ මුලපිරීම්වලට සහාය වීම සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කර ඇත. ඔහු ප්‍රතිපත්ති, අපනයන ප්‍රවර්ධන, FDI, ධාරිතා මුලපිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ සහ රාජ්‍ය ආයතනවල ප්‍රධාන කමිටු කිහිපයකම SLASSCOM නියෝජනය කරයි.",
        "මෙම පත්වීම පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් සභාපති ආෂික් අලි මහතා මෙසේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය: “අස්ථාවර සහ වේගයෙන් වෙනස් වන ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ/BPM ආයතන, එහි පුද්ගලයින් සහ පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතා දැඩි ලෙස අභියෝගයට ලක්වන අපගේ කර්මාන්තයට මෙය ඉතා දුෂ්කර හා දුෂ්කර කාලයක් වේ. අපේ රටේ.",
        "“බොහෝ අභියෝග මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, අපගේ සාමාජික සමාගම් විදේශීය ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට සහ ආයෝජකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ කැපවීම් ඉටු කිරීමට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ සේවකයින්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම ගැන සොයා බැලීමට කැපී පෙනෙන ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාවක් පෙන්නුම් කර ඇත.",
        "“අපගේ කර්මාන්තය සහ රට සඳහා වැඩි වර්ධනයක් ඇති කිරීම සඳහා අනාගතය සාර්ථක ලෙස සැරිසැරීමට උපායමාර්ගික සහ නව්‍ය ක්‍රම මේ කාලයන් ඉල්ලා සිටී. අපගේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය සහ සාමාන්‍ය සභා සාමාජිකයින් සමග අසමසම ස්ථීරභාවය සහ කර්මාන්ත විශේෂඥතාවයන් එක්රැස් කිරීමට මා හට වරප්‍රසාදයක් ඇත, එය කර්මාන්තයේ මීළඟ අදියරේ වර්ධනය සඳහා ස්ථානගත කිරීමට විශාල ශක්තියක් වනු ඇත.",
        "SLASSCOM හි නික්ම යන සභාපතිනි සැන්ඩ්‍රා ද සොයිසා, අලුතින් තේරී පත් වූ සභාපතිවරයාට සහ මණ්ඩලයට සිය සුබපැතුම් පිරිනමමින් මෙසේ පැවසුවාය: “SLASSCOM හි ආරම්භක සාමාජිකයෙකු ලෙස ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයේ නායකත්වයේ සහ අත්දැකීම්වල Ashique ගේ දිගු ඉතිහාසයක් ඇති අතර, SLASSCOM කණ්ඩායමට බොහෝ වටිනාකම් මත පදනම් වූ මුලපිරීම් දියත් කිරීමට සක්‍රීයව මග පෙන්වයි. කර්මාන්තය සඳහා, ඔහු මෙම භූමිකාව සඳහා සුදුසු පුද්ගලයෙකු බවට පත් කරයි. තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ/BPM ආයතන සහ එහි පුද්ගලයින් ඇතුළුව සියලුම කර්මාන්තයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන්ට ධනාත්මක බලපෑමක් ඇති කිරීමට ඔහුට සහාය වීමට මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි.",
        "ප්‍රථම උප සභාපති ලෙස ජෙහාන් පෙරින්පනායගම් සහ දෙවන උප සභාපති ලෙස නිශාන් මෙන්ඩිස්, මෙහෙයුම් අධ්‍යක්ෂ ලෙස ෂෙහානි සෙනෙවිරත්න සහ මුල්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ලෙස ෆෙරෝස් කාදර් පත් කරන ලද අනෙකුත් ප්‍රධාන නිලධාරී මණ්ඩලයට ඇතුළත් විය.",
        "SLASSCOM පළමු උප සභාපති ජෙහාන් පෙරින්පනායගම්, Informate Ltd හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සහ John Keells Holdings හි උප සභාපති වේ. BPM කර්මාන්තයේ වසර 25 කට වැඩි පළපුරුද්ද ගණනය කරමින්, ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු හවුල් සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථානය පිහිටුවීමට මූලික වූ අතර රටේ පළමු ග්‍රාමීය BPM හි පුරෝගාමියා විය.",
        "SLASSCOM හි දෙවන උප සභාපති නිශාන් මෙන්ඩිස්, PwC Sri Lanka හි විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ සහ තාක්ෂණ උපදේශක නායකයා සහ ප්‍රධාන තොරතුරු නිලධාරී (CIO) වේ. ජාතික වැදගත්කමකින් යුත් විවිධ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ඔහු සාර්ථකව මූලිකත්වය ගෙන වසර 23කට වඩා වැඩි අත්දැකීම් සම්භාරයක් හිමිකරගෙන ඇත.",
        "අධ්‍යක්ෂ මෙහෙයුම් තනතුරට පත් කරන ලද ෂෙහානි සෙනෙවිරත්න 99X Technology හි ප්‍රධාන මෙහෙයුම් නිලධාරිනිය වන අතර SLASSCOM HR Forum සහ Women’s Tech (Wtech) Forum හි ප්‍රධානියා වේ. ෂෙහානි ඩිජිටල් සඳහා කාන්තා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකාවක් වන අතර තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ කර්මාන්තයේ වැඩි කාන්තාවන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය ක්‍රියාකාරීව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි.",
        "මූල්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ තනතුරට පත් කර ඇති ෆෙරෝස් කාදර්, ලන්ඩන් කොටස් හුවමාරු සමූහයේ වෙළඳපල සේවා හවුල් මෙහෙයුම් ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කටයුතු කරයි. ඔහු මණ්ඩලයට උපදෙස් දෙන SLASSCOM හි උපාය මාර්ග කවුන්සිලයේ සාමාජිකයෙකු ද වී ඇත.",
        "SLASSCOM හි නව කීර්තිමත් අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයට hSenid  Business Solution හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සම්පත් ජයසුන්දර ඇතුළත් වේ; GTN සමූහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සහ හවුල් සේවා ප්‍රධානී අර්ජුන නානායක්කාර; VitalHub Innovations Lab කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ඩිලාන් රාජපක්ෂ; WNS Global Services DGM ශානක ප්‍රනාන්දු; SAKS ග්ලෝබල් ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී රෝහිත් ප්‍රදීප්; ලූප්ස් නිර්මාතෘ ෂෙහාන් සෙල්වනායගම්; සහ Inqbaytor සම-නිර්මාතෘ හර්ෂනී පෙරේරා.",
        "විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ නායකත්වය සහ කර්මාන්ත විශේෂඥතාව ගෙන එන එහි අලුතින් තේරී පත් වූ මණ්ඩලයේ පිටුබලය ඇතිව, අද වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය ඩොලර් බිලියන 5.0 ක ආදායමක් උත්පාදනය කිරීම, රැකියා 200,000 ක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම සහ ආරම්භක ව්‍යාපාර 1000 ක් උත්ප්‍රේරණය කිරීමේ දැක්ම සපුරාලීම සඳහා කර්මාන්තයේ අනාගත වර්ධනය සහ පරිවර්තනය වේගවත් කිරීමට හොඳින් සූදානම්ව සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLASSCOM",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඊළඟ යුගය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආශික් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මෘදුකාංග සේවා සමාගම් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික මහා සභා රැස්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආශික් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටැලියන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 30 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ඩීඅයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෙදාගැනීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආශික් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩලය සහ මහා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM හි නික්මයන සභාපතිනි සැන්ඩ්‍රා ද සොයිසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් පෙරින්පනායගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙහෙයුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් පෙරින්පනායගම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Informate Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 25 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 23 කට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහානි සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wtech) සංසදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහානි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් සඳහා කාන්තා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරෝස් කාදර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන් කොටස් හුවමාරු සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM හි උපාය මාර්ග කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "hSenid  ව්‍යාපාර විසඳුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GTN සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හවුල් සේවා අර්ජුන නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VitalHub නවෝත්පාදන විද්‍යාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WNS ගෝලීය සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශානක ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAKS ග්ලෝබල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලූප",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහාන් සෙල්වනායගම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂනී පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 5.0 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்லாஸ்காம் அதன் அடுத்த வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் மாற்றத்தின் சகாப்தத்தை ஆதரிப்பதற்காக வாரியத்தின் புதிய தலைவரை நியமித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLASSCOM தலைவர் ஆஷிக் அலி 2022/23 ஆண்டிற்கான அலுவலக நிர்வாகிகள் மற்றும் இயக்குநர் குழுவுடன்",
        "இலங்கை மென்பொருள் சேவை நிறுவனங்களுக்கான சங்கம் (SLASSCOM) அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற வருடாந்த பொதுக் கூட்டத்தில் 2022/23க்கான புதிய அலுவலகப் பொறுப்பாளர்களை நியமித்தது. 2022/2023 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான SLASSCOM இன் தலைவராக ஆஷிக் அலி நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவர் Talliance இன் நிர்வாக இயக்குநராக உள்ளார், மேலும் 30 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான அனுபவமுள்ள தொழில்துறையில் அனுபவம் வாய்ந்தவர். SLASSCOM இன் ஸ்தாபக உறுப்பினராக, அவர் அறையின் முன்முயற்சிகளை ஆதரிப்பதில் ஒரு ஒருங்கிணைந்த பங்கைக் கொண்டிருந்தார், IT/BPM துறையில் நாட்டின் முன்னணி சங்கமாக அதன் தற்போதைய நிலையை வழிநடத்தவும் வழிநடத்தவும் உதவுகிறார். கொள்கை, ஏற்றுமதி ஊக்குவிப்பு, FDI, திறன் முயற்சிகளில் அரசு மற்றும் மாநில நிறுவனங்களில் உள்ள பல முக்கிய குழுக்களில் SLASSCOM ஐ அவர் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறார்.",
        "இந்த நியமனம் குறித்த தனது எண்ணங்களைப் பகிர்ந்துகொண்ட தலைவர் ஆஷிக் அலி கூறியதாவது: \"இது எங்கள் தொழில்துறைக்கு கடினமான மற்றும் கடினமான நேரம், அங்கு IT/BPM நிறுவனங்கள், அதன் மக்கள் மற்றும் பங்குதாரர்களின் தேவைகள் நிலையற்ற மற்றும் வேகமாக மாறிவரும் பொருளாதார சூழ்நிலையால் கடுமையாக சவாலுக்கு உள்ளாகின்றன. எங்கள் நாட்டில்.",
        "\"பல சவால்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், எங்கள் உறுப்பு நிறுவனங்கள் வெளிநாட்டு வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கும் முதலீட்டாளர்களுக்கும் தங்கள் கடமைகளை வழங்குவதிலும், அவர்களின் ஊழியர்களின் நல்வாழ்வைக் கவனிப்பதிலும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பின்னடைவைக் காட்டியுள்ளன.",
        "\"எங்கள் தொழில் மற்றும் நாட்டிற்கு அதிக வளர்ச்சியை ஏற்படுத்த எதிர்காலத்தை வெற்றிகரமாக வழிநடத்துவதற்கான மூலோபாய மற்றும் புதுமையான வழிகளை இந்த காலங்கள் அழைக்கின்றன. நிகரற்ற உறுதியையும் தொழில் நிபுணத்துவத்தையும் ஒன்றிணைக்கும் எங்கள் வாரியம் மற்றும் பொதுக் கவுன்சில் உறுப்பினர்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றும் பாக்கியம் எனக்கு கிடைத்துள்ளது, இது தொழில்துறையை அதன் அடுத்த கட்ட வளர்ச்சிக்கு நிலைநிறுத்த உதவும் பெரும் பலமாக இருக்கும்.",
        "SLASSCOM அவுட்கோயிங் தலைவி சாண்ட்ரா டி சொய்சா, புதிதாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட தலைவர் மற்றும் வாரியத்திற்கு தனது வாழ்த்துக்களை தெரிவித்துக் கொண்டார்: “SLASSCOM இன் ஸ்தாபக உறுப்பினராக ஆஷிக்கின் நீண்ட தலைமைத்துவ வரலாறு மற்றும் தொழில்துறையில் அனுபவம் வாய்ந்தது, SLASSCOM குழுவை பல மதிப்பு சார்ந்த முயற்சிகளை தொடங்க தீவிரமாக வழிநடத்துகிறது. தொழில்துறைக்கு, இந்த பாத்திரத்திற்கு அவரை ஒரு சிறந்த நபராக ஆக்குகிறது. IT/BPM நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அதன் மக்கள் உட்பட அனைத்து தொழில்துறையின் பங்குதாரர்களுக்கும் நேர்மறையான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்த அவருக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க நான் எதிர்நோக்குகிறேன்.\"",
        "ஜெஹான் பேரின்பநாயகம் முதல் உப தலைவராகவும், நிஷான் மெண்டிஸ் இரண்டாவது உப தலைவராகவும், ஷெஹானி செனவிரத்ன செயற்பாட்டுப் பணிப்பாளராகவும், பெரோஸ் கார்டர் நிதிப் பணிப்பாளராகவும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள ஏனைய முக்கியப் பொறுப்பாளர்களில் அடங்குவர்.",
        "ஸ்லாஸ்காம் முதல் துணைத் தலைவர் ஜெஹான் பேரின்பநாயகம், இன்ஃபர்மேட் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தின் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி மற்றும் ஜான் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸின் துணைத் தலைவர் ஆவார். BPM துறையில் 25 வருடங்களுக்கும் மேலான அனுபவத்தை எண்ணி, இலங்கையில் முதலாவது பகிரப்பட்ட சேவை மையத்தை அமைப்பதில் முக்கிய பங்காற்றியவர் மற்றும் நாட்டின் முதல் கிராமப்புற BPM இன் முன்னோடியாகவும் இருந்தார்.",
        "SLASSCOM இன் இரண்டாவது துணைத் தலைவர் நிஷான் மெண்டிஸ், PwC Sri Lanka இன் நிறைவேற்றுப் பணிப்பாளர் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப ஆலோசனைத் தலைவர் மற்றும் தலைமை தகவல் அதிகாரி (CIO) ஆவார். அவர் 23 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான விரிவான அனுபவத்தைப் பெற்றவர், அங்கு அவர் தேசிய முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த பல்வேறு திட்டங்களை வெற்றிகரமாக முன்னெடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "பணிப்பாளர் செயற்பாட்டுப் பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ஷெஹானி செனவிரத்ன, 99X டெக்னாலஜியின் தலைமைச் செயற்பாட்டு அதிகாரி, SLASSCOM HR மன்றம் மற்றும் மகளிர் தொழில்நுட்ப (Wtech) மன்றத்திற்குத் தலைமை தாங்குகிறார். ஷெஹானி டிஜிட்டலுக்கான மகளிர் சேம்பர் குழு உறுப்பினராகவும் உள்ளார் மேலும் தகவல் தொழில்நுட்பத் துறையில் அதிக பெண்களின் பங்கேற்பை தீவிரமாக ஊக்குவிக்கிறார்.",
        "இயக்குநர் நிதி பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ஃபெரோஸ் கேடர், லண்டன் பங்குச் சந்தைக் குழுமத்தில் சந்தைச் சேவைகள் பகிரப்பட்ட செயல்பாடுகளின் இயக்குநராக உள்ளார். அவர் குழுவிற்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்கும் SLASSCOM இன் வியூக கவுன்சிலின் உறுப்பினராகவும் இருந்துள்ளார்.",
        "SLASSCOM இன் புதிய புகழ்பெற்ற இயக்குநர்கள் குழுவில் hSenid  Business Solution CEO சம்பத் ஜெயசுந்தர அடங்கும்; GTN குழுமத்தின் CEO மற்றும் பகிரப்பட்ட சேவைகளின் தலைவர் அர்ஜுன நாணயக்கார; VitalHub Innovations Lab முகாமைத்துவ பணிப்பாளர் திலான் ராஜபக்ஷ; WNS குளோபல் சர்வீசஸ் DGM ஷனக பெர்னாண்டோ; SAKS குளோபல் CEO ரோஹித் பிரதீப்; லூப்ஸ் நிறுவனர் ஷெஹான் செல்வநாயகம்; மற்றும் Inqbaytor இணை நிறுவனர் ஹர்ஷனி பெரேரா.",
        "பல்வகைப்பட்ட தலைமைத்துவம் மற்றும் தொழில் நிபுணத்துவம் ஆகியவற்றைக் கொண்டு புதிதாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட வாரியத்தின் ஆதரவுடன், 5.0 பில்லியன் டாலர் வருவாய் ஈட்டுதல், 200,000 வேலைகளை உருவாக்குதல் மற்றும் 1000 ஸ்டார்ட்அப்களை ஊக்குவிப்பதில் தொழில்துறையின் எதிர்கால வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் மாற்றத்தை விரைவுபடுத்துவதற்கு இன்று அறை தயாராக உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLASSCOM",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அடுத்த சகாப்தம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஷிக் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு 2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மென்பொருள் சேவை நிறுவனங்களுக்கான இலங்கை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு பொதுக்கூட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஷிக் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/2023 ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டாலியன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பகிர்தல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஷிக் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரியம் மற்றும் பொது கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM வெளியேறும் தலைவர் சாண்ட்ரா டி சொய்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IT/BPM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் பேரின்பநாயகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷான் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயல்பாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் பேரின்பநாயகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்பர்மேட் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிஎம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷான் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹானி செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wtech) மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹானி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டலுக்கான மகளிர் அறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரோஸ் காதர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன் பங்குச் சந்தை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM இன் வியூக கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLASSCOM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "hSenid  வணிக தீர்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிடிஎன் குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பகிரப்பட்ட சேவைகள் அர்ஜுன நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VitalHub இன்னோவேஷன்ஸ் லேப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலான் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WNS குளோபல் சர்வீசஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷனக பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAKS குளோபல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுழல்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹான் செல்வநாயகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷனி பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 5.0 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}