{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/22/sri-lanka-police-arrest-nine-people-as-forces-raid-anti-government-protest-camp/",
  "time_ut": 1658459220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka: Police arrest nine people as forces raid anti-government protest camp",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: Police arrest nine people as forces raid anti-government protest camp",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police said that nine people were arrested following a joint operation carried out early on Friday (22) morning to remove protestors who were occupying the main entrance to the President’s Office and the surrounding area.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said that the joint operation was carried out by the Three-Armed Forces, and the Police Special Task Force.",
        "Several people who were injured have been admitted to hospital, said Sri Lanka Police.",
        "It added that the suspects arrested are between the ages of 26 & 58, and are residents from Kelaniya, Embilipitiya, Ja-Ela, Ratnapura, Sevanagala, Wellampitiya, Pitigala, Wadduwa, and Nugegoda.",
        "The suspects will be produced to court today (22), said Sri Lanka Police.",
        "In addition, Police Scene Of Crime Officers have begun an investigation at the premises, and forensics will be called in when the need arises, said a statement from Sri Lanka Police.",
        "It added that the investigations are supervised by an SSP for the Colombo Central Division, and security has been tightened at the premises.",
        "Human Rights Commission calls for probe after troops raid Sri Lanka’s main protest site",
        "BASL condemns attack on protest site, calls for immediate investigation",
        "Sri Lanka: Police arrest nine people as forces raid anti-government protest camp"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "nine",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Three-Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between the ages of 26 & 58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sevanagala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellampitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitigala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wadduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "premises",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Central Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "premises",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂණ කඳවුරකට හමුදා කඩා වැදී පුද්ගලයන් 9 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිසිය පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශය අල්ලාගෙන සිටි විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීම සඳහා සිකුරාදා (22) අලුයම සිදුකළ ඒකාබද්ධ මෙහෙයුමකින් පුද්ගලයින් 9 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව සහ පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය එක්ව මෙම මෙහෙයුම ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "තුවාල ලැබූ කිහිප දෙනෙකු රෝහල් ගත කර ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් කැලණිය, ඇඹිලිපිටිය, ජා-ඇල, රත්නපුර, සෙවනගල, වැල්ලම්පිටිය, පිටිගල, වාද්දුව සහ නුගේගොඩ යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි වයස අවුරුදු 26ත් 58ත් අතර පසුවන්නන් බවයි පොලිසිය වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන් අද (22) අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මීට අමතරව, අපරාධ ස්ථාන පිළිබඳ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් විසින් එම පරිශ්‍රයේ පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර, අවශ්‍ය වූ විට අධිකරණ වෛද්‍යවරුන් කැඳවීමට නියමිත බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියේ ප්‍රකාශයක් පවසයි.",
        "කොළඹ මධ්‍යම කොට්ඨාශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරීවරයෙකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් විමර්ශන කටයුතු අධීක්‍ෂණය කෙරෙන අතර එම පරිශ්‍රයේ ආරක්ෂාව තර කර ඇති බවද එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතා ස්ථානය හමුදා වැටලීමෙන් පසු මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම පරීක්ෂණයක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "BASL විරෝධතා අඩවියට ප්‍රහාරය හෙළා දකියි, වහාම පරීක්ෂණයක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂණ කඳවුරකට හමුදා කඩා වැදී පුද්ගලයන් 9 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිසිය පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නවය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 26 සහ 58 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙවනගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලම්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාද්දුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරිශ්රය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම කොළඹ කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිශ්රය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: அரசுக்கு எதிரான போராட்ட முகாம் மீது படைகள் நடத்திய தாக்குதலில் 9 பேரை போலீசார் கைது செய்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (22) அதிகாலை ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தின் பிரதான நுழைவாயிலையும் அதனைச் சூழவுள்ள பகுதிகளையும் ஆக்கிரமித்து ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களை அகற்றுவதற்காக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட கூட்டு நடவடிக்கையைத் தொடர்ந்து ஒன்பது பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "முப்படையினரும், பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினரும் இணைந்து இந்த நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "காயமடைந்த பலர் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 26 மற்றும் 58 வயதுக்கு இடைப்பட்டவர்கள் எனவும், அவர்கள் களனி, எம்பிலிப்பிட்டிய, ஜா-எல, இரத்தினபுரி, செவனகல, வெல்லம்பிட்டிய, பிடிகல, வாதுவ மற்றும் நுகேகொட ஆகிய பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் இன்று (22) நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மேலும், குற்றவியல் அதிகாரிகளின் பொலிஸ் காட்சிகள் வளாகத்தில் விசாரணையைத் தொடங்கியுள்ளன, மேலும் தேவை ஏற்படும் போது தடயவியல் நிபுணர்கள் வரவழைக்கப்படுவார்கள் என்று இலங்கை காவல்துறையின் அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "விசாரணைகள் கொழும்பு மத்தியப் பிரிவிற்கான சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் ஒருவரால் கண்காணிக்கப்படுவதாகவும், வளாகத்தில் பாதுகாப்பு பலப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அது மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் பிரதான போராட்டத் தளத்தில் படையினர் சோதனையிட்டதை அடுத்து மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு விசாரணைக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
        "BASL போராட்ட தளத்தில் தாக்குதலை கண்டிக்கிறது, உடனடி விசாரணைக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது",
        "இலங்கை: அரசுக்கு எதிரான போராட்ட முகாம் மீது படைகள் நடத்திய தாக்குதலில் 9 பேரை போலீசார் கைது செய்தனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்பது",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று ஆயுதப் படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 மற்றும் 58 வயதுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவனகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாதுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளாகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மத்திய பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளாகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}