{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131556",
  "time_ut": 1657954196,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இன்று பல பகுதிகளில் மழை பெய்யும் சாத்தியம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rain is likely in many areas today",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology has predicted several times of rain in Upper, Sabaragamuwa and North-West provinces and Nuwara Eliya, Kandy, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "There is a chance of rain or thundershowers at some places in Uva province and Amparai and Batticaloa districts in the afternoon or night.",
        "Occasional gusty winds of up to 40 kilometers per hour may occur in the western slopes of the central hill country.",
        "There is a possibility of light rain over coastal areas from Puttalam through Colombo and Galle to Matara.",
        "Wind will blow from South-West direction with wind speed of 30-40 kmph. Wind speed may increase to 50-55 kmph over Puttalam through Mannar to Kangesanthurai and from Ambandottai to Pottuvil.",
        "From Puttalam to Kangesanthurai through Mannar and from Ambandottai to Pottuvil the sea surface will be turbulent from time to time. Other seas surrounding the country are expected to be moderate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-West",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amparai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "up to 40 kilometers per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South-West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-55 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambandottai",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kangesanthurai through Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambandottai",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට අද වැසි ඇති විය හැක",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉහළ, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් නුවරඑළිය, මහනුවර, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අනාවැකි පළ කරයි.",
        "අපරභාගයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී ඌව පළාතේ සහ අම්පාර සහ මඩකලපුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති විය හැකියි.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 40 දක්වා තද සුළං ඇති විය හැක.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ සහ ගාල්ල හරහා මාතර දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල සිහින් වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "සුළඟේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී. 30-40 දක්වාත් සමඟ නිරිත දෙසින් සුළඟ හමයි. පුත්තලම හරහා මන්නාරම හරහා කන්ගේසන්තුරේ දක්වා සහ අඹන්තොටේ සිට පොතුවිල් දක්වා සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-55 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට මන්නාරම හරහා කන්ගේසන්තුරේ දක්වාත්, අඹන්තොට්ටේ සිට පොතුවිල් දක්වාත් මුහුදු මතුපිට විටින් විට කැළඹිලි ස්වභාවයක් ගනී. රට වටා ඇති අනෙකුත් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ මධ්‍යස්ථව පවතිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාරයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර 40 දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිරිත-බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-55 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්ඩොට්ටයි",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම හරහා කන්ගේසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්ඩොට්ටයි",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று பல பகுதிகளில் மழை பெய்யும் சாத்தியம்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் நுவரெலியா, கண்டி, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் எதிர்வுகூறியுள்ளது.",
        "ஊவா மாகாணத்திலும் அம்பாறை மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு மாவட்டத்திலும் சில இடங்களில் பிற்பகல் அல்லது இரவு வேளையில் மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுகின்றது.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளில் அவ்வப்போது மணிக்கு 40 கிலோமீட்டர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும் காலி ஊடாக மாத்தறை வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் சிறிதளவு மழை பெய்யக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுகின்றது.",
        "காற்று தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும், காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. புத்தளத்திலிருந்து மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை வரையிலும் அம்பாந்தோட்டையிலிருந்து பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-55 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை வரையிலும் அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் இருந்து பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும். நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புகள் மிதமானதாக இருக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 40 கிலோமீட்டர் வரை",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50-55 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}