{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-parliament-to-select-new-president-on-july-20-amid-nomination-speculation-97261/",
  "time_ut": 1657586580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka parliament to select new president on July 20 amid nomination speculation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka parliament to select new president on July 20 amid nomination speculation",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s parliament will elect a new President on July 20, after meet calling for nominations on July 19, Speaker Mahinda Abeyewardene said after President Gotabaya Rajapaksa said he will resign following popular protests.",
        "Following a partly leader’s meeting on July 11, the speaker said parliament will meet on July 15.",
        "President Rajapaksa has said he will resign on July 13 and Prime Minister Wickremesinghe and the existing cabinet is expected to resign as soon as a new government is ready to take over.",
        "The Speaker said government chief whip Prasanna Ranatunga has told the meeting that the cabinet is ready to step down even on July 12 if an all party government is formed.",
        "Speaker Abeywardene said the election of the President by the parliament will be done according to the Article 40 of the constitution and a 1981 law on choosing a president.",
        "Under Sri Lanka’s law an election will take place if there are more than one nomination for the post.",
        "There have been calls to bring in a non-political person to parliament by the resignation of an existing member and make him president.",
        "Another possibility is to make Samagi Jana Balawegaya leader Sajith Premadasa the President and give the Prime Minister post to the Sri Lanka Podujana Party, political sources said.",
        "Among candidates speculated for the Prime Minister post is Dullas Alahapperuma.",
        "The current administration was ousted by the public due to monetary instability coming from a broken soft-peg which made it difficult to import fuel. (Colombo/July12/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Abeyewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Article 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාමයෝජනා සමපේක්ෂනය මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 20 වනදා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 19 වන දින නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීමෙන් පසු ජූලි 20 වන දින නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගනු ඇති බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු කථානායක මහින්ද අබේවර්ධන ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මහජන විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවයි.",
        "ජුලි 11 වනදා පැවති අර්ධ නායක රැස්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව කථානායකවරයා පැවසුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 15 වනදා රැස්වන බවයි.",
        "තමා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ පවසා ඇති අතර නව රජයක් බලයට පත්වීමට සූදානම් වූ වහාම අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ පවතින කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය ඉල්ලා අස්වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් ජුලි 12 වැනිදා වුවද කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට සූදානම් බව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා රැස්වීමට ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව කථානායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාව සහ 1981 ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ නීතිය අනුව සිදු කෙරෙන බව කථානායක අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නීතියට අනුව එම තනතුර සඳහා නාමයෝජනා එකකට වඩා තිබේ නම් මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වේ.",
        "දැනට සිටින මන්ත‍්‍රීවරයෙකු ඉල්ලා අස්වී දේශපාලනික නොවන අයෙකු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගෙන්වා ඔහුව ජනාධිපති කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලීම් ඉදිරිපත් වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජනාධිපති කර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පක්ෂයට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරය ලබාදීම තවත් අවස්ථාවක් බව දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "අගමැති අපේක්ෂකයින් අතර ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ද සිටී.",
        "වත්මන් පාලනය මහජනතාව විසින් නෙරපා හරින ලද්දේ, ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම දුෂ්කර වූ, කැඩුණු මෘදු කූඩුවකින් පැමිණි මුදල් අස්ථාවරත්වය හේතුවෙනි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි12/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் புதிய அதிபரை ஜூலை 20-ஆம் தேதி தேர்வு செய்ய வாய்ப்பு இருப்பதாக ஊகங்கள் எழுந்துள்ளன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பாராளுமன்றம் ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதி வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்த பின்னர் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ கூறியதைத் தொடர்ந்து மக்கள் எதிர்ப்புகளைத் தொடர்ந்து ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 11 ஆம் தேதி ஒரு பகுதி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜூலை 15 ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றம் கூடும் என்று சபாநாயகர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி தான் ராஜினாமா செய்யப் போவதாக அதிபர் ராஜபக்ச கூறியுள்ளதோடு, புதிய அரசாங்கம் பொறுப்பேற்கத் தயாராக இருக்கும் போதே பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவும் தற்போதுள்ள அமைச்சரவையும் ராஜினாமா செய்வார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட்டால் எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை 12ஆம் திகதி கூட அமைச்சரவையில் இருந்து விலகுவதற்கு தயார் என அரசாங்க பிரதம கொறடா பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவித்ததாக சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 ஆவது சரத்து மற்றும் 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்றத்தினால் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு செய்யப்படும் என சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் சட்டத்தின்படி பதவிக்கு ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட வேட்புமனுக்கள் இருந்தால் தேர்தல் நடைபெறும்.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள உறுப்பினர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்து அரசியல் சாராத ஒருவரை நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்கு கொண்டு வந்து ஜனாதிபதியாக்க வேண்டும் என்ற கோரிக்கைகள் எழுந்துள்ளன.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை ஜனாதிபதியாக்கி ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன கட்சிக்கு பிரதமர் பதவி வழங்குவது மற்றுமொரு சாத்தியம் என அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு போட்டியிடும் வேட்பாளர்களில் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவும் ஒருவர்.",
        "தற்போதைய நிர்வாகம், எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதை கடினமாக்கிய, உடைந்த மென்மையான-ஆப்பிலிருந்து வரும் பண ஸ்திரமின்மையால் பொதுமக்களால் வெளியேற்றப்பட்டது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை12/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}