{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83353/ccpi-based-headline-inflation-soars-to-546-in-june",
  "time_ut": 1656600600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CCPI-based headline inflation soars to 54.6% in June",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CCPI-based headline inflation soars to 54.6% in June",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s headline inflation, as measured by the year-on-year (Y-o-Y) change in the Colombo Consumer Price Index, soared to 54.6 percent in June from 39.1 percent in May this year, the Department of Census and Statistics (DCS) said today in a press release.",
        "This increase in Y-o-Y inflation is driven by the monthly increases of both Food and Non-Food categories.",
        "Food inflation (Y-o-Y) increased to 80.1 percent in June from 57.4 percent in May, while Non-Food inflation (Y-o-Y) increased to 42.4 percent in June from 30.6 percent in May.",
        "The monthly change of CCPI was recorded at 12.8 percent in June. The month-on-month change was contributed by the increases of Food items by 6.81 percent and Non-Food items by 5.99 percent, respectively.",
        "Accordingly, prices of items in the Non-Food category recorded increases mainly due to price increases observed in the transport (petrol, diesel and bus fare), restaurant & hotels, education, housing, water, electricity, gas and other fuels (LP gas, materials for maintenance/reconstruction, firewood purchasing), miscellaneous goods and services (car, insurance), and several other groups.",
        "Further, within the Food category, increases were mainly observed in the prices of sea fish, vegetables, bread, rice, milk powder, chicken, dried fish, Mysoor dhal, sugar, buns, eggs, potatoes, coconuts, chilli powder, biscuits, canned fish, red onions, ice-cream, infant milk powder, and big onions during the month.",
        "Meanwhile, moving average inflation rose to 18.4 percent in June from 14.2 percent in May.",
        "According to the DCS, the core inflation (Y-o-Y), which reflects the underlying inflation in the economy increased to 39.9 percent in June from 28.4 per cent in May.",
        "Sri Lanka CCPI-based Headline Inflation in June by Adaderana Online on Scribd"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "54.6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "June",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "May this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Census and Statistics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Food and Non-Food",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "57.4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Non-Food",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCPI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.81 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Non-Food",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.99 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Non-Food",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "restaurant & hotels",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Food",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "chilli powder",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18.4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.9 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28.4 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Headline Inflation",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Adaderana Online",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scribd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CCPI මත පදනම් වූ උද්ධමනය ජුනි මාසයේදී 54.6% දක්වා ඉහළ යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ පාරිභෝගික මිල දර්ශකයේ වසරින් වසර (Y-o-Y) වෙනස මගින් මනිනු ලබන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන උද්ධමනය, මේ වසරේ මැයි මාසයේ පැවති සියයට 39.1 සිට ජුනි මාසයේදී සියයට 54.6 දක්වා ඉහළ ගිය බව ජනලේඛන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (DCS) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. මාධ්ය නිවේදනයක.",
        "Y-o-Y උද්ධමනයේ මෙම වැඩිවීම ආහාර සහ ආහාර නොවන කාණ්ඩ දෙකෙහිම මාසික වැඩිවීම මගින් මෙහෙයවනු ලැබේ.",
        "ආහාර උද්ධමනය (Y-o-Y) මැයි මාසයේදී සියයට 57.4 සිට ජුනි මාසයේදී සියයට 80.1 දක්වා ඉහළ ගිය අතර ආහාර නොවන උද්ධමනය (Y-o-Y) මැයි මාසයේදී සියයට 30.6 සිට ජුනි මාසයේදී සියයට 42.4 දක්වා වැඩි විය.",
        "CCPI හි මාසික වෙනස ජුනි මාසයේදී 12.8 හි වාර්තා විය. මාසික වෙනසට ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය සියයට 6.81 කින් සහ ආහාර නොවන ද්‍රව්‍ය සියයට 5.99 කින් ඉහළ යාම දායක විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව, ප්‍රවාහන (පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල් සහ බස් ගාස්තු), ආපනශාලා සහ හෝටල්, අධ්‍යාපනය, නිවාස, ජලය, විදුලිය, ගෑස් සහ අනෙකුත් ඉන්ධන (LP ගෑස්) යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල දක්නට ලැබෙන මිල වැඩිවීම් හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ආහාර නොවන කාණ්ඩයේ භාණ්ඩවල මිල ඉහළ යාමක් වාර්තා විය. , නඩත්තු/ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය සඳහා ද්‍රව්‍ය, දර මිලදී ගැනීම), විවිධ භාණ්ඩ සහ සේවා (කාර්, රක්ෂණ) සහ තවත් කණ්ඩායම් කිහිපයක්.",
        "තවද, ආහාර කාණ්ඩය තුළ, මුහුදු මාළු, එළවළු, පාන්, සහල්, කිරිපිටි, කුකුල් මස්, කරවල, මයිසූර් පරිප්පු, සීනි, බනිස්, බිත්තර, අර්තාපල්, පොල්, මිරිස් කුඩු, බිස්කට්, මිල ගණන්වල ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ඉහළ යාමක් දක්නට ලැබුණි. මාසය තුළ ටින් මාළු, රතු ළූණු, අයිස්ක්‍රීම්, ළදරු කිරිපිටි සහ ලොකු ළූණු.",
        "මේ අතර, චලන සාමාන්‍ය උද්ධමනය මැයි මාසයේදී සියයට 14.2 සිට ජුනි මාසයේදී සියයට 18.4 දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "DCS ට අනුව, ආර්ථිකයේ යටින් පවතින උද්ධමනය පිළිබිඹු කරන මූලික උද්ධමනය (Y-o-Y) මැයි මාසයේදී සියයට 28.4 සිට ජුනි මාසයේදී සියයට 39.9 දක්වා වැඩි විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සීසීපීඅයි මත පදනම් වූ ප්‍රධාන උද්ධමනය ජූනි මස Scribd හි Adaderana Online විසිනි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "54.6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 54.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 39.1 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනලේඛන හා සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සහ ආහාර නොවන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 80.1 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 57.4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර නොවන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 42.4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 30.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCPI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 12.8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6.81 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර නොවන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 5.99 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආහාර නොවන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආපනශාලා සහ හෝටල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිස් කුඩු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 18.4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 14.2 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 39.9 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 28.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශීර්ෂය උද්ධමනය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අදදෙරණ ඔන්ලයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scribd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CCPI அடிப்படையிலான பணவீக்கம் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 54.6% ஆக உயர்ந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு நுகர்வோர் விலைச் சுட்டெண்ணில் வருடாவருடம் (Y-o-Y) மாற்றத்தின் அடிப்படையில் இலங்கையின் பிரதான பணவீக்கம், இந்த ஆண்டு மே மாதத்தில் 39.1 சதவீதமாக இருந்த 39.1 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 54.6 சதவீதமாக உயர்ந்துள்ளதாக மக்கள் தொகைக் கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றும் புள்ளிவிபரத் திணைக்களம் (DCS) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஒரு செய்திக்குறிப்பில்.",
        "Y-o-Y பணவீக்கத்தின் இந்த அதிகரிப்பு உணவு மற்றும் உணவு அல்லாத வகைகளின் மாதாந்திர அதிகரிப்புகளால் இயக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "உணவுப் பணவீக்கம் (Y-o-Y) மே மாதத்தில் 57.4 சதவீதத்தில் இருந்து ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 80.1 சதவீதமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது, அதே சமயம் உணவு அல்லாத பணவீக்கம் (Y-o-Y) மே மாதத்தில் 30.6 சதவீதத்தில் இருந்து ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 42.4 சதவீதமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "CCPI இன் மாதாந்திர மாற்றம் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 12.8 சதவீதமாக பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டது. உணவுப் பொருட்கள் 6.81 சதவீதம் மற்றும் உணவு அல்லாத பொருட்கள் 5.99 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்ததன் மூலம் மாதந்தோறும் மாற்றம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "அதன்படி, போக்குவரத்து (பெட்ரோல், டீசல் மற்றும் பஸ் கட்டணம்), உணவகம் மற்றும் ஹோட்டல்கள், கல்வி, வீட்டுவசதி, நீர், மின்சாரம், எரிவாயு மற்றும் பிற எரிபொருள்கள் (LP எரிவாயு) ஆகியவற்றில் காணப்பட்ட விலை அதிகரிப்பு காரணமாக உணவு அல்லாத வகையின் பொருட்களின் விலைகள் அதிகரித்துள்ளன. , பராமரிப்பு/புனரமைப்புக்கான பொருட்கள், விறகு வாங்குதல்), இதர பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகள் (கார், காப்பீடு) மற்றும் பல குழுக்கள்.",
        "மேலும், உணவு வகைக்குள், கடல் மீன், காய்கறிகள், ரொட்டி, அரிசி, பால் பவுடர், கோழிக்கறி, உலர் மீன், மைசூர் பருப்பு, சர்க்கரை, பன்கள், முட்டை, உருளைக்கிழங்கு, தேங்காய், மிளகாய் தூள், பிஸ்கட், பிஸ்கட் ஆகியவற்றின் விலைகள் முக்கியமாக அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட மீன், சிவப்பு வெங்காயம், ஐஸ்கிரீம், குழந்தை பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் பெரிய வெங்காயம் மாதத்தில்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், நகரும் சராசரி பணவீக்கம் மே மாதத்தில் 14.2 சதவீதத்தில் இருந்து ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 18.4 சதவீதமாக உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "DCS இன் படி, பொருளாதாரத்தின் அடிப்படை பணவீக்கத்தை பிரதிபலிக்கும் முக்கிய பணவீக்கம் (Y-o-Y), மே மாதத்தில் 28.4 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 39.9 சதவீதமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை CCPI அடிப்படையிலான ஹெட்லைன் பணவீக்கம் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் Adaderana ஆன்லைன் மூலம் Scribd"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "54.6%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் தொகை கணக்கெடுப்பு மற்றும் புள்ளியியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு மற்றும் உணவு அல்லாதவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "57.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு அல்லாத",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCPI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.81 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு அல்லாத",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.99 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உணவு அல்லாத",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவகம் & ஹோட்டல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உணவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிளகாய் தூள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DCS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைப்பு பணவீக்கம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடடெரனா ஆன்லைன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கிரிப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}