{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-rupee-guidance-peg-against-us-dollar-falls-govt-securities-hardly-traded-99391/",
  "time_ut": 1662136440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s rupee guidance peg against US dollar falls; Govt securities hardly traded",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s rupee guidance peg against US dollar falls; Govt securities hardly traded",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT –The Central Bank’s rupee guidance peg for interbank transactions against US dollar weakened by another 37 cents on Friday (02) while yields in Treasury Bills and  bonds remained unchanged in dull trade, dealers said.",
        "Bonds maturing on 01. 06. 2025 closed at 28.25/29.30 percent, while maturing on 15.05.2031 closed 29.00/75 percent, hardly changed from the previous close.",
        "Analysts said the debt market is closely monitoring the government’s debt restructuring process with concerns of possible restructuring in the rupee-denominated government securities.",
        "Sri Lanka’s central bank announced a guidance peg for interbank transactions which was 37 cents lower to 361.45 rupees against the US dollar on Friday from the previous day’s 361.08 rupees.",
        "Data showed that commercial banks offered dollars for telegraphic transfers between 368.45 and 370.00 for small transactions.",
        "Banks offered to buy inward remittances at 358.45 -359.00 rupees. (Colombo/ Sep 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Govt securities hardly",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Central Bank’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "another 37 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06.",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28.25/29.30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.05.2031",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.00/75 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 368.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sep",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට සාපේක්ෂව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුපියලේ මාර්ගෝපදේශ පහත වැටේ; රජයේ සුරැකුම්පත් වෙළඳාම් කළේ ඉතා අඩුවෙන්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට සාපේක්ෂව අන්තර් බැංකු ගනුදෙනු සඳහා මහ බැංකුවේ රුපියලේ මාර්ගෝපදේශය සිකුරාදා (02) තවත් ශත 37 කින් දුර්වල වූ අතර භාණ්ඩාගාර බිල්පත් සහ බැඳුම්කරවල අස්වැන්න අඳුරු වෙළඳාමේ දී නොවෙනස්ව පැවති බව අලෙවි නියෝජිතයෝ පවසති.",
        "2025 01. 06. දින කල් පිරෙන බැඳුම්කර සියයට 28.25/29.30 කින් අවසන් වූ අතර, 2031.05.15 දින කල් පිරෙන සියයට 29.00/75 කින් අවසන් වූ අතර, පෙර අවසානයට වඩා බොහෝ දුරට වෙනස් විය.",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයින් පැවසුවේ, රුපියලෙන් වෙන් කරන ලද රාජ්‍ය සුරැකුම්පත්වල ඇති විය හැකි ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම් පිළිබඳ උත්සුකයන් සමඟ ණය වෙළෙඳපොළ රජයේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව අන්තර් බැංකු ගනුදෙනු සඳහා මාර්ගෝපදේශනයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති අතර එය පෙර දින රුපියල් 361.08 සිට සිකුරාදා එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට සාපේක්ෂව රුපියල් 361.45 දක්වා ශත 37 කින් අඩු විය.",
        "කුඩා ගනුදෙනු සඳහා 368.45 සහ 370.00 අතර විදුලි පණිවුඩ හුවමාරු සඳහා වාණිජ බැංකු ඩොලර් ලබා දුන් බව දත්ත පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "බැංකු විසින් රුපියල් 358.45 -359.00 ආදී ප්‍රේෂණ මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉදිරිපත් විය. (කොළඹ/සැප් 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ සුරැකුම්පත් නැති තරම්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් ශත 37 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06.",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 28.25/29.30",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2031.05.15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.00/75 සියයට",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 37යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.45 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.08 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.45 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.45 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்க டொலருக்கு எதிரான இலங்கையின் ரூபாயின் வழிகாட்டல் மதிப்பு வீழ்ச்சி; அரசாங்கப் பத்திரங்கள் வர்த்தகம் செய்யவில்லை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு எதிரான வங்கிகளுக்கு இடையேயான பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கான மத்திய வங்கியின் ரூபாய் வழிகாட்டுதல் பெக் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (02) மேலும் 37 சென்ட்கள் பலவீனமடைந்தது, அதே நேரத்தில் திறைசேரி உண்டியல்கள் மற்றும்  பத்திரங்களின் வருவாய் மந்தமான வர்த்தகத்தில் மாறாமல் இருந்தது, விநியோகஸ்தர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "01. 06. 2025 அன்று முதிர்ச்சியடையும் பத்திரங்கள் 28.25/29.30 சதவீதத்தில் முடிவடைந்தன, அதே சமயம் 15.05.2031 அன்று முதிர்ச்சியடையும் போது 29.00/75 சதவீதமாக முடிவடைந்தது, முந்தைய முடிவில் இருந்து மாறவில்லை.",
        "ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான அரசுப் பத்திரங்களில் சாத்தியமான மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான கவலைகளுடன், கடன் சந்தை அரசாங்கத்தின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு செயல்முறையை உன்னிப்பாகக் கண்காணித்து வருவதாக ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் மத்திய வங்கியானது வங்கிகளுக்கிடையிலான பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கான வழிகாட்டல் பெக் ஒன்றை அறிவித்தது, இது வெள்ளியன்று அமெரிக்க டொலருக்கு எதிராக 361.45 ரூபாவாக 37 சென்ட்கள் குறைந்து, முந்தைய நாளான 361.08 ரூபாவாக இருந்தது.",
        "சிறிய பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கு 368.45 முதல் 370.00 வரையிலான தந்தி பரிமாற்றங்களுக்கு வணிக வங்கிகள் டாலர்களை வழங்குவதாக தரவு காட்டுகிறது.",
        "வங்கிகள் 358.45 -359.00 ரூபாயில் உள்நோக்கி அனுப்பும் பணத்தை வாங்க முன்வந்தன. (கொழும்பு/ செப் 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசாங்கப் பத்திரங்கள் அரிதாகவே உள்ளன",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு 37 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06.",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28.25/29.30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.05.2031",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.00/75 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.45 இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}