{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83616/trains-to-operate-despite-curfew-in-western-province",
  "time_ut": 1657695900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Trains to operate despite curfew in Western Province",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Trains to operate despite curfew in Western Province",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Railways says that despite curfew being imposed in the Western Province, trains will operate until commuters return to their homes.",
        "The General Manager of Railways Mr. Dhammika Jayasundara said that the department is working to fulfill that task so that the commuters are not inconvenienced.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, as the Acting President, has ordered to impose curfew in the Western Province with immediate effect and to impose emergency law island-wide, the Prime Minister’s Office announced earlier.",
        "PM Wickremesinghe has also ordered the security forces to arrest those engaging in unruly behaviour and to take into custody the vehicles they travel in, the statement said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Trains",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Western Province",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ඇඳිරි නීතිය නොතකා දුම්රිය ධාවනයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතට ඇඳිරි නීතිය පනවා තිබුණද මගීන් නැවත සිය නිවෙස් කරා යනතුරු දුම්රිය ධාවනය කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර මහතා පැවසුවේ, මගීන්ට අපහසුතාවයක් නොවන පරිදි එම කාර්යය ඉටු කිරීමට දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි බස්නාහිර පළාතට ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීමටත් දිවයින පුරා හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීමටත් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නියෝග කර ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය මීට පෙර නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "නොසන්සුන්කාරී ලෙස හැසිරෙන්නන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙසත් ඔවුන් ගමන් ගන්නා වාහන අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙසත් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ආරක්ෂක අංශවලට නියෝග කර ඇති බව එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දුම්රිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරාතුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை மீறி ரயில்கள் இயக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் ஊரடங்கு சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும், பயணிகள் வீடு திரும்பும் வரை புகையிரத சேவைகள் இடம்பெறும் என இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பயணிகளுக்கு அசௌகரியம் ஏற்படாத வகையில் அந்தப் பணியை நிறைவேற்ற திணைக்களம் செயற்பட்டு வருவதாக ரயில்வே பொது முகாமையாளர் திரு.தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் உடனடியாக அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தவும், நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தவும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி என்ற வகையில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அத்துமீறி நடந்துகொள்ளும் நபர்களை கைது செய்யவும், அவர்கள் பயணிக்கும் வாகனங்களை காவலில் எடுக்கவும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினருக்கு பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரயில்கள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பி.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}