{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/නිමල්ගේ-අල්ලස්-චෝදනාව-පරීක්ෂාවට-ත්‍රිපුද්ගල-කමිටුවක්/101-616905",
  "time_ut": 1658548307,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිමල්ගේ අල්ලස් චෝදනාව පරීක්ෂාවට ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A three-member committee to probe Nimal's bribery allegations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A three-member committee has been appointed by President Ranil Wickramasinghe to investigate the allegation that former Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva received a bribe from a Japanese company during his tenure as the Minister of Ports, Shipping and Aviation.",
        "Retired High Court Judge Ms. Kusala Sarojani Weerawardena is the chairperson of the committee and the other members are retired Senior DIG SM Wickramasinghe and SMG Perera, a senior officer in the Administrative Service.",
        "The report of the committee should be submitted to the President before the 31st.",
        "Mr. Nimal Siripala de Silva resigned from the ministry recently, giving the opportunity for an investigation after the accusation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nimal",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kusala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DIG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMG Perera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Administrative Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 31st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල්ගේ අල්ලස් චෝදනාව පරීක්ෂාවට ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා වරාය නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය ධූරයේ කටයුතු කළ සමයේ දී ජපානයේ සමාගමකින් අල්ලසක් ලබාගත් බවට ඉල්ලවූ චෝදනාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන පැවැත්වීම සඳහා  ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවක් පත් කරනු ලැබ සිටී.",
        "විශ්‍රාමික මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු  කුසලා සරෝජනී වීරවර්ධන මහත්මිය ගේ සභාපතිත්වයෙන් යුතු කමිටුවේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබ සිටින්නේ  විශ්‍රාමික ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති එස් එම් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ  පරිපාලන සේවයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියකු වන එස්.එම්.ජී පෙරේරාය.",
        "කමිටුවේ වාර්තාව ලබන 31 වෙනිදාට පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරයාට බාර දිය යුතුය.",
        "චෝදනාව එල්ල වීමෙන් පසු පරීක්ෂණයකට අවස්ථාව ලබාදෙමින්  නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ඒ අමාත්‍යධූරයෙන් පසුගියදා  ඉල්ලා අස්විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිමල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුසල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.අයි.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් එම් ජී පෙරේරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිපාලන සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமாலின் இலஞ்ச குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்த மூவரடங்கிய குழுவொன்று",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் அமைச்சராக இருந்த காலத்தில் ஜப்பானிய நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து இலஞ்சம் பெற்றதாக எழுந்த குற்றச்சாட்டு தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் மூவரடங்கிய குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி திருமதி குசலா சரோஜனி வீரவர்தன குழுவின் தலைவராகவும், ஓய்வுபெற்ற சிரேஷ்ட பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் எஸ்.எம்.விக்ரமசிங்க மற்றும் நிர்வாக சேவையின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரியான எஸ்.எம்.ஜி.பெரேரா ஆகியோர் உறுப்பினர்களாகவும் உள்ளனர்.",
        "அந்தக் குழுவின் அறிக்கை எதிர்வரும் 31ஆம் திகதிக்கு முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "திரு.நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா, குற்றச்சாட்டுக்குப் பின்னர் விசாரணைக்கு வாய்ப்பளித்து அண்மையில் அமைச்சுப் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிமல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குசலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.ஐ.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம்.ஜி பெரேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாக சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}