{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘මහින්ද-මැරෙනකම්-පිරිසක්-රතිඤ්ඤා-තියාගෙන-ඉන්නවා‘‘/101-615749",
  "time_ut": 1656774961,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘මහින්ද මැරෙනකම් පිරිසක් රතිඤ්ඤා තියාගෙන ඉන්නවා‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"A group of people are holding firecrackers until Mahinda dies.\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former minister Wimalaweera Dissanayake tearfully asked how unfortunate it is that some people in this country, who had celebrated by eating milk rice and lighting firecrackers when the murderer Prabhakaran who drenched the entire country in blood, are waiting for the death of Mahinda Rajapaksa, who led the murder of the murderer Prabhakaran. did",
        "He also mentioned that he wishes not to be born in this world even in the next soul.",
        "Mr. Dissanayake said that he is of the opinion that Mr. Mahinda Rajapaksa is a historical figure who has done a crucial mission for this country regardless of his shortcomings and said that it is an extremely tragic situation for such an ungrateful group of people to wait for such a person to die.",
        "Mr. Wimalaweera Dissanayake also said that he is not a happy person even if an animal dies and not a human being. Even though many people lit firecrackers on the day of Prabhakaran's death in Velupilla, he did not do so because his inner being shows that the death of a human being is not a happy event.",
        "The former minister said that Mr. Mahinda Rajapaksa had spoken to him the day before and said that he is in very good health.",
        "The former minister also said that when he told him about some people's propaganda that he was in a critical condition, Mr. Rajapaksa laughed out loud saying, \"That's it, Wimale..I don't even know that I'm in a critical condition.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimalaweera Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabhakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabhakaran",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimalaweera Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prabhakaran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velupilla",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimale",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘මහින්ද මැරෙනකම් පිරිසක් රතිඤ්ඤා තියාගෙන ඉන්නවා‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුළු රටක් ලෙයින් තෙත් කළ මිනීමරු ප්‍රභාකරන් මරා දැමූ අවස්ථාවේදී එදා කිරිබත් කා රතිඤ්ඤා පත්තු කරමින් ප්‍රීතිඝෝෂා පැවැත්වූ මේ රටේ සමහරුන් මිනීමරු ප්‍රභාකරන් විනාශ කිරීමට නායකත්වය දුන් මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මැරෙන තුරු රතිඤ්ඤා ලෑස්ති කරගෙන අද බලා සිටීම කෙතරම් අභාග්‍යසම්පන්න තත්වයක් දැයි හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමලවීර දිසානායක මහතා හැඬූ කඳුළින් යුතුව ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "මතු ආත්මයකදීවත් මේ දෙරණේ නොඉපදින්නට තමා ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරන්නේ මෙනිසා බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කුමන අඩුපාඩු තිබුණත් මේ රටට යම් තීරණාත්මක මෙහෙවරක් කළ ඓතිහාසික චරිතයක් බව තමාගේ අදහස යැයි පැවසූ දිසානායක මහතා එවැනි පුද්ගලයකු මැරෙන තුරු අකෘතඥ පිරිසක් මෙලෙස බලා සිටීම අතිශයින්ම ඛේදජනක තත්වයක් බවද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මිනිසකු නොව සතෙකු මිය ගියත් තමා සතුටු වන පුද්ගලයකු නොවේ යැයිද වේලුපිල්ලේ ප්‍රභාකරන් මියගිය දිනයේ බොහෝ දෙනෙකු රතිඤ්ඤා පත්තු කළද තමා එසේ නොකළේ මිනිසෙකු මිය යෑම සතුටුවිය හැකි සිද්ධියක් නොවන බව තමාගේ අභ්‍යන්තරය පෙන්වා දෙන නිසා යැයිද විමලවීර දිසානායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තමාට පෙරේදා දිනයේ කතා කළ බව පැවසූ හිටපු ඇමැතිවරයා ඔහු ඉතා හොඳ සුවයෙන් පසුවන බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අසාධ්‍ය තත්වයෙන් පසුවන බවට සමහරුන් ප්‍රචාර ගැන තමා ඔහුට පැවසූ අවස්ථාවේදී රාජපක්ෂ මහතා \" ඕවා ඔහොම තමයි විමලේ..මට අසාධ්‍යයි කියලා මම වත් දන්නෙ නෑ \" යනුවෙන් පවසා මහ හඬින් සිනාසුනු බවද හිටපු ඇමතිවරයා කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විමලවීර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාකරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමලවීර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාකරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේළුපිල්ලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "“மகிந்த சாகும் வரை ஒரு கூட்டம் பட்டாசு வெடிக்கிறது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முழு நாட்டையும் இரத்த வெள்ளத்தில் நனைத்த கொலைகாரன் பிரபாகரனை பால் சோறு சாப்பிட்டு பட்டாசு கொளுத்தி கொண்டாடிய இந்த நாட்டில் சிலர் தலைமை தாங்கிய மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவின் மரணத்திற்காக காத்திருப்பது எவ்வளவு துரதிஷ்டமானது என முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க கண்ணீருடன் கேட்டார். கொலைகாரன் பிரபாகரனின் கொலை",
        "அடுத்த ஆன்மாவில் கூட இவ்வுலகில் பிறக்கக்கூடாது என்று வாழ்த்துகிறேன் என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "திரு.மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச தனது குறைபாடுகளை பொருட்படுத்தாமல் இந்த நாட்டிற்கு முக்கியப் பணியை ஆற்றிய வரலாற்று நாயகன் என்று தான் கருதுவதாகத் தெரிவித்த திரு. அத்தகைய ஒரு நபர் இறப்பதற்கு.",
        "மனிதனல்ல மிருகம் செத்தாலும் மகிழ்ச்சியானவன் அல்ல என்றும் திரு.விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.வேலுப்பிலவில் பிரபாகரன் இறந்த தினத்தில் பலர் பட்டாசு கொளுத்திய போதும் தாம் அவ்வாறு செய்யவில்லையென்றால் அவரது உள்ளம் அதை வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது. ஒரு மனிதனின் மரணம் மகிழ்ச்சியான நிகழ்வு அல்ல.",
        "திரு.மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச தம்மிடம் நேற்றுமுன்தினம் பேசியதாகவும் அவர் மிகவும் நலமுடன் இருப்பதாகவும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தான் உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருப்பதாக சிலர் பிரசாரம் செய்வதை தன்னிடம் கூறியபோது, ​​“அதுதான் விமலே..எனக்கு கிரிகலில் இருப்பது கூட தெரியாது என ராஜபக்ச உரக்க சிரித்தார் என்றும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் கூறினார். நிலை.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாகரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபாகரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலுப்பிள்ளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமலே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}