{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/மலையகம்/ஜீவன்-அதிரடி-முடிவு/76-300469",
  "time_ut": 1657872847,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜீவன் அதிரடி முடிவு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jeevan Action Decision",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As a video of Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha member Susai Alexander threatening and assaulting a common man standing in a queue of gas cylinders is going viral on social media, the general secretary of the party Jeevan Thondaman has said that an inquiry will be held against him and till then he will be suspended from the party. .",
        "The media wing of the Congress has announced that the high-level disciplinary committee of the Sri Lanka Workers' Congress will soon conduct an investigation into the controversies and allegations against Norwood Regional Council member Soosai Alexander.",
        "Jeevan Thondaman, Secretary General of EC, has said that EC will never allow such activities and all the party membership rights of the said Pradeshiya Sabha member have been temporarily revoked with effect."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jeevan Action Decision",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Norwood Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susai Alexander",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Workers'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwood Regional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soosai Alexander",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pradeshiya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජීවන් ක්‍රියාකාරී තීරණය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රී සුසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ගෑස් සිලින්ඩර පෝලිමක සිටි සාමාන්‍ය පුද්ගලයෙකුට තර්ජනය කර පහර දෙන වීඩියෝවක් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ජාලා ඔස්සේ පැතිර යමින් පවතින බැවින් ඔහුට එරෙහිව පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බවත් එතෙක් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බවත් එම පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් මහතා පවසයි. එතකොට එයාව පක්‍ෂයෙන් තහනම් කරනවා..",
        "නොර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රී සූසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්ට එරෙහි මතභේද සහ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ ඉහළ පෙළේ විනය කමිටුව කඩිනමින් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන බව කොංග්‍රසයේ මාධ්‍ය අංශය නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "එවැනි කටයුතුවලට මැතිවරණ කොමිසම කිසිවිටෙකත් ඉඩ නොතබන බවත්, එම ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ පක්ෂ සාමාජිකත්වය තාවකාලිකව අහෝසි කර ඇති බවත් මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ මහලේකම් ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් මහතා පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජීවන් ක්‍රියාකාරී තීරණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරුවන්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වුඩ් ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසෙයි ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜீவன் அதிரடி முடிவு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபையின் இ.தொ.கா உறுப்பினர் சூசை அலக்ஸாண்டர் எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்கள் வரிசையாக வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த  வரிசையில் நிற்கும் பொது மகன் ஒருவரை அச்சுறுத்தி, தாக்க செல்லும் வீடியோ சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வைரலாகி வரும் நிலையில், அவர் மீது விசாரணை நடைப்பெறும் எனவும், அதுவரை கட்சியில் இருந்து இடைநிறுத்துவதாகவும் இ.தொ.காவின் பொதுசெயலாளர் ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபையின் உறுப்பினர் சூசை அலக்ஸாண்டர் மீது எழுந்துள்ள சர்ச்சைகள் மற்றும் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் தொடர்பில்,இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸின் உயர்மட்ட ஒழுக்காற்று குழு, வெகுவிரைவில் உரிய விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ளவுள்ளது என்று காங்கிரஸ் ஊடகப் பிரிவு அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதுபோன்ற செயல்களுக்கு இ.தொ.கா ஒருபொழுதும் அனுமதியளிக்காது என்பதோடு குறித்த பிரதேச சபை உறுப்பினரின் சகல கட்சி உறுப்புரிமைகளும் உடன் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் தற்காலிகமாக  நீக்கியதாக இ.தொ.காவின் பொதுச்செயலாளர்  ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜீவன் அதிரடி முடிவு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூசை அலெக்சாண்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர்கள்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோர்வூட் பிராந்திய சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூசை அலெக்சாண்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதேச சபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}