{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/පාකිස්තාන-පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ-කෑමවල-කැරපොත්තෝ/14-617355",
  "time_ut": 1659331379,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාකිස්තාන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කෑමවල කැරපොත්තෝ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cockroaches in Pakistan Parliament's food",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The authorities have taken steps to seal two dining halls of the Pakistani Parliament. That was after receiving complaints from the ministers that there were cockroaches in the food taken from the canteens.",
        "According to Pakistani media reports, after receiving the complaints, Islamabad public health inspectors suddenly broke into the Parliament complex and inspected the canteens, after which they decided to seal the canteens.",
        "After the raid, the public health inspectors told the media that both the sealed canteens were in very dirty conditions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pakistan Parliament's",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamabad",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාකිස්තාන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කෑමවල කැරපොත්තෝ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාකිස්තාන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ භෝජනාගාර දෙකක් සීල් තැබීමට බලධාරීන් පියවර ගෙන තිබේ. ඒ, එම භෝජනාගාරවලින් ලබා ගත් ආහාරවල කැරපොත්තන් සිටිනවා යැයි මැති ඇමැතිවරුන්ගෙන් පැමිණිලි ලැබීමත් සමඟය.",
        "පැමිණිලි ලැබීමත් සමඟ ඉස්ලාමාබාද් මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය පරීක්ෂකවරුන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයට හදිසියේ කඩා පනිමින් භෝජනාගාර පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කළ බවත්, ඉන්පසු ඔවුන් භෝජනාගාර මුද්‍රා තැබීමට තීරණය කළ බවත් පාකිස්තාන මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "සිදු කළ වැටළීමෙන් පසු මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය පරීක්ෂකවරුන් මාධ්‍ය වෙත පවසා ඇත්තේ මුද්‍රා තැබූ එම භෝජනාගාර දෙකම ඉතාමත් අපිරිසුදු තත්ත්වයෙන් පැවැති බවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථාන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමාබාද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தான் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் உணவில் கரப்பான் பூச்சிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாகிஸ்தான் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டு உணவகங்களுக்கு சீல் வைக்க அதிகாரிகள் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர். கேன்டீன்களில் இருந்து எடுக்கப்படும் உணவில் கரப்பான் பூச்சிகள் இருப்பதாக அமைச்சர்களிடம் புகார்கள் வந்ததையடுத்து இது நடந்தது.",
        "பாகிஸ்தான் ஊடக அறிக்கையின்படி, புகார்களைப் பெற்ற இஸ்லாமாபாத் பொது சுகாதார ஆய்வாளர்கள் திடீரென பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து கேன்டீன்களை ஆய்வு செய்தனர், அதன் பிறகு அவர்கள் கேன்டீன்களுக்கு சீல் வைக்க முடிவு செய்தனர்.",
        "சோதனையின் பின்னர், பொது சுகாதார பரிசோதகர்கள் ஊடகங்களுக்குக் கூறியது, சீல் வைக்கப்பட்ட இரண்டு கேன்டீன்களும் மிகவும் அழுக்கான நிலையில் உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் பாராளுமன்றத்தின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமாபாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}