{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කොළඹට-විශාල-ලෙස-හමුදාව-කැඳවයි/11-395388",
  "time_ut": 1657696267,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කොළඹට විශාල ලෙස හමුදාව කැඳවයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The army is called in large numbers to Colombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that the army has been called in large numbers near the Prime Minister's office in Malpara, Colombo. Videos showing how the army is coming to those areas are currently being shared on social media networks.",
        "Apart from this, there is also a video showing how a helicopter belonging to the Air Force is flying above Gallumudoora and the Prime Minister's Office."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Malpara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Videos",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gallumudoora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹට විශාල ලෙස හමුදාව කැඳවයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ මල්පාරේ පිහිටි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය අසළට විශාල ලෙස යුද හමුදාව කැඳවා ඇති බව වාර්තා වෙයි. හමුදාව එම ප්‍ර දේශවලට පැමිණෙන ආකාරය දැක්වෙන වීඩියෝ මේ වන විට සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ජාල තුළ හුවමාරු වෙයි.",
        "මිට අමතරව ගුවන් හමුදාවට අයත් හෙලිකොප්ටර් යානයක් ගාලුමුවදොර හා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය ඉහළින් පියාසර කරන ආකාරය දැක්වෙන වීඩියෝවක්ද පවතී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්පාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීඩියෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ලුමුදුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பிற்கு இராணுவம் பெருமளவில் வரவழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு மல்பாறையில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு அருகில் இராணுவத்தினர் பெருமளவில் வரவழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது. அந்த பகுதிகளுக்கு ராணுவம் எப்படி வருகிறது என்பதை காட்டும் வீடியோக்கள் தற்போது சமூக வலைதளங்களில் பகிரப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "இதுதவிர விமானப்படைக்கு சொந்தமான ஹெலிகாப்டர் கல்லுமுதூரை மற்றும் பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு மேலே எப்படி பறக்கிறது என்பதை காட்டும் வீடியோவும் உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மல்பாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடியோக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்லுமுதூரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}