{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/court-calls-for-report-on-dhaniz-ali-case/",
  "time_ut": 1661759400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Court calls for report on Dhaniz Ali case",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court calls for report on Dhaniz Ali case",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Colombo Chief Magistrate's Court on Monday (29) ordered Sri Lanka Police to provide a progress report on the investigations taking place against Aragalaya Activist Dhaniz Ali and several other suspects for allegedly entering the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation (SLRC) premises in Colombo 7, and interfering with its broadcasting,",
        "Another suspect related to the incident was released on bail on Monday (29).",
        "When the matter was called up, the Cinnamon Gardens Police noted that the investigations are yet to be concluded.",
        "Accordingly, the Cinnamon Gardens Police was ordered to produce the progress report on the 26th of September 2022.",
        "Sri Lanka calls for EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya Activist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Gardens Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Gardens Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 26th of September 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Dhaniz Ali නඩුවේ වාර්තාවක් අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); කොළඹ 7, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථා පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළු වූ බව කියන අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරික ධනීස් අලි ඇතුළු සැකකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට එරෙහිව සිදු කෙරෙන විමර්ශනවල ප්‍රගතිය වාර්තාවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය සඳුදා (29) ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය. එහි විකාශනයට බාධා කිරීම,",
        "සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ තවත් සැකකරුවෙකු සඳුදා (29) ඇප මත මුදා හැරුණා.",
        "අදාළ නඩුව කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේ විමර්ශන අවසන්ව නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 26 වැනි දින ප්‍රගති වාර්තාව ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසියට නියෝග කෙරිණි.",
        "SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව EOI ඉල්ලා සිටී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙක්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කේටරින් සහ බිම් හැසිරවීම සඳහා EOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனிஸ் அலி வழக்கில் அறிக்கை தாக்கல் செய்ய நீதிமன்றம் அழைப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பு 7 இல் உள்ள இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபன (SLRC) வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்ததாக கூறப்படும் அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர் தனிஸ் அலி மற்றும் பல சந்தேக நபர்களுக்கு எதிரான விசாரணைகளின் முன்னேற்ற அறிக்கையை வழங்குமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் திங்கட்கிழமை (29) இலங்கை பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது. அதன் ஒளிபரப்பில் குறுக்கீடு,",
        "சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய மற்றுமொரு சந்தேக நபர் திங்கட்கிழமை (29) பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்ட போது, ​​விசாரணைகள் இன்னும் முடிவடையவில்லை என கறுவாத்தோட்ட பொலிஸார் குறிப்பிட்டனர்.",
        "அதன்படி, 2022 செப்டெம்பர் 26 ஆம் திகதி முன்னேற்ற அறிக்கையை சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு கறுவாத்தோட்டம் பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிடப்பட்டது.",
        "SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling க்கான EOIக்கு இலங்கை அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கறுவாத்தோட்ட காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கறுவாத்தோட்ட காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 26, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங் & கிரவுண்ட் கையாளுதலுக்கான EOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}