{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131970",
  "time_ut": 1658408883,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் - பணி இடைநிறுத்தம் செய்யப்பட்ட பொலிஸ் அதிரடிப் படை எஸ்.எஸ்.பி. மீள சேவைக்கு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Attack on Journalists - Suspended Police Task Force S.S.P. Return to service",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Amidst the protests that started demanding the resignation of the President and the Prime Minister, Sirasa, who went for media activities, Shakti TV. Senior Superintendent of Police Romesh Lienake, who was suspended in connection with the incident in which four journalists were attacked in front of the house of President Ranil Wickremesinghe (who was the Prime Minister at the time of the incident), has been called back to duty. Information from the police headquarters revealed this.",
        "When Ranil Wickremesinghe was the Prime Minister on the 9th, 6 journalists were attacked in front of his house during media activities. Following this, on the orders of the Inspector General of Police, Senior Superintendent of Police Romesh Lienake, who was the commanding officer of the police team that attacked the journalists, was suspended.",
        "However, as Ranil Wickramasinghe was sworn in as the 8th Executive President yesterday, it is learned that a letter has been sent by the Inspector General of Police inviting Senior Police Inspector Romesh Lienake to return to service.",
        "The Colombo Crime Prevention Unit has started investigations into the incident where journalists were attacked. In this regard, the officers of the Colombo Crime Prevention Unit presented the matters through a report to the Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawala on the 12th and received orders for investigations.",
        "Accordingly, Justice Harshana Kekunawala ordered all the media to provide the unedited videos related to the attack to the investigators.",
        "On the night of the 9th, Sirasa TV's video cameraman Varuna Sampath, office reporter Sarasi Peiris, internet journalist Jannitha Mendis Sakthi R.V. went to collect information about the tension near the then Prime Minister's residence. It is noteworthy that 6 people including journalist Sindhujan were attacked by the police on duty there."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Task Force S.S.P. Return",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shakti TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Crime Prevention Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Prevention Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa TV's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Varuna Sampath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarasi Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jannitha Mendis Sakthi R.V.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sindhujan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට ප්‍රහාරයක් - අත්හිටවූ පොලිස් කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ එස්.එස්.පී. සේවාව වෙත ආපසු යන්න",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ අගමැතිට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ආරම්භ වූ විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ මාධ්‍ය කටයුතු සඳහා ගිය සිරස, ශක්ති ටී.වී. ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවස ඉදිරිපිටදී (සිද්ධිය සිදුවන අවස්ථාවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටි) මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සිව් දෙනෙකුට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩ තහනමට ලක්ව සිටි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී රොමේෂ් ලීනකේ මහතා යළි සේවයට කැඳවා තිබේ. . පොලිස් මූලස්ථානයේ තොරතුරුවලින් මේ බව අනාවරණය විය.",
        "පසුගිය 09 වැනිදා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටියදී මාධ්‍ය කටයුතු අතරතුර ඔහුගේ නිවස ඉදිරිපිටදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් 6 දෙනෙකුට පහර දුන්නා. ඉන් අනතුරුව පොලිස්පතිවරයාගේ නියෝග මත මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදුන් පොලිස් කණ්ඩායමේ අණදෙන නිලධාරියා වූ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී රොමේෂ් ලියෙනකේගේ වැඩ තහනම් කෙරුණා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ දිවුරුම් දුන් බැවින් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක රොමේෂ් ලියෙනකේ මහතාට නැවත සේවයට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ආරාධනා කරමින් පොලිස්පතිවරයා ලිපියක් යවා ඇති බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ ඒකකය පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ කර තිබෙනවා. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ ඒකකයේ නිලධාරීන් පසුගිය 12 වැනිදා කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත‍්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල මහතා වෙත වාර්තාවක් මගින් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කර විමර්ශන සඳහා නියෝග ලබා ගත්තා.",
        "ඒ අනුව ප්‍රහාරයට අදාළ සංස්කරණය නොකළ වීඩියෝ දර්ශන විමර්ශන නිලධාරීන්ට ලබාදෙන ලෙස විනිසුරු හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල මහතා සියලු මාධ්‍යවලට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය 09 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ සිරස රූපවාහිනියේ වීඩියෝ කැමරා ශිල්පි වරුණ සම්පත්, කාර්යාල වාර්තාකාරිනී සරසි පීරිස්, අන්තර්ජාල මාධ්‍යවේදිනියක් වන ජන්නිත මෙන්ඩිස් ශක්ති ආර්.වී. ඇතුළු පිරිසක් එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ නිවස අසල ඇති වූ උණුසුම්කාරී තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු රැස් කිරීමට ගියහ. මාධ්‍යවේදී සින්ධුජන් ඇතුලූ 6 දෙනෙකුට එහි රාජකාරියේ නිරතව සිටි පොලීසිය විසින් පහරදීම විශේෂත්වයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ එස්.එස්.පී. ආපසු",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්ති ටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ නිවාරණ ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ මර්දන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස ටීවී එකේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරුණ සම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරසි පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන්නිත මෙන්ඩිස් ශක්ති ආර්.වී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සින්ධුජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் - பணி இடைநிறுத்தம் செய்யப்பட்ட பொலிஸ் அதிரடிப் படை எஸ்.எஸ்.பி. மீள சேவைக்கு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை பதவி விலக வலியுறுத்தி ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட போராட்டத்தின் இடையே, ஊடக நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக சென்ற சிரச, சக்தி டீ.வி. ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் நால்வர், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின்  (சம்பவம் நடக்கும் போது பிரதமராக இருந்தார்) வீட்டின்  முன்பாக  வைத்து தாக்கப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில்  பணி இடை நிறுத்தம் செய்யப்பட்டிருந்த பொலிஸ் விஷேட அதிரடிப் படையின் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சர் ரொமேஷ் லியனகே மீள சேவைக்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். பொலிஸ் தலைமையகத்தின் தகவல்கள் இதனை வெளிப்படுத்தின.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பிரதமராக இருந்த போது கடந்த 9 ஆம் திகதி ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் 6 பேர் அவரது வீட்டின் முன்பாக ஊடக நடவடிக்கைகளிடையே தாக்கப்பட்டிருந்தனர். இதனையடுத்து  பொலிஸ் மா அதிபரின் உத்தரவின் பேரில், ஊடகவியலாளர்களை தாக்கிய பொலிஸ் குழுவின் கட்டளை அதிகாரியாக செயற்பட்ட சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சர் ரொமேஷ் லியனகே பணி இடைநிறுத்தம் செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் நேற்று ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க 8 ஆவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற நிலையில், சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சர் ரொமேஷ் லியனகேயை மீள சேவைக்கு  அழைப்பதற்கான கடிதம் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபரால் அனுப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அறிய முடிகிறது.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள்  தாக்கப்பட்ட  சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது. இது தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள்  கடந்த 12 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதிவான் ஹர்ஷன கெக்குனவலவிடம் அறிக்கை ஊடாக விடயங்களை முன் வைத்த நிலையில்,  விசாரணைகளுக்கான உத்தரவுகளையும் பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "அதன்படி குறித்த தாக்குதல் தொடர்பிலான  செம்மைப்படுத்தப்படாத காணொளிகளை விசாரணையாளர்களுக்கு வழங்குமாறு நீதிவான் ஹர்ஷன கெக்குனவல அனைத்து ஊடகங்களுக்கும் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 9 ஆம் திகதி இரவு வேளையில்,  அப்போதைய பிரதமரின் இல்லத்தை அண்மித்த பதற்ற நிலை தொடர்பில் தகவல் சேகரிக்க சென்ற சிரச தொலைக்காட்சியின் வீடியோ படப் பிடிப்பாளர் வருன சம்பத், அலுவலக செய்தியாளர் சரசி பீரிஸ், இணைய ஊடகவியலாளர்  ஜன்னித்த மெண்டிஸ் சக்தி ரி.வி.  ஊடகவியலாளர் சிந்துஜன்  உள்ளிட்ட 6 பேர்  அங்கு கடமையில் இருந்த பொலிஸாரால் தாக்கப்பட்டிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அதிரடிப்படை எஸ்.எஸ்.பி. திரும்பு",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வருணா சம்பத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரசி பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன்னிதா மெண்டிஸ் சக்தி ஆர்.வி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்துஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}