{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/30/video-diesel-should-be-supplied-to-people-in-all-parts-of-sri-lanka-army-intervenes-to-clear-protest/",
  "time_ut": 1656593100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "(Video) ‘Diesel should be supplied to people in all parts of Sri Lanka’ – Army intervenes to clear protest",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "(Video) ‘Diesel should be supplied to people in all parts of Sri Lanka’ – Army intervenes to clear protest",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Army Personnel intervened to disperse a protest that took place in Kanthale on Wednesday (29) evening, when people in fuel queues blocked two Colombo-bound Fuel Tankers from passing through the area.",
        "A Sri Lanka Army Officer demanded the protestors move noting that the Kanthale Filling Station received daily fuel deliveries, and it was unfair for them to protest when there is a delay of one day.",
        "“Diesel should be supplied to people in all parts of Sri Lanka, and not just for those in Kantale. We have sold enough fuel for people in Kantale. Will the problem be solved by blocking the road? Don’t be selfish. My family members have been in queues for three days. There is no fuel even in Colombo. Kantale receives the most amount of fuel,” he told the protestors.",
        "The Kanthale Police intervened to solve the matter, the protest by the locals was called off on the promise by the Kanthale OIC to deliver fuel.",
        "(Video) ‘Diesel should be supplied to people in all parts of Sri Lanka’ – Army intervenes to clear protest",
        "Six people sentenced to death 22 years after five people were shot dead in 2000"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Army Personnel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanthale",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fuel Tankers",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kanthale Filling Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantale",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kanthale OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "(වීඩියෝ) ‘ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෑම ප්‍රදේශයකම ජනතාවට ඩීසල් සැපයිය යුතුයි’ – විරෝධතාව ඉවත් කිරීමට හමුදාව මැදිහත් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බදාදා (29) සවස කන්තලේ නගරයේ පැවති විරෝධතාවක් විසුරුවා හැරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදා නිලධාරීන් මැදිහත් වූ අතර, ඉන්ධන පෝලිම්වල සිටි ජනතාව එම ප්‍රදේශය හරහා ගමන් කිරීමට නොහැකි වූ ඉන්ධන ටැංකි දෙකක් අවහිර කළහ.",
        "කන්තලේ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලට දෛනිකව ඉන්ධන ලැබෙන බවත් එක් දිනක් ප්‍රමාද වූ විට විරෝධතා දැක්වීම අසාධාරණ බවත් සඳහන් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදා නිලධාරියෙක් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“කන්තලේ අයට පමණක් නොව ලංකාවේ සෑම ප්‍රදේශයකම ජනතාවට ඩීසල් සැපයිය යුතුයි. අපි කන්තලේ ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය තරම් තෙල් විකුණා තිබෙනවා. පාර අවහිර කරලා ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳෙයිද? ආත්මාර්ථකාමී නොවන්න. මගේ පවුලේ අය දවස් තුනක් පෝලිම්වල ඉන්නවා. කොළඹත් තෙල් නැහැ. වැඩිම තෙල් ප්‍රමාණයක් ලැබෙන්නේ කන්තලේට” ඔහු විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "කන්තලේ පොලිසිය මැදිහත් වී ගැටලුව සමථයකට පත් කළ අතර, කන්තලේ පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන බවට දුන් පොරොන්දුව මත ප්‍රදේශවාසීන්ගේ විරෝධතාව අත්හිටුවන ලදී.",
        "(වීඩියෝ) ‘ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෑම ප්‍රදේශයකම ජනතාවට ඩීසල් සැපයිය යුතුයි’ – විරෝධතාව ඉවත් කිරීමට හමුදාව මැදිහත් වෙයි",
        "2000 වසරේදී පුද්ගලයන් පස් දෙනෙකු වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර වසර 22කට පසු හය දෙනෙකුට මරණ දණ්ඩනය නියම විය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදා සාමාජිකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන ටැංකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ පිරවුම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ ඕ.අයි.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 22 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "(வீடியோ) ‘இலங்கையின் அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளிலும் உள்ள மக்களுக்கு டீசல் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்’ – இராணுவம் தலையிட்டு ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை அகற்ற",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புதன்கிழமை (29) மாலை கந்தளேயில் இடம்பெற்ற போராட்டத்தை கலைக்க சிறிலங்கா இராணுவத்தினர் தலையிட்டனர், எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் நின்றவர்கள் கொழும்பு நோக்கிச் சென்ற இரண்டு எரிபொருள் தாங்கிகளை அந்தப் பகுதியினூடாகச் செல்லவிடாமல் தடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கந்தளே எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு நாளாந்த எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்யப்படுவதாகவும், ஒரு நாள் தாமதம் ஏற்படும் போது ஆர்ப்பாட்டம் செய்வது நியாயமற்றது எனவும் இலங்கை இராணுவ அதிகாரி ஒருவர் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "“கந்தளேயில் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு மட்டுமல்ல, இலங்கையின் அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளிலும் உள்ள மக்களுக்கு டீசல் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும். கந்தளே மக்களுக்கு தேவையான எரிபொருளை விற்பனை செய்துள்ளோம். சாலை மறியலால் பிரச்னை தீர்ந்துவிடுமா? சுயநலமாக இருக்காதீர்கள். எனது குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் மூன்று நாட்களாக வரிசையில் நிற்கின்றனர். கொழும்பில் கூட எரிபொருள் இல்லை. கந்தளே அதிக அளவு எரிபொருளைப் பெறுகிறது” என்று அவர் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "கந்தளாய் பொலிசார் தலையிட்டு பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு காண, கந்தளாய் பொலிஸ் நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரி எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்வதாக உறுதியளித்ததன் பேரில் பிரதேச மக்களின் போராட்டம் கைவிடப்பட்டது.",
        "(வீடியோ) ‘இலங்கையின் அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளிலும் உள்ள மக்களுக்கு டீசல் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்’ – இராணுவம் தலையிட்டு ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தை அகற்ற",
        "2000 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஐந்து பேர் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்ட பின்னர் 22 ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு ஆறு பேருக்கு மரண தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவப் பணியாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தலே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் டேங்கர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கந்தளாய் OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}