{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Exterminators-holds-first-AGM/34-739428",
  "time_ut": 1662143322,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Exterminators holds first AGM",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Exterminators holds first AGM",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "From left: Managing Director Marlon Ferreira, Chairman Chaaminda Ratnayake, and Executive Director Travis Ferreira",
        "Plans to increase the capital by Rs. 17.4 m to Rs. 100 m by way of a capitalisation of reserves",
        "Capitalisation offers one share for every 17.52 shares and is subject to CSE approval",
        "Exterminators PLC, Sri Lanka’s premier pest management and environmental technology company, held its first Annual General Meeting upon listing on the Colombo Stock Exchange on 30 March.",
        "Exterminators PLC shareholders approved all proposals at the hybrid AGM held on 30 August; this included re-electing Dr. Nihal Attygalle and Suhaniya Ferreira as non-executive non independent directors and Travis Ferreira as ‘Executive Director’. The annual review and the financial statements were approved, as were the proposed final dividend of Rs. 0.07 per share for the financial year 2021/22. The payment date would be 30 September 2022. Overall dividend payout for the financial year 21/22 is 30% value Rs. 8.02 million. The dividend represented an increase of 89% over the previous year’s dividend payout. The company plans to capitalise Rs. 17.4 million to increase its stated capital to Rs. 100 million in the proportion of 1 per 17.52 shares will be issued upon CSE approval.",
        "“We carved a unique niche within the industry as an environmental management company which extends its services beyond the realms of pest control. As a growth oriented business we hope to explore market development strategies by venturing across borders with global expansion,” Exterminators PLC Chairman Chaaminda Ratnayake stated.",
        "“Way back in 1998, we embarked on our journey to build a brand to determine our own destiny with an initial investment of Rs. 75,000. Today we are recognised as a leader in innovation, technology, sustainability and governance in Sri Lanka and the emerging world. Smart Missile ‘The world’s 1stcarbon neutral termite station’ was exported to Seychelles and ‘Smart Guard’ termiticide replenishment system was installed at Velana International Airport, Maldives. These products were designed, developed and manufactured by Exterminators. Exterminators PLC is a participant of the ‘United Nations Global Compact’ the world’s largest corporate sustainability initiative.",
        "“We are planning to move across borders throughout emerging and developing markets to colonise our proven and recognised business model to help communities to enhance living standards in South Asia, Southeast Asia, Central Asia, Middle East, Africa and pacific island nations via direct investment, joint ventures, and international franchising. Our success story thus far epitomises an entrepreneurial mindset and a strong conviction which has been guided by strong values,” Founder/Managing Director Marlon Ferreira stated."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AGM",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Marlon Ferreira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaaminda Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Travis Ferreira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 March",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nihal Attygalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Travis Ferreira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the financial year 2021/22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 September 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the financial year 21/22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.02 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous year’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "pest",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaaminda Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Smart Missile ‘The",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velana International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘United Nations Global Compact’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "pacific island",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marlon Ferreira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Exterminators පළමු AGM පවත්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වමේ සිට: කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ මාලන් ෆෙරේරා, සභාපති චමින්ද රත්නායක සහ විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ ට්‍රැවිස් ෆෙරේරා",
        "ප්‍රාග්ධනය රු. මීටර් 17.4 සිට රු. සංචිත ප්රාග්ධනීකරණයක් මාර්ගයෙන් 100 m",
        "ප්‍රාග්ධනීකරණය සෑම කොටස් 17.52ක් සඳහාම එක් කොටසක් පිරිනමන අතර CSE අනුමැතියට යටත් වේ",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සහ පාරිසරික තාක්‍ෂණ සමාගම වන Exterminators PLC, මාර්තු 30 වැනි දින කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළේ ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීමෙන් පසු සිය පළමු වාර්ෂික මහා සභා රැස්වීම පැවැත්වීය.",
        "Exterminators PLC කොටස් හිමියන් විසින් අගෝස්තු 30 දින පැවති දෙමුහුන් AGM හි සියලුම යෝජනා අනුමත කරන ලදී. ආචාර්ය නිහාල් ආටිගල සහ සුහානියා ෆෙරේරා විධායක නොවන ස්වාධීන අධ්‍යක්ෂවරුන් ලෙසත් ට්‍රැවිස් ෆෙරේරා ‘විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ’ ලෙසත් නැවත තේරී පත්වීම මෙයට ඇතුළත් විය. යෝජිත අවසාන ලාභාංශය වන රු. 2021/22 මූල්‍ය වර්ෂය සඳහා කොටසකට 0.07. ගෙවීමේ දිනය 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 30 වේ. 21/22 මූල්‍ය වර්ෂය සඳහා සමස්ත ලාභාංශ ගෙවීම 30% වටිනාකම රු. මිලියන 8.02 කි. ලාභාංශය පෙර වසරේ ලාභාංශ ගෙවීමට වඩා 89% ක වැඩිවීමක් නියෝජනය කරයි. සමාගම විසින් රු. මිලියන 17.4ක් එහි ප්‍රකාශිත ප්‍රාග්ධනය රු. කොටස් 17.52කට 1 බැගින් වූ අනුපාතයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 100ක් CSE අනුමැතිය මත නිකුත් කෙරේ.",
        "“පළිබෝධ පාලන ක්ෂේත්‍රවලින් ඔබ්බට සිය සේවාවන් පුළුල් කරන පාරිසරික කළමනාකරණ සමාගමක් ලෙස අපි කර්මාන්තය තුළ අද්විතීය ස්ථානයක් කැටයම් කළෙමු. වර්ධනය ඉලක්ක කරගත් ව්‍යාපාරයක් ලෙස ගෝලීය ව්‍යාප්තියත් සමඟ දේශසීමා හරහා ගමන් කරමින් වෙළඳපල සංවර්ධන උපාය මාර්ග ගවේෂණය කිරීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,” Exterminators PLC හි සභාපති චමින්ද රත්නායක මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“ආපසු 1998 දී, අපි රු. 75,000 කි. අද අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ නැගී එන ලෝකයේ නවෝත්පාදන, තාක්‍ෂණය, තිරසාරභාවය සහ පාලනයේ ප්‍රමුඛයා ලෙස පිළිගැනේ. ස්මාර්ට් මිසයිලය ‘ලෝකයේ පළමු කාබන් උදාසීන ටර්මයිට් ස්ටේෂන්’ සීෂෙල්ස් වෙත අපනයනය කරන ලද අතර ‘ස්මාර්ට් ගාඩ්’ ටර්මිටිසයිඩ් නැවත පිරවීමේ පද්ධතිය මාලදිවයිනේ වේලානා ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළේ ස්ථාපිත කරන ලදී. මෙම නිෂ්පාදන සැලසුම් කර, සංවර්ධනය කර නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලද්දේ Exterminators විසිනි. එක්ස්ටර්මිනේටර්ස් පීඑල්සී යනු ලොව විශාලතම ආයතනික තිරසාර මුලපිරීම වන ‘එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ගෝලීය සම්මුතියට’ සහභාගිවන්නකි.",
        "දකුණු ආසියාවේ, අග්නිදිග ආසියාවේ, මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ, මැදපෙරදිග, අප්‍රිකාවේ සහ පැසිෆික් දූපත් රටවල ජීවන තත්ත්වය ඉහළ නැංවීමට ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා අපගේ ඔප්පු කරන ලද සහ පිළිගත් ව්‍යාපාර ආකෘතිය යටත් විජිතයක් බවට පත් කිරීම සඳහා නැගී එන සහ සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින වෙළඳපල හරහා දේශසීමා හරහා ගමන් කිරීමට අපි සැලසුම් කරමු. හවුල් ව්‍යාපාර සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර බලය පැවරීම. අපගේ සාර්ථක කතාව මේ දක්වා ව්‍යවසායකත්ව මානසිකත්වය සහ ශක්තිමත් සාරධර්ම මගින් මෙහෙයවන ලද ශක්තිමත් විශ්වාසයක් විදහා දක්වයි,” නිර්මාතෘ/කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ මාලන් ෆෙරේරා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AGM",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලන් ෆෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාමින්ද රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රැවිස් ෆෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.52 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් ආටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රැවිස් ෆෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021/22 මුදල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් වර්ෂය 21/22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8.02 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 100 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.52 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළිබෝධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාමින්ද රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්මාර්ට් මිසයිලය 'ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේලාන ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාශ කරන්නන්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "'එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ගෝලීය ගිවිසුම'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිකොනදිග ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් දූපත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලන් ෆෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Exterminators முதல் AGM ஐ நடத்துகிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இடமிருந்து: முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் மார்லன் ஃபெரீரா, தலைவர் சமிந்த ரத்நாயக்க மற்றும் நிறைவேற்றுப் பணிப்பாளர் ட்ரவிஸ் ஃபெரீரா",
        "மூலதனத்தை ரூ.1000 உயர்த்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. 17.4 மீ முதல் ரூ. இருப்புக்களின் மூலதனமாக்கலின் மூலம் 100 மீ",
        "மூலதனமாக்கல் ஒவ்வொரு 17.52 பங்குகளுக்கும் ஒரு பங்கை வழங்குகிறது மற்றும் CSE ஒப்புதலுக்கு உட்பட்டது",
        "இலங்கையின் முதன்மையான பூச்சி மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனமான Exterminators PLC, கொழும்பு பங்குச்சந்தையில் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் தனது முதலாவது வருடாந்த பொதுக் கூட்டத்தை மார்ச் 30 அன்று நடத்தியது.",
        "எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் பிஎல்சி பங்குதாரர்கள் ஆகஸ்ட் 30 அன்று நடைபெற்ற ஹைப்ரிட் ஏஜிஎம்மில் அனைத்து திட்டங்களுக்கும் ஒப்புதல் அளித்தனர்; இதில் டாக்டர். நிஹால் ஆட்டிகல மற்றும் சுஹானியா ஃபெரீரா ஆகியோர் நிறைவேற்று அல்லாத சுயாதீன இயக்குநர்களாகவும், டிராவிஸ் ஃபெரீராவை ‘நிர்வாக இயக்குனராக’வும் மீண்டும் தெரிவு செய்தனர். வருடாந்திர மதிப்பாய்வு மற்றும் நிதிநிலை அறிக்கைகள் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டன, முன்மொழியப்பட்ட இறுதி ஈவுத்தொகை ரூ. 2021/22 நிதியாண்டில் ஒரு பங்கிற்கு 0.07. கட்டணம் செலுத்தும் தேதி செப்டம்பர் 30, 2022. 21/22 நிதியாண்டிற்கான மொத்த டிவிடெண்ட் பேஅவுட் 30% மதிப்பு ரூ. 8.02 மில்லியன். ஈவுத்தொகை முந்தைய ஆண்டின் ஈவுத்தொகையை விட 89% அதிகரித்துள்ளது. நிறுவனம் ரூ. 17.4 மில்லியன் அதன் கூறப்பட்ட மூலதனத்தை ரூ. 17.52 பங்குகளுக்கு 1 என்ற விகிதத்தில் 100 மில்லியன் CSE ஒப்புதலின் பேரில் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "\"சுற்றுச்சூழல் மேலாண்மை நிறுவனமாக தொழில்துறையில் ஒரு தனித்துவமான இடத்தை நாங்கள் செதுக்கினோம், இது பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு பகுதிகளுக்கு அப்பால் அதன் சேவைகளை விரிவுபடுத்துகிறது. ஒரு வளர்ச்சி சார்ந்த வணிகமாக, உலகளாவிய விரிவாக்கத்துடன் எல்லைகளைத் தாண்டிச் செல்வதன் மூலம் சந்தை மேம்பாட்டு உத்திகளை ஆராய்வோம் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்,” என்று எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் பிஎல்சி தலைவர் சமிந்த ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"1998 ஆம் ஆண்டு, ரூ. ஆரம்ப முதலீட்டில் எங்கள் சொந்த விதியை நிர்ணயிக்கும் ஒரு பிராண்டை உருவாக்குவதற்கான பயணத்தை நாங்கள் தொடங்கினோம். 75,000. இன்று நாம் இலங்கையிலும் வளர்ந்து வரும் உலகிலும் புத்தாக்கம், தொழில்நுட்பம், நிலைத்தன்மை மற்றும் ஆளுகை ஆகியவற்றில் முன்னணியில் உள்ளவர்களாக அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளோம். ஸ்மார்ட் ஏவுகணை ‘உலகின் 1வது கார்பன் நியூட்ரல் டெர்மைட் நிலையம்’ சீஷெல்ஸுக்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட்டது மற்றும் மாலத்தீவின் வேலனா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் ‘ஸ்மார்ட் கார்டு’ டெர்மிடைட்ஸை நிரப்பும் அமைப்பு நிறுவப்பட்டது. இந்த தயாரிப்புகள் எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்களால் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டு, உருவாக்கப்பட்டு, தயாரிக்கப்பட்டன. எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் பிஎல்சி என்பது உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய கார்ப்பரேட் நிலைத்தன்மை முயற்சியான ‘ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் குளோபல் காம்பாக்ட்’ இன் பங்கேற்பாளர்.",
        "தெற்காசியா, தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா, மத்திய ஆசியா, மத்திய கிழக்கு, ஆபிரிக்கா மற்றும் பசிபிக் தீவு நாடுகளில் நேரடி முதலீட்டின் மூலம் வாழ்க்கைத் தரத்தை மேம்படுத்த சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்காக, எங்கள் நிரூபிக்கப்பட்ட மற்றும் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட வணிக மாதிரியை காலனித்துவப்படுத்த, வளர்ந்து வரும் மற்றும் வளரும் சந்தைகள் முழுவதும் எல்லைகளைக் கடந்து செல்ல நாங்கள் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளோம். கூட்டு முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச உரிமம். எங்கள் வெற்றிக் கதை இதுவரை ஒரு தொழில்முனைவோர் மனநிலையையும் வலுவான மதிப்புகளால் வழிநடத்தப்பட்ட வலுவான நம்பிக்கையையும் எடுத்துக்காட்டுகிறது, ”என்று நிறுவனர் / நிர்வாக இயக்குனர் மார்லன் ஃபெரீரா கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஏஜிஎம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்லன் ஃபெரீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிராவிஸ் ஃபெரீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் ஆட்டிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிராவிஸ் ஃபெரீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021/22 நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 செப்டம்பர் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதியாண்டு 21/22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.02 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்மார்ட் ஏவுகணை ‘தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலனா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அழிப்பவர்கள்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "'ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் உலகளாவிய ஒப்பந்தம்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைய ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்லன் ஃபெரீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}