{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/07/strong-winds-expected-tonight-7/",
  "time_ut": 1657195380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Strong winds expected tonight (7)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Strong winds expected tonight (7)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Department of Meteorology announced that several spells of showers will occur in Sabaragamuwa province and Nuwara-Eliya and Kandy districts.",
        "A few showers may occur in the Western province and Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Strong winds of about (40-50) kmph can be expected at times in the western slopes of the Central hills and the Southern province.",
        "Court rejects police request on protests planned for 8th & 9th July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tonight",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara-Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8th & 9th July",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින් සඳහා පමණක් ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය කල් දමයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සබරගමුව පළාතේ සහ නුවරඑළිය සහ මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතේ සහ ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල වැසි ස්වල්පයක් ඇති විය හැක.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල සහ දකුණු පළාතේ විටින් විට හමන පැ.කි.මී. (40-50) පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක.",
        "ජූලි 8 සහ 9 යන දිනවල පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති විරෝධතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීම අධිකරණය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද රෑ",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 8 සහ 9",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று இரவு பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும் (7)",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் நுவரெலியா மற்றும் கண்டி மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மாகாணத்திலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சிறிதளவு மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாடு மற்றும் தென் மாகாணத்தின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளில் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு (40-50) கிலோமீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "ஜூலை 8 மற்றும் 9 ஆம் தேதிகளில் நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்ட போராட்டங்கள் குறித்த காவல்துறையின் கோரிக்கையை நீதிமன்றம் நிராகரித்தது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்றிரவு",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 8 & 9",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}