{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83315/one-country-one-law-task-force-hands-over-report-to-president",
  "time_ut": 1656483000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘One Country, One Law’ Task Force hands over report to President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘One Country, One Law’ Task Force hands over report to President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Presidential Task Force appointed to prepare proposals on the ‘One Country, One Law’ concept has handed over its report to President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the President’s Media Division (PMD) says.",
        "A 13-member task force, chaired by Ven. Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thero, was appointed on October 26, 2021, to study the implementation of the concept ‘One Country, One Law’ and to prepare a draft Act.",
        "However, two of its members, Prof. Dayananda Banda and Lecturer Mohamed Inthikab later stepped down from the panel and three new members, namely Ramalingam Chakrawarthy Karunakaran, Yogeswari Patgunarajah and Iyyampillai Dayanandaraja were later appointed to the task force,",
        "The task force now consists of 14 members in total, including Prof. Shanthinandana Wijesinghe, Prof. Sumedha Siriwardana, N.G. Sujeewa Panditharathna, Attorney-at-Law Iresh Senevirathne, Attorney-at-Law Sanjaya Marambe, Eranda Navarathna, Pani Wewala,, Moulavi Mohamed of Ulama Council in Galle, Kaleel Rahuman and Azeez Nizardeen."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Presidential Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayananda Banda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Inthikab",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramalingam Chakrawarthy Karunakaran",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yogeswari Patgunarajah and",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanthinandana Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumedha Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.G. Sujeewa Panditharathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranda Navarathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pani Wewala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moulavi Mohamed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaleel Rahuman",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azeez Nizardeen",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘එකම රටක් එකම නීතියක්’ කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ වාර්තාව ජනපතිට භාර දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘එකම රටක්, එකම නීතියක්’ සංකල්පයට අදාළ යෝජනා සකස් කිරීම සඳහා පත් කළ ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය සිය වාර්තාව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත භාර දුන් බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය (PMD) පවසයි.",
        "පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් 13 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කාර්ය සාධක බලකායක්. ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඥානසාර හිමියන් පත් කරනු ලැබුවේ 2021 ඔක්තෝම්බර් 26 වැනිදා ‘එකම රටක් එකම නීතියක්’ සංකල්පය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අධ්‍යයනය කර පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් සකස් කිරීම සඳහාය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එහි සාමාජිකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු වන මහාචාර්ය දයානන්ද බණ්ඩා සහ කථිකාචාර්ය මොහොමඩ් ඉන්තිකාබ් පසුව මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉවත් වූ අතර නව සාමාජිකයින් තිදෙනෙකු වන රාමලිංගම් චක්‍රවර්ති කරුණාකරන්, යෝගේශ්වරී පට්ගුණරාජා සහ අයියම්පිල්ලෙයි දයානන්දරාජා පසුව කාර්ය සාධක බලකායට පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය දැන් සාමාජිකයින් 14 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත වන අතර, මහාචාර්ය ශාන්තිනන්දන විජේසිංහ, මහාචාර්ය සුමේධා සිරිවර්ධන, එන්.ජී. සුජීව පණ්ඩිතරත්න, නීතීඥ ඉරේෂ් සෙනෙවිරත්න, නීතිඥ සංජය මාරඹේ, එරන්ද නවරත්න, පැනි වෑවල, ගාල්ල උලමා සභාවේ මවුලවි මොහොමඩ්, කලීල් රහුමාන් සහ අසීස් නිසාර්දීන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඥානසාර හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ඔක්තෝබර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයානන්ද බණ්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් ඉන්තිකාබ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමලිංගම් චක්‍රවර්ති කරුණාකරන්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෝගේස්වරී පත්ගුණරාජා සහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්තිනන්දන විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේධා සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.ජී. සුජීව පණ්ඩිතරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරන්ද නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැනි වෑවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මවුලවි මොහොමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලීල් රහුමාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azeez Nizardeen",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ செயலணி ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அறிக்கையை கையளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ யோசனைத் திட்டத்தை தயாரிப்பதற்காக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி செயலணி தனது அறிக்கையை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் கையளித்துள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "13 பேர் கொண்ட பணிக்குழு, தலைவர் வண. கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர், 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஒக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் திகதி, ‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ என்ற கருத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவது குறித்து ஆராய்வதற்கும் சட்ட வரைவை தயாரிப்பதற்கும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அதன் உறுப்பினர்களான பேராசிரியர் தயானந்த பண்டா மற்றும் விரிவுரையாளர் மொஹமட் இந்திகாப் ஆகியோர் பின்னர் குழுவிலிருந்து விலகினர் மற்றும் மூன்று புதிய உறுப்பினர்களான ராமலிங்கம் சக்கரவர்த்தி கருணாகரன், யோகேஸ்வரி பத்குணராஜா மற்றும் ஐயம்பிள்ளை தயானந்தராஜா ஆகியோர் பின்னர் பணிக்குழுவிற்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இப்பணிக்குழுவில் பேராசிரியர் சாந்திநந்தன விஜேசிங்க, பேராசிரியர் சுமேதா சிறிவர்தன, என்.ஜி. உட்பட மொத்தம் 14 பேர் உள்ளனர். சுஜீவ பண்டிதரத்ன, சட்டத்தரணி இரேஷ் செனவிரத்ன, சட்டத்தரணி சஞ்சய மரம்பே, எரந்த நவரத்ன, பாணி வெவல, காலி உலமா சபையின் மௌலவி மொஹமட், கலீல் ரகுமான் மற்றும் அஸீஸ் நிசார்தீன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 26, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயானந்த பண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது இந்திகாப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராமலிங்கம் சக்கரவர்த்தி கருணாகரன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோகேஸ்வரி பட்குணராஜா மற்றும்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாந்திநந்தன விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேதா சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.ஜி. சுஜீவ பண்டிதரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரந்த நவரத்தினம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணி வெவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மௌலவி மொஹமட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலீல் ரகுமான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜீஸ் நிசார்தீன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}