{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83689/sjb-reaffirms-sajiths-candidature-for-presidency",
  "time_ut": 1657975860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB reaffirms Sajith’s candidature for presidency",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB reaffirms Sajith’s candidature for presidency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The parliamentarians of the main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) and Samagi Jana Sandhanaya met today (July 16), under the leadership of Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa for a further discussion on the vacant position of the President.",
        "The SJB leader had earlier announced that he also plans to join the race for the presidency. His candidature was unanimously adopted by the parliamentary groups of the two parties.",
        "Accordingly, the adoption of the candidacy of the opposition leader was reaffirmed at today’s meeting.",
        "Several more rounds of discussions are scheduled to be held within the day with other political parties representing the opposition."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Sandhanaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB සජිත්ගේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය යළි තහවුරු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධුරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ සහ සමගි ජන සන්ධානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද (ජුලි 16) රැස්විය.",
        "SJB නායකයා මීට පෙර නිවේදනය කර තිබුණේ තමන්ද ජනාධිපතිවරණ තරඟයට එක්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවයි. ඔහුගේ අපේක්ෂකත්වය පක්ෂ දෙකේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම් විසින් ඒකමතිකව සම්මත කරන ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගේ අපේක්ෂකත්වය අද පැවති රැස්වීමේදී යළිත් තහවුරු කෙරුණා.",
        "විපක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරන අනෙකුත් දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමඟ තවත් සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් අද දිනයේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන සන්ධානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான சஜித்தின் வேட்புமனுவை SJB மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் வெற்றிடத்திற்கான மேலதிக கலந்துரையாடலுக்காக பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) மற்றும் சமகி ஜன சந்தானயவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்று (ஜூலை 16) எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தலைமையில் கூடியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான போட்டியில் தானும் இணைய உள்ளதாக SJB தலைவர் முன்னதாக அறிவித்திருந்தார். அவரது வேட்புமனுவை இரு கட்சிகளின் நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக்கள் ஏகமனதாக ஏற்றுக்கொண்டன.",
        "அதன்படி, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் வேட்புமனுவை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வது இன்றைய கூட்டத்தில் மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் ஏனைய அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடன் இன்னும் பல சுற்று கலந்துரையாடல்கள் நாளைய தினத்திற்குள் நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன சந்தனாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}