{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132602",
  "time_ut": 1659253820,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பொதுஜனபெரமுனவின் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத தேசிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது குறித்து ஆராய தயார் - சுமந்திரன்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sumanthran ready to explore support for non-PDP-dominated national government",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil National Alliance member of parliament Sumanthran said that if the government makes honest efforts to form a government of national parties that are not dominated by the PDP, the TNA will consider supporting such efforts.",
        "The Tamil National Federation has expressed its willingness to join an all-party government if the government makes sincere efforts to form a government of national parties that is not dominated by the Popular People's Party, the Tamil National Federation will consider supporting such efforts, the Sunday Times reported that Tamil National Federation Member of Parliament Sumanthran said.",
        "Sumanthran said that we are opposing the current government because it will become another government led by Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, which has lost its political mandate.",
        "Sumanthran mentioned that the people have rejected the Sri Lanka People's Party, and because of this, the President and the Prime Minister, who were elected by the party, have resigned from their positions.",
        "He further stated that an all-party government should be formed that includes the other opposition parties in the Parliament, he further stated that any attempt to form a national government should not be led by Sri Lanka Budujana Peramuna and we are following the position that that party should not dominate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sumanthran",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "non-PDP",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumanthran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Tamil National Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Popular People's Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumanthran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "People's Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Budujana Peramuna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "PDP-ආධිපත්‍ය නොවන ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවට සහය සෙවීමට සුමන්ත‍්‍රන් සූදානම්",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සුමන්ත‍්‍රන් පැවසුවේ පීඩීපී ආධිපත්‍යය නොමැති ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට රජය අවංක උත්සාහයක් දරන්නේ නම් එවැනි උත්සාහයන්ට සහාය දැක්වීම පිළිබඳව දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය සලකා බලන බවයි.",
        "ජනප්‍රිය ජනතා පක්‍ෂයේ ආධිපත්‍යය නොලබන ජාතික පක්‍ෂවල රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට රජය අවංක උත්සාහයක් දරන්නේ නම් සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයකට එක්වීමට දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය කැමැත්ත පළ කර ඇති අතර එම උත්සාහයන්ට සහාය දැක්වීමට දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය සලකා බලන බව ඉරිදා දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සුමන්ත‍්‍රන් පැවසූ බව ටයිම්ස් වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුවට අප විරුද්ධ වන්නේ දේශපාලන වරම අහිමි වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ තවත් ආණ්ඩුවක් බවට පත්වන නිසා බව සුමන්ත‍්‍රන් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පක්ෂය ජනතාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති බවත්, මේ හේතුවෙන් එම පක්ෂයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සිය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇති බවත් සුමන්ත්‍රන් සඳහන් කළා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විපක්ෂයේ අනෙකුත් පක්ෂද ඇතුළත් කර සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවත්, ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ කිසිදු උත්සාහයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා බුදුජන පෙරමුණ විසින් මෙහෙයවිය යුතු නැති බවත්, එම ස්ථාවරයේම අපි කටයුතු කරන බවත් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. පක්‍ෂය ආධිපත්‍යය නොගත යුතුයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PDP නොවන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනප්‍රිය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுஜனபெரமுனவின் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத தேசிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது குறித்து ஆராய தயார் - சுமந்திரன்",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கம் பொதுஜனபெரமுனவின் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத தேசிய கட்சிகளின் அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான நேர்மையான முயற்சிகளில் ஈடுபட்டால் அவ்வாறான முயற்சிகளிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது குறித்து தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு பரிசிலீக்கும் என தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பின சுமந்திரன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "தமிழ்தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பும் அனைத்து கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைவதற்கான விருப்பத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது அரசாங்கம் பொதுஜனபெரமுனவின் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத தேசிய கட்சிகளின் அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான நேர்மையான முயற்சிகளில் ஈடுபட்டால் அவ்வாறான முயற்சிகளிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது குறித்து தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு பரிசிலீக்கும் என தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்  சுமந்திரன் தெரிவித்தார் என சண்டே டைம்ஸ் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அரசியல் ஆணையை இழந்துள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலான இன்னொரு அரசாங்கமாக தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் மாறுவதற்கான காரணத்திற்காகவே நாங்கள் அதனை எதிர்க்கின்றோம் என சுமந்திரன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மக்கள் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜனபெரமுனவை நிராகரித்துள்ளனர்,இதன் காரணமாகவே அந்த கட்சி மூலம் தெரிவான ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமரும் தங்கள் பதவிகளை இராஜினாமா செய்யநிலையேற்பட்டது என சுமந்திரன் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள ஏனைய எதிர்கட்சிகளை உள்வாங்கிய அனைத்து கட்சி அரசாங்கம் உருவாகவேண்டும்,என மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ள அவர் தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்கும் எந்த முயற்சியும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜனபெரமுன தலைமையில் இடம்பெறக்கூடாது அந்த கட்சி ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தக்கூடாது என்ற நிலைப்பாட்டை நாங்கள் பின்பற்றி வருகின்றோம் எனவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PDP அல்லாத",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபலமான மக்கள் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}