{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131672",
  "time_ut": 1658124727,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இந்திய கடன் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் 21,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் யூரியா உரம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "21,000 MT of Urea Fertilizer under India Loan Scheme",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Ministry of Agriculture, 21,000 metric tonnes of fertilizer will reach the country in two weeks under the Indian loan scheme.",
        "The first batch of 44,000 metric tonnes of fertilizer received under India loan assistance arrived in the country last week.",
        "The said fertilizer is currently being distributed to farmers by Sri Lanka Fertilizer Company Limited and Colombo Commercial Fertilizer Company.",
        "The Ministry of Agriculture has informed that today (18) the money required for the purchase of fuel will be given to the Sri Lanka Petroleum Corporation to address the fuel crisis in fertilizer supply."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Urea Fertilizer",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India Loan Scheme",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Fertilizer Company Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියානු ණය යෝජනා ක්‍රමය යටතේ යූරියා පොහොර මෙ.ටොන් 21,000ක්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය ණය යෝජනා ක්‍රමය යටතේ සති දෙකකින් පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 21,000ක් මෙරටට ලැබෙන බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය ආධාර යටතේ ලැබුණු පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 44,000ක පළමු කාණ්ඩය පසුගිය සතියේ දිවයිනට පැමිණියේය.",
        "එම පොහොර දැනට සීමාසහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම සහ කොළඹ කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම මගින් ගොවීන් වෙත බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ.",
        "පොහොර සැපයුමේ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයට පිළියම් යෙදීම සඳහා අද (18) ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය මුදල් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට ලබා දෙන බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය දැනුම් දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "යූරියා පොහොර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියානු ණය යෝජනා ක්රමය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 21,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 44,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய கடன் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் 21,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் யூரியா உரம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய கடன்திட்டத்தின் கீழ் 21,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் உரம் இன்னும் இரண்டு வாரங்களில் நாட்டை வந்தடையும் என விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய கடன் உதவியின் கீழ் பெறப்பட்ட 44,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் உரத்தின் முதல் தொகுதி கப்பல் கடந்த வாரம் நாட்டை வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "இலங்கை உரக் கம்பனி லிமிடெட் மற்றும் கொழும்பு கொமர்ஷல் உரக் கம்பனி ஆகியவற்றினால் குறித்த உரம் தற்போது விவசாயிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "உர விநியோகத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை நிவர்த்தி செய்ய எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு தேவையான பணம் இன்று (18) இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு வழங்கப்பட உள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "21,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "யூரியா உரம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்திய கடன் திட்டம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உர நிறுவனம் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}