{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/front_page/UK-PM-pledges-support-to-Sri-Lanka/238-244215",
  "time_ut": 1662138252,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UK PM pledges support to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UK PM pledges support to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "British Prime Minister Boris Johnson commended the efforts of President Ranil Wickremesinghe for establishing an inclusive government that will bring the stability needed to address issues for the Sri Lankan people. In a congratulatory message to President Wickremesinghe on his appointment as the Head of State, the British Prime Minister said that upholding democratic principles and seeking democratic consensus will be vital to President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s success.",
        "Reiterating the British Government’s sincere commitment to Sri Lanka, Prime Minister Boris Johnson said, “The UK will continue to work with the people of Sri Lanka, especially during the current economic and social challenges.",
        "I hope that you will be able to make quick and positive progress with the International Monetary Fund. The UK stands ready to engage with our international partners to support Sri Lanka on this issue. ”The British Prime Minister also expressed confidence that the two governments can work together to achieve long-lasting and substantive progress on reconciliation and accountability in Sri Lanka. “The 51st UN Human Rights Council in September will be a moment for your government to demonstrate your human rights credentials with a change of approach.",
        "We- and others in the international community – want to work with Sri Lanka to make real and tangible progress on these issues.”  He also highlighted the recently announced Developing Countries Trading Scheme. This, he said, will offer Sri Lanka the opportunity to benefit from duty-free access for the vast majority of total goods exported to the UK. “As we continue to strengthen our bilateral relationship, I hope we can find more opportunities to enhance trade and investment. I anticipate that there are strong opportunities for UK support with green finance and renewable energy,” the British PM said, recalling the conversation the two leaders had in May about shared ambitions on climate change.",
        "British Prime Minister Boris Johnson concluded his message by expressing confidence that with Sri Lanka due to celebrate its 75th Anniversary of Independence, the UK and Sri Lanka would continue to build an even deeper and stronger partnership. He also appreciated Sri Lanka’s efforts to prioritize UK-Sri Lanka relations and wished President Wickremesinghe the very best in his efforts to restore stability and prosperity in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the British Government’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය පළ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට අවශ්‍ය ස්ථාවරත්වය ගෙන එන සියලු දෙනා ඇතුළත් රජයක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දරන උත්සාහය බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ පැසසුමට ලක් විය. ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස පත්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සුබ පැතුම් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මූලධර්ම ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සම්මුතියක් අපේක්ෂා කිරීම ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ සාර්ථකත්වයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය රජයේ අවංක කැපවීම නැවත අවධාරණය කරමින් අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන් පැවසුවේ, “විශේෂයෙන්ම වර්තමාන ආර්ථික හා සමාජීය අභියෝගවලදී එක්සත් රාජධානිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟින් ඔබට ඉක්මන් සහ ධනාත්මක ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කර ගැනීමට හැකිවනු ඇතැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. මෙම ගැටලුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීම සඳහා අපගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වීමට එක්සත් රාජධානිය සූදානම්. ”ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සංහිඳියාව සහ වගවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දීර්ඝ කාලීන සහ සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කර ගැනීමට රජයන් දෙකට එක්ව කටයුතු කළ හැකි බවට බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය. “සැප්තැම්බරයේ පැවැත්වෙන 51 වැනි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය ප්‍රවේශයේ වෙනසක් සමඟ ඔබේ මානව හිමිකම් අක්තපත්‍ර ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමට ඔබේ රජයට අවස්ථාවක් වනු ඇත.",
        "අපට සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවේ අනෙකුත් අයට - මෙම ගැටළු සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැබෑ සහ ප්‍රත්‍යක්ෂ ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ වැඩ කිරීමට අවශ්‍යයි. ඔහු මෑතකදී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල වෙළඳ යෝජනා ක්‍රමය ද ඉස්මතු කළේය. මෙමගින් එක්සත් රාජධානියට අපනයනය කරන සමස්ත භාණ්ඩවලින් අතිමහත් බහුතරයක් සඳහා තීරුබදු රහිත ප්‍රවේශයෙන් ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා ගැනීමේ අවස්ථාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දෙන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. “අපි අපගේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතාව ශක්තිමත් කරගනිමින් ඉදිරියට යන විට, වෙළෙඳාම සහ ආයෝජන වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමට අපට තවත් අවස්ථා සොයා ගත හැකි වනු ඇතැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. හරිත මූල්‍ය සහ පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය සමඟ එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සහාය සඳහා ශක්තිමත් අවස්ථා ඇති බව මම අපේක්ෂා කරමි, ”බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති පැවසුවේ දේශගුණික විපර්යාස පිළිබඳ හවුල් අභිලාෂයන් පිළිබඳව නායකයින් දෙදෙනා මැයි මාසයේදී කළ සංවාදය සිහිපත් කරමින්.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන් සිය පණිවිඩය අවසන් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ එහි 75 වැනි නිදහස් සංවත්සරය සැමරීම හේතුවෙන් එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඊටත් වඩා ගැඹුරු සහ ශක්තිමත් හවුල්කාරිත්වයක් තවදුරටත් ගොඩනඟා ගන්නා බවට විශ්වාසය පළ කරමිනි. එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතාවලට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දරන උත්සාහය ද අගය කළ ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ සෞභාග්‍යය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමට දරන ප්‍රයත්නයේ උපරිමය ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත ප්‍රාර්ථනා කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக இங்கிலாந்து பிரதமர் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்குத் தேவையான ஸ்திரத்தன்மையைக் கொண்டுவரும் அனைவரையும் உள்ளடக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கான ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் முயற்சிகளை பிரித்தானியப் பிரதமர் பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன் பாராட்டினார். ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வெற்றிக்கு ஜனநாயகக் கோட்பாடுகளை நிலைநிறுத்துவதும் ஜனநாயக இணக்கப்பாட்டைக் கோருவதும் இன்றியமையாததாக இருக்கும் என பிரித்தானியப் பிரதமர் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு அரச தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான பிரித்தானிய அரசாங்கத்தின் உண்மையான அர்ப்பணிப்பை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்திய பிரதமர் பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன், “இலங்கை மக்களுடன் குறிப்பாக தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக சவால்களின் போது இங்கிலாந்து தொடர்ந்து பணியாற்றும்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் நீங்கள் விரைவான மற்றும் நேர்மறையான முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைய முடியும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன். இந்த விடயத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கு எமது சர்வதேச பங்காளிகளுடன் ஈடுபடுவதற்கு இங்கிலாந்து தயாராக உள்ளது. \"இலங்கையில் நல்லிணக்கம் மற்றும் பொறுப்புக்கூறல் ஆகியவற்றில் நீண்டகால மற்றும் கணிசமான முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைய இரு அரசாங்கங்களும் இணைந்து பணியாற்ற முடியும் என்றும் பிரித்தானிய பிரதமர் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார். “செப்டம்பரில் நடைபெறவுள்ள 51வது ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை, அணுகுமுறை மாற்றத்துடன் உங்களது மனித உரிமைச் சான்றுகளை உங்கள் அரசாங்கம் நிரூபிக்கும் தருணமாக அமையும்.",
        "நாங்களும் சர்வதேச சமூகத்தில் உள்ள மற்றவர்களும் - இந்த பிரச்சினைகளில் உண்மையான மற்றும் உறுதியான முன்னேற்றத்தை அடைய இலங்கையுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்ற விரும்புகிறோம். சமீபத்தில் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட வளரும் நாடுகளின் வர்த்தகத் திட்டத்தையும் அவர் எடுத்துரைத்தார். இது, ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்திற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்படும் மொத்தப் பொருட்களில் பெரும்பாலானவற்றை வரியில்லா அணுகல் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு பயனளிக்கும் வாய்ப்பை வழங்கும் என்றார். “எங்கள் இருதரப்பு உறவை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து வலுப்படுத்துவதால், வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டை மேம்படுத்த அதிக வாய்ப்புகளை நாம் காணலாம் என்று நம்புகிறேன். பசுமை நிதி மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றலுடன் இங்கிலாந்து ஆதரவிற்கு வலுவான வாய்ப்புகள் உள்ளன என்று நான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன்,\" என்று பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமர் கூறினார், காலநிலை மாற்றம் குறித்த பகிரப்பட்ட அபிலாஷைகள் குறித்து இரு தலைவர்களும் மே மாதம் நடத்திய உரையாடலை நினைவு கூர்ந்தார்.",
        "பிரித்தானியப் பிரதமர் பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன், இலங்கையின் 75வது சுதந்திர தினத்தை கொண்டாடும் நிலையில், இங்கிலாந்தும் இலங்கையும் இன்னும் ஆழமான மற்றும் வலுவான பங்காளித்துவத்தை தொடர்ந்து கட்டியெழுப்ப முடியும் என்று நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்து தனது செய்தியை முடித்தார். ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்-இலங்கை உறவுகளுக்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிப்பதற்கான இலங்கையின் முயற்சிகளை அவர் பாராட்டியதுடன், இலங்கையில் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் செழிப்பை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான தனது முயற்சிகளில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க சிறந்து விளங்க வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் அரசாங்கத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}