{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/பதவி-விலகல்-கடிதம்-போலியானது/175-300450",
  "time_ut": 1657842853,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "’பதவி விலகல் கடிதம்’ போலியானது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The 'resignation letter' is fake",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The President's Secretariat has said that the document being shared on social media as the President's resignation letter is fake.",
        "Meanwhile, President Gotabaya Rajapakse from Singapore had sent his resignation letter to Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena through the Singapore Embassy in Sri Lanka.",
        "In this case, the Speaker's office announced that it will investigate the legal validity of the said letter and the Speaker will issue a special report in this regard today.",
        "However, it is noteworthy that the letter sent by the President has not been made public by the Speaker so far. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Singapore Embassy",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ව්‍යාජ ය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ලෙස සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ හුවමාරු වන ලේඛනය ව්‍යාජ එකක් බව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිංගප්පූරු තානාපති කාර්යාලය හරහා කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා වෙත යවා තිබේ.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී කථානායක කාර්යාලය නිවේදනය කළේ එම ලිපියේ නීත්‍යානුකූල වලංගුභාවය පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන බවත් ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කථානායකවරයා විසින් අද විශේෂ වාර්තාවක් නිකුත් කරන බවත්ය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් යවන ලද ලිපිය කථානායකවරයා විසින් මෙතෙක් ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් කර නොතිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "’பதவி விலகல் கடிதம்’ போலியானது",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவி விலகல் கடிதம் என சமூக வலைத்தளங்களில் பகிரப்படும் ஆவணம் போலியானது என ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, சிங்கப்பூரிலிருந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது பதவி விலகல் கடிதத்தை இலங்கைக்கான சிங்கப்பூர் தூதரகம் ஊடாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு அனுப்பியிருந்தார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், குறித்த கடிதத்தின் சட்டரீதியான செல்லுபடியாகும் தன்மை குறித்து ஆராய்வதாகவும், இது தொடர்பில் இன்று  சபாநாயகர் விசேட அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிடுவார் எனவும் சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் அறிவித்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி அனுப்பியுள்ள கடிதம் இதுவரையில் சபாநாயகரினால் பகிரங்கமாக வெளியிடப்படவில்லை என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}