{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131598",
  "time_ut": 1657960538,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவுக்கான அரசியலமைப்பு விதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Constitutional provision for election of Interim President",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Following the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Article 04 of the Presidential Election (Special Provisions) Act No. 20 of 1981 states that in the event of a vacancy in the office of the President in the event that the Parliament is not dissolved, action must be taken to convene the Parliament within three days of such vacancy. The Parliament session convened today under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana.",
        "The Parliament session convened today at 10 am with the Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena presiding over the formalities.",
        "During this, Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena presented the letter sent by the President to the Speaker regarding President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's resignation from the presidency in accordance with Article 38 (1) of the Constitution, and Parliamentary Secretary General Tammika Dasanayake submitted to the House.",
        "Also, according to Article 04 of the Presidential Election (Special Elections) Act No. 02 of 1981, nomination papers must be received not later than 48 hours and not later than 48 hours after the sitting of Parliament. Accordingly, the Secretary General of the Parliament informed the House that the Parliament has decided to meet on Tuesday at 10 AM to receive the nominations.",
        "Also, the Secretary General explained to the House about the procedure for submission of nominations as per Article 6 of the Constitution. The member filing the nomination must meet the council on the 19th.",
        "The Secretary General of the Parliament informed that it has been decided to hold a referendum to elect a new President for the vacancy of the Presidency on Wednesday, the 20th, as planned, and urged all members to take note of the disqualifications mentioned in Section 92 of the Constitution.",
        "I have decided to resign from the office of the President in response to the demand of the people and the decision of the political party leaders. When the Secretary General read the letter sent by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to the Speaker in the House, a few members of the United People's Shakti clapped the table and the members nearby protested in a 'no' tone.",
        "The members of the ruling party welcomed the fact that the President mentioned that he has done his best service to the motherland and will continue to do his best in the future.",
        "Following this, Parliament was adjourned by Chief Minister Dinesh Gunawardena. Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena informed the House that the next session of Parliament will convene on Tuesday (19) at 10.00 am.",
        "Following the adjournment of the House, members of the ruling party congratulated President Ranil Wickremesinghe in response. A few independent members of Parliament conversed with President Ranil Wickremesinghe in an amiable manner.",
        "Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa and Samal Rajapaksa did not attend today's Parliament session. Former minister Dalas Alagaperuma, who announced that he will contest for the presidential election, also did not attend the council session."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 04 of the Presidential Election (Special Provisions) Act No. 20 of 1981",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 38",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Article 04 of the Presidential Election (Special Elections) Act No. 02 of 1981",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "later than 48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "later than 48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 AM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 6 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the council on the 19th",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 92 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Shakti",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ව්යවස්ථාමය විධිවිධාන",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු 1981 අංක 20 දරණ ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ 04 වැනි වගන්තියේ සඳහන් වන්නේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හරිනු නොලබන අවස්ථාවක ජනාධිපති ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වුවහොත් ඒ සඳහා පියවර ගත යුතු බවයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පුරප්පාඩු වී දින තුනක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද රැස්විය.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය අද පෙරවරු 10ට රැස්විය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 38 (1) වගන්තියට අනුව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් එවන ලද ලිපිය කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් කථානායකවරයා වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ටම්මික දසනායක විසින් සභාවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී.",
        "එසේම 1981 අංක 02 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ මැතිවරණ) පනතේ 04 වැනි වගන්තිය අනුව නාමයෝජනා පත්‍ර භාරගත යුත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වී පැය 48කට පසුව සහ පැය 48කට පසුව නොවේ. ඒ අනුව නාමයෝජනා භාර ගැනීම සඳහා අඟහරුවාදා පෙරවරු 10 ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වීමට තීරණය කළ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා සභාවට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 6 වැනි වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව නාමයෝජනා භාරදීමේ ක්‍රමවේදය පිළිබඳවද මහලේකම්වරයා සභාවට කරුණු පැහැදිලි කළේය. නාමයෝජනා ගොනු කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරයා 19 වැනිදා සභාව හමුවිය යුතුය.",
        "පුරප්පාඩු වන ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ජනමත විචාරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති පරිදි 20 වැනි බදාදා දින තීරණය කර ඇති බව දන්වා සිටි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා 92 වැනි වගන්තියේ සඳහන් නුසුදුසුකම් පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරන ලෙස සියලු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ.",
        "ජනතා ඉල්ලීමට සහ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයන්ගේ තීරණයට අනුව මම ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා.ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කථානායකවරයාට යැවූ ලිපිය මහලේකම්වරයා සභාවේදී කියවූ විට මන්ත්‍රීවරු කිහිප දෙනෙක් එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති පක්ෂයේ මේසයට අත්පුඩි ගැසූ අතර අසල සිටි මන්ත්‍රීවරු ‘නැහැ’ ස්වරයෙන් විරෝධය පළ කළහ.",
        "මාතෘභූමිය වෙනුවෙන් කළ හැකි උපරිම සේවය තමන් කළ බවත් ඉදිරියේදීත් කළ හැකි උපරිමය ඉටු කරන බවත් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කිරීම ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු පිළිගත්තා.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තබන ලදී. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මීළඟ සැසිවාරය අඟහරුවාදා (19) පෙරවරු 10.00ට රැස්වන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා සභාවට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "සභාව කල් තැබීමෙන් පසු ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු ඊට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සුබ පැතූහ. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරු කිහිප දෙනෙක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ සුහදව කතා බහ කළහ.",
        "අද පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයට හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ සහ සමල් රාජපක්ෂ එක්ව සිටියේ නැහැ. ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම ද සභා සැසිවාරයට පැමිණ සිටියේ නැහැ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 අංක 20 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ 04 වැනි වගන්තිය.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරවරු 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1981 අංක 02 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ මැතිවරණ) පනතේ 04 වැනි වගන්තිය.",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 48 කට පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 48 කට පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 6 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාව 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 92 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவுக்கான அரசியலமைப்பு விதி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி விலகலை தொடர்ந்து  1981ஆம் ஆண்டு 20ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் 04 ஆவது உறுப்புரைக்கு அமைய,பாராளுமன்றம் கலைக்கப்படாத சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் ஜனாதிபதிப் பதவியில் வெற்றிடம் ஏற்படும் போது, அவ்வாறான வெற்றிடம் ஏற்பட்டு மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் பாராளுமன்றத்தைக் கூட்டுமாறு அழைப்பதற்குச் செயற்படுதல் வேண்டும் என்பதால், பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் நேற்று வெளியிட்ட விசேட வர்த்தமானிக்கமைய பாராளுமன்றம் அமர்வு இன்று சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் கூடியது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு இன்று காலை 10 மணிக்கு சம்பிரதாய முறைக்கமைய சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் கூடியது.",
        "இதன்போது சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன அரசியலமைப்பின் 38 (1) உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தமை குறித்து ஜனாதிபதி சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்பிய கடிதத்தை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக தஸநாயக்க சபையில் சமர்ப்பித்தார்.",
        "அத்துடன் 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு 02 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு (சிறப்பு ஏற்பற்டுகள்) சட்டத்தின் 04 ஆவது உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு இடம்பெற்று 48 மணித்தியாலங்கள் முந்தாமலும், 7 நாட்கள் பிந்தாமலும் வேட்பு மனுக்கல் பெற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட வேண்டும். அதற்கமைய எதிர்வரும் செவ்வாய்கிழமை மு.ப.10 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்றம் கூடி வேட்புமனுக்களை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் சபையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அத்துடன் அரசியலமைப்பின் 6 ஆவது உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் வேட்பு மனுக்களை சமர்ப்பித்தல் முறைமை தொடர்பில் செயலாளர் நாயகம் சபைக்கு தெளிவுப்படுத்தினார். வேட்பு மனுக்கலை தாக்கல் செய்யும் உறுப்பினர் எதிர்வரும் 19ஆம் திகதி கட்டாயம் சபைக்கு சமுகமளிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "தற்போது உத்தேசித்துள்ளதற்கமைய எதிர்வரும் 20 ஆம் திகதி புதன் கிழமை பாராளுமன்றம் கூடி ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வெற்றிடத்திற்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்துக்கொள்ள வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்த தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம், ஜனாதிபதியாக தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கு அரசியலமைப்பின் 92 ஆவது பிரிவில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள தகுதியின்மைகளை சகல உறுப்பினர்களும் கவனத்திற்கொள்ள வேண்டும் எனவும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்களின் கோரிக்கைக்கமையவும், அரசியல் கட்சி தலைவர்களின் தீர்மானத்திற்கமையவும் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்ய தீர்மானித்தேன், அரசியலமைப்பிற்கமைய அடுத்தக்கட்ட நடவடிக்கையினை முன்னெடுக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்பிய கடிதத்தை செயலாளர் நாயகம் சபையில் வாசிக்கையில் ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் ஒருசில உறுப்பினர்கள் மேசையினை தட்டி ஆரவாரம் தெரிவித்தனர், அதற்கு அருகில் இருந்த உறுப்பினர்கள் ' வேண்டாம்'என்ற தொனியில் மறுப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தாய் நாட்டிற்கு முடிந்த சேவையினை செய்துள்ளேன், இனி வரும் காலங்களிலும் இயலுமான சேவையினை ஆற்றுவேன் என ஜனாதிபதி குறிப்பிட்டதை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் குறிப்பிட்டதை ஆளும் தரப்பின் உறுப்பினர்கள் வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "அதனை தொடர்ந்து பாராளுமன்ற ஒத்திவைப்பு சபை முதல்வர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவினால் பிரேரிக்கப்பட்டது. அதற்கமைய அடுத்த பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு எதிர்வரும் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு கூடும் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன சபைக்கு அறிவித்தார்.",
        "சபை நடவடிக்கை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து ஆளும் தரப்பின் உறுப்பினர்கள் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்தனர். பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் ஒருசில உறுப்பினர்கள் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடல் சுமுகமான முறையில் உரையாடினார்கள்.",
        "இன்று இடம்பெற்ற பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வில் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ,சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோர் கலந்துக்கொள்ளவில்லை. ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவுக்காக போட்டியில் கலந்துக்கொள்ள போவதாக அறிவித்த முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகபெருமவும் சபை அமர்வில் கலந்துக்கொள்ளவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 20 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் 04 வது பிரிவு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 38",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 02 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல் (சிறப்புத் தேர்தல்கள்) சட்டத்தின் 04 வது பிரிவு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 மணி நேரத்திற்கு பிறகு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 மணி நேரத்திற்கு பிறகு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 6",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "19ம் தேதி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 92",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}