{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83393/actor-jackson-anthony-transferred-to-colombo-national-hospital",
  "time_ut": 1656818640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Actor Jackson Anthony transferred to Colombo National Hospital",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Actor Jackson Anthony transferred to Colombo National Hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Veteran actor Jackson Anthony who was hospitalised following a motor accident yesterday (July 02), has been transferred from the Anuradhapura Teaching Hospital to the National Hospital in Colombo.",
        "According to hospital sources, the veteran actor is slated to undergo surgery there.",
        "Jackson Anthony and two other people were wounded after the vehicle they were travelling in collided with a wild elephant at Thalawa last night.",
        "They had been on their way back after finishing filming at the Haththikuchchi Viharaya in Galgamuwa when the vehicle crashed against a wild elephant.",
        "According to reports, the brother of the veteran actor is also among those who were injured.",
        "The police suspect that the wild elephant might have been critically wounded in the crash.",
        "Further investigations into the accident are being carried out by the Thalawa Police."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jackson Anthony",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo National Hospital",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Anuradhapura Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Haththikuchchi Viharaya",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galgamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Thalawa Police",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රංගන ශිල්පී ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට මාරුකර යවා තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ (ජුලි 02) සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් රෝහල් ගත කළ ප්‍රවීණ රංගන ශිල්පී ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී අනුරාධපුර ශික්ෂණ රෝහලෙන් කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට මාරුකර යවා තිබේ.",
        "එහිදී ප්‍රවීණ රංගන ශිල්පියාට ශල්‍යකර්මයක් සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත බව රෝහල් ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ තලාව ප්‍රදේශයේදී ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු ගමන් ගත් රථය වන අලියෙකුගේ ගැටීමෙන් තුවාල ලබා තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඔවුන් ගල්ගමුව හත්තිකුච්චි විහාරස්ථානයේ රූගත කිරීම් අවසන් කර ආපසු එමින් සිටියදී වන අලියෙකුගේ ගැටීමෙන් මෙම අනතුර සිදුව තිබෙනවා.",
        "වාර්තා වන අන්දමට තුවාල ලැබූවන් අතර ප්‍රවීණ රංගන ශිල්පියාගේ සොහොයුරා ද සිටින බව සඳහන්.",
        "අනතුරින් වන අලියා බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා සිටින්නට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය සැක කරයි.",
        "අනතුර සම්බන්ධයෙන් තලාව පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත්තිකුච්චි විහාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තලාව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நடிகர் ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி கொழும்பு தேசிய மருத்துவமனைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று (ஜூலை 02) இடம்பெற்ற வாகன விபத்தினால் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டிருந்த மூத்த நடிகர் ஜாக்சன் அந்தோனி அனுராதபுரம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மருத்துவமனை வட்டாரங்களின்படி, மூத்த நடிகருக்கு அங்கு அறுவை சிகிச்சை செய்ய திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நேற்றிரவு தலாவ பிரதேசத்தில் காட்டு யானையுடன் பயணித்த வாகனம் மோதியதில் ஜாக்சன் அந்தோனி மற்றும் இருவர் படுகாயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கல்கமுவ ஹத்திகுச்சி விகாரையில் படப்பிடிப்பை முடித்துவிட்டு திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்தபோது, ​​காட்டு யானை மீது வாகனம் மோதி விபத்துக்குள்ளானது.",
        "காயமடைந்தவர்களில் மூத்த நடிகரின் சகோதரரும் அடங்குவதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்த விபத்தில் காட்டு யானை பலத்த காயம் அடைந்திருக்கலாம் என போலீசார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "விபத்து தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை தலாவ பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹத்திகுச்சி விகாரை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவா போலீஸ்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}