{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/විභාග-කාලසටහන-මැතිසබේදී-ප්‍රකාශයට/101-615918",
  "time_ut": 1657028087,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විභාග කාලසටහන මැතිසබේදී ප්‍රකාශයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Exam schedule to be announced in the meeting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Education Susil Premajayantha announced the dates of Aposa Advanced Level, Aposa Ordinary Level and Grade 5 Scholarship Examination in Parliament today (5).",
        "He announced the dates in response to a question raised by Kegalu District Councilor Mr. Udayakantha Gunathilaka during the adjournment of the House.",
        "\"The results of the last A-level examination will be released in August. The next A-level examination is expected to be held at least three months after the release of the results, probably in November-December. Also, the grade 5 scholarship exam to be held this year is expected to be held on a day before the start of A-level. It is planned to hold the Aposa General Examination at the end of this year in February March next year.",
        "It is necessary to give some period between two main examinations to the examination department to plan the necessary activities. Aposa High Level Examination was held last time. The examination results are in the final stage.",
        "In 2020-21 due to the Covid situation, the school period in the Western Province was lost by about 50 percent. Forty percent of school time was lost in the outer provinces during that time."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aposa Advanced Level",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalu District",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udayakantha Gunathilaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November-December",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Aposa General Examination",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February March next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aposa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forty percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විභාග කාලසටහන මැතිසබේදී ප්‍රකාශයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අපොස උසස් පෙළ, අපොස සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ   සහ 5 ශ්‍රේණිය ශිෂ්‍යත්ව විභාගය පැවැත්වෙන දින වකවානු අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අද (5) ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය.",
        "ඔහු එම දින වකවානු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ කෑගලු දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී උදයකාන්ත ගුණතිලක මහතා සභාව  කල්තබන අවස්ථාවේදී  යොමු කළ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමිනි.",
        "\" පසුගිය  උසස් පෙළ විභාගයේ  ප්‍රතිඵල   ලබන අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී නිකුත් කෙරෙනවා. මීළඟ උසස් පෙළ විභාගය ඒ  ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කර අඩු තරමින් මාස තුනකින් පසු බොහෝවිට නොවැම්බර් දෙසැම්බර් පැවැත්වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා. එසේම මේ වසරේදී පැවැත්විමට නියමිත 5 ශ්‍රේණිය ශිෂ්‍යත්ව විභාගය උසස් පෙළ ආරම්භ කිරීමට පෙරාතු දිනයක පවත්වීමට  අපේක්ෂා කරනවා. මේ වසර අවසානයේ තිබෙන අපොස  සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගය ලබන වසරේ පෙබරවාරි මාර්තු පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කරලා තියෙනවා.",
        "ප්‍රධාන විභාග දෙකක් අතර යම් කාල පරිච්ඡේදයක් අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු සැලසුම් කිරීම සඳහා විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට  ලබාදීම අවශ්‍යයි. අපොස උසස් පෙළ විභාගය පසු ගිය සැරේ   පැවැත්වුණා. ඒ විභාගයේ ප්‍රතිඵල පරික්ෂා කිරීම අවසන් අදියරේ පවතිනවා.",
        "කොවිඩ්  තත්වය නිසා 2020- 21 වර්ෂවලදී   බස්නාහිර පළාතේ පාසල් කාලය  සියයට 50කින් පමණ අහිමි වුණා. පිට පළාත්වල එම කාලයේදී අහිමිවුණු පාසල් කාලය සියයට හතළිහකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපෝසා උසස් පෙළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගලු දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදයකාන්ත ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්-දෙසැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපෝසා සාමාන්‍ය විභාගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසරේ පෙබරවාරි මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපෝසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට හතළිහක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கூட்டத்தில் தேர்வு அட்டவணை அறிவிக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அபோசா உயர்தரம், அபோசா சாதாரண தரம் மற்றும் தரம் 5 புலமைப்பரிசில் பரீட்சைக்கான திகதிகளை கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த இன்று (5) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "சபை ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் வேளையில் கேகாலு மாவட்ட சபை உறுப்பினர் திரு.உதயகாந்த குணதிலக்க எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே அவர் திகதிகளை அறிவித்தார்.",
        "\"கடந்த உயர்தரப் பரீட்சையின் பெறுபேறுகள் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் வெளியாகும். அடுத்த உயர்தரப் பரீட்சை பெறுபேறுகள் வெளியாகி குறைந்தது மூன்று மாதங்களுக்குப் பின்னர், அநேகமாக நவம்பர்-டிசம்பர் மாதங்களில் நடத்தப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. மேலும், தரம் 5 புலமைப்பரிசில்களும் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன. இந்த வருடம் நடைபெறவுள்ள பரீட்சை உயர்தரப் பரீட்சை ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு ஒரு நாள் முன்னதாக நடத்தப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.அபோசா பொதுத்தேர்வை இந்த வருட இறுதியில் அடுத்த வருடம் பெப்ரவரி மாதம் நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பரீட்சை திணைக்களத்திற்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை திட்டமிடுவதற்கு இரண்டு பிரதான பரீட்சைகளுக்கு இடையில் சிறிது கால அவகாசம் வழங்குவது அவசியம். அபோசா உயர்தரப் பரீட்சை கடந்த முறை நடைபெற்றது. தேர்வு முடிவுகள் இறுதி கட்டத்தில் உள்ளன.",
        "2020-21 ஆம் ஆண்டில் கோவிட் நிலைமை காரணமாக, மேல் மாகாணத்தில் பாடசாலைக் காலம் சுமார் 50 வீதத்தால் இழக்கப்பட்டது. அக்காலப்பகுதியில் வெளி மாகாணங்களில் நாற்பது வீதமான பாடசாலை நேரம் இழக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபோசா உயர்நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதயகாந்த குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் டிசம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபோசா பொதுத் தேர்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு பிப்ரவரி மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபோசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாற்பது சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}