{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ඇමෙරිකාව-සමග-ඕනෑම-ගැටුමකට-සූදානම්---කිම්/3-395826",
  "time_ut": 1659000464,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඇමෙරිකාව සමග ඕනෑම ගැටුමකට සූදානම් - කිම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ready for any conflict with America - Kim",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The leader of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, Kim Jong-un, says that his government is ready to fight any mobilization to prevent North Korea's nuclear war power and any US military provocation.",
        "Kim made the announcement while addressing a ceremony to mark the 69th anniversary of the Korean War armistice on July 27.",
        "His latest warnings come as South Korea and the United States move to step up joint military exercises, saying Pyongyang is preparing for an invasion.",
        "This week, the US military conducted live-fire exercises using high-tech Apache helicopters stationed in South Korea for the first time since 2019."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "America",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Democratic People's Republic of Korea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kim Jong-un",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Korea's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Korean War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pyongyang",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apache",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇමෙරිකාව සමග ඕනෑම ගැටුමකට සූදානම් - කිම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "උතුරු කොරියාවේ න්‍යෂ්ටික යුද ශක්තිය වැළැක්වීම වෙනුවෙන් සිදුකරන ඕනෑම බලමුලු ගැන්වීමකට සහ ඕනෑම එක්සත් ජනපද යුදමය ප්‍රකෝප කිරීමකටට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීමට තම රජය සූදානම් බව කොරියානු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මහජන සමූහාණ්ඩුවේ නායක කිම් ජොන්ග්-උන් පවසයි.",
        "කිම් මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, ජුලි 27දා කොරියානු යුද සටන් විරාමයේ 69 වැනි සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් පැවති උත්සවයක් අමතමිනි.",
        "ඔහුගේ නවතම අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් පැමිණෙන්නේ ප්යොන්යැන්ග් හි ආක්‍රමණය සඳහා පෙරහුරුවක් යැයි පවසමින්, දකුණු කොරියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය ඒකාබද්ධ යුද අභ්‍යාස වේගවත් කිරීමට පියවර ගැනීමත් සමගිනි.",
        "මෙම සතියේ, එක්සත් ජනපද හමුදාව 2019 සිට ප්‍රථම වතාවට දකුණු කොරියාවෙහි ස්ථානගත කර ඇති අධි තාක්ෂණයෙන් යුතු අපාචේ හෙලිකොප්ටර් භාවිත කරමින් සජීවී-වෙඩි අභ්‍යාස පැවැත්වීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මහජන ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිම් ජොන් උන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු කොරියාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියොංයැං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apache",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவுடன் எந்த மோதலுக்கும் தயார் - கிம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வட கொரியாவின் அணு ஆயுதப் போர் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க இராணுவ ஆத்திரமூட்டலைத் தடுக்கும் எந்தவொரு அணிதிரட்டலையும் எதிர்த்துப் போராடத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக கொரிய ஜனநாயக மக்கள் குடியரசின் தலைவர் கிம் ஜாங்-உன் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "ஜூலை 27 அன்று கொரியப் போர் போர் நிறுத்தத்தின் 69 வது ஆண்டு விழாவைக் குறிக்கும் விழாவில் உரையாற்றியபோது கிம் இந்த அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "தென் கொரியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் கூட்டு இராணுவப் பயிற்சிகளை முடுக்கிவிட, பியோங்யாங் படையெடுப்புக்குத் தயாராகி வருவதாகக் கூறி அவரது சமீபத்திய எச்சரிக்கைகள் வந்துள்ளன.",
        "இந்த வாரம், 2019 க்குப் பிறகு முதல் முறையாக தென் கொரியாவில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள உயர் தொழில்நுட்ப அப்பாச்சி ஹெலிகாப்டர்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி அமெரிக்க இராணுவம் நேரடி துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு பயிற்சிகளை நடத்தியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரியா ஜனநாயக மக்கள் குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிம் ஜாங்-உன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட கொரியாவின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியோங்யாங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்பாச்சி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}