{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/24/navy-brings-ashore-ill-fisherman-for-treatment/",
  "time_ut": 1661316000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy brings ashore ill fisherman for treatment",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy brings ashore ill fisherman for treatment",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Navy brought ashore a fisherman who fell ill while at sea and rushed him to the hospital for treatment on 23rd August 2022. The fisherman who was aboard a local multiday fishing trawler, in seas about 47 nautical miles (about 87 km) northeast of the Foul Point, Trincomalee, had suddenly fallen ill and was in need of medical attention.",
        "The multiday fishing trawler ‘Manuki’(Reg. No. IMUL-A-0345 KLT) was on a fishing voyage leaving the Cod Bay Fishery Harbour, Trincomalee on 08th August 2022, with 06 fishermen. Meanwhile, the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources, has disseminated the distress to the Maritime Rescue Coordination Centre (MRCC) Colombo at Navy Headquarters, about this ill fisherman who was aboard the trawler.",
        "In response to a request for assistance, Sri Lanka Navy sent out the Fast Attack Craft P 4443 of the 04th Fast Attack Craft Flotilla (4 FAF) attached to the Eastern Naval Command to bring the ill fisherman for treatment. Having taken over him to the Navy’s craft on the evening of 23rd August 2022 amidst rough sea condition, the patient was brought to the Trincomalee Harbour administering first aid and subsequently he was rushed to the General Hospital, Trincomalee for further treatment.",
        "Besides, the Navy stays prepared to respond to eventualities of this nature, with a view to assist naval and fishing communities in distress in Sri Lanka’s Search and Rescue Region.",
        "IMF delegation in Sri Lanka for talks on economic and financial reforms"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23rd August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 nautical miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "87 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foul Point",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "multiday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "KLT",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cod Bay Fishery Harbour",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maritime Rescue Coordination Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening of 23rd August 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාවික හමුදාව රෝගාතුර වූ ධීවරයෙකු ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා ගොඩබිමට රැගෙන එයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව මුහුදේ සිටියදී රෝගාතුර වූ ධීවරයෙකු ගොඩට ගෙනැවිත් ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා රෝහලට රැගෙන ගියේ 2022 අගෝස්තු 23 වැනිදාය. දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක සිටි ධීවරයා නාවික සැතපුම් 47ක් (කිලෝමීටර් 87ක් පමණ) ඊසාන දෙසින් වූ මුහුදේදී ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ Foul Point හි හදිසියේ රෝගාතුර වී වෛද්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාර අවශ්‍ය විය.",
        "‘මනුකි’ බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව (Reg. No. IMUL-A-0345 KLT) 2022 අගෝස්තු 08 වන දින ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ කෝඩ් බේ ධීවර වරායෙන් ධීවර ගමනක් යමින් සිටියේය. මේ අතර, ධීවර හා ජලජ සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, යාත්‍රාවේ සිටි මෙම රෝගී ධීවරයා පිළිබඳව නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ පිහිටි කොළඹ සමුද්‍රීය මුදාගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය (MRCC) වෙත කනස්සල්ල පළ කර ඇත.",
        "සහය සඳහා කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත 04 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රා Flotilla (4 FAF) හි P 4443 වේගවත් ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව රෝගී ධීවරයා ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා රැගෙන ඒම සඳහා පිටත් කර යවන ලදී. රළු මුහුදු තත්ත්වය මධ්‍යයේ 2022 අගෝස්තු මස 23 වන දින සවස ඔහු නාවික හමුදා යාත්‍රාව වෙත භාර ගැනීමෙන් පසු රෝගියා ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරායට ගෙනැවිත් ප්‍රථමාධාර ලබා දී වැඩිදුර ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා ත්‍රිකුණාමලය මහ රෝහල වෙත රැගෙන ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෙවීම් සහ මුදවාගැනීම් කලාපයේ ආපදාවට ලක්ව සිටින නාවික සහ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීමේ අරමුණින් නාවික හමුදාව මෙවැනි සිදුවීම්වලට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට සූදානමින් සිටී.",
        "ආර්ථික හා මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා IMF නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික සැතපුම් 47 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝමීටර 87 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foul Point",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බහුදින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "KLT",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝඩ් බේ ධීවර වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර හා ජලජ සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර ගලවා ගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 23 සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட மீனவரை சிகிச்சைக்காக கடற்படையினர் கரைக்கு அழைத்து வந்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 23 அன்று கடலில் இருந்தபோது உடல் நலக்குறைவு ஏற்பட்ட ஒரு மீனவரை இலங்கை கடற்படை கரைக்கு கொண்டு வந்து சிகிச்சைக்காக மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு சென்றது. வடகிழக்கே சுமார் 47 கடல் மைல் (சுமார் 87 கிமீ) கடலில், உள்ளூர் பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகில் இருந்த மீனவர். திருகோணமலை, ஃபௌல் பாயிண்ட், திடீரென நோய்வாய்ப்பட்டு மருத்துவ கவனிப்பு தேவைப்பட்டது.",
        "பல நாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு ‘மானுகி’ (பதிவு எண். IMUL-A-0345 KLT) 06 மீனவர்களுடன் 08 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று திருகோணமலை, கோட் பே மீன்பிடித் துறைமுகத்திலிருந்து மீன்பிடிப் பயணத்தை மேற்கொண்டிருந்தது. இதற்கிடையில், மீன்பிடி மற்றும் நீரியல் வளங்கள் திணைக்களம், கடற்படைத் தலைமையகத்தில் உள்ள கடல்சார் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையத்திற்கு (MRCC) கொழும்பு, இழுவை படகில் இருந்த இந்த நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட மீனவர் குறித்து துயரத்தை பரப்பியுள்ளது.",
        "உதவிக்கான வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க, இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட 04 வது விரைவு தாக்குதல் கப்பலான புளோட்டிலாவின் (4 FAF) விரைவு தாக்குதல் கப்பலான P 4443 ஐ நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட மீனவரை சிகிச்சைக்காக கொண்டு வர அனுப்பியது. 2022 ஆகஸ்டு 23 ஆம் திகதி மாலை கடல் சீற்றத்திற்கு மத்தியில் அவரை கடற்படையினரின் கப்பலில் ஏற்றிச் சென்ற நோயாளி திருகோணமலை துறைமுகத்திற்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்டு முதலுதவி வழங்கப்பட்டு பின்னர் மேலதிக சிகிச்சைக்காக திருகோணமலை பொது வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "தவிர, இலங்கையின் தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பிராந்தியத்தில் துன்பத்தில் உள்ள கடற்படை மற்றும் மீனவ சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவும் நோக்கில், இதுபோன்ற நிகழ்வுகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்க கடற்படை தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "பொருளாதார மற்றும் நிதி சீர்திருத்தங்கள் தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளுக்காக IMF பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கை வந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 கடல் மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "87 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தவறான புள்ளி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "KLT",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட் பே மீன்வளத் துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்பிடி மற்றும் நீரியல் வளங்கள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23, 2022 மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}