{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Extension-of-state-of-emergency-to-hit-tourism-industry-hard/108-241917",
  "time_ut": 1658949259,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Extension of state of emergency to hit tourism industry hard",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Extension of state of emergency to hit tourism industry hard",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The decision to extend the state of emergency for a month by Parliament yesterday will further hit the tourism industry that is expected to bring in the necessary foreign exchange to Sri Lanka, as more countries could slap travel bans on Sri Lanka.",
        "Shortly after the proclamation by Parliament yesterday, they said while declaring a state of emergency was bad enough to the hard-hit sector, the decision to continue with it is an extremely negative signal.",
        "“Our arrivals to the country will further drop in the coming weeks and months. We cannot promote or sell a destination when a state of emergency is imposed. This is well known. It is going to get tougher for us as we go forward,” The Hotels Association Sri Lanka (THASL) President M. Shanthikumar said.",
        "He shared that the tourism sector stakeholders were of the view that President Ranil Wickremesinghe would lift the state of emergency without much delay.",
        "However, last evening, Parliament voted to continue the state of emergency with 120 members voting for and 63 voting against.",
        "Reflecting similar sentiments, the Sri Lanka Association of Tourism Inbound Tour Operators (SLAITO) said the proclamation would negatively impact on tourist arrivals.",
        "The SLAITO said more governments would issue travel advisories against Sri Lanka and it is near impossible to remove the advisories that are already in place.",
        "“It just gets worse. With travel advisories issued against the nation, tourists do not feel safe coming in. Also, making matters worse is that insurance companies are not keen to offer travel insurance policies in nations with emergency imposed. Even if they do, the policies are very expensive. This doesn’t augur well for us,” said SLAITO Immediate Past President Mahen Kariyawasam."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the coming weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Hotels Association Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Shanthikumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Association of Tourism Inbound Tour Operators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAITO Immediate Past",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahen Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල කිරීම සඳහා හදිසි නීතිය දීර්ඝ කිරීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තවත් රටවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරක තහනමක් පැනවිය හැකි බැවින් ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් හදිසි නීතිය මසකට දීර්ඝ කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය විදේශ විනිමය ගෙන ඒමට අපේක්ෂා කරන සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයට තවදුරටත් පහර දෙනු ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශයෙන් ටික වේලාවකට පසු, ඔවුන් කියා සිටියේ හදිසි තත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීම දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් ක්ෂේත්‍රයට ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවන අතර, එය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට ගත් තීරණය අතිශයින්ම සෘණාත්මක සංඥාවක් බවයි.",
        "“ඉදිරි සති සහ මාසවලදී අප රටට පැමිණීම තවදුරටත් පහත වැටෙනු ඇත. හදිසි තත්වයක් පැනවූ විට ගමනාන්තයක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට හෝ විකිණීමට අපට නොහැකිය. මෙය හොඳින් දන්නා කරුණකි. අපි ඉදිරියට යන විට එය අපට දැඩි වනු ඇත,” හෝටල් සංගමයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා (THASL) සභාපති එම් ශාන්තිකුමාර් පැවසීය.",
        "වැඩි ප්‍රමාදයකින් තොරව හදිසි නීතිය ඉවත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කටයුතු කරනු ඇතැයි සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ අදහස වී ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඊයේ සවස පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හදිසි නීතිය දිගටම ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 120 දෙනෙකුට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර 63 දෙනෙකු විපක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සමාන හැඟීම් පිළිබිඹු කරමින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය (SLAITO) කියා සිටියේ මෙම ප්‍රකාශය සංචාරක පැමිණීම් කෙරෙහි අහිතකර ලෙස බලපානු ඇති බවයි.",
        "තවත් රජයන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව සංචාරක උපදේශන නිකුත් කරනු ඇති බවත් දැනටමත් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන උපදේශන ඉවත් කිරීමට නොහැකි බවත් SLAITO පවසයි.",
        "“එය නරක අතට හැරේ. ජාතියට එරෙහිව නිකුත් කර ඇති සංචාරක උපදේශන සමඟ, සංචාරකයින්ට ආරක්ෂිත බවක් දැනෙන්නේ නැත. එසේම, තත්වය වඩාත් නරක අතට හැරෙන්නේ හදිසි අවස්ථා පනවන ලද රටවල සංචාරක රක්ෂණ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ලබා දීමට රක්ෂණ සමාගම් උනන්දු නොවීමයි. ඔවුන් එසේ කළත්, ප්රතිපත්ති ඉතා මිල අධිකයි. මෙය අපට සුබදායක නොවේ,” SLAITO හිටපු සභාපති මහේන් කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හෝටල් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් ශාන්තිකුමාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAITO Immediate Past",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේන් කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுற்றுலாத்துறையை கடுமையாக பாதிக்கும் வகையில் அவசரகால நிலை நீட்டிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை நேற்றைய தினம் பாராளுமன்றம் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு நீடிப்பதற்கான தீர்மானம் இலங்கைக்கு தேவையான அந்நிய செலாவணியைக் கொண்டுவரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் சுற்றுலாத்துறைக்கு மேலும் பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும்.",
        "நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பிரகடனத்திற்குப் பிறகு, அவர்கள் அவசரகால நிலையைப் பிரகடனப்படுத்துவது கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்ட துறைக்கு மிகவும் மோசமானது, அதைத் தொடர முடிவு செய்வது மிகவும் எதிர்மறையான சமிக்ஞையாகும்.",
        "“வரும் வாரங்கள் மற்றும் மாதங்களில் நாட்டிற்கு எங்களின் வருகை மேலும் குறையும். அவசரகால நிலை விதிக்கப்படும் போது, ​​ஒரு இலக்கை விளம்பரப்படுத்தவோ விற்கவோ முடியாது. இது நன்கு அறியப்பட்டதாகும். நாங்கள் முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும்போது இது எமக்கு கடினமாக இருக்கும்” என்று ஹோட்டல் சங்கம் இலங்கை (THASL) தலைவர் எம். சாந்திகுமார் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை அதிக தாமதமின்றி நீக்குவார் என்று சுற்றுலாத்துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் கருதுவதாக அவர் பகிர்ந்து கொண்டார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நேற்று மாலை, அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை தொடர பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 120 உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆதரவாகவும் 63 பேர் எதிராகவும் வாக்களித்தனர்.",
        "இதேபோன்ற உணர்வுகளைப் பிரதிபலிக்கும் வகையில், இலங்கை சுற்றுலா உள்வரும் சுற்றுலா நடத்துநர்களின் சங்கம் (SLAITO) இந்த அறிவிப்பு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகையை எதிர்மறையாக பாதிக்கும் என்று கூறியது.",
        "மேலும் பல அரசாங்கங்கள் இலங்கைக்கு எதிரான பயண ஆலோசனைகளை வெளியிடும் என்றும் ஏற்கனவே நடைமுறையில் உள்ள ஆலோசனைகளை அகற்றுவது கிட்டத்தட்ட சாத்தியமற்றது என்றும் SLAITO தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இது மோசமாகிறது. தேசத்திற்கு எதிராக வழங்கப்படும் பயண ஆலோசனைகளால், சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் பாதுகாப்பாக உள்ளே வருவதில்லை. மேலும், அவசரகாலத் திணிக்கப்பட்ட நாடுகளில் பயணக் காப்பீட்டுக் கொள்கைகளை வழங்க காப்பீட்டு நிறுவனங்கள் ஆர்வம் காட்டாதது விஷயங்களை மோசமாக்குகிறது. அவர்கள் செய்தாலும், பாலிசிகள் மிகவும் விலை உயர்ந்தவை. இது எமக்கு நல்லதல்ல என SLAITO உடனடி முன்னாள் தலைவர் மஹேன் காரியவசம் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோட்டல் சங்கம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மு. சாந்திகுமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "120",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா உள்வரும் சுற்றுலா நடத்துபவர்களின் இலங்கை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAITO உடனடி கடந்த காலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேன் காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}