{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලාංකිකයන්ට-තුන්වේල-කන-එක-ගැටලුවක්/101-615891",
  "time_ut": 1657001459,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලාංකිකයන්ට තුන්වේල කන එක ගැටලුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Eating three meals a day is a problem for Sri Lankans",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Reuters news agency stated that in view of the rapidly rising inflation in Sri Lanka, it has become a problem for the Sri Lankan people to get three meals a day.",
        "According to Reuters news service, the livelihood of many people is also at risk due to the lack of fuel.",
        "Reuters reports that due to the increase in food prices, family members have to reduce the number of meals they eat. Inflation in June in Sri Lanka was 54.6 percent, transport charges increased by 128 percent, and food inflation was 80.1 percent, according to Reuters, citing official data reports. The news service said.",
        "Economist Rehana Tawfiq, an expert in calculating food inflation, has told Reuters that a Sri Lankan family should earn 93,675 to 148,868 rupees per month to eat a nutritious diet recommended by the World Health Organization.",
        "But the average income of a Sri Lankan family is 76,414 rupees per month and the monthly income of a poor family, which is 20 percent of the Sri Lankan population, is 17,572 rupees, according to official data reports.",
        "Reuters news agency said that due to the current crisis in Sri Lanka, the price of vegetables has doubled and the price of a kilo of rice, which was 145 rupees last year, has become 230 rupees today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "128 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "80.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rehana Tawfiq",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93,675",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "148,868",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76,414",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,572",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "230",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලාංකිකයන්ට තුන්වේල කන එක ගැටලුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් ඉහළ යන උද්ධමනය හමුවේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට තුන්වේල ආහාර ලබා ගැනීම ගැටලුවක් වී ඇතැයි රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් බොහෝ පිරිසකගේ ජීවනෝපායද අවදානමට ලක්ව ඇතැයි රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය පවසයි.",
        "ආහාර මිල ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් පවුලක සාමාජිකයින්  ආහාර ගන්නා වේල් ප්‍රමාණය අඩු කිරීමට සිදුව ඇතැයි රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය පෙන්වා දෙයි.ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජුනි මස උද්ධමනය සියයට 54.6 ක් බවත් ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු සියයට 128 කින් වැඩි වී ඇති බවත් ආහාර උද්ධමනය සියයට 80.1 බවත් නිල දත්ත වාර්තා උපුටා දක්වමින් රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය නිර්දේශ කරන පෝෂ්‍යදායි ආහාර වේලක් ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පවුලක් මසකට රුපියල් 93,675 සිට 148,868 මුදලක් ඉපැයිය යුතු  බව ආහාර උද්ධමනය ගණනය කිරීමේ විශේෂඥයෙකු වන ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥ රෙහානා තව්ෆීක් මහත්මිය රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකික පවුලක සාමාන්‍ය ආදායම මසකට රුපියල් 76,414 බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනගහණයෙන් සියයට 20 ක් වන දුප්පත් පවුලක මාසික ආදායම රුපියල් 17,572 ක් බවත් නිල දත්ත වාර්තා උපුටා දක්වමින් රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ජනතාව විඳින දුෂ්කරතා තවත් උග්‍ර කරමින් එළවළු මිල දෙගුණ වී ඇති බවත් ගිය වසරේ රුපියල් 145 ක් වූ සහල් කිලෝවක මිල අද වන විට රුපියල් 230 ක් වී ඇති බවත්  රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය පැවසුවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 54.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 128 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 80.1 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙහානා තවුෆික්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93,675 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "148,868 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76,414 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,572 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "230",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மூன்று வேளை உணவு உண்பது இலங்கையர்களுக்கு ஒரு பிரச்சினை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் வேகமாக அதிகரித்து வரும் பணவீக்கத்தை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு மூன்று வேளை உணவு கிடைப்பது பிரச்சினையாக மாறியுள்ளதாக ரொய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி நிறுவனம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையால் பலரின் வாழ்வாதாரமும் ஆபத்தில் இருப்பதாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்திச் சேவை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலை அதிகரிப்பு காரணமாக குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் உண்ணும் உணவின் எண்ணிக்கையை குறைக்க வேண்டியுள்ளதாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.இலங்கையில் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் பணவீக்கம் 54.6 சதவீதமாகவும், போக்குவரத்து கட்டணங்கள் 128 சதவீதமாகவும், உணவுப் பணவீக்கம் 80.1 சதவீதமாகவும் இருந்தது. , உத்தியோகபூர்வ தரவு அறிக்கைகளை மேற்கோள் காட்டி செய்தி சேவை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "உலக சுகாதார ஸ்தாபனத்தினால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட சத்தான உணவை உண்பதற்காக இலங்கை குடும்பம் மாதம் ஒன்றுக்கு 93,675 முதல் 148,868 ரூபாய் வரை வருமானம் ஈட்ட வேண்டும் என உணவுப் பணவீக்கத்தைக் கணக்கிடுவதில் நிபுணரான பொருளாதார நிபுணர் ரெஹானா தவ்பிக் ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆனால் இலங்கைக் குடும்பம் ஒன்றின் சராசரி வருமானம் மாதாந்தம் 76,414 ரூபா எனவும் இலங்கை சனத்தொகையில் 20 வீதமான வறிய குடும்பத்தின் மாத வருமானம் 17,572 ரூபா எனவும் உத்தியோகபூர்வ தரவு அறிக்கைகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடி நிலை காரணமாக மரக்கறிகளின் விலை இரண்டு மடங்காக அதிகரித்துள்ளதுடன் கடந்த வருடம் 145 ரூபாவாக இருந்த ஒரு கிலோ அரிசியின் விலை இன்று 230 ரூபாவாக மாறியுள்ளதாக ரொய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "128 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "80.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரெஹானா தவ்பிக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93,675",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "148,868",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "76,414",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,572",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "230",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}