{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Party-leaders-to-meet-shortly/56-737280",
  "time_ut": 1657362413,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Party leaders to meet shortly",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Party leaders to meet shortly",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Party Leaders' meeting is scheduled to take place at 4.00 p.m. today.",
        "The move follows Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe requesting all leaders of parties represented in Parliament to meet to resolve the current political impasse.",
        "The PM also requested the Speaker to convene Parliament soon.",
        "A group of government MPs also called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to resign immediately. In a letter addressed to the President, 16 Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) MPs have called on him to provide the opportunity for a mature leader without allegations of corruption.",
        "They also point out the need to provide the opportunity for a leader who can win a clear Parliamentary majority representing Parliament.",
        "Frantic efforts follow anti-Rajapaksa protestors in thousands breaking into the President's House and Presidential Secretariat calling for his and interim-Government's resignation over the failure to resolve the worst economic crisis in the country. President Rajapaksa wasn't present in either of the locations and his whereabouts are unknown.",
        "Millions thronged to Galle Face and Fort area from today morning as the anti-Rajapaksa people's movement  via GotaGoHome and GotaGoGama marked three months."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "4.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Frantic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "anti-Rajapaksa",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "GotaGoGama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තව නොබෝ දිනකින් පක්ෂ නායක හමුවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීම සවස 4.00 ට පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය. අද.",
        "පවතින දේශපාලන අර්බුදය විසඳා ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින් රැස්වන ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුවයි මෙම පියවර ගෙන ඇත්තේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කඩිනමින් කැඳවන ලෙස ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා කථානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා.",
        "ආණ්ඩුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් ද ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙසයි. දූෂණ චෝදනාවලින් තොර පරිණත නායකයෙකුට අවස්ථාව සලසන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 16 දෙනෙකු ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත ලිපියක් යොමු කරමින් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන පැහැදිලි පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරයක් දිනාගත හැකි නායකයෙකුට අවස්ථාව සැලසීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය ද ඔවුන් පෙන්වා දෙනවා.",
        "රටේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමට අසමත් වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහුගේ සහ අන්තර්වාර-ආණ්ඩුවේ ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු යැයි කියමින් දහස් ගණනින් රාජපක්ෂ විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදීමෙන් වියරු ප්‍රයත්නයන් අනුගමනය කරයි. ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ එම ස්ථාන දෙකෙහිම නොසිටි අතර ඔහු සිටින ස්ථානය නොදනී.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ විරෝධී ජනතා ව්‍යාපාරය GotaGoHome සහ GotaGoGama හරහා මාස තුනක් සපිරීමත් සමඟ අද උදෑසන සිට ගාලුමුවදොර සහ කොටුව ප්‍රදේශයට මිලියන ගණනක් රොක් වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "4.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වියරුයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ විරෝධී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාගෝගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் விரைவில் சந்திப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் மாலை 4.00 மணிக்கு நடைபெற உள்ளது. இன்று.",
        "தற்போதைய அரசியல் முட்டுக்கட்டைக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களும் ஒன்று கூடுமாறு பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கோரிக்கை விடுத்ததை அடுத்து இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை விரைவில் கூட்டுமாறு சபாநாயகரிடம் பிரதமர் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரியுள்ளது. ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் 16 எம்.பி.க்கள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அனுப்பியுள்ள கடிதத்தில், ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் இல்லாத முதிர்ந்த தலைவருக்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்குமாறு கோரியுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் தெளிவான பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை வெல்லக்கூடிய தலைவருக்கு சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தையும் அவர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்கத் தவறியதற்காக ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தின் பதவி விலகக் கோரி ஆயிரக்கணக்கான ராஜபக்ச எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து வெறித்தனமான முயற்சிகள். ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ச இரண்டு இடங்களிலும் இல்லை மற்றும் அவர் இருக்கும் இடம் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "கோட்டகோஹோம் மற்றும் கோட்டகோகம ஊடாக ராஜபக்சவுக்கு எதிரான மக்கள் இயக்கம் மூன்று மாதங்கள் நிறைவடைந்ததையடுத்து இன்று காலை முதல் காலிமுகத்திடலுக்கும் கோட்டைப் பகுதிக்கும் மில்லியன் கணக்கானோர் குவிந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெறித்தனமான",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ஷ எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டகோகாமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}