{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/over-1-000-people-killed-by-pakistan-monsoon-rains-and-floods/",
  "time_ut": 1661756400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Over 1,000 people killed by Pakistan monsoon rains and floods",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Over 1,000 people killed by Pakistan monsoon rains and floods",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(CNN); Pakistan needs financial help to deal with \"overwhelming\" floods, its foreign minister said on Sunday (Aug 28), adding that he hoped financial institutions such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) would take the economic fallout into account.",
        "Unusually heavy monsoon rains have caused devastating floods in the country's north and south, affecting more than 30 million people and killing more than 1,000.",
        "\"I haven't seen the destruction of this scale, I find it very difficult to put into words … it is overwhelming,\" said Pakistan's Foreign Minister Bilawal Bhutto-Zardari in an interview with Reuters, adding many crops that provided much of the population's livelihoods had been wiped out.",
        "The South Asian nation was already in an economic crisis, facing high inflation, a depreciating currency, and a current account deficit.",
        "The IMF board will decide this week on whether to release US$1.2 billion as part of the seventh and eighth tranches of Pakistan's bailout program, which it entered in 2019.",
        "Bhutto-Zardari said the board was expected to approve the release given an agreement between Pakistani officials and IMF staff had already been reached and he hoped in coming months the IMF would recognize the impact of the floods.",
        "\"Going forward, I would expect not only the IMF, but the international community and international agencies to truly grasp the level of devastation,\" he said.",
        "Bhutto-Zardari, the son of assassinated former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto, said the economic impact was still being assessed, but that some estimates had put it at US$4 billion. Given the impact on infrastructure and people's livelihoods, he expected the total figure to be much higher.",
        "Pakistan's central bank had already flagged the record monsoon rainfall as a threat to economic output given its impact on agriculture.",
        "Pakistan would this week launch an appeal asking United Nations member states to contribute to relief efforts, Bhutto-Zardari said, and the country needed to look at how it would handle the longer-term impacts of climate change.",
        "\"In the next phase, when we look towards rehabilitation and reconstruction, we will have conversations not only with the IMF but with the World Bank, the Asian Development Bank,” Bhutto-Zardari said.",
        "Bhutto-Zardari said after relief efforts, the country would have to look at how to develop infrastructure that was more resistant to both floods and droughts and address the huge changes faced by the agriculture sector.",
        "\"Even though Pakistan contributes negligible amounts to the overall carbon footprint … we are devastated by climate disasters such as these time and time again, and we have to adapt within our limited resources, however, we can, to live in this new environment,\" he said.",
        "Over 1,000 people killed by Pakistan monsoon rains and floods"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Pakistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 30 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bilawal Bhutto-Zardari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$1.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "seventh",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bhutto-Zardari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bhutto-Zardari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Benazir Bhutto",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bhutto-Zardari",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Development Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bhutto-Zardari",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bhutto-Zardari",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පකිස්ථානයේ මෝසම් වැසි සහ ගංවතුර හේතුවෙන් 1000කට අධික පිරිසක් මිය ගියහ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(සීඑන්එන්); පකිස්ථානයට \"අධික\" ගංවතුර සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට මූල්‍ය ආධාර අවශ්‍ය බව එහි විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉරිදා (අගෝස්තු 28) ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) වැනි මූල්‍ය ආයතන ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීම සැලකිල්ලට ගනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ය.",
        "අසාමාන්‍ය ලෙස ඇද හැලෙන අධික මෝසම් වර්ෂාව නිසා රටේ උතුරේ සහ දකුණේ විනාශකාරී ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇති වී ඇති අතර, මිලියන 30කට අධික ජනතාවකට බලපෑම් එල්ල වී ඇති අතර 1,000කට අධික පිරිසක් ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "\"මෙම පරිමාණයේ විනාශය මම දැක නැත, මට වචන වලින් පැවසීම ඉතා අපහසුයි ... එය අතිමහත් ය\" යනුවෙන් පකිස්ථාන විදේශ අමාත්‍ය බිලාවල් භූතෝ-සර්දාරි රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් කියා සිටියේ ජනගහනයෙන් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබා දුන් බොහෝ බෝග එකතු කරමිනි. ජීවනෝපායන් අතුගා දමා තිබුණි.",
        "ඉහළ උද්ධමනයකට, අවප්‍රමාණය වන මුදල් ඒකකයකට සහ ජංගම ගිණුමේ හිඟයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් දකුණු ආසියාතික ජාතිය දැනටමත් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක සිටියේය.",
        "2019 දී ඇතුල් වූ පකිස්තානයේ ඇපදීමේ වැඩසටහනේ හත්වන සහ අටවන වාරිකයේ කොටසක් ලෙස ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.2 නිදහස් කරන්නේද යන්න පිළිබඳව IMF මණ්ඩලය මෙම සතියේ තීරණය කරනු ඇත.",
        "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි පැවසුවේ පාකිස්තාන නිලධාරීන් සහ IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අතර එකඟතාවක් ලබා දී නිදහස් කිරීම සඳහා මණ්ඩලය අනුමත කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත් ඉදිරි මාසවලදී ගංවතුරේ බලපෑම IMF හඳුනා ගනු ඇතැයි ඔහු බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත්ය.",
        "\"ඉදිරියේදී, IMF පමණක් නොව, ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර නියෝජිතායතන විනාශයේ මට්ටම සැබවින්ම ග්‍රහණය කර ගනු ඇතැයි මම අපේක්ෂා කරමි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ හිටපු අගමැතිනි බෙනාසීර් භූතෝගේ පුත් භූතෝ-සර්දාරි පැවසුවේ ආර්ථික බලපෑම තවමත් තක්සේරු කරමින් පවතින නමුත් සමහර ඇස්තමේන්තු අනුව එය ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4ක් ලෙස ගණන් බලා ඇති බවයි. යටිතල පහසුකම් සහ මිනිසුන්ගේ ජීවනෝපායන් කෙරෙහි ඇති බලපෑම සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන, ඔහු මුළු අගය බොහෝ වැඩි වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කළේය.",
        "පාකිස්තානයේ මහ බැංකුව දැනටමත් වාර්තාගත මෝසම් වර්ෂාපතනය කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයට එහි බලපෑම අනුව ආර්ථික නිෂ්පාදනයට තර්ජනයක් ලෙස සලකුණු කර ඇත.",
        "පකිස්ථානය මේ සතියේ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සාමාජික රටවලින් සහන කටයුතු සඳහා දායක වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා අභියාචනයක් දියත් කරන බව භූතෝ-සර්දාරි පැවසීය, දේශගුණික විපර්යාසවල දිගුකාලීන බලපෑම් සමඟ කටයුතු කරන්නේ කෙසේදැයි රට සොයා බැලිය යුතුය.",
        "“ඊළඟ අදියරේදී, අපි පුනරුත්ථාපනය සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය දෙස බලන විට, අපි IMF සමඟ පමණක් නොව, ලෝක බැංකුව, ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරන්නෙමු,” භූතෝ-සර්දාරි පැවසීය.",
        "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි පැවසුවේ සහන ප්‍රයත්නයන්ගෙන් පසුව, ගංවතුර සහ නියඟ දෙකටම වඩා ප්‍රතිරෝධී වන යටිතල පහසුකම් සංවර්ධනය කරන්නේ කෙසේද සහ කෘෂිකාර්මික ක්ෂේත්‍රය මුහුණ දෙන විශාල වෙනස්කම් වලට විසඳුම් ලබා දෙන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව රටට සොයා බැලිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "\"පකිස්තානය සමස්ත කාබන් පියසටහනට නොසැලකිය හැකි ප්‍රමාණවලින් දායක වුවද ... අපි නැවත නැවතත් මෙවැනි දේශගුණික විපත්වලින් විනාශයට පත් වී සිටින අතර, අපගේ සීමිත සම්පත් තුළ අපට අනුගත විය යුතුය, කෙසේ වෙතත්, අපට මෙම නව පරිසරය තුළ ජීවත් වීමට හැකි වේ.\" ඔහු කිව්වා.",
        "පකිස්ථානයේ මෝසම් වැසි සහ ගංවතුර හේතුවෙන් 1000කට අධික පිරිසක් මිය ගියහ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 30 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලාවල් භූතෝ-සර්දාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙනාසීර් භූතෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4ක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සංවර්ධන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භූතෝ-සර්දාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தானில் பெய்த மழை மற்றும் வெள்ளத்தால் 1,000க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(சிஎன்என்); \"மிகப்பெரும்\" வெள்ளத்தைச் சமாளிக்க பாகிஸ்தானுக்கு நிதி உதவி தேவை, அதன் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (ஆகஸ்ட் 28) கூறினார், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) போன்ற நிதி நிறுவனங்கள் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியை கணக்கில் எடுத்துக்கொள்ளும் என்று நம்புவதாகவும் கூறினார்.",
        "வழக்கத்திற்கு மாறான கனமழை காரணமாக நாட்டின் வடக்கு மற்றும் தெற்கில் பேரழிவுகரமான வெள்ளம் ஏற்பட்டு 30 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்கள் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர் மற்றும் 1,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "\"இந்த அளவின் அழிவை நான் பார்க்கவில்லை, வார்த்தைகளில் கூறுவது எனக்கு மிகவும் கடினமாக உள்ளது ... இது மிகப்பெரியது\" என்று பாகிஸ்தானின் வெளியுறவு மந்திரி பிலாவல் பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி ராய்ட்டர்ஸுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியில் கூறினார். வாழ்வாதாரங்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "தெற்காசிய நாடு ஏற்கனவே பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்தது, அதிக பணவீக்கம், தேய்மானம் மற்றும் நடப்புக் கணக்கு பற்றாக்குறை ஆகியவற்றை எதிர்கொள்கிறது.",
        "2019 இல் நுழைந்த பாகிஸ்தானின் பிணை எடுப்புத் திட்டத்தின் ஏழாவது மற்றும் எட்டாவது தவணைகளின் ஒரு பகுதியாக 1.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை வெளியிடுவது குறித்து IMF வாரியம் இந்த வாரம் முடிவு செய்யும்.",
        "பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி, பாக்கிஸ்தான் அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் IMF ஊழியர்களுக்கும் இடையே ஒப்பந்தம் ஏற்கனவே எட்டப்பட்டுவிட்டதால், இந்த வெளியீட்டை வாரியம் அங்கீகரிக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும், வரும் மாதங்களில் IMF வெள்ளத்தின் பாதிப்பை அங்கீகரிக்கும் என்று நம்புவதாகவும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும்போது, ​​IMF மட்டுமல்ல, சர்வதேச சமூகமும் சர்வதேச நிறுவனங்களும் பேரழிவின் அளவை உண்மையாகப் புரிந்துகொள்ளும் என்று நான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட முன்னாள் பிரதம மந்திரி பெனாசிர் பூட்டோவின் மகன் பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி, பொருளாதார தாக்கம் இன்னும் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும், ஆனால் சில மதிப்பீடுகள் 4 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் எனக் கூறுவதாகக் கூறினார். உள்கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் மக்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தின் மீதான தாக்கத்தை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, மொத்த எண்ணிக்கை மிக அதிகமாக இருக்கும் என்று அவர் எதிர்பார்த்தார்.",
        "பாக்கிஸ்தானின் மத்திய வங்கி ஏற்கனவே பருவமழையின் சாதனையை பொருளாதார உற்பத்திக்கு அச்சுறுத்தலாகக் கூறியது.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் உறுப்பு நாடுகளை நிவாரண முயற்சிகளுக்கு பங்களிக்குமாறு பாகிஸ்தான் இந்த வாரம் ஒரு முறையீட்டைத் தொடங்கும், பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி கூறினார், மேலும் காலநிலை மாற்றத்தின் நீண்டகால தாக்கங்களை அது எவ்வாறு கையாளும் என்பதை நாடு பார்க்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "\"அடுத்த கட்டத்தில், நாங்கள் மறுவாழ்வு மற்றும் மறுகட்டமைப்பைப் பார்க்கும்போது, ​​IMF உடன் மட்டுமல்லாமல், உலக வங்கி, ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கியுடன் நாங்கள் உரையாடுவோம்\" என்று பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி கூறினார்.",
        "புட்டோ-சர்தாரி நிவாரணப் பணிகளுக்குப் பிறகு, வெள்ளம் மற்றும் வறட்சி ஆகிய இரண்டையும் எதிர்க்கும் உள்கட்டமைப்பை எவ்வாறு மேம்படுத்துவது மற்றும் விவசாயத் துறை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பெரும் மாற்றங்களை நிவர்த்தி செய்வது எப்படி என்று நாடு பார்க்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "\"ஒட்டுமொத்த கார்பன் அடிச்சுவடுக்கு பாக்கிஸ்தான் மிகக் குறைவான பங்களிப்பை அளித்தாலும் ... இது போன்ற காலநிலை பேரழிவுகளால் நாம் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் பேரழிவிற்கு ஆளாகிறோம், மேலும் நமது வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட வளங்களுக்குள் நாம் மாற்றியமைக்க வேண்டும், இருப்பினும், இந்த புதிய சூழலில் வாழ முடியும்.\" அவன் சொன்னான்.",
        "பாகிஸ்தானில் பெய்த மழை மற்றும் வெள்ளத்தால் 1,000க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலாவல் பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$1.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெனாசிர் பூட்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூட்டோ-சர்தாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}