{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉන්දියාවේ-නව-ජනපති-ද්‍රෞපදී-මුර්මු/101-616863",
  "time_ut": 1658470977,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දියාවේ නව ජනපති ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Draupadi Murmu is the new President of India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "With the aim of electing the 15th president, the Indian presidential election was held on the 18th, and the results were released last night (21st).",
        "A woman managed to achieve a magnificent and historic victory in the presidential election. She is Draupadi Murmu, 64 years old.",
        "Draupadi Murmu is a woman representing the tribal community of the Indian state of Odisha.",
        "Accordingly, this is the first time that a woman representing the tribal community of India won the presidency. Draupadi Murmu will be sworn in as the new president on the 25th.",
        "According to the Constitution of India, the President of the country is elected not by popular vote, but by parliamentary vote. The central government of India is divided into two parts namely Lok Sabha (House of Representatives) and Raj Sabha (Upper House).",
        "The President is elected by the votes of the members of the Lok Sabha and the Raj Sabha and the representatives of the state councils.",
        "The role of the President of India is very important. The President is the formative leader of the Indian Executive, Legislature and Judiciary.",
        "The tenure of the President of India is 5 years. Draupadi Murmu contested the presidential election representing Prime Minister Narendra Modi's Bharatiya Janata Party-led National Democratic Alliance. Murmu's opponent was the 84-year-old Yashwant Sinha, who ran for the presidential election representing the opposition political groups led by the United Progressive Alliance. This is the second time that a woman has won the presidency of India.",
        "Pratibha Patil was the first woman to become the President of India. She was the 12th President of India and her tenure was from 2007 to 2012. Pratibha Patil is a member of the Indian Congress Party; A lawyer.",
        "Draupadi Murmu is a BJP member and she is also a teacher. She also served as the Governor of Jharkhand from 2015 to 2021. With the victory confirmed, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi met Draupadi Murmu and congratulated her.",
        "A vote will also be held in Parliament for the post of Vice President of India. That is next August. This year, Jagdeep Dankar from the ruling party alliance and Margaret Alva from the opposition alliance are going to run for the post of vice president."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 18th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Odisha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House of Representatives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Raj Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upper House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bharatiya Janata Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Democratic Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "84-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Congress Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jharkhand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "from 2015 to 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Margaret Alva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ නව ජනපති ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "15 වැනි ජනාධිපති තෝරාපත් කර ගැනීමේ අරමුණින්, ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරණය පසුගිය 18 වැනිදා පැවැත්වුණු අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කිරීම ඊයේ (21) රාත්‍රියේ සිදුවිය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණයෙන් අති විශිෂ්ට, ඓතිහාසික ජයක් අත්පත් කර ගැනීමට සමත් වූයේ කාන්තාවකි. ඇය 64 හැවිරිදි ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ය.",
        "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු, ඉන්දියාවේ ඔඩිස්සා ප්‍රාන්තයේ ගෝත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව නියෝජනය කරන කාන්තාවකි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, ඉන්දියාවේ ගෝත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව නියෝජනය කරන කාන්තාවක විශිෂ්ට ජයක් හිමි කර ගනිමින්, ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් වුණු පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු නව ජනාධිපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙන්නේත් ලබන 25 වැනිදාය.",
        "ඉන්දියානු ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත්කර ගනු ලබන්නේ මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් නොව, පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයෙනි. ඉන්දීය මධ්‍යම ආණ්ඩුව ලෝක් සභාව (නියෝජිත මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩලය) සහ රාජ් සභාව (ඉහළ මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩලය) ආදී වශයෙන් කොටස් දෙකකි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සිදුවන්නේ, ලෝක් සභාවේත්, රාජ් සභාවේත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඡන්දයෙන් සහ ප්‍රාන්ත මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩල නියෝජිතයන්ගේ ඡන්දයෙනි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ කාර්යභාරය ඉතා වැදගත්ය.ඉන්දීය විධායකයේ, ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයේ සහ අධිකරණයේ ආකෘතික නායකයා වන්නේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ධුර කාලය වසර 5 කි. ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වූයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය නියෝජනය කරමිනි. මුර්මුගේ ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූයේ එක්සත් ප්‍රගතශීලී සන්ධානය ප්‍රමුඛ විපක්ෂ දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් නියෝජනය කරමින් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වුණු අපේක්ෂක 84 හැවිරිදි යෂ්වාන්ත් සිංහා ය. ඉන්දියාවේ ජනාධිපති ධුරය කාන්තාවකට හිමිවුණු දෙවැනි අවස්ථාව මෙයයි.",
        "මීට පෙර ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් වුණු කාන්තාව ප්‍රතිභා පාතිල් ය. ඇය ඉන්දියාවේ 12 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා වූ අතර ඇගේ ධුර කාලය 2007 සිට 2012 දක්වාය. ප්‍රතිභා පාතිල් ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකාවකි; නීතීඥවරියකි.",
        "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂ සාමාජිකාවක වන අතර ඇය ගුරුවරියක ද වෙයි. 2015 සිට 2021 තෙක් කාලයේ ජර්කාන්ද් ප්‍රාන්ත ආණ්ඩුකාරවරිය ලෙස කටයුතු කළේ ද ඇයයි. ජයග්‍රහණය තහවුරු වීමත් සමඟ ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි, ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු හමුවී ඇයට සුබ පැතුවේය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ උප ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා ද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයක් පැවැත්වෙයි. ඒ එලඹෙන අගෝස්තු මාසයේය. මෙවර උප ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා පාලක පක්ෂ සන්ධානයෙන් ජග්දීප් දන්කාර් සහ විපක්ෂ සන්ධානයෙන් මාග්‍රට් අල්වා ඉදිරිපත් වීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 64 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔඩිෂා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිත මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු විධායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 5 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "84 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාර්කන්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 සිට 2021 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දන්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාග්‍රට් අල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திரௌபதி முர்மு இந்தியாவின் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "15வது ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் நோக்கில், இந்திய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் கடந்த 18ம் தேதி நடத்தப்பட்டு, முடிவுகள் நேற்று (21ம் தேதி) இரவு வெளியாகின.",
        "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் ஒரு பெண் ஒரு அற்புதமான மற்றும் வரலாற்று வெற்றியைப் பெற முடிந்தது. அவர் திரௌபதி முர்மு, 64 வயது.",
        "திரௌபதி முர்மு இந்திய மாநிலமான ஒடிசாவின் பழங்குடி சமூகத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பெண்.",
        "அதன்படி, இந்தியாவின் பழங்குடியின சமூகத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பெண் ஒருவர் ஜனாதிபதியாக வெற்றி பெறுவது இதுவே முதல் முறை. புதிய அதிபராக திரௌபதி முர்மு வரும் 25ம் தேதி பதவியேற்கிறார்.",
        "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின்படி, நாட்டின் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மக்களால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவதில்லை, மாறாக நாடாளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகிறார். இந்திய மத்திய அரசு மக்களவை (பிரதிநிதிகள் சபை) மற்றும் ராஜ் சபா (மேல்சபை) என இரண்டு பகுதிகளாக பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மக்களவை மற்றும் ராஜ்சபா உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் மாநில கவுன்சில்களின் பிரதிநிதிகளின் வாக்குகளால் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகிறார்.",
        "இந்திய ஜனாதிபதியின் பங்கு மிகவும் முக்கியமானது.இந்திய நிறைவேற்று, சட்டமன்றம் மற்றும் நீதித்துறையின் உருவாக்கத் தலைவர் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ஆவார்.",
        "இந்திய ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவிக்காலம் 5 ஆண்டுகள். பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடியின் பாரதிய ஜனதா தலைமையிலான தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி சார்பில் திரௌபதி முர்மு குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்டார். முர்முவின் எதிரியான 84 வயதான யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா, ஐக்கிய முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணியின் தலைமையிலான எதிர்க்கட்சி அரசியல் குழுக்களின் பிரதிநிதியாக ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்டார். இந்திய ஜனாதிபதியாக பெண் ஒருவர் வெற்றி பெறுவது இது இரண்டாவது முறையாகும்.",
        "இந்தியாவின் குடியரசுத் தலைவரான முதல் பெண்மணி பிரதீபா பாட்டீல் ஆவார். அவர் இந்தியாவின் 12 வது ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்தார், மேலும் அவரது பதவிக்காலம் 2007 முதல் 2012 வரை இருந்தது. பிரதிபா பாட்டீல் இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர்; ஒரு வழக்கறிஞர்.",
        "திரௌபதி முர்மு ஒரு பாஜக உறுப்பினர் மற்றும் அவர் ஒரு ஆசிரியரும் கூட. 2015 முதல் 2021 வரை ஜார்க்கண்ட் ஆளுநராகவும் பணியாற்றினார். வெற்றி உறுதி செய்யப்பட்ட நிலையில், இந்திய பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி திரௌபதி முர்முவை சந்தித்து வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்திய துணை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வாக்கெடுப்பும் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறும். அது அடுத்த ஆகஸ்ட். இந்த ஆண்டு துணைத் தலைவர் பதவிக்கு ஆளும் கட்சி கூட்டணியில் இருந்து ஜெகதீப் டாங்கரும், எதிர்க்கட்சி கூட்டணி சார்பில் மார்கரெட் ஆல்வாவும் போட்டியிட உள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒடிசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதிநிதிகள் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜ் சபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "84 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்கண்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 முதல் 2021 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்கரெட் அல்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}