{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/சிசில்-வசந்த-பிணையில்-விடுதலை/175-303194",
  "time_ut": 1661772533,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சிசில் வசந்த பிணையில் விடுதலை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cecil Spring released on bail",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe today (29) ordered the police to submit a report on the progress of investigations in the case against three suspects, including Danis Ali, accused of trespassing into the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation and disrupting broadcasts.",
        "When the Magistrate's hearing was held today, Karuwathottam Police informed the court that the investigations on the first suspect, Danis Ali, have not yet been completed.",
        "Accordingly, the judge directed the police to submit a report on the progress of investigations on September 26.",
        "Also, the judge ordered the release of Cecil Vasantha, who was arrested and remanded in connection with the incident, on a cash bail of 25,000 rupees and 2 body bonds worth 5 lakh rupees each.",
        "It is noteworthy that on July 26, Danis Ali was arrested on board a SriLankan Airlines flight from Katunayake International Airport to Dubai."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danis Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karuwathottam Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Danis Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cecil Vasantha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිසිල් වසන්ත ඇප මත මුදා හැරියේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට අනවසරයෙන් ඇතුළු වී විකාශන කටයුතුවලට බාධා කළ බවට චෝදනා ලැබ සිටින ඩැනිස් අලි ඇතුළු විත්තිකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකුට එරෙහි නඩුවේ විමර්ශනවල ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳ වාර්තාවක් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා අද (29) පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගේ සාක්ෂි විභාගය අද පැවති අවස්ථාවේදී කරුවාතෝට්ටම් පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට දන්වා සිටියේ පළමු සැකකරු වන ඩැනිස් අලි සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන පරීක්ෂණ මෙතෙක් අවසන් වී නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව විමර්ශනවල ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳ වාර්තාවක් සැප්තැම්බර් 26 වැනිදා අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස විනිසුරුවරයා පොලිසියට නියම කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කර සිටින සිසිල් වසන්ත රුපියල් 25,000ක මුදල් ඇප සහ රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 5 බැගින් වූ ශරීර බැඳුම්කර දෙකක් මත මුදා හැරීමට විනිසුරුවරයා නියෝග කළා.",
        "පසුගිය ජූලි 26 වැනිදා කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ සිට ඩුබායි බලා පිටත්ව ගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකදී ඩැනිස් අලි අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩැනිස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරුවාතෝට්ටම් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩැනිස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිසිල් වසන්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிசில் வசந்த பிணையில் விடுதலை",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்துக்குள் அத்துமீறி நுழைந்து ஒளிபரப்புக்கு இடையூறு விளைவித்தனர் என்று குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்ட டனிஸ் அலி உள்ளிட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவருக்கு எதிரான வழக்கில், விசாரணைகளின் முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க, பொலிஸாருக்கு, இன்று (29) கட்டளையிட்டார்.",
        "இன்றையதினம் நீதவான் விசாரணை இடம்பெற்ற போது, முதலாவது சந்தேகநபரான டனிஸ் அலி குறித்த விசாரணைகள் இன்னும் முடிவடையவில்லை என்று கறுவாத்தோட்டம் பொலிஸார், மன்றுக்கு அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதற்கமைய எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் 26 ஆம் திகதியன்று, விசாரணைகளின் முன்னேற்றம் குறித்த அறிக்கையை சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு பொலிஸாருக்கு நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "அத்துடன், சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கைது செய்யப்பபட்டு விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த சிசில் வசந்த என்ற சந்கேநபரை 25,000 ரூபாய் ரொக்கப் பிணையிலும் 5 இலட்சம் ரூபாய் பெறுமதியான 2 சரீரப் பிணைகளிலும் விடுவிக்குமாறு நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 26ஆம் திகதியன்று கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து டுபாய் நோக்கி புறப்பட இருந்த ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் வைத்து டனிஸ் அலி கைது செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவாத்தோட்டம் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிசில் வசந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}