{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83967/china-defends-military-ships-planned-visit-to-sri-lanka-as-india-voices-concern",
  "time_ut": 1659120840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China defends military ship’s planned visit to Sri Lanka as India voices concern",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China defends military ship’s planned visit to Sri Lanka as India voices concern",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China said on Friday it hoped “relevant parties” would refrain from interfering with its legitimate maritime activities, after New Delhi voiced concern over a Chinese military ship’s planned visit to a port in India’s southern neighbour Sri Lanka.",
        "India worries that the Chinese-built and leased port of Hambantota will be used by China as a military base in India’s backyard. The $1.5 billion port is near the main shipping route from Asia to Europe.",
        "Shipping data from Refinitiv Eikon showed Chinese research and survey vessel Yuan Wang 5 was en route to Hambantota and due to arrive on Aug. 11, at a time when Sri Lanka is facing its worst economic crisis in seven decades. India has provided Sri Lanka with nearly $4 billion in support this year alone.",
        "During a weekly briefing late on Thursday, an Indian foreign ministry spokesman said the government was monitoring the planned visit of the Chinese ship, adding that New Delhi would protect its security and economic interests.",
        "India has already lodged a verbal protest with the Sri Lankan government against the ship’s visit, Reuters reported on Thursday.",
        "In response to questions from Reuters, China’s foreign ministry said Beijing had always exercised freedom of the high seas lawfully.",
        "“China hopes that the relevant parties will view and report on China’s marine scientific research activities correctly and refrain from interfering with normal and legitimate maritime activities,” the ministry said in a statement.",
        "Relations between India and China have been strained since armed clashes on their border two years ago killed at least 20 Indian and four Chinese soldiers and led to a massive build-up of troops on both sides.",
        "Foreign security analysts describe the Yuan Wang 5 as one of China’s latest generation space-tracking ships, used to monitor satellite, rocket and intercontinental ballistic missile launches.",
        "The Pentagon’s annual report on China’s military modernisation says the Yuan Wang ships are operated by the Strategic Support Force of the People’s Liberation Army (PLA).",
        "A Sri Lankan consulting firm, the Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka, said on its website that the Yuan Wang 5 would be in Hambantota for a week and “conduct space tracking, satellite control and research tracking in the northwestern part of the Indian Ocean region through August and September”.",
        "Sri Lanka formally handed over commercial activities at its main southern port to a Chinese company in 2017 on a 99-year lease after struggling to repay its debt.",
        "China is one of Sri Lanka’s biggest lenders and has also funded airports, roads and railways, unnerving India, which is now trying to claw back lost ground.",
        "Sri Lanka angered India in 2014 when it allowed a Chinese submarine and a warship to dock in Colombo."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Refinitiv Eikon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aug. 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly $4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year alone",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pentagon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Liberation Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටින අතර, චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදා නෞකාවේ සැලසුම් සහගත සංචාරය ආරක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ දකුණු අසල්වැසි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වරායකට චීන හමුදා නෞකාවක් සැලසුම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් නව දිල්ලිය විසින් කනස්සල්ල පළ කිරීමෙන් පසු “අදාළ පාර්ශ්වයන්” එහි නීත්‍යානුකූල නාවික කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් වීමෙන් වැළකී සිටිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව චීනය සිකුරාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "චීනය විසින් ඉදිකරන ලද සහ බදු දී ඇති හම්බන්තොට වරාය චීනය විසින් ඉන්දියාවේ මිදුලේ හමුදා කඳවුරක් ලෙස භාවිතා කරනු ඇතැයි ඉන්දියාව කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටී. ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 ක වරායක් ආසියාවේ සිට යුරෝපයට යන ප්‍රධාන නැව් මාර්ගයට ආසන්නයි.",
        "Refinitiv Eikon වෙතින් නැව්ගත කිරීමේ දත්ත පෙන්නුම් කළේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දශක හතකට පසු දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින අවස්ථාවක, චීන පර්යේෂණ සහ සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් වන Yuan Wang 5 හම්බන්තොට බලා පැමිණෙමින් තිබූ අතර අගෝස්තු 11 වනදා පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ බවයි. ඉන්දියාව මේ වසරේ පමණක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් බිලියන 4කට ආසන්න ආධාරයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අගභාගයේදී සතිපතා පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු පැවසුවේ චීන නෞකාවේ සැලසුම්ගත සංචාරය රජය නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටින බවත්, නවදිල්ලිය එහි ආරක්ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා ආරක්ෂා කරන බවත්ය.",
        "නෞකාවේ සංචාරයට එරෙහිව ඉන්දියාව දැනටමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට වාචික විරෝධයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව රොයිටර් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයේ ප්‍රශ්නවලට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් චීනයේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය පැවසුවේ බීජිං සෑම විටම මහ මුහුදේ නිදහස නීත්‍යානුකූලව භාවිත කළ බවයි.",
        "\"අදාළ පාර්ශ්වයන් චීනයේ සාගර විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් නිවැරදිව නරඹා වාර්තා කරනු ඇතැයි චීනය බලාපොරොත්තු වන අතර සාමාන්‍ය හා නීත්‍යානුකූල නාවික කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් වීමෙන් වළකිනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් අමාත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "වසර දෙකකට පෙර ඔවුන්ගේ දේශසීමාවේ සන්නද්ධ ගැටුම් වලින් අවම වශයෙන් ඉන්දීය සොල්දාදුවන් 20 දෙනෙකු සහ චීන සොල්දාදුවන් හතර දෙනෙකු මිය ගිය අතර දෙපාර්ශවයේම දැවැන්ත හමුදා ගොඩ නැගීමකට තුඩු දීමෙන් ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය අතර සබඳතා පළුදු වී ඇත.",
        "විදේශ ආරක්ෂක විශ්ලේෂකයින් Yuan Wang 5 විස්තර කරන්නේ චන්ද්‍රිකා, රොකට් සහ අන්තර් මහද්වීපික බැලිස්ටික් මිසයිල දියත් කිරීම් නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීම සඳහා භාවිතා කරන චීනයේ නවතම පරම්පරාවේ අභ්‍යවකාශ ලුහුබැඳීමේ නෞකාවක් ලෙස ය.",
        "චීනයේ මිලිටරි නවීකරණය පිළිබඳ පෙන්ටගනයේ වාර්ෂික වාර්තාව පවසන්නේ යුවාන් වැන්ග් නැව් මෙහෙයවනු ලබන්නේ මහජන විමුක්ති හමුදාවේ (පීඑල්ඒ) උපායමාර්ගික ආධාරක බලකාය විසිනි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා උපදේශන සමාගමක් වන Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka සිය වෙබ් අඩවියේ සඳහන් කළේ යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 යානය සතියක කාලයක් හම්බන්තොට පවතින බවත් ඉන්දියන් සාගර කලාපයේ වයඹ දිග ප්‍රදේශයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ නිරීක්ෂණ, චන්ද්‍රිකා පාලනය සහ පර්යේෂණ ලුහුබැඳීම් සිදු කරන බවත්ය. අගෝස්තු සහ සැප්තැම්බර් හරහා.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ප්‍රධාන දකුණු වරායේ වාණිජ කටයුතු 2017 දී චීන සමාගමකට 99 අවුරුදු බදු පදනම මත නිල වශයෙන් භාර දුන්නේ සිය ණය ගෙවීමට අරගල කිරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාලතම ණය දෙන්නන්ගෙන් එකක් වන අතර ගුවන් තොටුපළවල්, මාර්ග සහ දුම්රිය සඳහා ද අරමුදල් සපයා ඇති අතර, දැන් අහිමි වූ භූමිය ආපසු ලබා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන ඉන්දියාව නොසන්සුන් කරයි.",
        "2014 දී චීනයේ සබ්මැරීනයකට සහ යුද නැවකට කොළඹට නැංගීමට ඉඩ දීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියාව කෝපයට පත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Refinitiv Eikon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ පමණක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙන්ටගනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තීරය සහ මාර්ග මුලපිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 99",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கான இராணுவக் கப்பலின் திட்டமிட்ட பயணத்தை இந்தியா கவலையுடன் தெரிவித்துள்ள நிலையில், சீனா அதனைப் பாதுகாத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவின் தெற்கு அண்டை நாடான இலங்கையில் உள்ள துறைமுகத்திற்கு சீன இராணுவக் கப்பலின் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வருகை குறித்து புது டெல்லி கவலை தெரிவித்ததை அடுத்து, \"சம்பந்தப்பட்ட கட்சிகள்\" அதன் சட்டபூர்வமான கடல்சார் நடவடிக்கைகளில் தலையிடுவதைத் தவிர்க்கும் என நம்புவதாக சீனா வெள்ளிக்கிழமை கூறியது.",
        "சீனாவால் கட்டப்பட்டு குத்தகைக்கு எடுக்கப்பட்ட ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை இந்தியாவின் கொல்லைப்புறத்தில் ராணுவ தளமாக சீனா பயன்படுத்திக்கொள்ளும் என இந்தியா கவலை கொண்டுள்ளது. $1.5 பில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள துறைமுகம் ஆசியாவில் இருந்து ஐரோப்பாவிற்கு செல்லும் முக்கிய கப்பல் பாதைக்கு அருகில் உள்ளது.",
        "ஏழு தசாப்தங்களில் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டிருக்கும் இவ்வேளையில், சீன ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் ஆய்வுக் கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 அம்பாந்தோட்டையை நோக்கி வந்துகொண்டிருந்ததாகவும் ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் திகதி வரவிருந்ததாகவும் Refinitiv Eikon இன் கப்பல் தரவுகள் காட்டுகின்றன. இந்த ஆண்டு மட்டும் இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா 4 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை உதவியாக வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "வியாழன் பிற்பகுதியில் ஒரு வாராந்திர மாநாட்டின் போது, ​​இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், சீனக் கப்பலின் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வருகையை அரசாங்கம் கண்காணித்து வருவதாகக் கூறினார், புது தில்லி அதன் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களைப் பாதுகாக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "கப்பலின் வருகைக்கு எதிராக இந்தியா ஏற்கனவே இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திடம் வாய்மொழி எதிர்ப்பை தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ராய்ட்டர்ஸின் கேள்விகளுக்குப் பதிலளித்த சீனாவின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம், பெய்ஜிங் எப்போதும் உயர் கடல்களின் சுதந்திரத்தை சட்டப்பூர்வமாகப் பயன்படுத்தியது.",
        "“சீனாவின் கடல்சார் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகளை சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினர் சரியாகப் பார்த்து அறிக்கை செய்வார்கள் என்றும், சாதாரண மற்றும் சட்டபூர்வமான கடல்சார் நடவடிக்கைகளில் தலையிடுவதைத் தவிர்ப்பார்கள் என்றும் சீனா நம்புகிறது,” என்று அமைச்சகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு தங்கள் எல்லையில் ஆயுதம் தாங்கிய மோதல்களில் குறைந்தது 20 இந்திய மற்றும் நான்கு சீன வீரர்கள் கொல்லப்பட்டதில் இருந்து இந்தியாவிற்கும் சீனாவிற்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகள் இறுக்கமடைந்துள்ளன, மேலும் இரு தரப்பிலும் துருப்புக்கள் பெருமளவில் குவிக்க வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு பாதுகாப்பு ஆய்வாளர்கள் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஐ சீனாவின் சமீபத்திய தலைமுறை விண்வெளி கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல்களில் ஒன்றாக விவரிக்கின்றனர், இது செயற்கைக்கோள், ராக்கெட் மற்றும் கண்டம் விட்டு கண்டம் பாயும் ஏவுகணை ஏவுதல்களை கண்காணிக்கப் பயன்படுகிறது.",
        "சீனாவின் இராணுவ நவீனமயமாக்கல் பற்றிய பென்டகனின் வருடாந்திர அறிக்கை யுவான் வாங் கப்பல்கள் மக்கள் விடுதலை இராணுவத்தின் (பிஎல்ஏ) மூலோபாய ஆதரவுப் படையால் இயக்கப்படுகிறது என்று கூறுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஆலோசனை நிறுவனமான Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka தனது இணையத்தளத்தில் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் ஒரு வாரம் இருக்கும் என்றும் “இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பிராந்தியத்தின் வடமேற்குப் பகுதியில் விண்வெளி கண்காணிப்பு, செயற்கைக்கோள் கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் ஆராய்ச்சி கண்காணிப்பு ஆகியவற்றை நடத்தும் என்றும் கூறியுள்ளது. ஆகஸ்ட் மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் வரை.\"",
        "கடனை அடைக்க முடியாமல் திணறிய இலங்கை தனது பிரதான தெற்கு துறைமுகத்தின் வர்த்தக நடவடிக்கைகளை 99 வருட குத்தகைக்கு 2017 இல் சீன நிறுவனத்திடம் கையளித்தது.",
        "சீனா இலங்கையின் மிகப்பெரிய கடன் வழங்குபவர்களில் ஒன்றாகும், மேலும் விமான நிலையங்கள், சாலைகள் மற்றும் ரயில் பாதைகளுக்கு நிதியளித்துள்ளது, இந்தியாவை கவலையடையச் செய்துள்ளது, இது இப்போது இழந்த நிலத்தை மீண்டும் பெற முயற்சிக்கிறது.",
        "2014ஆம் ஆண்டு சீனாவின் நீர்மூழ்கிக் கப்பலையும் போர்க்கப்பலையும் கொழும்பில் நிறுத்த அனுமதித்ததால் இலங்கை இந்தியாவைக் கோபப்படுத்தியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Refinitiv Eikon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மட்டும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐங்கோணம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎல்ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெல்ட் & ரோடு முன்முயற்சி இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "99-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}