{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Tamil-politicians-welcome-delisting-of-diaspora-organisations/56-738738",
  "time_ut": 1660595826,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tamil politicians welcome delisting of diaspora organisations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tamil politicians welcome delisting of diaspora organisations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "TNA says ban imposed was not according to prescribed procedure",
        "The Tamil National Alliance (TNA) Spokesman MP M.A. Sumanthiran says the party welcomes the delisting of some diaspora organisations and individuals from the terrorism list.",
        "The Ministry of Defence on Saturday announced it has decided to lift the ban imposed on six international Tamil organisations, namely the Australian Tamil Congress, Global Tamil Forum, World Dravidian Coordination Committee, Dravida Eelam People’s Congress, Canadian Tamil Congress and British Tamil Forum and another 316 persons.",
        "However, Sumanthiran noted that others who remain on the list have been included in the list without any supporting evidence to connect them to terrorism-related activities. He also said the authorities had not followed the prescribed procedure when banning the organisations and persons.",
        "Sumanthiran said he urged the Government to however continue this process of re-evaluating and de-proscribing all individuals and organisations who ought not to have been listed.",
        "The groups were earlier delisted during the tenure of former Foreign Affairs Minister Mangala Samaraweera following talks with representatives of the Tamil diaspora in 2015. The Government had delisted the organisations in an attempt to seek their support for the reconciliation process and development of the North. However, the ban was re-imposed following former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s rise to power.",
        "In a related development Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP Mano Ganesan said the decision made by the Government of President Ranil Wickremesinghe is a positive move. According to Ganesan, the international community will look upon Sri Lankan favourably as a result of it.",
        "Ganesan made these comments at a press conference held in Colombo yesterday. Mano Ganesan also said that if proper discussions are held with the diaspora, solutions can be provided to the country’s current financial crisis. He also offered to intervene on behalf of the Government to facilitate the talks with the diaspora. “The Government must think differently,” he said.",
        "Commenting on the delisting, Tamil Peoples’ National Alliance (TPNA) leader MP C.V. Vigneswaran said it is a good move by the Government. However, Vigneswaran also said the decision is perhaps an attempt by President Ranil Wickremesinghe to score points with the international community in exchange for support ahead of the upcoming UNHRC session."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.A. Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Australian Tamil Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Tamil Forum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Dravidian Coordination Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravida Eelam People’s Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian Tamil Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British Tamil Forum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "316",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthiran",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mangala Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Peoples’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "C.V. Vigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vigneswaran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධාන ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කිරීම දෙමළ දේශපාලනඥයන් සාදරයෙන් පිළිගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තහනම පැනවූයේ නියමිත පටිපාටියට අනුව නොවන බව TNA පවසයි",
        "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ (ටීඑන්ඒ) ප්‍රකාශක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන් මහතා පවසන්නේ ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයන් ත්‍රස්තවාදී ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කිරීම පක්ෂය සාදරයෙන් පිළිගන්නා බවයි.",
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියානු ද්‍රවිඩ කොංග්‍රසය, ගෝලීය ද්‍රවිඩ සංසදය, ලෝක ද්‍රවිඩ සම්බන්ධීකරණ කමිටුව, ද්‍රවිඩ ඊළාම් මහජන කොංග්‍රසය, කැනේඩියානු දෙමළ කොංග්‍රසය සහ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය දෙමළ සංසදය සහ තවත් ජාත්‍යන්තර දෙමළ සංවිධාන හයකට පනවා තිබූ තහනම ඉවත් කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය සෙනසුරාදා නිවේදනය කළේය. පුද්ගලයන් 316 දෙනෙක්.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සුමන්තිරන් සඳහන් කළේ ලැයිස්තුවේ රැඳී සිටින අනෙකුත් පුද්ගලයින් ත්‍රස්තවාදයට සම්බන්ධ ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට සම්බන්ධ කිරීමට කිසිදු සහායක සාක්ෂියක් නොමැතිව ලැයිස්තුවට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති බවයි. සංවිධාන සහ පුද්ගලයින් තහනම් කිරීමේදී බලධාරීන් නියමිත ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය අනුගමනය කර නොමැති බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "සුමන්තිරන් කියා සිටියේ ලැයිස්තුගත නොකළ යුතු සියලුම පුද්ගලයින් සහ සංවිධාන නැවත ඇගයීම සහ තහනම් කිරීමේ මෙම ක්‍රියාවලිය දිගටම කරගෙන යන ලෙස තමා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "2015 දී දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරාවේ නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලින් පසුව හිටපු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය මංගල සමරවීරගේ පාලන සමයේදී මෙම කණ්ඩායම් මීට පෙර ඉවත් කරන ලදී. උතුරේ සංහිඳියා ක්‍රියාවලියට සහ සංවර්ධනයට ඔවුන්ගේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස රජය එම සංවිධාන ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කර තිබුණි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බලයට පත්වීමත් සමඟ මෙම තහනම යළි පනවනු ලැබුවා.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනෝ ගනේෂන් කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ රජය ගත් තීරණය සාධනීය පියවරක් බවයි. ගනේෂන්ට අනුව ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දෙස යහපත් ලෙස බලනු ඇත.",
        "ගනේෂන් මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ ඊයේ කොළඹදී පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදීය. ඩයස්පෝරාව සමඟ නිසි ලෙස සාකච්ඡා කළහොත් රටේ වත්මන් මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් ලබාදිය හැකි බවද මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා පැවසීය. ඩයස්පෝරාව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා පහසුකම් සැලසීමට රජය වෙනුවෙන් මැදිහත් වීමට ද ඔහු ඉදිරිපත් විය. \"ආණ්ඩුව වෙනස් ලෙස සිතිය යුතුයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානයේ (TPNA) නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන් කියා සිටියේ එය රජයේ යහපත් ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එළඹෙන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිල සැසිවාරයට පෙර සහාය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව සමඟ ලකුණු රැස් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ගත් උත්සාහයක් මෙම තීරණය විය හැකි බව ද විග්නේෂ්වරන් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු දෙමළ කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය දෙමළ සංසදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ද්‍රවිඩ සම්බන්ධීකරණ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ ඊළාම් මහජන කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු දෙමළ කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය දෙමළ සංසදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "316",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මංගල සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගනේෂන් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාව'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புலம்பெயர் அமைப்புக்கள் பட்டியலில் இருந்து நீக்கப்படுவதை தமிழ் அரசியல்வாதிகள் வரவேற்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தடை விதிக்கப்பட்ட நடைமுறையின்படி தடை விதிக்கப்படவில்லை என்று TNA கூறுகிறது",
        "சில புலம்பெயர் அமைப்புக்கள் மற்றும் தனிநபர்கள் பயங்கரவாத பட்டியலில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்டதை தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் பேச்சாளர் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் வரவேற்கின்றார்.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியத் தமிழர் பேரவை, உலகத் தமிழர் பேரவை, உலக திராவிட ஒருங்கிணைப்புக் குழு, திராவிட ஈழ மக்கள் பேரவை, கனடியத் தமிழர் பேரவை, பிரித்தானியத் தமிழர் பேரவை ஆகிய 6 சர்வதேச தமிழ் அமைப்புக்களுக்கு விதிக்கப்பட்ட தடையை நீக்கத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு சனிக்கிழமை அறிவித்துள்ளது. 316 பேர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பட்டியலில் எஞ்சியிருக்கும் ஏனையவர்கள் பயங்கரவாதம் தொடர்பான நடவடிக்கைகளுடன் தொடர்புபடுத்துவதற்கான ஆதாரங்கள் எதுவுமின்றி பட்டியலில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சுமந்திரன் குறிப்பிட்டார். நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் நபர்களை தடை செய்யும் போது அதிகாரிகள் நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட நடைமுறையை பின்பற்றவில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பட்டியலிடப்படாத அனைத்து தனிநபர்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவனங்களின் மறு மதிப்பீடு மற்றும் தடை நீக்கும் இந்த செயல்முறையை தொடருமாறு அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்துவதாக சுமந்திரன் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் மங்கள சமரவீரவின் காலத்தில் 2015 ஆம் ஆண்டு புலம்பெயர்ந்த தமிழ் மக்களின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் நடத்திய பேச்சுவார்த்தையைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்தக் குழுக்கள் முன்னர் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டன. வடக்கின் நல்லிணக்கச் செயற்பாடுகள் மற்றும் அபிவிருத்திக்கு அவர்களின் ஆதரவைக் கோரும் முயற்சியில் அரசாங்கம் அந்த அமைப்புகளை பட்டியலிட்டிருந்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஆட்சிக்கு வந்ததை அடுத்து இந்தத் தடை மீண்டும் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசாங்கத்தினால் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானம் ஒரு சாதகமான நடவடிக்கை என சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். கணேசனின் கூற்றுப்படி, சர்வதேச சமூகம் இலங்கையை சாதகமாகப் பார்க்கும்.",
        "கொழும்பில் நேற்று நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போதே கணேசன் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். புலம்பெயர் மக்களுடன் முறையான கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்தினால், நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வுகளை வழங்க முடியும் என்றும் மனோ கணேசன் கூறினார். புலம்பெயர் மக்களுடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தையை எளிதாக்குவதற்கு அரசாங்கத்தின் சார்பில் தலையிடவும் அவர் முன்வந்தார். \"அரசு வித்தியாசமாக சிந்திக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பட்டியல் நீக்கம் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் தலைவர் எம்.பி சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன் இது அரசாங்கத்தின் நல்ல நடவடிக்கையாகும். எவ்வாறாயினும், எதிர்வரும் ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் கூட்டத் தொடருக்கு முன்னதாக சர்வதேச சமூகத்திடம் ஆதரவைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்வதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மேற்கொண்டுள்ள முயற்சியே இந்தத் தீர்மானம் எனவும் விக்னேஸ்வரன் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவுஸ்திரேலிய தமிழ் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோபல் தமிழ் மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக திராவிட ஒருங்கிணைப்புக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிட ஈழ மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடிய தமிழ் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் தமிழ் மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "316",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மங்கள சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கணேசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள்'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}