{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SL-to-support-flood-hit-Pakistan/108-244297",
  "time_ut": 1662340976,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL to support flood hit Pakistan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL to support flood hit Pakistan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has phoned Pakistani Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif and has offered relief to Pakistan, Pakistan media reported yesterday. President Wickremesinghe offered sympathies on the widespread devastation caused by the recent floods in Pakistan and condoled Prime Minister Sharif on the loss of lives.",
        "He expressed solidarity with the government and people of Pakistan braving the unforeseen natural calamity, it was reported.",
        "PM Shehbaz thanked the Sri Lankan president for his compassion and expression of support in these testing times and briefed him on the large-scale destruction caused across Pakistan by unprecedented rainfall resulting in floods and landslides.",
        "The prime minister highlighted that the floods have caused extensive loss of human lives, livelihoods, livestock, crops, property, and critical infrastructure.",
        "He also appraised President Wickremesinghe of the government’s well-coordinated humanitarian response including the establishment of a relief fund in which people in Pakistan and overseas can donate to the flood relief efforts."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pakistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehbaz Sharif",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sharif",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shehbaz",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගංවතුරෙන් පීඩාවට පත් පකිස්ථානයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහය දක්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පකිස්ථාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ෂෙබාස් ෂරීෆ් මහතාට දුරකථන ඇමතුමක් ලබාදී පාකිස්ථානයට සහන ලබාදී ඇති බව පකිස්ථාන මාධ්‍ය ඊයේ වාර්තා කළේය. පකිස්ථානයේ පසුගියදා ඇති වූ ගංවතුර තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් සිදු වූ පුලුල් විනාශය පිළිබඳව සිය සංවේගය පළ කළ ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ, ජීවිත හානි පිළිබඳව අගමැති ෂරීෆ් වෙත ශෝකය පළ කළේය.",
        "අනපේක්ෂිත ස්වභාවික විපතට මුහුණ දුන් පකිස්ථානයේ රජය සහ ජනතාව සමඟ ඔහු සහයෝගය පළ කළ බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෙම පරීක්ෂණ කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා දැක්වූ දයානුකම්පාව සහ සහයෝගය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් PM Shehbaz ස්තුතිය පුද කළ අතර ගංවතුර සහ නායයෑම් හේතුවෙන් පෙර නොවූ විරූ වර්ෂාපතනයෙන් පාකිස්තානය පුරා සිදු වූ මහා පරිමාණ විනාශය පිළිබඳව ඔහු දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "ගංවතුර හේතුවෙන් මිනිස් ජීවිත, ජීවනෝපාය, පශු සම්පත්, භෝග, දේපළ සහ තීරණාත්මක යටිතල පහසුකම් විශාල වශයෙන් විනාශ වී ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "පාකිස්ථානයේ සහ විදේශයන්හි සිටින ජනතාවට ගංවතුර සහන සේවා කටයුතු සඳහා පරිත්‍යාග කළ හැකි සහන අරමුදලක් පිහිටුවීම ඇතුළු රජයේ මනා සම්බන්ධීකරණයෙන් යුත් මානුෂීය ප්‍රතිචාරය පිළිබඳව ද ඔහු ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඇගයීමට ලක් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehbaz Sharif",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂරීෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහ්බාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தானில் வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதை ஆதரித்து இலங்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பாகிஸ்தான் பிரதமர் ஷெபாஸ் ஷெரீப்புக்கு தொலைபேசியில் தொடர்பு கொண்டு, பாகிஸ்தானுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக பாகிஸ்தான் ஊடகங்கள் நேற்று தெரிவித்துள்ளன. பாகிஸ்தானில் அண்மையில் ஏற்பட்ட வெள்ளத்தினால் ஏற்பட்ட பரவலான அழிவுகளுக்கு அனுதாபங்களை தெரிவித்த ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, உயிர் இழப்புகளுக்கு பிரதமர் ஷெரீப்பிற்கு இரங்கல் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எதிர்பாராத இயற்கைப் பேரிடரை எதிர்கொண்ட பாகிஸ்தான் அரசுக்கும் மக்களுக்கும் அவர் ஒற்றுமையை வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "இந்த சோதனைக் காலங்களில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியின் கருணை மற்றும் ஆதரவை வெளிப்படுத்தியமைக்கு பிரதமர் ஷெஹ்பாஸ் நன்றி தெரிவித்ததோடு, வெள்ளம் மற்றும் நிலச்சரிவுகள் காரணமாக பாகிஸ்தானில் வரலாறு காணாத மழையினால் ஏற்பட்ட பாரிய அழிவுகள் குறித்து அவருக்கு விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "வெள்ளத்தால் மனித உயிர்கள், வாழ்வாதாரங்கள், கால்நடைகள், பயிர்கள், சொத்துக்கள் மற்றும் முக்கியமான உள்கட்டமைப்புகள் பெருமளவில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன என்பதை பிரதமர் எடுத்துரைத்தார்.",
        "பாக்கிஸ்தான் மற்றும் வெளிநாடுகளில் உள்ள மக்கள் வெள்ள நிவாரணப் பணிகளுக்கு நன்கொடை அளிக்கக்கூடிய நிவாரண நிதியை ஸ்தாபித்தல் உட்பட அரசாங்கத்தின் நன்கு ஒருங்கிணைந்த மனிதாபிமானப் பதிலையும் அவர் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பாராட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெபாஸ் ஷெரீப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெரீப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹ்பாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}