{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/sapugaskand-refinery-to-continue-operations/",
  "time_ut": 1661498280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sapugaskand refinery to continue operations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sapugaskand refinery to continue operations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Power and Energy says that it will take steps to continue operating the Sapugaskanda Oil Refinery.",
        "A senior official of the Ministry said that another crude oil ship will arrive in the country today (26) or tomorrow (27).",
        "When inquired considering whether there is a shortage of fuel in the country, a senior official in the Ministry emphasized that sufficient stocks of fuel are available to meet the local demand.",
        "The shortage of fuel reported in the Puttalam and Kurunegala Districts has been addressed to a greater extent.",
        "Military should be ready for technological knowledge for cyber warfare – President",
        "Is Sri Lanka’s economic crisis spiraling into a humanitarian one?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sapugaskand",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sapugaskanda Oil Refinery",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සපුගස්කන්ද පිරිපහදුව අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සපුගස්කන්ද තෙල් පිරිපහදුව අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට පියවර ගන්නා බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "තවත් බොරතෙල් නෞකාවක් අද (26) හෝ හෙට (27) දිවයිනට පැමිණෙනු ඇති බව එම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ උසස් නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "රට තුළ ඉන්ධන හිඟයක් පවතින්නේද යන්න පිළිබඳව කළ විමසීමකදී අමාත්‍යාංශයේ උසස් නිලධාරියෙකු අවධාරණය කළේ දේශීය ඉල්ලුමට සරිලන පරිදි ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන තොග පවතින බවයි.",
        "පුත්තලම සහ කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල වාර්තා වූ ඉන්ධන හිඟයට වැඩි දුරකට විසඳුම් ලැබී තිබෙනවා.",
        "සයිබර් යුද්ධයට අවශ්‍ය තාක්ෂණික දැනුම සඳහා හමුදාව සූදානම් විය යුතුයි – ජනපති",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මානුෂීය අර්බුදයක් බවට පත්වෙමින් තිබේද?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සපුගස්කන්ද",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සපුගස්කන්ද තෙල් පිරිපහදුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சபுகஸ்கண்ட் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் தொடர்ந்து செயல்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சபுகஸ்கந்த எண்ணெய் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையத்தை தொடர்ந்து செயற்படுத்த நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மற்றுமொரு கச்சா எண்ணெய் கப்பல் இன்று (26) அல்லது நாளை (27) நாட்டை வந்தடையவுள்ளதாக அமைச்சின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் எரிபொருளுக்கு தட்டுப்பாடு உள்ளதா என வினவியபோது, ​​உள்ளூர் தேவைக்கு ஏற்ப போதுமான அளவு எரிபொருள் இருப்பு உள்ளதாக அமைச்சின் மூத்த அதிகாரி ஒருவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "புத்தளம் மற்றும் குருநாகல் மாவட்டங்களில் நிலவிய எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு பாரியளவில் நிவர்த்தி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சைபர் போருக்கான தொழில்நுட்ப அறிவுக்கு ராணுவம் தயாராக இருக்க வேண்டும் - ஜனாதிபதி",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மனிதாபிமானமாக மாறுகிறதா?"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சபுகஸ்கண்ட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபுகஸ்கந்த எண்ணெய் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}