{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Cop-who-joined-Aragalaya-arrested-with-a-sharp-weapon-at-Presidents-House/108-240844",
  "time_ut": 1657528414,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cop who joined Aragalaya arrested with a sharp weapon at President’s House",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cop who joined Aragalaya arrested with a sharp weapon at President’s House",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police Sergeant who extended his support to the people’s struggle at the Maharagama Town on Saturday has been arrested on charges of possessing a sharp weapon while entering the President’s House in Colombo, early this morning.",
        "They said the suspect, who was wearing a pair of sandals and wearing a police uniform, came to enter the President's House and was stopped and searched by the security forces on duty for suspicious behaviour.",
        "They recovered a sharp weapon from the possession of the sergeant and was handed over to the Fort Police.",
        "Police said the sergeant, attached to the Narahenpita Police Garage, is a resident of Homagama. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Aragalaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Narahenpita Police Garage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අරගලයට ගිය පොලිස් නිලධාරියා තියුණු ආයුධයක් සමඟ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෙනසුරාදා මහරගම නගරයේ පැවති ජන අරගලයට සහය දුන් පොලිස් සැරයන්වරයා අද අලුයම කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වෙමින් සිටියදී තියුණු ආයුධයක් ළඟ තබා ගැනීමේ චෝදනාව මත අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "පොලිස් නිල ඇඳුමින් සැරසී සෙරෙප්පු යුගලක් පැළඳ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වීමට පැමිණි සැකකරු සැකකටයුතු ලෙස හැසිරීම හේතුවෙන් රාජකාරියේ නියුතු ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් ඔහුව නවතා පරීක්ෂා කළ බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "එහිදී සැරයන්වරයා සන්තකයේ තිබී තියුණු ආයුධයක් සොයාගෙන කොටුව පොලිසියට භාරදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "නාරාහේන්පිට පොලිස් ගරාජයට අනුයුක්තව සේවය කරන මෙම සැරයන්වරයා හෝමාගම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු බවයි පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අරගලය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාරාහේන්පිට පොලිස් ගරාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එස්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரகலயவில் இணைந்த பொலிஸ்காரர் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் கூரிய ஆயுதத்துடன் கைது!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மஹரகம நகரில் நேற்று சனிக்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற மக்கள் போராட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்கிய பொலிஸ் சார்ஜன்ட் இன்று அதிகாலை கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்த போது கூரிய ஆயுதம் வைத்திருந்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஒரு ஜோடி செருப்பு அணிந்து, பொலிஸ் சீருடை அணிந்திருந்த சந்தேக நபர் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைய வந்ததாகவும், சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான நடத்தைக்காக கடமையிலிருந்த பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் தடுத்து நிறுத்தி சோதனையிட்டதாகவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சார்ஜன்ட் வசம் இருந்த கூரிய ஆயுதம் ஒன்றை மீட்டு கோட்டை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைத்தனர்.",
        "நாரஹேன்பிட்டி பொலிஸ் கராஜில் கடமையாற்றும் சார்ஜன்ட் ஹோமாகம பிரதேசத்தில் வசிப்பவர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். (டி.எஸ்.பி.)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரகலயா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாரஹேன்பிட்டி பொலிஸ் கேரேஜ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}