{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/souls-for-sale/",
  "time_ut": 1658768280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Souls for sale!",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Souls for sale!",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The JVP is notorious for miscalculations, which are legion, but it seems to have got its maths right for once anent the outcome of the recent vote in Parliament. Leader of the JVP-led NPP Anura Kumara Dissanayake has sought to bolster his claim that some Opposition MPs had their palms greased to back Ranil Wickremesinghe at the 20 July vote in the House to elect the eighth Executive President. Wickremesinghe polled 134, Dullas Alahapperuma 82 and Dissanayake 03.",
        "There weren’t as many as 134 MPs sitting with Wickremesinghe in Parliament when he was the Prime Minister, and therefore it was obvious that some Opposition MPs backed him for money without breaking ranks, the JVP leader has said, noting that they lack the courage to stand up and be counted. Dissanayake insists that some SJB MPs voted for Wickremesinghe. This fact will become evident if a vote is taken in the House on the extension of Emergency on 27 July, Dissanayake has argued, predicting that the government will not be able to secure the support of 134 MPs tomorrow as there will not be a secret ballot. The Standing Order 47 provides for vote by voice, vote by name or vote by rising.",
        "The only way the Opposition could expose the government’s real strength tomorrow is to ensure that all its MPs will be present in the House during the Emergency debate, and then call for a division so that the SLPP will have to go full steam ahead and get every government MP to vote. If the SLPP fails to obtain 134 votes, then the JVP’s claim of a fifth column in the Opposition will hold water.",
        "It is not only the Opposition MPs who take money to vote in favour of their political rivals; there are situations where the ruling party MPs also do so even at the risk of placing national security in peril. In 2007, following an abortive attempt by the then Opposition to defeat Budget 2008 presented by the Mahinda Rajapaksa government at the height of war, Alahapperuma, who was a minister at the time, disclosed at a media briefing that some government MPs had been bribed to vote against the budget, as part of a conspiracy to bring down the government and derail the war; they had been found in hotels with foreign prostitutes, he said, claiming that the government had fought quite a battle to prevent those corrupt, randy elements in the garb of MPs from doing what they had taken bribes for. The Rajapaksa government won the budget vote. Alahapperuma stopped short of revealing how that task had been accomplished, but there is reason to believe that the Rajapaksas outbribed their opponents.",
        "While it is being debated whether some MPs sold their souls last week, the SLPP is reported to have decided to initiate disciplinary action against its Chairman Prof. G. L. Peiris for backing Alahapperuma in the presidential contest. The SLPP General Secretary Sagara Kariyawasam publicly endorsed the then Prime Minister Wickremesinghe’s candidacy, but Prof. Peiris contradicted him, saying the SLPP had to support its MP, Alahapperuma. Wickremesinghe’s victory has thus caused another crippling rift in the SLPP at this crucial juncture.",
        "If the SLPP resorts to disciplinary action against Prof. Peiris for backing Alahapperuma, it will have to mete out the same treatment to former President Mahinda Rajapaksa as well. It may be recalled that while leaving Parliament after the election of Wickremesinghe as the President, Mahinda, in answer to a question from a journalist, said, “We supported Dullas, but he lost!” Now that Mahinda has said so—for whatever reason— Kariyawasam will have to explain why he has not called for any action against Mahinda; he apparently has no leg to stand on.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "as many as 134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe in Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134 MPs",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Budget 2008",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආත්මය විකිණීමට ඇත!",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජවිපෙ වැරදි ගනන් බැලීම් සඳහා කුප්‍රකටය, නමුත් එය ලෙජියන් ලෙස සැලකේ, නමුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මෑත කාලීන ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිඵලයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය දෙස බලන විට එහි ගණිතය එක වරම නිවැරදි වී ඇති බව පෙනේ. JVP ප්‍රමුඛ NPP නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක, අටවැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ජූලි 20 වන දින පැවති ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහාය දැක්වීම සඳහා විපක්ෂයේ සමහර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ අත්වල තෙල් ගෑවා යැයි කරන ප්‍රකාශය තහවුරු කිරීමට උත්සාහ කර ඇත. වික්‍රමසිංහ 134, ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම 82 සහ දිසානායක 03 ලබා ගත්හ.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගමැතිව සිටියදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134ක් පමණ අසුන්ගෙන නොසිටි බවත්, ඒ නිසා විපක්ෂයේ ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඔහුට මුදලට පිටුබලය දුන් බව පෙනෙන බවත් ඔවුන්ට ධෛර්යයක් නොමැති බවත් ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායකයා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත. නැගී සිටීමට සහ ගණන් කිරීමට. සමහර SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වික්‍රමසිංහට ඡන්දය දුන් බව දිසානායක අවධාරනය කරයි. ජුලි 27 වැනි දින හදිසි නීතිය දීර්ඝ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සභාව තුළ ඡන්දයක් පැවැත්වුවහොත් මේ කාරණය පැහැදිලි වනු ඇති බවත්, රහස් ඡන්දයක් නොපැවැත්වෙන බැවින් හෙට දිනයේදී ආණ්ඩුවට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134කගේ සහය ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇති බවට අනාවැකි පළ කරමින් දිසානායක මහතා තර්ක කළේය. . ස්ථාවර නියෝග 47 මගින් හඬින් ඡන්දය, නමෙන් ඡන්දය හෝ නැඟී සිට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට විධිවිධාන සලසා ඇත.",
        "විපක්ෂයට හෙට ආණ්ඩුවේ සැබෑ ශක්තිය හෙළිදරව් කළ හැකි එකම ක්‍රමය වන්නේ හදිසි විවාදයේදී එහි සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සභාවේ සිටීම සහතික කර, පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ඉදිරියට ගොස් සෑම දෙයක්ම ලබා ගැනීමට බෙදීමක් ඉල්ලා සිටීමයි. ඡන්දය දීමට ආණ්ඩුවේ මන්ත්‍රී. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඡන්ද 134ක් ලබා ගැනීමට අපොහොසත් වුවහොත් විපක්ෂයේ පස්වැනි තීරුව සඳහා ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රකාශය ජලය රඳවා ගනු ඇත.",
        "තම දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිවාදීන්ට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය දීමට මුදල් ගන්නේ විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පමණක් නොවේ; ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ද ජාතික ආරක්‍ෂාව අනතුරේ හෙළීමේ අවදානමක්‌ තිබියදීත් එසේ කරන තත්ත්වයන් තිබේ. 2007 වසරේ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ රජය යුද්ධයේ උච්චතම අවස්ථාව වන විට ඉදිරිපත් කළ 2008 අයවැය පරාජය කිරීමට එවකට විපක්ෂය ගත් උත්සාහය අසාර්ථක වීමෙන් පසු ආණ්ඩුවේ ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට අල්ලස් දී ඇතැයි එවකට ඇමැතිවරයකුව සිටි අලහප්පෙරුම මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී හෙළි කළේය. ආන්ඩුව පෙරලා යුද්ධය පීලි පැනීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක කොටසක් ලෙස අයවැයට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය දෙන්න; ඔවුන් විදේශීය ගණිකාවන් සිටින හෝටල්වල තිබී සොයාගෙන ඇති බවත්, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඇඳුමින් සැරසී සිටින එම දූෂිතයන් අල්ලස් ගත් දේ කිරීම වැළැක්වීමට රජය සෑහෙන සටනක් කළ බවත් ඔහු කියා සිටියේය. අයවැය ඡන්දයෙන් රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය. අලහප්පෙරුම එම කර්තව්‍යය ඉටු වූ ආකාරය හෙළිදරව් කිරීමෙන් පසු නතර වූ නමුත් රාජපක්ෂලා තම විරුද්ධවාදීන් අභිබවා ගිය බව විශ්වාස කිරීමට හේතුවක් තිබේ.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සිය ආත්මය විකුණා දැමුවාද යන්න පිළිබඳව වාද විවාද වෙමින් පවතින අතරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතාට එරෙහිව විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට තීරණය කර ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් එවකට අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහගේ අපේක්ෂකත්වය ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ අනුමත කළ නමුත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ එහි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දිය යුතු බව පවසමින් මහාචාර්ය පීරිස් ඔහුට විරුද්ධ විය. වික්‍රමසිංහගේ ජයග්‍රහණය මේ තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ තවත් අබලන් විරසකයක් ඇති කර තිබේ.",
        "අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහාචාර්ය පීරිස්ට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගතහොත් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ද එම සැලකීම සිදු කිරීමට සිදුවනු ඇත. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් පිටව යන අතරතුර මාධ්‍යවේදියකු ඇසූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් “අපි ඩලස්ට සහාය දුන්නා, නමුත් ඔහු පැරදුණා!” යනුවෙන් මහින්ද ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව සිහිපත් කළ හැකිය. දැන් මහින්ද එසේ කී විට - කුමන හේතුවක් නිසා හෝ - මහින්දට එරෙහිව කිසිදු ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ඉල්ලා නොසිටියේ මන්දැයි කාරියවසම්ට පැහැදිලි කිරීමට සිදුවනු ඇත. පෙනෙන විදිහට ඔහුට නැගී සිටීමට කකුලක් නැත.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134 තරම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008 අයවැය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆன்மாக்கள் விற்பனைக்கு!",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜே.வி.பி தவறான கணக்கீடுகளுக்குப் பெயர் போனது, அவை படையணிகள், ஆனால் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமீபத்தில் நடந்த வாக்கெடுப்பின் முடிவைப் பார்க்கும்போது அது அதன் கணிதத்தை சரியாகப் பெற்றுள்ளது. ஜே.வி.பி தலைமையிலான என்.பி.பி.யின் தலைவர் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான சபையில் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க சில எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் உள்ளங்கையில் நெய் தடவியதாக தனது கூற்றை வலுப்படுத்த முயன்றார். விக்கிரமசிங்க 134, டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும 82 மற்றும் திசாநாயக்க 03 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றனர்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக இருந்த போது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 134 எம்.பி.க்கள் அமர்ந்திருக்கவில்லை, எனவே சில எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் அவருக்கு பணத்துக்காக ஆதரவளித்தனர் என்பது வெளிப்படை என ஜே.வி.பி.யின் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். எழுந்து நின்று எண்ண வேண்டும். சில SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு வாக்களித்ததாக திஸாநாயக்க வலியுறுத்துகிறார். ஜுலை 27ஆம் திகதி அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை நீடிப்பது தொடர்பில் சபையில் வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டால் இந்த உண்மை புலப்படும், இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு நடைபெறாததால் நாளை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு 134 எம்.பி.க்களின் ஆதரவைப் பெற முடியாது என திஸாநாயக்க வாதிட்டார். . நிலையியற் கட்டளை 47 குரல் மூலம் வாக்களிக்கவும், பெயரால் வாக்களிக்கவும் அல்லது எழுந்து வாக்களிக்கவும் வழிவகை செய்கிறது.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தின் உண்மையான பலத்தை எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் நாளை அம்பலப்படுத்தும் ஒரே வழி, அவசரகால விவாதத்தின் போது அதன் அனைத்து எம்.பி.க்களும் சபையில் இருப்பதை உறுதிசெய்து, பின்னர் பிரிவினைக்கு அழைப்பு விடுப்பதே ஆகும் வாக்களிக்க அரசு எம்.பி. ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெறத் தவறினால், ஜே.வி.பி.யின் ஐந்தாவது பத்தியை எதிர்க்கட்சியாகக் கூறுவது நீர்ப்பிடிக்கும்.",
        "அரசியல் எதிரிகளுக்கு ஆதரவாக வாக்களிக்க பணம் வாங்குவது எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் மட்டுமல்ல; தேசிய பாதுகாப்பை ஆபத்தில் ஆழ்த்தினாலும் ஆளும் கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களும் அவ்வாறு செய்யும் சூழ்நிலைகள் உள்ளன. 2007ஆம் ஆண்டு, மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கம் போர் உச்சக்கட்டத்தில் சமர்ப்பித்த 2008ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை தோற்கடிக்க அப்போதைய எதிர்கட்சியினர் மேற்கொண்ட முயற்சியைத் தொடர்ந்து, அப்போது அமைச்சராக இருந்த அழகப்பெரும, சில அரசாங்க நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு இலஞ்சம் கொடுக்கப்பட்டதாக ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார். அரசாங்கத்தை வீழ்த்தி, போரைத் தடம் புரளச் செய்யும் சதியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்திற்கு எதிராக வாக்களியுங்கள்; அவர்கள் வெளிநாட்டு விபச்சாரிகளுடன் ஹோட்டல்களில் காணப்பட்டனர், அவர்கள் லஞ்சம் வாங்கியதைச் செய்வதிலிருந்து எம்.பி.க்களின் உடையில் இருக்கும் ஊழல், ஆக்கிரமிப்பு சக்திகளைத் தடுக்க அரசாங்கம் மிகவும் போரில் ஈடுபட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார். பட்ஜெட் வாக்கெடுப்பில் ராஜபக்சே அரசு வெற்றி பெற்றது. அந்த பணி எவ்வாறு நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது என்பதை வெளிப்படுத்தாமல் அலஹப்பெரும நிறுத்தினார், ஆனால் ராஜபக்ஷக்கள் தங்கள் எதிரிகளை மிஞ்சினார்கள் என்று நம்புவதற்கு காரணம் உள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் சில பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தமது ஆன்மாக்களை விற்றுக்கொண்டார்களா என விவாதிக்கப்பட்டு வரும் நிலையில், ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளித்தமைக்காக அதன் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸுக்கு எதிராக ஒழுக்காற்று நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம், அப்போதைய பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வேட்புமனுவை பகிரங்கமாக ஆமோதித்தார், ஆனால் பேராசிரியர் பீரிஸ் அதற்கு முரண்பட்டார், SLPP அதன் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறினார். விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வெற்றியானது இந்த முக்கியமான தருணத்தில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் மற்றுமொரு முடங்கும் பிளவை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளித்த பேராசிரியர் பீரிஸுக்கு எதிராக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ஒழுக்காற்று நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டால், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவுக்கும் அதே நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டியிருக்கும். விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறும் போது, ​​ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவரின் கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த மஹிந்த, “டலஸை ஆதரித்தோம், ஆனால் அவர் தோற்றுப்போனார்!” என்று கூறியது நினைவிருக்கலாம். இப்போது மகிந்த அவ்வாறு கூறியுள்ள நிலையில் - எக்காரணம் கொண்டும் - மகிந்தவுக்கு எதிராக எந்த நடவடிக்கையும் எடுக்க தாம் ஏன் அழைப்பு விடுக்கவில்லை என்பதை காரியவசம் விளக்க வேண்டும்; அவருக்கு நிற்க கால் இல்லை.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "134 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134 எம்.பி.க்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2007",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட் 2008",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}