{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Six-including-5-year-old-child-drown/108-242254",
  "time_ut": 1659412992,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Six including 5-year old child drown",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Six including 5-year old child drown",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At least six persons including a 5-year-old child drown during three separate incidents yesterday in Polpitiya, Nawalapitiya and Hatton.",
        "Police said woman (62) and a 5-year old child who were returning home from pre-school drowned and went missing in Hitinegama, Polpitiya yesterday.",
        "The bodies of woman and the  child - a grandmother and a granddaughter - were found during a search by police and local residents.",
        "Meanwhile, two men and a woman who went to cross the Katambulawa Oya in Akkaravatta area of ​​Nawalapitiya were suspected to have drowned and gone missing since then.",
        "The missing were aged 36, 46 and 47 are residents of Katabula area.",
        "Meanwhile, the Hatton Police have launched investigation after a man accompanied by another three men, slipped and fell into the Panmoore Lake.",
        "The police arrested the other two who were accompanying the missing man at that time under suspicion. (Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "5-year old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "At least six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nawalapitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5-year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hitinegama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polpitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katambulawa Oya",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akkaravatta",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36, 46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katabula",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Hatton Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Panmoore Lake",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "5 හැවිරිදි දරුවා ඇතුළු 6 දෙනෙකු දියේ ගිලී මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොල්පිටිය, නාවලපිටිය සහ හැටන් යන ප්‍රදේශවල ඊයේ දිනයේදී සිදුවූ අවස්ථා තුනකදී අවුරුදු 5ක දරුවෙකු ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයින් 6 දෙනෙකු දියේ ගිලී ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "පොලීසිය පැවසුවේ, පොල්පිටිය, හිටිනේගම ප්‍රදේශයේදී පෙර පාසල නිමවී නිවස බලා යමින් සිටි කාන්තාවක් (62) සහ අවුරුදු 5ක දරුවෙකු ඊයේ දියේ ගිලී අතුරුදන්ව ඇති බව ය.",
        "පොලිසිය සහ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් විසින් කරන ලද සෝදිසි කිරීමකදී කාන්තාවගේ සහ දරුවාගේ - මිත්තණියක සහ මිනිබිරියකගේ සිරුරු සොයාගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර නාවලපිටිය අක්කරවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ කැටඹුලාව ඔයෙන් එගොඩ වීමට ගිය පිරිමින් දෙදෙනෙකු සහ කාන්තාවක් දියේ ගිලී අතුරුදන්ව ඇති බවටයි සැක කෙරුණේ.",
        "අතුරුදන් වූවන් අවුරුදු 36, 46 සහ 47 යන වයස්වල පසුවන කටබුල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන්.",
        "මේ අතර තවත් පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු සමඟ පුද්ගලයෙකු ලිස්සා ගොස් පන්මූර් වැවට වැටීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් හැටන් පොලීසිය පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවේ අතුරුදන් වූ පුද්ගලයා සමඟ සිටි අනෙක් දෙදෙනාද පොලිසිය සැකපිට අත්අඩංගුවට ගත්තා. (දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 5 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5 ක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවලපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිටිනේගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්පිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටඹුලාව ඔය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කරවත්ත",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36, 46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටබුල",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැටන් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්මූර් විල",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நீரில் மூழ்கி 5 வயது குழந்தை உட்பட 6 பேர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொல்பிட்டிய, நாவலப்பிட்டி மற்றும் ஹட்டன் ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற மூன்று வெவ்வேறு சம்பவங்களில் 5 வயது குழந்தை உட்பட குறைந்தது ஆறு பேர் நீரில் மூழ்கி உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பொல்பிட்டிய, ஹிதினேகம பிரதேசத்தில் நேற்று முன்பள்ளியிலிருந்து வீடு திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்த பெண்ணும் (62) மற்றும் 5 வயது குழந்தையும் நீரில் மூழ்கி காணாமல் போயுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பொலிசார் மற்றும் உள்ளூர்வாசிகள் நடத்திய தேடுதலின் போது பெண் மற்றும் குழந்தை - ஒரு பாட்டி மற்றும் ஒரு பேத்தியின் உடல்கள் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இதேவேளை நாவலப்பிட்டி அக்கரவத்தை பகுதியில் கடம்புலவ ஓயாவை கடக்க சென்ற இரு ஆண்களும் பெண் ஒருவரும் நீரில் மூழ்கி காணாமல் போயிருக்கலாம் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "காணாமல் போனவர்கள் 36, 46 மற்றும் 47 வயதுடைய கட்டபுல பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள்.",
        "இதேவேளை, மேலும் மூவருடன் சென்ற நபர் ஒருவர் பன்மூர் ஏரியில் தவறி விழுந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் ஹட்டன் பொலிஸார் விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அப்போது காணாமல் போன நபருடன் வந்த மற்ற இருவரை சந்தேகத்தின் பேரில் போலீசார் கைது செய்தனர். (தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "5 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாவலப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிட்டிநேகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடம்புலவ ஓயா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்கரவத்தை",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36, 46",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடாபுலா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன் பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்மூர் ஏரி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}