{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-military-calls-for-politicians-to-get-their-act-together-public-to-be-calm-97359/",
  "time_ut": 1657714620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka military calls for politicians to get their act together, public to be calm",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka military calls for politicians to get their act together, public to be calm",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s military chiefs had asked party leaders to meet with the Parliamentary speaker and tell them next political steps they intended to take until a new President is elected and called on the public and young protestors to be calm, Chief of Staff Shavendra Silva said.",
        "The speaker had said President Rajapaksa will resign later today. The military chiefs had had discussion with the speaker.",
        "“The heads of the tri-forces and police chief made a request from the speaker to call a meeting of party leaders and clarify the next political steps, and inform us of the political steps,”General Silva said in a televised address flanked by the heads of Air Force, Army, Navy and Police.",
        "“We expect these decisions to be made public in the evening,”",
        "“Until the new President is elected we appeal to the public to be calm.”",
        "Sri Lanka’s Prime Minister Ranil Wickremsinghe said earlier in the day that fascist segments among protestors are making trouble while opposition leader Sajith Premadasa also made a rhetoric charged statement while calling for calm.",
        "Ex-President Maithripala Sirisena said the quickest way to calm young protestors was for Ranil Wickremesighe who was appointed acting President to resign."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremsinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesighe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හමුදාව දේශපාලනඥයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ එකට ක්‍රියා කරන ලෙසත්, මහජනතාව සන්සුන් වන ලෙසත් ය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන් පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායකවරයා හමුවී නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා තෙක් තමන් ගැනීමට අදහස් කරන ඉදිරි දේශපාලන පියවර ඔවුන්ට පවසන ලෙසත් මහජනතාවගෙන් සහ තරුණ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් සන්සුන් වන ලෙසත් ඉල්ලා සිටි බව මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය. .",
        "අද දිනයෙන් පසු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව කථානායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත. හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන් කථානායකවරයා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ.",
        "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන් සහ පොලිස් ප්‍රධානීන් කථානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් කැඳවා ඉදිරි දේශපාලන පියවර පැහැදිලි කර දේශපාලන පියවර පිළිබඳව අපට දන්වන ලෙසයි. ගුවන්, යුද, නාවික සහ පොලිස් ප්‍රධානීන්.",
        "\"මෙම තීරණ සවස් වරුවේ ප්‍රසිද්ධ කරනු ඇතැයි අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු\"",
        "\"නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තේරී පත්වන තුරු අපි මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ සන්සුන්ව සිටින ලෙසයි.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පෙරේදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් අතර ෆැසිස්ට්වාදී කොටස් කරදර ඇති කරන බවයි.",
        "තරුණ විරෝධතාකරුවන් සන්සුන් කිරීමට ඉක්මන්ම ක්‍රමය වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත්කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීම බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல்வாதிகள் ஒன்றிணைந்து செயற்படுமாறும், பொதுமக்கள் அமைதியாக இருக்குமாறும் இலங்கை இராணுவம் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் இராணுவத் தளபதிகள் கட்சித் தலைவர்களை பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரைச் சந்தித்து புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் வரையில் தாங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளவிருக்கும் அடுத்த அரசியல் நடவடிக்கைகளைத் தெரிவிக்குமாறு கேட்டுக் கொண்டதாகவும், பொதுமக்கள் மற்றும் இளம் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை அமைதியாக இருக்குமாறும் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளதாக இராணுவத் தளபதி சவேந்திர சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சே இன்று பதவி விலகுவார் என சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இராணுவத் தளபதிகள் சபாநாயகருடன் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "முப்படைகளின் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர்கள் சபாநாயகரிடம் கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் கூட்டத்தை கூட்டி அடுத்த அரசியல் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து தெளிவுபடுத்துமாறும், அரசியல் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து எமக்கு அறிவிக்குமாறும் சபாநாயகரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர் என ஜெனரல் சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். விமானப்படை, ராணுவம், கடற்படை மற்றும் போலீஸ் தலைவர்கள்.",
        "\"இந்த முடிவுகள் மாலையில் பகிரங்கப்படுத்தப்படும் என்று நாங்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கிறோம்\"",
        "புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படும் வரை பொதுமக்கள் அமைதியாக இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம்.",
        "சிறிலங்காவின் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் மத்தியில் பாசிசப் பிரிவுகள் சிக்கலை ஏற்படுத்துவதாகக் கூறியதுடன், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவும் அமைதியைக் கடைப்பிடிக்க வேண்டும் என்று ஒரு வாய்வீச்சு அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "இளம் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை அமைதிப்படுத்துவதற்கான விரைவான வழி, பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவி விலகுவதே என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}