{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/දෙමෝදරදී-දුම්රියේ-ගැටී-බරපතළව-රෝහලේ/101-617083",
  "time_ut": 1658841475,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දෙමෝදරදී දුම්රියේ ගැටී බරපතළව රෝහලේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hit by a train at Demodara and seriously in hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Ella Police, a person who was hit by a train this afternoon (26) was seriously injured and admitted to the Badulla General Hospital near the historic Skyscraper Arch Bridge between Ella Demodara railway stations.",
        "Police said that the injured person is a 46-year-old resident of Ella Karadagolla area.",
        "The police said that part of the left leg and part of the left arm of the person who was hit by the train were separated from the body.",
        "The police said that he hit the goods train which was running between Badulla and Kandy.",
        "The police said that the injured person was immediately taken to the Badulla General Hospital by a Suvasarya 1990 ambulance on the basis of information provided by a passer-by who saw the seriously injured person lying down with blood near the railway track.",
        "Dr. Palitha Rajapaksa, Senior Medical Officer of Badulla General Hospital, Uva Provincial Coordinator of the Government Medical Officers Association, stated that although the part of the injured person's leg and hand were put in an ice box and taken to the hospital, the leg and the hand were not in a suitable condition for re-transplantation. .",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa further said that the delicate and other blood vessels of the separated parts of the leg and hand were destroyed by being hit by the train. Ella police are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ella Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a train this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skyscraper Arch Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ella Demodara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ella Karadagolla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suvasarya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitha Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva Provincial Coordinator",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Medical Officers Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙමෝදරදී දුම්රියේ ගැටී බරපතළව රෝහලේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇල්ල දෙමෝදර දුම්රිය ස්ථාන අතර දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ඓතිහාසික අහස්නවය ආරුක්කු පාලම ආසන්නයේ දී අද (26) පස්වරුවේ දුම්රියක ගැටුණු පුද්ගලයකු බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා  බදුල්ල මහ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කළ බව ඇල්ල පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ ඇල්ල  කරදගොල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 46 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයකු බව පොලිසිය කීය .",
        "දුම්රියේ ගැටුණු මෙම පුද්ගලයාගේ වම් පාදයේ කොටසක් සහ වම් අතේ කොටසක් ශරීරයෙන් වෙන්වී තිබූ බව පොලිසිය පැවැසීය.",
        "බදුල්ල  මහනුවර අතර  ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබූ භාණ්ඩ දුම්රියට මොහු ගැටි ඇතැයි පොලිසිය පැවසීය .",
        "බරපතළ තුවාල ලැබූ පුද්ගලයා දුම්රිය මාර්ගය ආසන්නයේ ලේ සහිතව වැටී  සිටියදී ඒ අසලින් ගමන් ගත් අයෙකු දැක ලබා දුන් තොරතුරක් මත වහාම සුවසැරිය 1990 ගිලන් රථයක් මගින් තුවාලකරු බදුල්ල මහ රෝහලට රැගෙන ගොස් ඇති බව පොලිසිය කීය.",
        "තුවාලකරුගේ වෙන්වූ පාදයේ කොටස සහ අතේ කොටස අයිස් දැමූ පෙට්ටියක දමා රෝහලට රැගෙන ගියද එම පාදයේ මෙන්ම අතේ කොටස  ඒ වනවිටත් නැවත බද්ධ කිරිමට සුදුසු තත්ත්වයේ නොතිබුණු බවත් බදුල්ල මහ රෝහලේ හදිසි ප්‍රතිකාර ඒකකයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී රජයේ වෛද්‍ය  නිලධාරී සංගමයේ ඌව පලාත් සම්බන්ධීකාරක වෛද්‍ය පාලිත රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සදහන් කළේය .",
        "දුම්රියට හසු වීමෙන් එම පාදයේ සහ අතේ වෙන්වූ කොටස්වල සියුම් මෙන්ම අනෙකුන් රුධිර නාළ ද විනාශ වී තිබූ බව රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. ඇල්ල පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර පරික්ෂණ පවත්වති ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද හවස කෝච්චියක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skyscraper Arch Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ල දෙමෝදර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ල කරදගොල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුවසැරිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව පළාත් සම්බන්ධීකාරක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டெமோதராவில் ரயிலில் மோதி படுகாயமடைந்து மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எல்ல தெமோதர புகையிரத நிலையங்களுக்கு இடையிலான வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க வானளாவிய வளைவுப் பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் இன்று (26) பிற்பகல் புகையிரதத்தில் மோதுண்டு ஒருவர் படுகாயமடைந்து பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக எல்ல பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "காயமடைந்தவர் எல்ல கரடகொல்ல பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 46 வயதுடையவர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ரயிலில் அடிபட்ட நபரின் இடது காலின் ஒரு பகுதியும், இடது கையின் ஒரு பகுதியும் உடலில் இருந்து பிரிக்கப்பட்டதாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பதுளைக்கும் கண்டிக்கும் இடையில் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த சரக்கு ரயிலில் மோதியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "புகையிரத பாதைக்கு அருகில் படுகாயமடைந்த நபர் இரத்தத்துடன் கிடப்பதைக் கண்ட அவ்வழியே சென்ற ஒருவர் வழங்கிய தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் காயமடைந்த நபரை சுவாசார்யா 1990 அம்புலன்ஸ் மூலம் உடனடியாக பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலைக்கு அழைத்துச் சென்றதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலையின் சிரேஷ்ட வைத்திய அதிகாரி, அரசாங்க வைத்திய அதிகாரிகள் சங்கத்தின் ஊவா மாகாண இணைப்பாளர் டொக்டர் பாலித ராஜபக்ஷ, காயமடைந்த நபரின் கால் மற்றும் கை பகுதியை ஐஸ் பெட்டிக்குள் வைத்து வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு சென்ற போதிலும், கால் மற்றும் கை மீண்டும் மாற்று அறுவை சிகிச்சைக்கு ஏற்ற நிலையில் இல்லை.",
        "ரயிலில் அடிபட்டு கால் மற்றும் கையின் பிரிக்கப்பட்ட பகுதிகளின் மென்மையான மற்றும் பிற இரத்த நாளங்கள் அழிந்துவிட்டதாக திரு.ராஜபக்ஷ மேலும் கூறினார். எல்ல பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்ல காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம் ஒரு ரயில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வானளாவிய ஆர்ச் பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்லா தெமோதர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "46 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்ல கரடகொல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவாசார்யா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா மாகாண இணைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க மருத்துவ அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}