{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/india-has-helped-sri-lanka-to-best-of-its-ability-will-assist-with-imf-jaishankar-98784/",
  "time_ut": 1660898640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India has helped Sri Lanka to best of its ability, will assist with IMF: Jaishankar",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India has helped Sri Lanka to best of its ability, will assist with IMF: Jaishankar",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – India has helped the crisis-hit Sri Lanka to the best of its ability and will help the island nation with its negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), India’s External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said.",
        "Indian media quoted Jaishankar as saying at an event in Bangkok on Thursday August 17 that this year alone, India has extended 3.8 billion US dollars in support to Sri Lanka including lines of credit and swap arrangement.",
        "“Any help we can give to Sri Lanka at the IMF that we will naturally do,” India’s NDTV quoted Jaishankar as saying on its website.",
        "Jaishankar’s speech focused on India’s relations with China India, which he said was going through an “extremely difficult phase” after what Beijing has done at the border.",
        "The Asian Century will not happen if the two neighbours could not join hands, he said.",
        "The foreign minister did not make any explicit reference to the recent diplomatic standoff between India, Sri Lanka and China over a Chinese tracking vessel that is currently docked in the island’s Hambantota Port for replenishment purposes.",
        "Chinese tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 docks at Sri Lanka’s Hambantota Port",
        "“At the moment (the India-China) relationship is going through an extremely difficult phase after what China did at the border,” he said.",
        "“I think if India and China have to come together, there are many reasons to do so, not necessarily only Sri Lanka,” he said, adding that it is in India and China’s own interest to join hands. (Colombo/Aug19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaishankar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday August 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year alone",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.8 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Asian Century",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug19/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපරිමයෙන් උදව් කර ඇත, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට සහාය වනු ඇත: ජයශංකර්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ඉන්දියාව අර්බුදයට ලක්ව ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපරිමයෙන් උදව් කර ඇති අතර ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට දිවයිනට උදව් කරන බව ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය එස් ජයශංකර් පැවසීය.",
        "අගෝස්තු 17 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා බැංකොක්හි පැවති උත්සවයකදී ජයිශංකර් උපුටා දක්වමින් ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේ, මේ වසරේ පමණක් ඉන්දියාව ණය සහ හුවමාරු විධිවිධාන ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක ආධාරයක් ලබා දී ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දිය හැකි ඕනෑම උදව්වක් අපි ස්වභාවිකවම කරන්නෙමු\" යනුවෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ NDTV සිය වෙබ් අඩවියේ සඳහන් කර ඇති බව Jaishankar උපුටා දක්වයි.",
        "ජායිශංකර්ගේ කථාව අවධානය යොමු කළේ චීනය ඉන්දියාව සමඟ ඉන්දියාවේ සබඳතා කෙරෙහි වන අතර, බීජිං දේශසීමාවේ සිදු කර ඇති දෙයින් පසු “අතිශයින් දුෂ්කර අවධියක්” හරහා ගමන් කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අසල්වාසීන් දෙදෙනාට අත්වැල් බැඳ ගැනීමට නොහැකි වුවහොත් ආසියානු ශතවර්ෂය සිදු නොවන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නැවත පිරවීමේ අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා දැනට දිවයිනේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම්ලා ඇති චීන ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ චීනය අතර මෑතදී ඇති වූ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුම පිළිබඳව විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා කිසිදු පැහැදිලි සඳහනක් නොකළේය.",
        "චීන ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායට නැංගේ",
        "\"මේ මොහොතේ (ඉන්දියා-චීන) සම්බන්ධතාවය චීනය දේශසීමාවේ කළ දේවලින් පසු අතිශය දුෂ්කර අවධියක් හරහා ගමන් කරයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"මම හිතන්නේ ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය එකට එකතු විය යුතු නම්, එසේ කිරීමට බොහෝ හේතු තිබේ, අවශ්‍යයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පමණක් නොවේ,\" ඔහු කියා සිටියේ අත්වැල් බැඳ ගැනීම ඉන්දියාවට සහ චීනයට අවශ්‍ය බවයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජයශංකර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 17 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ පමණක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු සියවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝ.19/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா தனது இயன்றவரை இலங்கைக்கு உதவியுள்ளது, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் உதவி செய்யும்: ஜெய்சங்கர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா தன்னால் இயன்றவரை உதவி செய்துள்ளது மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த தீவு நாட்டிற்கு உதவும் என இந்திய வெளியுறவுத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஜெய்சங்கர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 17 வியாழன் அன்று பேங்கொக்கில் நடந்த நிகழ்வொன்றில் ஜெய்சங்கர் கூறியதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் மேற்கோள் காட்டி, இந்த ஆண்டு மட்டும் இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை கடன் மற்றும் பரிமாற்ற ஏற்பாடுகள் உட்பட ஆதரவாக நீட்டித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"நாங்கள் IMF இல் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கக்கூடிய எந்த உதவியையும் நாங்கள் இயல்பாகவே செய்வோம்\" என்று இந்தியாவின் NDTV ஜெய்சங்கரை மேற்கோள் காட்டி தனது இணையதளத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜெய்சங்கரின் பேச்சு சீனா இந்தியாவுடனான இந்தியாவின் உறவுகளை மையமாகக் கொண்டது, இது பெய்ஜிங் எல்லையில் செய்ததற்குப் பிறகு \"மிகவும் கடினமான கட்டத்தை\" கடந்து வருவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இரண்டு அண்டை நாடுகளும் கைகோர்க்க முடியாவிட்டால் ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு நடக்காது, என்றார்.",
        "தற்போது தீவின் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிரப்பும் நோக்கத்திற்காக நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சீன கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் தொடர்பாக இந்தியா, இலங்கை மற்றும் சீனாவுக்கு இடையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள சமீபத்திய இராஜதந்திர முறுகல் குறித்து வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் வெளிப்படையான குறிப்பு எதையும் தெரிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "சீன கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கையின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "எல்லையில் சீனா செய்ததற்குப் பிறகு தற்போது (இந்தியா-சீனா) உறவு மிகவும் கடினமான கட்டத்தில் உள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்தியாவும் சீனாவும் ஒன்று சேர வேண்டுமானால், அவ்வாறு செய்வதற்கு பல காரணங்கள் உள்ளன, இலங்கை மட்டும் அவசியமில்லை,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவின் சொந்த நலன் கைகோர்க்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 17 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மட்டும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்டிடிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்19/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}