{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83372/extensive-talks-between-president-advisory-group-on-multilateral-engagement-debt-sustainability",
  "time_ut": 1656695700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Extensive talks between President & advisory group on multilateral engagement, debt sustainability",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Extensive talks between President & advisory group on multilateral engagement, debt sustainability",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa says he had an extensive zoom discussion with the members of the Advisory Group on Multilateral Engagement and Debt Sustainability.",
        "The future of International Monetary Fund (IMF) procedures and methods to overcome the challenges Sri Lanka is facing were taken up for discussion, President Rajapaksa said in a tweet.",
        "In April, a team of eminent economic and fiscal experts were appointed as the members of this presidential advisory group.",
        "It consists of Dr. Indrajit Coomaraswamy, former Governor, Central Bank of Sri Lanka and Former Director, Economic Affairs Division of the Commonwealth Secretariat; Prof. Shanta Devarajan, Professor of the Practice of Development, Georgetown University and Former Chief Economist, World Bank; and Dr. Sharmini Coorey, former Director, Institute of Capacity Development of the IMF Institute, and Former Deputy Director, Africa Department, IMF."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "President & advisory group",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Advisory Group on Multilateral Engagement",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Debt Sustainability",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indrajit Coomaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Affairs Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanta Devarajan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Practice of Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Georgetown University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sharmini Coorey",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Institute of Capacity Development of the IMF Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Africa Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බහුපාර්ශ්වික නියැලීම, ණය තිරසාරභාවය පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති සහ උපදේශක කණ්ඩායම අතර පුළුල් සාකච්ඡා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බහුපාර්ශ්වික බැඳීම් සහ ණය තිරසාරභාවය පිළිබඳ උපදේශක කණ්ඩායමේ සාමාජිකයින් සමඟ තමන් පුළුල් විශාලන සාකච්ඡාවක නිරත වූ බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) ක්‍රියාපටිපාටියේ අනාගතය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින අභියෝග ජයගැනීමේ ක්‍රමවේදයන් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡාවට ගත් බව ජනාධිපතිතුමා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී මෙම ජනාධිපති උපදේශක කණ්ඩායමේ සාමාජිකයන් ලෙස කීර්තිමත් ආර්ථික සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය විශේෂඥයින් කණ්ඩායමක් පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "එය සමන්විත වන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ හිටපු අධිපති ආචාර්ය ඉන්ද්‍රජිත් කුමාරස්වාමි සහ පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ආර්ථික කටයුතු අංශයේ හිටපු අධ්‍යක්ෂ; ජෝර්ජ්ටවුන් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ සංවර්ධන පරිචය පිළිබඳ මහාචාර්ය ශාන්තා දේවරාජන් සහ ලෝක බැංකුවේ හිටපු ප්‍රධාන ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥ; සහ IMF ආයතනයේ ධාරිතා සංවර්ධන ආයතනයේ හිටපු අධ්‍යක්ෂ ආචාර්ය Sharmini Coorey සහ IMF හි අප්‍රිකානු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සභාපති සහ උපදේශක කණ්ඩායම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහුපාර්ශ්වික කටයුතු පිළිබඳ උපදේශක කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය තිරසාර බව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ද්‍රජිත් කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික කටයුතු අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත දේවරාජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනයේ පරිචය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝර්ජ්ටවුන් විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂර්මිණි කුරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF ආයතනයේ ධාරිතා සංවර්ධන ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්‍රිකානු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பலதரப்பு ஈடுபாடு, கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை குறித்து ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் ஆலோசனைக் குழு இடையே விரிவான பேச்சு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பலதரப்பு ஈடுபாடு மற்றும் கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை தொடர்பான ஆலோசனைக் குழுவின் உறுப்பினர்களுடன் தாம் விரிவான ஜூம் கலந்துரையாடலை நடத்தியதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) எதிர்கால நடைமுறைகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்களை சமாளிப்பதற்கான வழிமுறைகள் விவாதத்திற்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்டன, ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் கூறினார்.",
        "ஏப்ரலில், இந்த ஜனாதிபதி ஆலோசனைக் குழுவின் உறுப்பினர்களாக புகழ்பெற்ற பொருளாதார மற்றும் நிதி நிபுணர்கள் குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இது இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி இந்திரஜித் குமாரசுவாமி மற்றும் பொதுநலவாய செயலகத்தின் பொருளாதார விவகாரப் பிரிவின் முன்னாள் பணிப்பாளர்; பேராசிரியர் சாந்தா தேவராஜன், ஜார்ஜ்டவுன் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் வளர்ச்சிப் பயிற்சிப் பேராசிரியர் மற்றும் உலக வங்கியின் முன்னாள் தலைமைப் பொருளாதார நிபுணர்; மற்றும் டாக்டர். ஷர்மினி கூரே, முன்னாள் இயக்குனர், IMF இன்ஸ்டிட்யூட் ஆப் திறன் மேம்பாட்டு நிறுவனம் மற்றும் முன்னாள் துணை இயக்குனர், ஆப்பிரிக்கா துறை, IMF."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தலைவர் & ஆலோசனைக் குழு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலதரப்பு ஈடுபாடு குறித்த ஆலோசனைக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திரஜித் குமாரசுவாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார விவகாரங்கள் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாந்தா தேவராஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சியின் நடைமுறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்ஜ்டவுன் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷர்மினி குரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF நிறுவனத்தின் திறன் மேம்பாட்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்கா துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}