{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/கந்தகாடு-மோதல்-விசாரணை-அறிக்கை-இன்று/175-299746",
  "time_ut": 1656995705,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கந்தகாடு மோதல்: விசாரணை அறிக்கை இன்று",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kandakhadu conflict: Inquiry report today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Commissioner General of Rehabilitation, Major General Darshana Hettiarachi, has said that he will receive the investigation report regarding the clash that took place last Tuesday night at Kantagadu Rehabilitation Centre.",
        "After receiving it, it will be handed over to Justice Minister Vijayadasa Rajapaksa, he said.",
        "A four-member committee was appointed to investigate the incident and submit a report.",
        "Of the approximately 800 prisoners who escaped during the unrest, 701 were arrested and remanded in custody.",
        "The Commissioner General of Rehabilitation mentioned that steps have been taken to find 27 more people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rehabilitation, Major",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshana Hettiarachi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantagadu Rehabilitation Centre",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijayadasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "701",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rehabilitation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්දකාඩු ගැටුම: විමර්ශන වාර්තාව අද",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කන්තගාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ පසුගිය අඟහරුවාදා රාත්‍රියේ ඇති වූ ගැටුම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන වාර්තාව තමන් වෙත ලැබෙනු ඇති බව පුනරුත්ථාපන කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් මේජර් ජෙනරාල් දර්ශන හෙට්ටිආරච්චි මහතා පවසයි.",
        "එය ලැබීමෙන් පසු අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිත බව ද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සොයා බලා වාර්තාවක් ලබාදීමට සිව් පුද්ගල කමිටුවක් පත් කළා.",
        "නොසන්සුන්තාව අතරතුර පැන ගිය සිරකරුවන් 800 ක් පමණ අතරින් 701 ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කරන ලදී.",
        "තවත් පුද්ගලයින් 27 දෙනෙකු සොයා ගැනීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බවයි පුනරුත්ථාපන කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල්වරයා සඳහන් කළේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පුනරුත්ථාපනය, මේජර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශන හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්ටගාඩු පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "701",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුනරුත්ථාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கந்தகாடு மோதல்: விசாரணை அறிக்கை இன்று",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "கந்தகாடு புனர்வாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் கடந்த செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை இரவு இடம்பெற்ற மோதல் சம்பவம் தொடர்பான விசாரணை அறிக்கையை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளவுள்ளதாக புனர்வாழ்வு ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் தர்ஷன ஹெட்டியாராச்சி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதனை பெற்றுக் கொண்ட பின்னர் நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் கையளிக்கப்படும் என அவர் கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்தி அறிக்கை சமர்பிக்க நான்கு பேர் கொண்ட குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அமைதியின்மையின் போது தப்பியோடிய சுமார் 800 கைதிகளில் 701 கைதிகள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும் 27 பேரை கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளதாக புனர்வாழ்வு ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மறுவாழ்வு, மேஜர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷன ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தகாடு மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "701",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புனர்வாழ்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}