{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/National-People-s-Council-to-resolve-public-issues-through-Parliament-Sajith-Premadasa/56-737942",
  "time_ut": 1658875171,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘National People’s Council’ to resolve public issues through Parliament: Sajith Premadasa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘National People’s Council’ to resolve public issues through Parliament: Sajith Premadasa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Council will take place at 2 p.m. on Mondays at Opposition Leader’s office",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa says a ‘National People’s Council’ will be established for the purpose of taking the proposals put forward by the people to the Parliament and making an optimal",
        "“The reason for public pressure is that there is no way to implement a systematic program to implement participatory democracy.” Premadasa said adding that there should be a correct exchange of ideas between the people and the leaders of the country.  “This can ensure the leaders are guided down a correct path,” he said. The Opposition Leader said that progressive proposals received by the national council will be submitted to Parliament.",
        "The Opposition Leader said that participatory governance should be implemented at all times rather than leaders going among the people only during elections every five years. “This is what the people engaged in the citizen’s struggle are also asking for,” he added.",
        "Premadasa said the ‘National People’s Council’ will be formed by bringing together all the mass societies, trade unions and civil organisations. Tissa Attanayake has been appointed as the convener of the council and Mujiber Rahman has been appointed as the secretary. The council will meet every Monday at 2 p.m.",
        "The leader of the Opposition said that the council will set an example for the existing Government and that it should become a legal program. “The proposals people submit will be supported as an Opposition and it will be implemented through Parliament,” he said.  “Any member of the public can submit proposals,” he said. Premadasa said that the Council will come up with proposals regarding the future program of building the country and alleviating current difficulties faced by the people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament: Sajith Premadasa",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mondays",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the national council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "every five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujiber Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘ජාතික මහජන සභාව’ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා මහජන ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට: සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සභාව ප.ව. සඳුදා විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී",
        "ජනතාව ඉදිරිපත් කරන යෝජනා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගෙන ගොස් ප්‍රශස්ත ලෙස ගෙන ඒම සඳහා ජාතික මහජන සභාවක් පිහිටුවන බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසයි.",
        "\"මහජන පීඩනයට හේතුව සහභාගීත්ව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා ක්‍රමානුකූල වැඩපිළිවෙලක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ක්‍රමයක් නොමැති වීමයි.\" රටේ ජනතාව සහ නායකයින් අතර නිවැරදි අදහස් හුවමාරුවක් සිදුවිය යුතු බවද ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය. \"මෙය නායකයින් නිවැරදි මාවතකට යොමු කිරීම සහතික කළ හැකිය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. ජාතික සභාවට ලැබෙන ප්‍රගතිශීලී යෝජනා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "සෑම වසර පහකට වරක් මැතිවරණවලදී පමණක් නායකයින් ජනතාව අතරට යනවාට වඩා සහභාගිත්ව පාලනයක් සෑම විටම ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතු බව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය. \"පුරවැසි අරගලයේ යෙදී සිටින ජනතාවද ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ මෙයයි\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "සියලුම බහුජන සමාජ, වෘත්තීය සමිති සහ සිවිල් සංවිධාන එකතු කර ‘ජාතික මහජන සභාව’ පිහිටුවන බව ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය. එම සභාවේ කැඳවුම්කරු ලෙස තිස්ස අත්තනායක පත් කර ඇති අතර ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස මුජිබර් රහ්මාන් පත් කර තිබේ. සභාව සෑම සඳුදා දිනකම ප.ව.",
        "එම සභාව පවතින රජයට ආදර්ශයක් දෙන බවත් එය නීත්‍යානුකූල වැඩපිළිවෙළක් බවට පත් විය යුතු බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය. “ජනතාව ඉදිරිපත් කරන යෝජනාවලට විපක්ෂයක් ලෙස සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන අතර එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා ක්‍රියාත්මක කරනවා,” ඔහු පැවසීය. “ඕනෑම මහජනතාවකට යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකියි,” ඔහු පැවසීය. ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ රට ගොඩනැගීමේ ඉදිරි වැඩපිළිවෙල සහ ජනතාව මුහුණ දී සිටින වත්මන් දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන යෝජනා සභාවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව: සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසර පහකට වරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘தேசிய மக்கள் பேரவை’ பொதுப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாகத் தீர்வு காணும்: சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மதியம் 2 மணிக்கு கவுன்சில் நடக்கும். திங்கட்கிழமைகளில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில்",
        "மக்களால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணைகளை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு எடுத்துச் சென்று சிறந்த முறையில் நிறைவேற்றும் நோக்கில் ‘தேசிய மக்கள் பேரவை’ ஸ்தாபிக்கப்படும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"பங்கேற்பு ஜனநாயகத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்த ஒரு முறையான திட்டத்தை செயல்படுத்த வழி இல்லை என்பதே பொது அழுத்தத்திற்கான காரணம்.\" நாட்டு மக்களுக்கும் தலைவர்களுக்கும் இடையில் சரியான கருத்துப் பரிமாற்றம் இருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் பிரேமதாச கூறினார். \"தலைவர்கள் சரியான பாதையில் வழிநடத்தப்படுவதை இது உறுதி செய்ய முடியும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். தேசிய சபைக்கு கிடைத்துள்ள முற்போக்கான முன்மொழிவுகள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஐந்தாண்டுகளுக்கு ஒருமுறை தேர்தல்களின் போது மட்டும் மக்கள் மத்தியில் தலைவர்கள் செல்வதை விட பங்கேற்பு ஆட்சிமுறை எல்லா நேரங்களிலும் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார். “குடிமக்கள் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள மக்களும் இதைத்தான் கேட்கிறார்கள்,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அனைத்து வெகுஜன சமூகங்கள், தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புகளை ஒன்றிணைத்து ‘தேசிய மக்கள் பேரவை’ உருவாக்கப்படும் என்று பிரேமதாச கூறினார். சபையின் அழைப்பாளராக திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்கவும் செயலாளராக முஜிபர் ரஹ்மானும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். கவுன்சில் ஒவ்வொரு திங்கட்கிழமையும் பிற்பகல் 2 மணிக்கு கூடும்.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள அரசாங்கத்திற்கு முன்னுதாரணமாக இந்த சபை அமையும் எனவும் அது சட்ட திட்டமாக மாற வேண்டும் எனவும் எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார். \"மக்கள் சமர்ப்பிக்கும் முன்மொழிவுகள் எதிர்க்கட்சியாக ஆதரிக்கப்படும், அது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூலம் செயல்படுத்தப்படும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். \"பொதுமக்கள் எவரும் முன்மொழிவுகளை சமர்ப்பிக்கலாம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான எதிர்கால வேலைத்திட்டம் மற்றும் மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் தற்போதைய சிரமங்களை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கான முன்மொழிவுகளை சபை முன்வைக்கும் என்று பிரேமதாச கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்: சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}