{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84416/imf-eyes-creditor-assurances-as-it-prepares-sri-lanka-visit",
  "time_ut": 1660962120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF eyes creditor assurances as it prepares Sri Lanka visit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF eyes creditor assurances as it prepares Sri Lanka visit",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The International Monetary Fund said it will need “adequate assurances” from Sri Lanka’s creditors for a new program as it prepares a visit to Colombo later this month.",
        "The goal of the visit is to make progress on a staff-level agreement for an aid package “in the near term,” to help the island nation weather a severe economic crisis, the IMF said on Friday.",
        "Staff from the global lender will be in Colombo from August 24 to 31, the IMF said.",
        "“Because Sri Lanka’s public debt is assessed as unsustainable, approval by the IMF Executive Board of the Extended Fund Facility program would require adequate assurances by Sri Lanka’s creditors that debt sustainability will be restored,” the IMF said.",
        "Reuters reported on Thursday that Sri Lanka will ask Japan to invite the Indian Ocean island’s main creditor nations, including China and India, to talks on bilateral debt restructuring.",
        "The loan package being negotiated with the IMF is for between $2 billion and $3 billion according to President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who said he would present an interim budget in September focusing on fiscal consolidation measures agreed with the IMF.",
        "The country of 22 million people is facing its most severe financial crisis since independence from Britain in 1948, resulting from the combined impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and economic mismanagement.",
        "Ordinary Sri Lankans have been battling shortages for months amid crippling inflation and a devalued currency, stoking unprecedented mass protests. Thousands of people stormed the colonial-era presidential residence in Colombo, the commercial capital, in early July.",
        "Sri Lanka’s total bilateral debt earlier this year was estimated at $6.2 billion as of the end of 2020 by the IMF. It also has $14 billion of international sovereign bond debt."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "later this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24 to 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the IMF Executive Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between $2 billion and $3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ordinary Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$14 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරයට සූදානම් වන විට ණයහිමියන්ගේ සහතිකය දෙස බලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල මේ මස අගදී කොළඹ සංචාරයක් සූදානම් කරන බැවින් නව වැඩසටහනක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් “ප්‍රමාණවත් සහතික කිරීම්” අවශ්‍ය වනු ඇතැයි පැවසීය.",
        "සංචාරයේ ඉලක්කය වන්නේ දිවයිනේ ජාතිය දරුණු ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා උපකාර පැකේජයක් සඳහා \"නුදුරු කාලීනව\" කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් මත ප්රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීම බව IMF සිකුරාදා පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝලීය ණය දෙන්නාගේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා කොළඹ සිටින බව IMF පවසයි.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ණය තිරසාර නොවන ලෙස තක්සේරු කර ඇති නිසා, විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම් වැඩසටහනේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ විධායක මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතිය සඳහා ණය තිරසාරභාවය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන්ගේ ප්‍රමාණවත් සහතිකයක් අවශ්‍ය වනු ඇත,\" IMF පැවසීය.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා රොයිටර් වාර්තා කළේ, ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු ඉන්දීය සාගර දූපතේ ප්‍රධාන ණය දෙන රටවල්වලට ආරාධනා කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් පවතින ණය පැකේජය ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ත් 3 ත් අතර මුදලක් වන අතර, IMF සමඟ එකඟ වූ මූල්‍ය ඒකාග්‍රතා ක්‍රියාමාර්ග කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරමින් සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී අතුරු අයවැයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් සිටින රට 1948 දී බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයෙන් නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු එහි දරුණුතම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටින අතර, COVID-19 වසංගතයේ සහ ආර්ථික වැරදි කළමනාකරණයේ ඒකාබද්ධ බලපෑම හේතුවෙන්.",
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ මහජන විරෝධතා අවුලුවාලන උද්ධමනය සහ අවප්‍රමාණය වූ මුදල් ඒකකයක් මධ්‍යයේ සාමාන්‍ය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මාස ගණනාවක් හිඟ හිඟයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටිති. ජුලි මස මුලදී වාණිජ අගනුවර වූ කොළඹ පිහිටි යටත් විජිත යුගයේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට දහස් ගණන් ජනයා කඩා වැදුණහ.",
        "මෙම වසර මුලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුළු ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රමාණය 2020 අවසානය වන විට IMF විසින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 ක් ලෙස ගණන් බලා ඇත. එහි ජාත්‍යන්තර ස්වෛරීත්ව බැඳුම්කර ණය ඩොලර් බිලියන 14ක් ද ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මාසයේ පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 සිට 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 සිට ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාමාන්‍ය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 14 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் இலங்கை விஜயத்தை தயார் செய்யும் போது கடன் வழங்குனர் உத்தரவாதத்தை கவனிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம், இந்த மாத இறுதியில் கொழும்புக்கு விஜயம் செய்யவுள்ள நிலையில், புதிய திட்டமொன்றுக்கு இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகளிடமிருந்து \"போதுமான உத்தரவாதங்கள்\" தேவைப்படுவதாக கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "தீவு தேசம் கடுமையான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்வதற்கு உதவுவதற்காக \"அருகில்\" ஒரு உதவிப் பொதிக்கான பணியாளர் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தத்தில் முன்னேற்றம் காண்பதே இந்த விஜயத்தின் குறிக்கோள் என்று IMF வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "உலகளாவிய கடன் வழங்குநரின் ஊழியர்கள் ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை கொழும்பில் இருப்பார்கள் என்று IMF தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் பொதுக் கடன் நீடிக்க முடியாதது என மதிப்பிடப்படுவதால், விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி திட்டத்தின் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிறைவேற்று வாரியத்தின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு, கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுக்கும் என்று இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகளால் போதுமான உத்தரவாதம் தேவைப்படும்\" என்று IMF கூறியது.",
        "இருதரப்பு கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு, சீனா மற்றும் இந்தியா உள்ளிட்ட இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் தீவின் முக்கிய கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளை அழைக்குமாறு ஜப்பானை இலங்கை கேட்கும் என்று வியாழனன்று ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கூற்றுப்படி, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தப்படும் கடன் தொகுப்பு $2 பில்லியன் முதல் $3 பில்லியன் வரையிலானது.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்களைக் கொண்ட நாடு 1948 இல் பிரிட்டனில் இருந்து சுதந்திரம் பெற்றதிலிருந்து அதன் மிகக் கடுமையான நிதி நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்கிறது, இது கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் மற்றும் பொருளாதார தவறான நிர்வாகத்தின் ஒருங்கிணைந்த தாக்கத்தின் விளைவாகும்.",
        "ஊனமுற்ற பணவீக்கம் மற்றும் மதிப்பிழந்த நாணயத்தின் மத்தியில் சாதாரண இலங்கையர்கள் பல மாதங்களாக பற்றாக்குறையுடன் போராடி வருகின்றனர். ஜூலை தொடக்கத்தில், வணிகத் தலைநகரான கொழும்பில் உள்ள காலனித்துவ கால ஜனாதிபதி இல்லத்தை ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டனர்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் இலங்கையின் மொத்த இருதரப்புக் கடன் 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் 6.2 பில்லியன் டாலர்களாக IMF மதிப்பிட்டுள்ளது. இது $14 பில்லியன் சர்வதேச இறையாண்மை பத்திரக் கடனையும் கொண்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF நிர்வாக வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$2 பில்லியன் மற்றும் $3 பில்லியன் இடையே",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாதாரண இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$14 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}