{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Dialog-partners-OnMobile-to-launch-mobile-cloud-gaming-platform-ONMO/34-736904",
  "time_ut": 1656633392,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dialog partners OnMobile to launch mobile cloud gaming platform ONMO",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dialog partners OnMobile to launch mobile cloud gaming platform ONMO",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dialog Axiata PLC, Sri Lanka’s premier connectivity provider, partnered OnMobile, the global leader in mobile entertainment, to launch ONMO (www.onmo.dgl.lk) to provide Dialog mobile customers a unique, immersive and interactive gaming experience.",
        "ONMO, a mobile gaming platform that blends cloud streaming, social Esports and Artificial Intelligence (AI), offers Dialog mobile users access to more than 60 exciting mobile games spanning genres such as action, arcade, racing, adventure, puzzles, and more with new games added every week. Users can enjoy ONMO and all of its wide range of games for Rs. 399 + taxes per month. ONMO’s challenge creation Vision AI engine brings casual Esports to everyone on a social platform with no friction and with no prior download necessary. The platform also offers a social play aspect, with short, curated game moments and virtual rewards, along with many more exciting features.",
        "Speaking on the launch of the platform, Dialog Axiata PLC Group Chief Innovation Officer and Chief Architect Anthony Rodrigo stated, “Dialog is excited to be the first to launch a commercial cloud gaming platform in Sri Lanka in collaboration with our partner, OnMobile. This cloud gaming platform has been optimised for smartphones and to seamlessly run on Dialog’s 4G mobile and Home Broadband networks. We are also excited to witness the full potential that 5G will unlock for Cloud Gaming in future for all Sri Lankans.”",
        "ONMO CEO Krish Seshadri said, “We believe ONMO will emerge as a go-to-destination for cloud gaming in the region. We are excited to partner with Dialog to launch the first cloud gaming platform in Sri Lanka. The social play aspect, short, curated game moments and virtual rewards will make ONMO a fun and engaging experience for Dialog consumers.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ONMO",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OnMobile",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.onmo.dgl.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "social Esports and Artificial Intelligence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "every week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "399 +",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vision AI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esports",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anthony Rodrigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OnMobile",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Broadband",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krish Seshadri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජංගම ක්ලවුඩ් ක්‍රීඩා වේදිකාව ONMO දියත් කිරීමට Dialog හවුල්කරුවන් OnMobile",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම සම්බන්ධතා සැපයුම්කරු වන Dialog Axiata PLC, ජංගම දුරකථන විනෝදාස්වාදයේ ගෝලීය ප්‍රමුඛයා වන OnMobile සමඟ හවුල් වී ONMO (www.onmo.dgl.lk) ඩයලොග් ජංගම පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට අද්විතීය, ගිලී ගිය සහ අන්තර්ක්‍රියාකාරී ක්‍රීඩා අත්දැකීමක් ලබා දීමට.",
        "Cloud streaming, social Esports සහ Artificial Intelligence (AI) සම්මිශ්‍රණය කරන ජංගම ක්‍රීඩා වේදිකාවක් වන ONMO, Dialog ජංගම දුරකථන භාවිතා කරන්නන්ට ක්‍රියාදාම, ආකේඩ්, රේසිං, වික්‍රමාන්විත, ප්‍රහේලිකා සහ තවත් බොහෝ ප්‍රභේදයන්ගෙන් විහිදෙන ආකර්ෂණීය ජංගම ක්‍රීඩා සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය ලබා දෙයි. සෑම සතියකම ක්‍රීඩා එකතු වේ. පරිශීලකයින්ට ONMO සහ එහි සියලුම පුළුල් පරාසයක ක්‍රීඩා රු. මසකට 399 + බදු. ONMO හි අභියෝගාත්මක නිර්මාණයක් වන Vision AI එන්ජිම ඝර්ෂණයකින් තොරව සහ පෙර බාගත කිරීමකින් තොරව සමාජ වේදිකාවක සිටින සෑම කෙනෙකුටම අනියම් Esports ගෙන එයි. වේදිකාව කෙටි, සංක්ෂිප්ත ක්‍රීඩා අවස්ථා සහ අතථ්‍ය ත්‍යාග සමඟින් තවත් බොහෝ ආකර්ෂණීය විශේෂාංග සමඟින් සමාජ ක්‍රීඩා අංගයක් ද පිරිනමයි.",
        "වේදිකාව දියත් කිරීම පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් Dialog Axiata PLC සමූහයේ ප්‍රධාන නවෝත්පාදන නිලධාරී සහ ප්‍රධාන ගෘහ නිර්මාණ ශිල්පී Anthony Rodrigo මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, “අපගේ හවුල්කරු වන OnMobile සමඟ එක්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වාණිජ ක්ලවුඩ් ක්‍රීඩා වේදිකාවක් දියත් කරන ප්‍රථම අවස්ථාව ඩයලොග් විසින් ප්‍රබෝධමත් කරන බවයි. මෙම ක්ලවුඩ් ක්‍රීඩා වේදිකාව ස්මාර්ට්ෆෝන් සඳහා ප්‍රශස්ත කර ඇති අතර Dialog හි 4G ජංගම සහ Home Broadband ජාල මත බාධාවකින් තොරව ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ. සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සඳහා අනාගතයේදී Cloud Gaming සඳහා 5G අගුළු හැරීමේ පූර්ණ විභවය දැකීමට අපි සතුටු වෙමු. ”",
        "ONMO හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී ක්‍රිෂ් ශේෂාද්‍රි පැවසුවේ, “කලාපයේ වලාකුළු ක්‍රීඩා සඳහා ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස ONMO මතු වනු ඇතැයි අපි විශ්වාස කරමු. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු ක්ලවුඩ් ක්‍රීඩා වේදිකාව දියත් කිරීමට ඩයලොග් සමඟ හවුල් වීමට ලැබීම ගැන අපි සතුටු වෙමු. සමාජ ක්‍රීඩා අංගය, කෙටි, සංක්‍රමණික ක්‍රීඩා අවස්ථා සහ අතථ්‍ය ත්‍යාග ONMO Dialog පාරිභෝගිකයින් සඳහා විනෝදජනක සහ ආකර්ෂණීය අත්දැකීමක් බවට පත් කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ONMO",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OnMobile",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.onmo.dgl.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ එස්පෝර්ට්ස් සහ කෘතිම බුද්ධිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයලොග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම සතියකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "399 +",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැක්ම AI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esports",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්තනි රුද්‍රිගු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OnMobile",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයලොග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Broadband",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂ් ශේෂාද්‍රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයලොග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மொபைல் கிளவுட் கேமிங் பிளாட்ஃபார்ம் ONMO ஐ அறிமுகப்படுத்த Dialog பங்காளிகள் OnMobile",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dialog மொபைல் வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு தனித்துவமான, அதிவேகமான மற்றும் ஊடாடும் கேமிங் அனுபவத்தை வழங்குவதற்காக ONMO (www.onmo.dgl.lk) ஐ அறிமுகப்படுத்த, இலங்கையின் முதன்மையான இணைப்பு வழங்குனரான Dialog Axiata PLC, மொபைல் பொழுதுபோக்குகளில் உலகளாவிய முன்னணி நிறுவனமான OnMobile உடன் இணைந்து கொண்டது.",
        "கிளவுட் ஸ்ட்ரீமிங், சோஷியல் எஸ்போர்ட்ஸ் மற்றும் செயற்கை நுண்ணறிவு (AI) ஆகியவற்றை இணைக்கும் மொபைல் கேமிங் தளமான ONMO ஆனது, டயலொக் மொபைல் பயனர்களுக்கு அதிரடி, ஆர்கேட், பந்தயம், சாகசம், புதிர்கள் மற்றும் பல வகைகளை உள்ளடக்கிய 60க்கும் மேற்பட்ட அற்புதமான மொபைல் கேம்களுக்கான அணுகலை வழங்குகிறது. ஒவ்வொரு வாரமும் விளையாட்டுகள் சேர்க்கப்படும். பயனர்கள் ONMO மற்றும் அதன் பரந்த அளவிலான கேம்கள் அனைத்தையும் ரூ. மாதத்திற்கு 399 + வரிகள். ONMO இன் சவால் உருவாக்கம் விஷன் AI இன்ஜின் உராய்வு மற்றும் முன் பதிவிறக்கம் தேவையில்லாமல், சமூக தளத்தில் அனைவருக்கும் சாதாரண Esports ஐ வழங்குகிறது. மேலும் பல அற்புதமான அம்சங்களுடன் குறுகிய, க்யூரேட்டட் கேம் தருணங்கள் மற்றும் மெய்நிகர் வெகுமதிகளுடன், சமூக விளையாட்டு அம்சத்தையும் இந்த தளம் வழங்குகிறது.",
        "மேடையை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியதில், Dialog Axiata PLC குழுமத்தின் பிரதம கண்டுபிடிப்பு அதிகாரியும் தலைமைக் கட்டிடக்கலை நிபுணருமான Anthony Rodrigo பேசுகையில், “Dialog எங்கள் பங்காளியான OnMobile உடன் இணைந்து இலங்கையில் வர்த்தக கிளவுட் கேமிங் தளத்தை முதன்முதலில் அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதில் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறது. இந்த கிளவுட் கேமிங் இயங்குதளமானது ஸ்மார்ட்போன்களுக்காகவும், டயலொக்கின் 4G மொபைல் மற்றும் ஹோம் பிராட்பேண்ட் நெட்வொர்க்குகளில் தடையின்றி இயங்குவதற்கும் உகந்ததாக உள்ளது. அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களுக்கும் எதிர்காலத்தில் கிளவுட் கேமிங்கிற்கு 5G திறக்கும் முழு திறனையும் காண்பதில் நாங்கள் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம்.",
        "ONMO தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி கிரிஷ் சேஷாத்ரி கூறுகையில், “இந்தப் பகுதியில் கிளவுட் கேமிங்கிற்குச் செல்லும் இடமாக ONMO உருவாகும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். இலங்கையில் முதல் கிளவுட் கேமிங் தளத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்த டயலொக் உடன் கூட்டு சேருவதில் நாங்கள் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறோம். சமூக விளையாட்டு அம்சம், குறுகிய, க்யூரேட்டட் கேம் தருணங்கள் மற்றும் மெய்நிகர் வெகுமதிகள் ஆகியவை ONMOவை டயலொக் வாடிக்கையாளர்களுக்கு வேடிக்கையான மற்றும் ஈர்க்கக்கூடிய அனுபவமாக மாற்றும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ONMO",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OnMobile",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.onmo.dgl.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக விளையாட்டு மற்றும் செயற்கை நுண்ணறிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரையாடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வாரமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "399 +",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்வை AI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்போர்ட்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்தோனி ரோட்ரிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OnMobile",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரையாடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகப்பு பிராட்பேண்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரிஷ் சேஷாத்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ONMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரையாடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}