{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/05/sri-lanka-appoints-committee-to-facilitate-return-of-refugees-in-india/",
  "time_ut": 1662371280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka appoints committee to facilitate return of Refugees in India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka appoints committee to facilitate return of Refugees in India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A committee was appointed by President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake to facilitate and efficiently carry out the process of repatriation of Sri Lankans who have gone to India as refugees due to the war, said the President's Media Division.",
        "The committee is headed by Ms. Chandima Wickramasinghe, Additional Secretary to the President, and the other members are the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration, senior official of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, senior official of the Registrar General's Department and a senior official of the Ministry of Justice.",
        "This decision was reached during the discussion held on Monday (05) at the President's Office under the chairmanship of the President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake at the request of the Organization for Eelam Refugees Rehabilitation (OFERR), to bring back the Sri Lankans who have gone to India as refugees due to the war.",
        "It was stated that about 58,000 Sri Lankans are currently residing in Tamil Nadu, India as refugees and only 3,800 of them are ready to return to Sri Lanka at present. The Sri Lanka Deputy High Commissioner’s Office in Chennai is coordinating the efforts in this regard.",
        "Sri Lanka appoints committee to facilitate return of Refugees in India",
        "President wants full implementation of 19th Amendment – Foreign Minister"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandima Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Registrar General's Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Organization for Eelam Refugees Rehabilitation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OFERR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 58,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 3,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ සිටින සරණාගතයින් ආපසු පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); යුද්ධය හේතුවෙන් සරණාගතයින් ලෙස ඉන්දියාවට ගොස් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් නැවත ගෙන්වා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය පහසු සහ කාර්යක්ෂමව සිදුකිරීමට ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා විසින් කමිටුවක් පත් කළ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් චන්දිමා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් මෙම කමිටුවේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් වන්නේ ආගමන විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්වරයා, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියා, රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකු සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකුයි. අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය.",
        "ඊළාම් සරණාගතයින් පුනරුත්ථාපනය සඳහා වූ සංවිධානයේ (OFERR) ඉල්ලීම පරිදි ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් සඳුදා (05) ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවේදී මෙම තීරණයට එළැඹී ඇත. ඉන්දියාව යුද්ධය නිසා සරණාගතයන් ලෙස.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් 58,000ක් පමණ මේ වන විට සරණාගතයින් ලෙස ඉන්දියාවේ තමිල්නාඩුවේ පදිංචිව සිටින බවත්, ඔවුන්ගෙන් 3800ක් පමණක් මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට සූදානමින් සිටින බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කෙරුණා. චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය මේ සම්බන්ධ කටයුතු සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරයි.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සිටින සරණාගතයින් ආපසු පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
        "19 වැනි සංශෝධනය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ජනපතිට අවශ්‍යයි – විදේශ ඇමැති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම් සරණාගතයන් පුනරුත්ථාපනය සඳහා වූ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිනැමීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "58,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,800 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவில் உள்ள அகதிகள் நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதியாக இலங்கை குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); யுத்தம் காரணமாக இந்தியாவிற்கு அகதிகளாகச் சென்ற இலங்கையர்களை நாடு திரும்புவதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை இலகுவாகவும் வினைத்திறனுடனும் முன்னெடுப்பதற்காக ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்கவினால் குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் திருமதி சந்திமா விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தலைமையில் இந்தக் குழுவிலுள்ளதுடன், குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் நாயகம், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி, பதிவாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களத்தின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி ஆகியோர் உறுப்பினர்களாக உள்ளனர். நீதி அமைச்சகம்.",
        "ஈழ அகதிகள் புனர்வாழ்வுக்கான அமைப்பின் (OFERR) வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏகநாயக்க தலைமையில் திங்கட்கிழமை (05) ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் போதே, இலங்கையர்களை அழைத்து வருவதற்கான தீர்மானம் எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது. போரினால் அகதிகளாக இந்தியா.",
        "சுமார் 58,000 இலங்கையர்கள் தற்போது இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாட்டில் அகதிகளாக தங்கியுள்ளதாகவும் அவர்களில் 3800 பேர் மாத்திரமே தற்போது இலங்கைக்குத் திரும்பத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது. சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கை துணை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் அலுவலகம் இது தொடர்பான முயற்சிகளை ஒருங்கிணைத்து வருகிறது.",
        "இந்தியாவில் உள்ள அகதிகள் நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதியாக இலங்கை குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது",
        "19வது திருத்தத்தை முழுமையாக அமுல்படுத்த ஜனாதிபதி விரும்புகிறார் – வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திம விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈழ அகதிகள் மறுவாழ்வுக்கான அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OFERR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 58,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,800 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}