{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83733/nominations-presented-to-elect-sri-lankas-new-president",
  "time_ut": 1658206440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Nominations presented to elect Sri Lanka’s new President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Nominations presented to elect Sri Lanka’s new President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The parliamentary procedure to elect a new president commenced today with the presenting of the nominations for the position.",
        "The names of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, SLPP MP Dullas Alahapperuma and NPP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake were officially nominated for the presidency, after the parliamentary session commenced a short while ago.",
        "MP Dullas Alahapperuma was nominated for the post by Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa while it was seconded by Foreign Minister Prof. G.L. Peiris.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s name was nominated for the presidency by Leader of the House and Minister Dinesh Gunawardena and it was seconded by Minister Manusha Nanayakkara.",
        "National People’s Power (NPP) leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake’s name was nominated for the post of President by MP Vijitha Herath and seconded by MP Harini Amarasuriya.",
        "Accordingly, the parliamentary session was subsequently adjourned until 10.00 a.m. tomorrow (20), when MPs will vote to elect a new president, who will serve out the remainder of former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s term until November 2024."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harini Amarasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා නාමයෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු අද ආරම්භ වූයේ එම තනතුර සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාරදීමත් සමඟයි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ එන්පීපී නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර ආරම්භ වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයෙන් අනතුරුව නිල වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නම් කෙරුණා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා එම ධූරය සඳහා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් නම් කරනු ලැබූ අතර විදේශ අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතා විසින් එය ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නම සභානායක හා අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර එය ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබුවේ අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා විසිනි.",
        "ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (NPP) නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාගේ නම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කරන ලද අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හරිනි අමරසූරිය මහත්මිය විසින් ස්ථිර කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ධූර කාලය 2024 නොවැම්බර් මාසය දක්වා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන විට පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය හෙට (20) පෙරවරු 10.00 දක්වා කල් තැබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිනි අමරසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் புதிய அதிபரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான பாராளுமன்ற நடைமுறைகள் இன்று (27) ஆரம்பமாகி அந்த பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "சற்று முன்னர் பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு ஆரம்பமானதை அடுத்து பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் NPP தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச அந்தப் பதவிக்கு பரிந்துரை செய்திருந்த நிலையில், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பெயர் சபைத் தலைவரும் அமைச்சருமான தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவினால் முன்மொழியப்பட்டதுடன், அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்காரவினால் அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் (NPP) தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவின் பெயரை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத் பரிந்துரை செய்ததோடு, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹரிணி அமரசூரியவினால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு நாளை (20) காலை 10.00 மணி வரை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது, அப்போது முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக்காலம் 2024 நவம்பர் வரை நீடிக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரினி அமரசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}