{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/20/stop-using-terrorism-act-amnesty-appeals-from-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1660968960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Stop using terrorism act, Amnesty appeals from Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Stop using terrorism act, Amnesty appeals from Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Amnesty International has urged the Government of Sri Lanka to not to use the draconian anti-terror law, the Prevention of Terrorism Act, against protestors for their acts of civil disobedience.",
        "Amnesty International further states that the organization is deeply concerned by reports that the IUSF Convener Wasantha Mudalige is currently being held at the Terrorism Investigation Division (TID) under the PTA.",
        "The organization emphasizes that arbitrarily detaining protesters and charging them with serious criminal offences that are not justified by their actions, such as terrorism-related charges, is against international law.",
        "The organization has called for the Government to repeal the PTA instead.",
        "Sri Lanka: President calls Armed Forces to maintain public order"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Amnesty",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amnesty International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amnesty International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IUSF Convener",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Terrorism Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදී පනත භාවිතා කිරීම නවත්වන්න, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් ඇම්නෙස්ටි ආයාචනා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සිවිල් අකීකරු ක්‍රියාවන් සඳහා විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත නම් කුරිරු ත්‍රස්ත විරෝධී නීතිය භාවිතා නොකරන ලෙස ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්ෂමා සංවිධානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ මේ වන විට ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශය යටතේ ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශයේ (TID) රඳවා සිටින බවට පළ වන වාර්තා සම්බන්ධයෙන් එම සංවිධානය දැඩි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටින බව ජාත්‍යන්තර ක්ෂමා සංවිධානය වැඩිදුරටත් පවසයි.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් අත්තනෝමතික ලෙස රඳවා තබා ගැනීම සහ ත්‍රස්තවාදයට සම්බන්ධ චෝදනා වැනි ඔවුන්ගේ ක්‍රියාවලින් යුක්ති සහගත නොවන බරපතල අපරාධ චෝදනා එල්ල කිරීම ජාත්‍යන්තර නීතියට පටහැනි බව එම සංවිධානය අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "ඒ වෙනුවට ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත ඉවත් කරන ලෙස එම සංවිධානය රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: මහජන සාමය පවත්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සන්නද්ධ හමුදා කැඳවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සමාව දීම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇම්නෙස්ටි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම කැඳවුම්කරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්ත විමර්ශන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயங்கரவாதச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதை நிறுத்துங்கள், இலங்கையிடம் இருந்து மன்னிப்பு வேண்டுகோள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சிவில் ஒத்துழையாமைச் செயல்களுக்காக ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக கொடூரமான பயங்கரவாத எதிர்ப்புச் சட்டமான பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம் என்று சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தை வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபையின் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே தற்போது பயங்கரவாத விசாரணைப் பிரிவில் (TID) PTA இன் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெளியான தகவல்களால் அமைப்பு மிகவும் கவலையடைந்துள்ளதாக சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை தன்னிச்சையாக தடுத்து வைப்பது மற்றும் பயங்கரவாதம் தொடர்பான குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் போன்ற அவர்களின் நடவடிக்கைகளால் நியாயப்படுத்தப்படாத கடுமையான கிரிமினல் குற்றங்களைச் சுமத்துவது சர்வதேச சட்டத்திற்கு எதிரானது என்று அந்த அமைப்பு வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "அதற்கு பதிலாக பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தை ரத்து செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று அந்த அமைப்பு அரசுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை: பொது ஒழுங்கை பராமரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஆயுதப்படைகளுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மன்னிப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச மன்னிப்புச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF கன்வீனர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாத விசாரணைப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுத படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}