{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/18/decision-on-naganandas-petition-against-ranil-on-tuesday-19/",
  "time_ut": 1658151480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Decision on Nagananda’s petition against Ranil on Tuesday (19)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Decision on Nagananda’s petition against Ranil on Tuesday (19)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Attorney-at-Law Nagananda Kodituwakku told Sri Lanka’s Supreme Court that if Ranil Wickremesinghe, who is not even suitable to be a member of parliament, is appointed as the Executive President of the country, it may have a negative impact on the future of Sri Lanka.",
        "Nagananda Kodituwakku presented facts to the court seeking to invalidate Wickremesinghe’s seat in Parliament.",
        "However, the Supreme Court will meet on Tuesday to decide whether or not Nagananda Kodituwakku’s will be taken up for examination.",
        "Nagananda Kodituwakku notes that as per the provisions of Article 99 (a) of the Constitution a National List Member of Parliament should submit nominations within one week after the election, and pointed out that the name of Ranil Wickramasinghe was proposed after eight months of the election.",
        "He argued at the Supreme Court that the appointment of Wickremesinghe had violated the constitution and the Parliamentary Elections Act.",
        "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s application was taken up in the presence of Justices Gamini Amarasekera, Shiran Gunaratne, and Janak De Silva.",
        "The application requests for an order to be made against Wickremesinghe preventing him from functioning as a Member of Parliament and preventing him from exercising his vote.",
        "Nagananda Kodituwakku states that Ranil Wickremesinghe was defeated in the recent elections, and was later appointed to Parliament from the National List.",
        "He also argued that a person with no public mandate cannot be appointed to the Constitutional Council, and a person who was defeated at the polls being appointed to Parliament is illegal.",
        "The Justices of the Supreme Court had pointed out that Ranil Wickremesinghe was appointed to Parliament based on the number of votes received by the United National Party, adding that it was a legal avenue etched in the constitution to appoint MPs from the people’s ballot.",
        "The bench also directed its attention to the fact that the petitioner had not taken action to send notice to the respondents mentioned in the petition, including the Attorney General.",
        "President’s Counsel Ronald Perera appearing for Ranil Wickremesinghe noted that he had not received any documentation over the matter.",
        "Easter Attacks: Sri Lanka to seek UK Govt & Intel assistance, says Acting President",
        "Britain should lead international aid effort for Sri Lanka – Former British Diplomat",
        "Friday Forum points out need to elect new President not linked to the GR government"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nagananda",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tuesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 99",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Elections Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justices Gamini Amarasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janak De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ronald Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Easter Attacks:",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK Govt & Intel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල්ට එරෙහි නාගානන්දගේ පෙත්සමේ තීන්දුව අඟහරුවාදා (19)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු වීමටවත් සුදුසු නැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කළහොත් එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනාගතයට අයහපත් බලපෑමක් ඇති කළ හැකි බව නීතීඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ලංකා.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය බලරහිත කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු මහතා අධිකරණයට කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කුගේ කරුණු විභාගයට ගන්නවාද නැද්ද යන්න තීරණය කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අඟහරුවාදා රැස්වේ.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 99 (අ) ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධාන අනුව ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු මැතිවරණයෙන් සතියක් ඇතුළත නාමයෝජනා භාරදිය යුතු බව සඳහන් කරන නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු, මැතිවරණයෙන් මාස අටකට පසුව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා වූ බවද පෙන්වා දෙයි. .",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කිරීමෙන් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනත උල්ලංඝනය කර ඇති බවට ඔහු ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ තර්ක කළේය.",
        "නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කුගේ අයදුම්පත ගාමිණී අමරසේකර, ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න සහ ජනක් ද සිල්වා යන විනිසුරුවරුන් ඉදිරියේ විභාගයට ගැනිණි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීම වළක්වාලමින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම වළක්වාලමින් ඔහුට එරෙහිව නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස එම අයදුම්පතෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "පසුගිය මැතිවරණවලින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පරාජයට පත් වූ බවත්, පසුව ඔහු ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කළ බවත් නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු පවසනවා.",
        "මහජන වරමක් නොමැති පුද්ගලයකු ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවට පත් කළ නොහැකි බවත්, මැතිවරණයෙන් පරාජය වූ පුද්ගලයකු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කිරීම නීති විරෝධී බවත් ඔහු තර්ක කළේය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කරනු ලැබුවේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය ලැබූ ඡන්ද ප්‍රමාණය මත බව පෙන්වා දුන් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන් එය මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පත් කිරීම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ සඳහන් නීත්‍යානුකූල මාර්ගයක් බව ද පෙන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "නීතිපතිවරයා ඇතුළු පෙත්සමේ සඳහන් වගඋත්තරකරුවන්ට නොතීසි යැවීමට පෙත්සම්කරු කටයුතු කර නොතිබීම පිළිබඳවද විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල සිය අවධානය යොමු කළේය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා මහතා සඳහන් කළේ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන්ට කිසිදු ලියවිල්ලක් ලැබී නොමැති බවයි.",
        "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය: ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එක්සත් රාජධානියේ රජයේ සහ ඉන්ටෙල් සහාය ලබා ගන්නා බව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා පවසයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ආධාර ප්‍රයත්නයට බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය නායකත්වය දිය යුතුයි - හිටපු බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය තානාපති",
        "ජීආර් රජයට සම්බන්ධ නැති නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සිකුරාදා සංසදය පෙන්වා දෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාගානන්ද",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "99 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස අටක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනිසුරු ගාමිණී අමරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනක් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොනල්ඩ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ප්‍රහාරය:",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ රජය සහ ඉන්ටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலுக்கு எதிரான நாகாநந்தாவின் மனு மீதான தீர்ப்பு செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19)",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இருப்பதற்கு கூட தகுதியற்ற ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நாட்டின் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்தால் அது இலங்கையின் எதிர்காலத்தில் பாதகமான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் என சட்டத்தரணி நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு இலங்கை உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இலங்கை.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பாராளுமன்ற ஆசனத்தை செல்லுபடியற்றதாக்குமாறு கோரி நாகானந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு நீதிமன்றில் உண்மைகளை முன்வைத்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்குவை பரீட்சைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்வதா இல்லையா என்பதை தீர்மானிக்க உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் செவ்வாய்கிழமை கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 99 (அ) சரத்தின் பிரகாரம் தேர்தல் முடிந்து ஒரு வாரத்திற்குள் தேசியப்பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வேட்புமனுக்களை சமர்ப்பிக்க வேண்டும் என குறிப்பிட்ட நாகானந்த கொடிதுவக்கு, தேர்தல் நடந்து 8 மாதங்களின் பின்னர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பெயர் முன்மொழியப்பட்டதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். .",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் நியமனம் அரசியலமைப்பு மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் சட்டத்தை மீறியுள்ளது என அவர் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் வாதிட்டார்.",
        "நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்குவின் விண்ணப்பம் காமினி அமரசேகர, ஷிரான் குணரத்ன மற்றும் ஜனக் டி சில்வா ஆகியோர் முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராகச் செயற்படவிடாமல் தடுக்கும் வகையிலும், வாக்களிப்பதைத் தடுக்கும் வகையிலும் அவருக்கு எதிராக உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்குமாறு அந்த மனுவில் கோரப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற தேர்தலில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், பின்னர் தேசியப்பட்டியலில் இருந்து பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பொது ஆணை இல்லாத ஒருவரை அரசியலமைப்பு பேரவைக்கு நியமிக்க முடியாது எனவும், தேர்தலில் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட ஒருவர் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்கப்படுவது சட்டவிரோதமானது எனவும் அவர் வாதிட்டார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி பெற்ற வாக்குகளின் அடிப்படையிலேயே ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டார் என சுட்டிக்காட்டிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதியரசர்கள், மக்கள் வாக்கு மூலம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை நியமிப்பது அரசியலமைப்பில் பொறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சட்ட வழி எனவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சட்டமா அதிபர் உட்பட மனுவில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு நோட்டீஸ் அனுப்ப மனுதாரர் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவில்லை என்பது குறித்தும் பெஞ்ச் தனது கவனத்திற்கு உத்தரவிட்டது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா, இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் தமக்கு எவ்வித ஆவணங்களும் கிடைக்கவில்லை என குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்: பிரிட்டன் அரசு மற்றும் உளவுத்துறையின் உதவியை இலங்கை நாட வேண்டும் என்று பதில் அதிபர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "இலங்கைக்கான சர்வதேச உதவி முயற்சிகளுக்கு பிரித்தானியா தலைமை தாங்க வேண்டும் - முன்னாள் பிரித்தானிய இராஜதந்திரி",
        "வெள்ளி மன்றம் GR அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணைக்கப்படாத புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாகாநந்தா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "செவ்வாய்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 99",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதியரசர்கள் காமினி அமரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிரான் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொனால்ட் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் தாக்குதல்கள்:",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே அரசு & இன்டெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}