{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84449/supreme-court-commences-hearing-petitions-against-22nd-amendment",
  "time_ut": 1661145600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Supreme Court commences hearing petitions against 22nd Amendment",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Supreme Court commences hearing petitions against 22nd Amendment",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court today commenced hearing of nine petitions filed challenging the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution.",
        "The hearing of the petitions is held before the three-judge bench consisting of Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, Justices Buwaneka Aluvihare and Arjuna Obeysekera.",
        "The petitions have been filed by nine citizens including the Secretary of the ‘Vinivinda Peramuna’ attoney-at-law Nagananda Kodituwakku, Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara, attorney-at-law Nuwan Ballantudawa, Tissa Bandara Ratnayake, H.D.J. Kulatunga and B.P. Dahanayake.",
        "The Attorney General has been named as the respondent in the petitions.",
        "The petitioners claim that the “Draft Bill of the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution” proposed to be presented to the current constitution by the government was submitted to the parliamentary agenda on the 10th of August.",
        "The petitioners also alleged that certain clauses in it are against the provisions of the present constitution.",
        "The petitions have also allege that the fundamental human rights guaranteed by the Constitution are being violated through this.",
        "Therefore, the petitions have further requested the Supreme Court to give a decision that if it is necessary to pass the clauses included in the relevant bill, it should be passed by a two-thirds majority vote of the Parliament and a referendum."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Supreme Court",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Obeysekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Vinivinda Peramuna’",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Ballantudawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Bandara Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.D.J. Kulatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "B.P. Dahanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draft Bill",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 10th of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට එරෙහි පෙත්සම් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විභාග කිරීම අරඹයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය අභියෝගයට ලක් කරමින් ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම් නවයක් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් අද විභාගයට ගැනුණා.",
        "අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ සහ අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර යන ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල හමුවේ පෙත්සම් විභාගය පැවැත්වෙයි.",
        "විනිවින්ද පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් නීතිඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු, වෛද්‍ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර, නීතිඥ නුවන් බැල්ලන්තුඩාව, තිස්ස බණ්ඩාර රත්නායක, එච්.ඩී.ජේ. කුලතුංග සහ බී.පී. දහනායක.",
        "එම පෙත්සම්වල වගඋත්තරකරු ලෙස නීතිපතිවරයා නම් කර ඇත.",
        "රජය විසින් වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට යෝජිත “22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත” අගෝස්තු 10 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තු න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ බව පෙත්සම්කරුවෝ කියා සිටිති.",
        "එහි ඇතැම් වගන්ති වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ විධිවිධානවලට පටහැනි බවද පෙත්සම්කරුවෝ චෝදනා කළහ.",
        "මෙමගින් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් සහතික කර ඇති මූලික මානව හිමිකම් කඩවන බවටද පෙත්සම් මගින් චෝදනා කර ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් අදාළ පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ ඇතුළත් වගන්ති සම්මත කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තුනෙන් දෙකක බහුතර ඡන්දයෙන් සහ ජනමත විචාරණයකින් සම්මත කළ යුතු බවට තීන්දුවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස එම පෙත්සම් මඟින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයෙන් වැඩිදුරටත් ඉල්ලා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "'විනිවින්ද පෙරමුණ'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවන් බැල්ලන්තුඩාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස බණ්ඩාර රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.ඩී.ජේ. කුලතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.පී. දහනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙටුම්පත් පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22வது திருத்தத்திற்கு எதிரான மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணையை உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தத்தை எதிர்த்து தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட 9 மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணை உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் இன்று தொடங்கியது.",
        "பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, நீதியரசர்களான புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே மற்றும் அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர ஆகிய மூவரடங்கிய நீதிபதிகள் குழாம் முன்னிலையில் இந்த மனுக்கள் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "வினிவிந்த பெரமுனவின் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு, கலாநிதி குணதாச அமரசேகர, சட்டத்தரணி நுவான் பல்லந்துடாவ, திஸ்ஸ பண்டார ரத்நாயக்க, எச்.டி.ஜே உள்ளிட்ட ஒன்பது பிரஜைகளால் இந்த மனுக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன. குலதுங்க மற்றும் பி.பி. தஹநாயக்க.",
        "இந்த மனுக்களில் பிரதிவாதியாக சட்டமா அதிபர் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தினால் தற்போதைய அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு முன்வைக்க உத்தேசிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள “அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்ட வரைவு” ஆகஸ்ட் 10 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்ற நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டதாக மனுதாரர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "அதில் உள்ள சில ஷரத்துகள் தற்போதைய அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளுக்கு எதிரானது என்றும் மனுதாரர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டினர்.",
        "இதன் மூலம் அரசியல் சாசனம் உறுதி செய்துள்ள அடிப்படை மனித உரிமைகள் மீறப்படுவதாகவும் மனுக்களில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, குறித்த சட்டமூலத்தில் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சரத்துக்களை நிறைவேற்றுவது அவசியமானால், அதனை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மை வாக்குகளாலும், வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலமாகவும் நிறைவேற்ற வேண்டும் என உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்திடம் மனுக்கள் மேலும் கோரியுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "'வினிவிந்த பெரமுன'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவன் பலந்துடாவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ பண்டார ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்.டி.ஜே. குலதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பி. தஹநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரைவு மசோதா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}