{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Nimal-Siripala-takes-up-delay-in-Japan-funded-BIA-expansion/34-736669",
  "time_ut": 1656097436,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Nimal Siripala takes up delay  in Japan-funded BIA expansion",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Nimal Siripala takes up delay  in Japan-funded BIA expansion",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Recalls Japan has always come forward to help SL in “hour of need”",
        "Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva yesterday reiterated that Japan has always come forward to help Sri Lanka in the hour of need.",
        "“Japan has always assisted in the development of Sri Lanka for the closer political and socio-economic ties between the two countries and we are grateful of the people of Japan who always came forward to help Sri Lankans at their hour of need,” the Minister said during a meeting with Japanese Ambassador MIZUKOSHI Hideaki.",
        "Recalling of the immense assistance extended by the Japanese Government for the Peradeniya Children’s Hospital, Polonnaruwa General Hospital and many other health sector development projects during his tenure as the Minister of Health, the Minister also regretted the cancellation of important development projects signed between Japan and Sri Lanka due to several political decisions taken in the past.",
        "He said that on the invitation of the World Health Organisation (WHO), he also served a Consultant to the WHO Centre for Health Development in Kobe also known as the WHO Kobe Centre.",
        "The Minister emphasised the Ambassador, on the delay of construction of the Phase II of the Bandaranaike International Airport, commenced with a loan facility from the Government of Japan. A special report on the matter was also handed over by the Minister to the Japanese Ambassador. In particular, the Minister said that the Sri Lankan media has repeatedly raised the issue accusing him, as the Subject Minister and the Government, of delays in the said constructions at the airport.",
        "The Japanese Ambassador said that he had been informed that the construction works were delayed due to the COVID-19 Pandemic and the current fuel crisis in Sri Lanka and pointed out that several other foreign companies engaged in the construction industry in Sri Lanka have also faced the situation.",
        "The Ambassador expressed his confidence to resolve the matter soon and urged the Minister to sustain the strong ties and credibility secured and continued between Japan and the Government of Sri Lanka.",
        "Since, 65% of the payments for the constructions of the Phase II of the Bandaranaike International Airport is made via Japanese Yen, and if such foreign exchange could be utilised to purchase quantities of fuel required for the construction work from foreign exporters, the Minister said that the Government could facilitate unloading them in discussion with the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC).",
        "The Minister also requested a meeting with the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JAICA), Taisai Corporation Japan that has undertaken the constructions of the project and the Airport and Aviation Services Sri Lanka Ltd. with the presence of Japanese Ambassador, the Secretary to the Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Aviation and staff to discuss the issues on the Phase II constructions of the Bandaranaike International Airport. He also requested the Ambassador to encourage Japanese investors for the proposed new industrial Zone related to the Port of Trincomalee.",
        "First Secretary of the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI, Japan Deputy Head of Mission KATSUKI Kotaro, Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Aviation Secretary K.D.S. Ruwanchandra and Additional Secretary Sunil Gunarathna also attended the meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Siripala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "their hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIZUKOSHI Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Government for the Peradeniya Children’s Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the WHO Centre for Health Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the WHO Kobe Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Phase II",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Phase II",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Japan International Cooperation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisai Corporation Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Airport and Aviation Services Sri Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Phase II",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Trincomalee",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mission KATSUKI Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.D.S. Ruwanchandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Gunarathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ජපානයේ අරමුදල් සහිත BIA ව්‍යාප්තිය ප්‍රමාද කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"අවශ්‍ය පැයකදී\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීමට ජපානය සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වූ බව සිහිපත් කරයි",
        "ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය මොහොතේදී ආධාර කිරීමට ජපානය සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වන බව වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ඊයේ යළි අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දෙරට අතර සමීප දේශපාලන හා සමාජ-ආර්ථික සබඳතා සඳහා ජපානය සෑම විටම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධනයට සහාය වී ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතාවලදී උපකාර කිරීමට සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වූ ජපානයේ ජනතාවට අපි ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමු,\" අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. ජපාන තානාපති MIZUKOSHI Hideaki සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "තමා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටියදී පේරාදෙණිය ළමා රෝහල, පොළොන්නරුව මහ රෝහල ඇතුළු සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති රැසකට ජපන් රජය ලබාදුන් අතිමහත් ආධාර පිළිබඳව සිහිපත් කළ අමාත්‍යවරයා ජපානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර අත්සන් කළ වැදගත් සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති අවලංගු කිරීම පිළිබඳව ද කනගාටුව පළ කළේය. පසුගිය කාලයේ ගත් දේශපාලන තීන්දු කිහිපයක් නිසා ලංකාව.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ (WHO) ආරාධනය මත ඔහු WHO කෝබේ මධ්‍යස්ථානය ලෙසද හැඳින්වෙන කෝබේ හි WHO සෞඛ්‍ය සංවර්ධන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ උපදේශකයෙකු ලෙසද සේවය කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ දෙවන අදියරේ ඉදිකිරීම් ප්‍රමාදය පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරයා තානාපතිවරයාට අවධාරණය කළේ ජපාන රජයේ ණය පහසුකම් යටතේය. ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශේෂ වාර්තාවක් ද අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා වෙත භාර දෙනු ලැබුවා. විශේෂයෙන්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ විෂය භාර අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙසත් රජය ලෙසත් ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ඉහත කී ඉදිකිරීම් ප්‍රමාද වන බවට චෝදනා කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මාධ්‍ය විසින් දිගින් දිගටම ප්‍රශ්නය මතු කළ බවයි.",
        "කොවිඩ්-19 වසංගතය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ඉදිකිරීම් ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති බව තමාට දන්වා ඇති බව පැවසූ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉදිකිරීම් ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ නියැලී සිටින තවත් විදේශීය සමාගම් කිහිපයක් ද මෙම තත්ත්වයට මුහුණ දී ඇති බව පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. තත්ත්වය.",
        "මෙම ගැටළුව කඩිනමින් විසඳා ගැනීමට තම විශ්වාසය පළ කළ තානාපතිවරයා ජපානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අතර සුරක්ෂිතව සහ අඛණ්ඩව පවතින ශක්තිමත් බැඳීම් සහ විශ්වසනීයත්වය පවත්වාගෙන යන ලෙස අමාත්‍යවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ II අදියරේ ඉදිකිරීම් සඳහා ගෙවීම්වලින් 65% ක් ජපන් යෙන් හරහා සිදුවන බැවින් එවැනි විදේශ විනිමය යොදාගෙන ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන ප්‍රමාණය විදේශ අපනයනකරුවන්ගෙන් මිලදී ගත හැකි බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඒවා ගොඩබෑමට රජයට පහසුකම් සැලසිය හැකි බව.",
        "ජපාන තානාපති, අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්, ව්‍යාපෘතියේ ඉදිකිරීම් භාරගෙන ඇති ජපානයේ ජපන් ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය (JAICA), ව්‍යාපෘතියේ ඉදිකිරීම් භාරගෙන ඇති ජපානයේ Taisai Corporation සහ සීමාසහිත ගුවන්තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාගම සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක් පවත්වන ලෙස ද ඇමැතිවරයා ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ දෙවන අදියරේ ඉදිකිරීම් පිළිබඳ ගැටළු සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට වරාය, නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා සහ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය. ත්‍රිකුණාමල වරාය ආශ්‍රිතව යෝජිත නව කර්මාන්ත කලාපය සඳහා ජපාන ආයෝජකයින් දිරිමත් කරන ලෙස ද ඔහු තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ පළමු ලේකම් Chiharu HOSHIAI, ජපානයේ නියෝජ්‍ය දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී KATSUKI Kotaro, වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් K.D.S. රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර, අතිරේක ලේකම් සුනිල් ගුණරත්න යන මහත්වරු ද මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිරිපාල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔවුන්ගේ පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIZUKOSHI Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය ළමා රෝහල සඳහා ජපන් රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය සංවර්ධනය සඳහා WHO මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝබේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO කෝබේ මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "II අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "II අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානයේ ටයිසායි සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "II අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමල වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mission KATSUKI Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.ඩී.එස්. රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமல் சிறிபால ஜப்பானின் நிதியுதவியுடன் கூடிய BIA விரிவாக்கத்தில் தாமதத்தை மேற்கொள்கிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"தேவையான நேரத்தில்\" இலங்கைக்கு உதவ ஜப்பான் எப்போதும் முன்வந்துள்ளது என்பதை நினைவு கூர்ந்தார்.",
        "தேவைப்படும் நேரத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ ஜப்பான் எப்போதும் முன்வருவதாக துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா நேற்று மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்குமிடையிலான நெருக்கமான அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக பொருளாதார உறவுகளுக்காக இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்திக்கு ஜப்பான் எப்போதும் உதவி வருகின்றது மேலும் இலங்கையர்களின் தேவையின் போது அவர்களுக்கு உதவ முன்வந்த ஜப்பானிய மக்களுக்கு நாம் நன்றி கூறுகின்றோம் என அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார். ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர் MIZUKOSI Hideaki உடனான சந்திப்பின் போது கூறினார்.",
        "தாம் சுகாதார அமைச்சராக இருந்த காலத்தில் பேராதனை சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலை, பொலன்னறுவை பொது வைத்தியசாலை மற்றும் பல சுகாதாரத் துறை அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டங்களுக்கு ஜப்பானிய அரசாங்கம் வழங்கிய மகத்தான உதவிகளை நினைவுகூர்ந்த அமைச்சர், ஜப்பானுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்ட முக்கியமான அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டங்கள் இரத்துச் செய்யப்பட்டமைக்கு வருத்தம் தெரிவித்தார். கடந்த காலங்களில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட பல அரசியல் தீர்மானங்களின் காரணமாக இலங்கை.",
        "உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் (WHO) அழைப்பின் பேரில், WHO கோப் மையம் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படும் கோபியில் உள்ள WHO சுகாதார மேம்பாட்டு மையத்தின் ஆலோசகராகவும் பணியாற்றினார் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் இரண்டாம் கட்ட நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கத்தின் கடனுதவியுடன் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட தாமதம் குறித்து அமைச்சர் தூதுவரிடம் வலியுறுத்தினார். இது தொடர்பான விசேட அறிக்கையும் அமைச்சரினால் ஜப்பானிய தூதுவரிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது. குறிப்பாக, இலங்கை ஊடகங்கள் இந்த விடயத்தை மீண்டும் மீண்டும் எழுப்பியதாகவும், அமைச்சர் என்ற ரீதியிலும் அரசாங்கம் என்ற ரீதியிலும் விமான நிலையத்தில் மேற்படி நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் தாமதப்படுத்தப்படுவதாக குற்றம் சுமத்துவதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொவிட்-19 தொற்று மற்றும் இலங்கையில் தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் தாமதமாகியுள்ளதாகத் தமக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகத் தெரிவித்த ஜப்பானியத் தூதுவர், இலங்கையில் நிர்மாணத் தொழிலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள மேலும் பல வெளிநாட்டு நிறுவனங்களும் இந்தச் சிக்கலை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். நிலைமை.",
        "இப்பிரச்சினைக்கு விரைவில் தீர்வு காண்பதற்குத் தனது நம்பிக்கையை வெளிப்படுத்திய தூதுவர், ஜப்பானுக்கும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்துக்கும் இடையில் பாதுகாக்கப்பட்ட மற்றும் தொடரும் வலுவான உறவுகளையும் நம்பகத்தன்மையையும் நிலைநிறுத்துமாறு அமைச்சரிடம் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் இரண்டாம் கட்ட நிர்மாணப் பணிகளுக்கான கொடுப்பனவுகளில் 65% ஜப்பானிய யென் மூலம் செலுத்தப்படுவதால், அத்தகைய அந்நியச் செலாவணியை வெளிநாட்டு ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களிடமிருந்து கட்டுமானப் பணிகளுக்குத் தேவையான அளவு எரிபொருளைக் கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார். இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்துடன் (CPC) கலந்துரையாடி அவற்றை இறக்குவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் உதவ முடியும்.",
        "இத்திட்டத்தின் நிர்மாணப் பணிகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ள ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம் (JAICA), ஜப்பானிய தைசாய் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் மற்றும் விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் ஸ்ரீலங்கா லிமிடெட் ஆகியவற்றுடன் ஜப்பானிய தூதுவர், அமைச்சின் செயலாளரின் முன்னிலையில் ஒரு சந்திப்பையும் அமைச்சர் கோரினார். பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் இரண்டாம் கட்ட நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கு துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் ஊழியர்கள். திருகோணமலை துறைமுகத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய உத்தேச புதிய கைத்தொழில் வலயத்திற்காக ஜப்பானிய முதலீட்டாளர்களை ஊக்குவிக்குமாறும் அவர் தூதுவரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "ஜப்பானிய தூதரகத்தின் முதல் செயலாளர் சிஹாரு ஹோஷியா, ஜப்பான் துணைத் தூதுவர் கட்சுகி கோட்டாரோ, துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகத்தின் செயலாளர் கே.டி.எஸ். ருவன்சந்திர மற்றும் மேலதிக செயலாளர் சுனில் குணரத்ன ஆகியோரும் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிறிபால",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவர்களின் நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIZUKOSHI Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலைக்கு ஜப்பானிய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO சுகாதார மேம்பாட்டு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO கோபி மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் கட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் கட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைசாய் கார்ப்பரேஷன் ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் ஸ்ரீலங்கா லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் கட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mission KATSUKI Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.டி.எஸ். ருவன்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் குணரத்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Nimal Siripala takes up delay  in Japan-funded BIA expansion",
  "body_lines": [
    "Recalls Japan has always come forward to help SL in “hour of need”",
    "Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva yesterday reiterated that Japan has always come forward to help Sri Lanka in the hour of need.",
    "“Japan has always assisted in the development of Sri Lanka for the closer political and socio-economic ties between the two countries and we are grateful of the people of Japan who always came forward to help Sri Lankans at their hour of need,” the Minister said during a meeting with Japanese Ambassador MIZUKOSHI Hideaki.",
    "Recalling of the immense assistance extended by the Japanese Government for the Peradeniya Children’s Hospital, Polonnaruwa General Hospital and many other health sector development projects during his tenure as the Minister of Health, the Minister also regretted the cancellation of important development projects signed between Japan and Sri Lanka due to several political decisions taken in the past.",
    "He said that on the invitation of the World Health Organisation (WHO), he also served a Consultant to the WHO Centre for Health Development in Kobe also known as the WHO Kobe Centre.",
    "The Minister emphasised the Ambassador, on the delay of construction of the Phase II of the Bandaranaike International Airport, commenced with a loan facility from the Government of Japan. A special report on the matter was also handed over by the Minister to the Japanese Ambassador. In particular, the Minister said that the Sri Lankan media has repeatedly raised the issue accusing him, as the Subject Minister and the Government, of delays in the said constructions at the airport.",
    "The Japanese Ambassador said that he had been informed that the construction works were delayed due to the COVID-19 Pandemic and the current fuel crisis in Sri Lanka and pointed out that several other foreign companies engaged in the construction industry in Sri Lanka have also faced the situation.",
    "The Ambassador expressed his confidence to resolve the matter soon and urged the Minister to sustain the strong ties and credibility secured and continued between Japan and the Government of Sri Lanka.",
    "Since, 65% of the payments for the constructions of the Phase II of the Bandaranaike International Airport is made via Japanese Yen, and if such foreign exchange could be utilised to purchase quantities of fuel required for the construction work from foreign exporters, the Minister said that the Government could facilitate unloading them in discussion with the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC).",
    "The Minister also requested a meeting with the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JAICA), Taisai Corporation Japan that has undertaken the constructions of the project and the Airport and Aviation Services Sri Lanka Ltd. with the presence of Japanese Ambassador, the Secretary to the Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Aviation and staff to discuss the issues on the Phase II constructions of the Bandaranaike International Airport. He also requested the Ambassador to encourage Japanese investors for the proposed new industrial Zone related to the Port of Trincomalee.",
    "First Secretary of the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI, Japan Deputy Head of Mission KATSUKI Kotaro, Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Aviation Secretary K.D.S. Ruwanchandra and Additional Secretary Sunil Gunarathna also attended the meeting."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Nimal Siripala takes up delay  in Japan-funded BIA expansion",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Recalls Japan has always come forward to help SL in “hour of need”",
        "Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva yesterday reiterated that Japan has always come forward to help Sri Lanka in the hour of need.",
        "“Japan has always assisted in the development of Sri Lanka for the closer political and socio-economic ties between the two countries and we are grateful of the people of Japan who always came forward to help Sri Lankans at their hour of need,” the Minister said during a meeting with Japanese Ambassador MIZUKOSHI Hideaki.",
        "Recalling of the immense assistance extended by the Japanese Government for the Peradeniya Children’s Hospital, Polonnaruwa General Hospital and many other health sector development projects during his tenure as the Minister of Health, the Minister also regretted the cancellation of important development projects signed between Japan and Sri Lanka due to several political decisions taken in the past.",
        "He said that on the invitation of the World Health Organisation (WHO), he also served a Consultant to the WHO Centre for Health Development in Kobe also known as the WHO Kobe Centre.",
        "The Minister emphasised the Ambassador, on the delay of construction of the Phase II of the Bandaranaike International Airport, commenced with a loan facility from the Government of Japan. A special report on the matter was also handed over by the Minister to the Japanese Ambassador. In particular, the Minister said that the Sri Lankan media has repeatedly raised the issue accusing him, as the Subject Minister and the Government, of delays in the said constructions at the airport.",
        "The Japanese Ambassador said that he had been informed that the construction works were delayed due to the COVID-19 Pandemic and the current fuel crisis in Sri Lanka and pointed out that several other foreign companies engaged in the construction industry in Sri Lanka have also faced the situation.",
        "The Ambassador expressed his confidence to resolve the matter soon and urged the Minister to sustain the strong ties and credibility secured and continued between Japan and the Government of Sri Lanka.",
        "Since, 65% of the payments for the constructions of the Phase II of the Bandaranaike International Airport is made via Japanese Yen, and if such foreign exchange could be utilised to purchase quantities of fuel required for the construction work from foreign exporters, the Minister said that the Government could facilitate unloading them in discussion with the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC).",
        "The Minister also requested a meeting with the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JAICA), Taisai Corporation Japan that has undertaken the constructions of the project and the Airport and Aviation Services Sri Lanka Ltd. with the presence of Japanese Ambassador, the Secretary to the Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Aviation and staff to discuss the issues on the Phase II constructions of the Bandaranaike International Airport. He also requested the Ambassador to encourage Japanese investors for the proposed new industrial Zone related to the Port of Trincomalee.",
        "First Secretary of the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI, Japan Deputy Head of Mission KATSUKI Kotaro, Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Aviation Secretary K.D.S. Ruwanchandra and Additional Secretary Sunil Gunarathna also attended the meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Siripala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "their hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIZUKOSHI Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Government for the Peradeniya Children’s Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the WHO Centre for Health Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the WHO Kobe Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Phase II",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Phase II",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Japan International Cooperation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisai Corporation Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Airport and Aviation Services Sri Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Phase II",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Trincomalee",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mission KATSUKI Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.D.S. Ruwanchandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Gunarathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ජපානයේ අරමුදල් සහිත BIA ව්‍යාප්තිය ප්‍රමාද කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"අවශ්‍ය පැයකදී\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීමට ජපානය සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වූ බව සිහිපත් කරයි",
        "ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය මොහොතේදී ආධාර කිරීමට ජපානය සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වන බව වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ඊයේ යළි අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දෙරට අතර සමීප දේශපාලන හා සමාජ-ආර්ථික සබඳතා සඳහා ජපානය සෑම විටම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධනයට සහාය වී ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතාවලදී උපකාර කිරීමට සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වූ ජපානයේ ජනතාවට අපි ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමු,\" අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. ජපාන තානාපති MIZUKOSHI Hideaki සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "තමා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයාව සිටියදී පේරාදෙණිය ළමා රෝහල, පොළොන්නරුව මහ රෝහල ඇතුළු සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති රැසකට ජපන් රජය ලබාදුන් අතිමහත් ආධාර පිළිබඳව සිහිපත් කළ අමාත්‍යවරයා ජපානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර අත්සන් කළ වැදගත් සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති අවලංගු කිරීම පිළිබඳව ද කනගාටුව පළ කළේය. පසුගිය කාලයේ ගත් දේශපාලන තීන්දු කිහිපයක් නිසා ලංකාව.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ (WHO) ආරාධනය මත ඔහු WHO කෝබේ මධ්‍යස්ථානය ලෙසද හැඳින්වෙන කෝබේ හි WHO සෞඛ්‍ය සංවර්ධන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ උපදේශකයෙකු ලෙසද සේවය කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ දෙවන අදියරේ ඉදිකිරීම් ප්‍රමාදය පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරයා තානාපතිවරයාට අවධාරණය කළේ ජපාන රජයේ ණය පහසුකම් යටතේය. ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශේෂ වාර්තාවක් ද අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා වෙත භාර දෙනු ලැබුවා. විශේෂයෙන්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ විෂය භාර අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙසත් රජය ලෙසත් ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ඉහත කී ඉදිකිරීම් ප්‍රමාද වන බවට චෝදනා කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මාධ්‍ය විසින් දිගින් දිගටම ප්‍රශ්නය මතු කළ බවයි.",
        "කොවිඩ්-19 වසංගතය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ඉදිකිරීම් ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති බව තමාට දන්වා ඇති බව පැවසූ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉදිකිරීම් ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ නියැලී සිටින තවත් විදේශීය සමාගම් කිහිපයක් ද මෙම තත්ත්වයට මුහුණ දී ඇති බව පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. තත්ත්වය.",
        "මෙම ගැටළුව කඩිනමින් විසඳා ගැනීමට තම විශ්වාසය පළ කළ තානාපතිවරයා ජපානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අතර සුරක්ෂිතව සහ අඛණ්ඩව පවතින ශක්තිමත් බැඳීම් සහ විශ්වසනීයත්වය පවත්වාගෙන යන ලෙස අමාත්‍යවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ II අදියරේ ඉදිකිරීම් සඳහා ගෙවීම්වලින් 65% ක් ජපන් යෙන් හරහා සිදුවන බැවින් එවැනි විදේශ විනිමය යොදාගෙන ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන ප්‍රමාණය විදේශ අපනයනකරුවන්ගෙන් මිලදී ගත හැකි බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඒවා ගොඩබෑමට රජයට පහසුකම් සැලසිය හැකි බව.",
        "ජපාන තානාපති, අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්, ව්‍යාපෘතියේ ඉදිකිරීම් භාරගෙන ඇති ජපානයේ ජපන් ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය (JAICA), ව්‍යාපෘතියේ ඉදිකිරීම් භාරගෙන ඇති ජපානයේ Taisai Corporation සහ සීමාසහිත ගුවන්තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාගම සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක් පවත්වන ලෙස ද ඇමැතිවරයා ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළේ දෙවන අදියරේ ඉදිකිරීම් පිළිබඳ ගැටළු සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට වරාය, නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා සහ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය. ත්‍රිකුණාමල වරාය ආශ්‍රිතව යෝජිත නව කර්මාන්ත කලාපය සඳහා ජපාන ආයෝජකයින් දිරිමත් කරන ලෙස ද ඔහු තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ජපාන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ පළමු ලේකම් Chiharu HOSHIAI, ජපානයේ නියෝජ්‍ය දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී KATSUKI Kotaro, වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් K.D.S. රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර, අතිරේක ලේකම් සුනිල් ගුණරත්න යන මහත්වරු ද මෙම රැස්වීමට සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිරිපාල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔවුන්ගේ පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "MIZUKOSHI Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය ළමා රෝහල සඳහා ජපන් රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය සංවර්ධනය සඳහා WHO මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝබේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO කෝබේ මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "II අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "II අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානයේ ටයිසායි සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "II අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමල වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Embassy Chiharu HOSHIAI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mission KATSUKI Kotaro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.ඩී.එස්. රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமல் சிறிபால ஜப்பானின் நிதியுதவியுடன் கூடிய BIA விரிவாக்கத்தில் தாமதத்தை மேற்கொள்கிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"தேவையான நேரத்தில்\" இலங்கைக்கு உதவ ஜப்பான் எப்போதும் முன்வந்துள்ளது என்பதை நினைவு கூர்ந்தார்.",
        "தேவைப்படும் நேரத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ ஜப்பான் எப்போதும் முன்வருவதாக துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா நேற்று மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
