{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SLAF-denies-reports-that-President-staying-at-Air-Chiefs-private-residence/108-240917",
  "time_ut": 1657617525,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLAF denies reports that President staying at Air Chief’s private residence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLAF denies reports that President staying at Air Chief’s private residence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Air Force (SLAF) today denied social media reports that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is currently staying in a private house belonging to Air Force Chief Air Marshal Sudarshana Pathirana.",
        "The SLAF said a video released by Ajith Dharmapala, a former police officer who claims to be the president of the International Organization to Devoid Sri Lankan Police from Politics, claimed that the President is staying in a private house belonging to the Air Force Commander.",
        "The SLAF Spokesman Dushan Wijesinghe said that there is no truth behind the reports and it was a propaganda to tarnish the image of the SLAF and its chief.(Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Air Chief’s",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Dharmapala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Organization to Devoid Sri Lankan Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Politics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force Commander",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ගුවන් හමුදාපතිවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසේ රැඳී සිටින බවට පළවන වාර්තා ගුවන් හමුදාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ වන විට ගුවන් හමුදා ප්‍රධානී එයාර් මාර්ෂල් සුදර්ශන පතිරණ මහතාට අයත් පෞද්ගලික නිවසක නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටින බවට සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ පළවන වාර්තා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය දේශපාලනයෙන් ඈත් කිරීමේ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානයේ සභාපති යැයි කියන හිටපු පොලිස් නිලධාරියකු වන අජිත් ධර්මපාල මහතා විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද වීඩියෝ පටයක ජනාධිපතිවරයා රැඳී සිටින්නේ ගුවන් හමුදාපතිවරයාට අයත් පෞද්ගලික නිවසක බව ගුවන් හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "ගුවන් හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක දුෂාන් විජේසිංහ මහතා පැවසුවේ එම වාර්තා පිටුපස කිසිදු සත්‍යතාවක් නොමැති බවත් එය ගුවන් හමුදාවේ සහ එහි ප්‍රධානියාගේ ප්‍රතිරූපයට හානි කිරීමේ ප්‍රචාරයක් බවත්ය.(දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාපති",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් ධර්මපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසියෙන් තොර ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விமானப்படை தளபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி தங்கியிருப்பதாக வெளியான செய்திகளை விமானப்படை மறுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தற்போது விமானப்படைத் தளபதி எயார் மார்ஷல் சுதர்சன பத்திரனவுக்கு சொந்தமான வீட்டில் தங்கியிருப்பதாக சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான செய்திகளை இலங்கை விமானப்படை (SLAF) இன்று மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கைப் பொலிஸாரை அரசியலில் இருந்து விலக்குவதற்கான சர்வதேச அமைப்பின் தலைவர் எனக் கூறிக்கொள்ளும் முன்னாள் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி அஜித் தர்மபால வெளியிட்ட காணொளியில் ஜனாதிபதி விமானப்படைத் தளபதிக்கு சொந்தமான வீட்டில் தங்கியிருப்பதாக விமானப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த செய்திகளில் உண்மையில்லை என விமானப்படையின் பேச்சாளர் துஷான் விஜேசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விமானப்படை தளபதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் தர்மபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொலிஸை இல்லாத சர்வதேச அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை தளபதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}