{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SJB-disassociates-itself-from-SFs-call-for-August-9-final-battle/342-242034",
  "time_ut": 1659089191,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB disassociates itself from SF’s call for August 9 final battle",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB disassociates itself from SF’s call for August 9 final battle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) has not made any decision to participate in a protest which is claimed to be the final battle against the corrupt politicians on August 9 although party Chairman Sarath Fonseka had claimed he and others will participate in it, an SJB MP said today.",
        "SJB MP Mujibur Rahman told a press conference that the party had not made any official decision to participate in any decision to participate in any protest on August 9th. “One has to ask Field Marshal Fonseka as to what made him come out with such a remark,” the MP said.",
        "Field Marshal said in Parliament on July 27 that he and his party will participate in a mass protest together with Aragalaya youth on August 9 which he called a final battle to remove corrupt politicians from power and set up a new administration comprising non corrupt MPs from all political parties representing the House.",
        "At the same time Mr. Rahman said his party is fully opposed to arrests of Aragalaya members and raids carried out by the police. “Sri Lanka is going to suffer with this type of suppression as international organizations including Fitch Ratings have warned further disruption if suppression continues.",
        "Also he questioned why the police had not produced cash which was found at the President's House to Courts. “One wonders as to why the police failed in this regard and what had become of this cash,” he said.(Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SF",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujibur Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Field Marshal Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Field Marshal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House to Courts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB අගෝස්තු 9 අවසන් සටන සඳහා SF ගේ කැඳවීමෙන් ඉවත් වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දූෂිත දේශපාලකයන්ට එරෙහි අවසන් සටන ලෙස සැලකෙන අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා පැවැත්වෙන විරෝධතාවයකට තමන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් සහභාගි වන බව පක්‍ෂයේ සභාපති සරත් ෆොන්සේකා ප්‍රකාශ කළද ඊට සහභාගි වීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගය කිසිදු තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැති බව SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් පැවසීය. අද.",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මුජිබර් රහුමාන් මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී කියා සිටියේ අගෝස්තු 9 වනදා කිසිදු විරෝධතාවයකට සහභාගී වීමේ කිසිදු තීරණයකට සහභාගී වීමට පක්ෂය නිල තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැති බවයි. ෆීල්ඩ් මාර්ෂල් ෆොන්සේකා මහතාගෙන්ම අහන්න වෙනවා ඔහු මේ වගේ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරන්න හේතුව මොකක්ද කියලා,” මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "දූෂිත දේශපාලනඥයන් බලයෙන් පහකර සියලු දෙනාගෙන්ම දූෂිත නොවන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් නව පාලනයක් පිහිටුවීමේ අවසන් සටනට තමන් ඇතුළු පිරිස අරගලය තරුණයන් සමඟ එක්ව අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා ජනතා විරෝධතාවයකට සහභාගි වන බව ෆීල්ඩ් මාෂල් මහතා ජූලි 27 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. සභාව නියෝජනය කරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ.",
        "ඒ අතරම අරගලය සාමාජිකයන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම්වලට සහ පොලිසිය සිදුකරන වැටලීම්වලට තම පක්ෂය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම විරුද්ධ බව රහ්මාන් මහතා පැවසීය. “මර්දනය දිගටම පැවතුනහොත් ෆිච් රේටින්ග්ස් ඇතුළු ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධාන තවදුරටත් කඩාකප්පල් වනු ඇතැයි අනතුරු අඟවා ඇති බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙවැනි මර්දනයකින් පීඩා විඳීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ තිබී සොයාගත් මුදල් පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකළේ මන්දැයි ඔහු ප්‍රශ්න කළේය. “මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිසිය අසමත් වූයේ ඇයිද යන්න සහ මෙම මුදල්වලට සිදුවූයේ කුමක්දැයි කෙනෙකුට පුදුමයි.” (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SF",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජිබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆීල්ඩ් මාර්ෂල් ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆීල්ඩ් මාර්ෂල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෙයින් ගෙට උසාවිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9 இறுதிப் போருக்கான SF இன் அழைப்பிலிருந்து SJB தன்னைத் துண்டித்துக் கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஊழல் அரசியல்வாதிகளுக்கு எதிரான இறுதிப் போராகக் கூறப்படும் ஆகஸ்ட் 9ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறும் போராட்டத்தில் தானும் ஏனையோரும் பங்கேற்பதாக கட்சியின் தலைவர் சரத் பொன்சேகா கூறியிருந்த போதிலும், அதில் பங்கேற்பது தொடர்பில் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) எந்த தீர்மானமும் எடுக்கவில்லை என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இன்று.",
        "எஸ்ஜேபி எம்பி முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் கூறுகையில், ஆகஸ்ட் 9ம் தேதி நடைபெறும் எந்த ஒரு போராட்டத்திலும் பங்கேற்பது குறித்து கட்சி அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக எந்த முடிவும் எடுக்கவில்லை. பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் பொன்சேகாவை எதனால் இவ்வாறானதொரு கருத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தினார் என்று கேட்க வேண்டும் என எம்.பி.",
        "ஊழல் அரசியல்வாதிகளை ஆட்சியில் இருந்து அகற்றி, ஊழல் அற்ற எம்.பி.க்கள் அனைவரையும் உள்ளடக்கிய புதிய நிர்வாகத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான இறுதிப் போருக்கு ஆகஸ்ட் 9-ம் தேதி அரகலய இளைஞர்களுடன் இணைந்து மாபெரும் போராட்டத்தில் தானும் தனது கட்சியும் பங்கேற்போம் என்று ஜூலை 27 அன்று நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் கூறினார். சபையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அரசியல் கட்சிகள்.",
        "அதே நேரத்தில் திரு. ரஹ்மான், அரகலயா உறுப்பினர்களைக் கைது செய்வதையும், காவல்துறையினரால் நடத்தப்படும் சோதனைகளையும் தனது கட்சி முழுமையாக எதிர்க்கிறது என்றார். “அடக்குமுறை தொடர்ந்தால் மேலும் சீர்குலைவு ஏற்படும் என ஃபிட்ச் ரேட்டிங்ஸ் உள்ளிட்ட சர்வதேச நிறுவனங்கள் எச்சரித்துள்ளதால், இந்த வகையான அடக்குமுறையால் இலங்கை பாதிக்கப்படப் போகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் காணப்பட்ட பணத்தை ஏன் பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் சமர்ப்பிக்கவில்லை எனவும் அவர் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார். “இந்த விடயத்தில் காவல்துறை ஏன் தோல்வியடைந்தது மற்றும் இந்த பணத்திற்கு என்ன ஆனது என்று ஒருவர் ஆச்சரியப்படுகிறார்,” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.(யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ் எப்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜிபுர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீல்ட் மார்ஷல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றங்களுக்கு வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}