{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131891",
  "time_ut": 1658320339,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவில் ரணிலுக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சியினர் பலர் ஆதரவு வழங்கியதை மறைக்க இயலாது -  தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It is impossible to hide the fact that many opposition parties supported Ranil in the presidential election - Dinesh Gunawardena",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chief Minister Dinesh Gunawardena told the House that it cannot be hidden that most members of the opposition have voted in support of Ranil Wickremesinghe who contested as a candidate during the secret ballot for the presidential election.",
        "He mentioned the above in his address following the announcement of the results of the presidential poll held today (20) Wednesday in Parliament.",
        "It is the second time in Sri Lankan political history that the President has been elected through Parliament.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who has won with majority support, can fulfill his responsibilities as he is the longest serving member of Parliament and has served as Prime Minister and Minister.",
        "The country is facing an unprecedented challenge due to the corona virus. After several months, the challenge was overcome.",
        "However, like other countries in the world, Sri Lanka faced an economic crisis due to the protests, which forced former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to resign from the presidency.",
        "It is true that many members of the opposition voted for us in the secret ballot to elect the President.",
        "There is nothing to hide in that. I also thank the presidential candidates Anurakumara Dissanayake and Dalus Alagapperuma.",
        "Political position may change. But man is one for all. The world has proven that things don't always happen the same way. He said that we can overcome the challenge that the country is facing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalus Alagapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ රැසක් රනිල්ට සහය දුන් බව වසන් කරන්න බැහැ - දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණයේ රහස් ඡන්දයේදී අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පක්ෂ විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වැඩි පිරිසක් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බව සැඟවිය නොහැකි බව ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා සභාවට පැවසීය.",
        "අද (20) බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණ ප්‍රතිඵල ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඔහු කළ කතාවේදී ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත් වූ දෙවන අවස්ථාව මෙයයි.",
        "බහුතර සහයෝගයෙන් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වැඩිම කාලයක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සිටි මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මෙන්ම අගමැති හා ඇමැති ධුර ද දරා ඇති බැවින් ඔහුට වගකීම් ඉටු කළ හැකිය.",
        "කොරෝනා වෛරසය හේතුවෙන් රට පෙර නොවූ විරූ අභියෝගයකට මුහුණ දී සිටී. මාස කිහිපයකට පසු අභියෝගය ජය ගැනීමට හැකි විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ලෝකයේ අනෙකුත් රටවල් මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දුන් අතර, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සිදු විය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේ රහස් ඡන්දයේදී විපක්ෂයේ බොහෝ දෙනෙක් අපට ඡන්දය දුන් බව ඇත්ත.",
        "ඒකේ හංගන්න දෙයක් නැහැ.ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක අනුරකුමාර දිසානායකට සහ ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුමටත් මම ස්තුතිවන්ත වෙනවා.",
        "දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරය වෙනස් විය හැක. නමුත් මිනිසා සැමට එකයි. සෑම විටම දේවල් එකම ආකාරයෙන් සිදු නොවන බව ලෝකය ඔප්පු කර ඇත. රට මුහුණ දී සිටින අභියෝගය ජයගත හැකි බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දලස් අලගප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவில் ரணிலுக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சியினர் பலர் ஆதரவு வழங்கியதை மறைக்க இயலாது -  தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவுக்கான இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பின்போது வேட்பாளராக போட்டியிட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பெரும்பாலான உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆதரவாக வாக்களித்துள்ளார்கள் என்பதை மறைக்க முடியாது என சபை முதல்வர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன சபையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றில் இன்று புதன்கிழமை (20) ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு இடம் பெற்று பெறுபேறு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து உரையாற்றுகையில் மேற்கண்டவாறு குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக இரண்டாவது முறையாக ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "பெரும்பான்மை ஆதரவுடன்  வெற்றிப்பெற்றுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நீண்டக்காலமாக இருந்த சிரேஷ்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் என்பதாலும் பிரதமராகவும்,அமைச்சராகவும் செயற்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவால் தனது பொறுப்புக்களை நிறைவேற்ற முடியும்.",
        "கொரோனா வைரஸ் காரணமாக முன்னொருபோதும் இல்லாத சவாலுக்கு நாடு முகங்கொடுத்ததுள்ளது. பல மாதங்களுக்குப் பின்னர் அந்த சவாலை வெற்றிக்கொள்ள முடிந்தது.",
        "ஆனாலும் உலகில் உள்ள ஏனைய நாடுகளைபோல இலங்கையும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்தால் ஏற்பட்ட எதிர்ப்புக்களால் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து இராஜிநாமா செய்ய வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் எதிர்க்கட்சியைச் சேர்ந்த பலர் எங்களுக்கு ஆதரவாக வாக்களித்தார் என்பது உண்மை.",
        "அதில் மறைப்பதற்கு ஒன்றுமில்லை.ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர்களான அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோருக்கும் நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "அரசியல் நிலைப்பாடு மாறலாம். ஆனால் மனிதம் அனைவருக்கும் ஒன்று. எப்போதும் ஒரேமாதிரியான விடயங்கள் நடக்காது என்பது உலகில்  நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. நாடு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் சவாலை எம்மால் வெற்றிக்கொள்ள முடியும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}