{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/18/pohottuwa-wants-gotabaya-back-in-sri-lanka-with-security-and-facilities/",
  "time_ut": 1660839000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pohottuwa wants Gotabaya back in Sri Lanka with security, and facilities",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pohottuwa wants Gotabaya back in Sri Lanka with security, and facilities",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has made a request from President Ranil Wickremesinghe to take necessary measures to bring back Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to Sri Lanka.",
        "The SLPP also requests that Rajapaksa be awarded propoer security following his arrival and that the necessary facilities be made available.",
        "SLPP General Secretary Attorney-at-Law Sagara Kariyawasam said that the request was made during talks between the SLPP and the President today.",
        "Pohottuwa wants Gotabaya back in Sri Lanka with security, and facilities"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොට්ටුවට අවශ්‍ය ගෝඨාභය ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ පහසුකම් සහිතව නැවත ලංකාවට පැමිණීමයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඔහුට නිසි ආරක්ෂාව ලබා දෙන ලෙසත් අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙසත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා අතර අද පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලදී මෙම ඉල්ලීම සිදුකළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පොහොට්ටුවට අවශ්‍ය ගෝඨාභය ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ පහසුකම් සහිතව නැවත ලංකාවට පැමිණීමයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வசதிகளுடன் கோட்டாபய மீண்டும் இலங்கைக்கு வர வேண்டும் என்று பொஹொட்டுவா விரும்புகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை இலங்கைக்கு அழைத்து வருவதற்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்ச வருகையை தொடர்ந்து அவருக்கு உரிய பாதுகாப்பு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும், தேவையான வசதிகளை செய்து தருமாறும் SLPP கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிற்கும் ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் இடையில் இன்று இடம்பெற்ற பேச்சுவார்த்தையின் போது இந்த கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வசதிகளுடன் கோட்டாபய மீண்டும் இலங்கைக்கு வர வேண்டும் என்று பொஹொட்டுவா விரும்புகிறார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}