{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/parliament-to-meet-tomorrow-27-to-debate-emergency/",
  "time_ut": 1658836980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament to meet tomorrow (27) to debate emergency",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament to meet tomorrow (27) to debate emergency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Parliament is scheduled to convene tomorrow (27) at 10.00 AM and the proclamation on the state of emergency declared by the Acting President under the Public Security Ordinance is to be approved after debate until 4.30 pm.",
        "This proclamation was made by the then Acting President through the Special Gazette No. 2288/30 dated July 17, 2022, and according to the legal provisions, if the approval of the Parliament is not obtained within 14 days for the said proclamation, it will be canceled.",
        "It is stated in the gazette that this proclamation has been issued following the powers vested in the President in terms of the Public Security Ordinance to ensure public security and the protection of the public order and the maintenance of supplies and services essential to the life of the community.",
        "Meanwhile, Wajira Abeywardena, who was nominated by the Election Commission for the National List Member of the United National Party, was vacant due to the swearing-in of the President, Hon. Ranil Wickramasinghe is scheduled to be sworn in as a Member of Parliament tomorrow morning.",
        "Five COVID deaths for Monday (25), over 100 cases today (26)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 AM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 17, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Security Ordinance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හදිසි අවස්ථා විවාදය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට (27) රැස්වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට (27) පෙරවරු 10.00 ට රැස්වීමට නියමිත අතර මහජන ආරක්ෂක ආඥාපනත යටතේ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීතිය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රකාශය පස්වරු 4.30 දක්වා විවාදයෙන් අනතුරුව අනුමත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "2022 ජූලි 17 දිනැති අංක 2288/30 දරන විශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රය මගින් එවකට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් මෙම ප්‍රකාශය සිදු කර ඇති අතර නීතිමය ප්‍රතිපාදන අනුව එම ප්‍රකාශය සඳහා දින 14ක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතිය ලබා නොගතහොත් එය අවලංගු වේ.",
        "මහජන ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ මහජන සාමය ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීම සහ ජන ජීවිතයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සැපයුම් හා සේවා පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහා මහජන ආරක්‍ෂක ආඥාපනත ප‍්‍රකාරව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත පැවරී ඇති බලතල අනුව මෙම ප‍්‍රකාශය නිකුත් කර ඇති බව එම ගැසට් නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ. ප්රජාව.",
        "මේ අතර, එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහා මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් නම් කරන ලද වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ දිවුරුම් දීම හේතුවෙන් පුරප්පාඩු විය. රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හෙට පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "සඳුදා (25) කොවිඩ් මරණ පහක්, අද (26) රෝගීන් 100 ඉක්මවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන ආරක්ෂක ආඥාපනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவசரகால விவாதம் தொடர்பாக நாளை (27) பாராளுமன்றம் கூடவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாராளுமன்றம் நாளை (27) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு கூடவுள்ளதுடன், பொது பாதுகாப்பு கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியினால் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் தொடர்பான பிரகடனம் மாலை 4.30 மணி வரை விவாதத்தின் பின்னர் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 17, 2022 தேதியிட்ட சிறப்பு வர்த்தமானி இலக்கம் 2288/30 மூலம் இந்த பிரகடனம் அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியால் வெளியிடப்பட்டது, மேலும் சட்ட விதிகளின்படி, மேற்படி பிரகடனத்திற்கு 14 நாட்களுக்குள் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஒப்புதல் பெறப்படாவிட்டால், அது ரத்து செய்யப்படும்.",
        "பொது பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொது ஒழுங்கைப் பாதுகாத்தல் மற்றும் மக்களின் வாழ்க்கைக்கு அத்தியாவசியமான விநியோகங்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளைப் பேணுதல் ஆகியவற்றை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் பொது பாதுகாப்பு கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்த பிரகடனம் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வர்த்தமானியில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. சமூக.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் உறுப்பினருக்கு தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவினால் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட வஜிர அபேவர்தன ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் காரணமாக வெற்றிடமாக இருந்தார். ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாளை காலை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்ய உள்ளார்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (25) ஐந்து கோவிட் இறப்புகள், இன்று (26) 100 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வழக்குகள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 17, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பாதுகாப்பு ஆணை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}