{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84619/foreign-minister-to-address-51st-session-of-unhrc",
  "time_ut": 1661794320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Foreign Minister to address 51st session of UNHRC",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Foreign Minister to address 51st session of UNHRC",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC) is scheduled to be held from September 12 to October 07, 2022 in Geneva.",
        "Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry will lead the Sri Lanka delegation and deliver a statement at the Council during the Interactive Dialogue on Sri Lanka scheduled for Monday (September 12).",
        "The Minister of Justice, Prison Affairs and Constitutional Reforms Dr. Wijayedasa Rajapaksa, will also join the Delegation, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51st",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "UNHRC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "51st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 12 to October 07, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday (September 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prison Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijayedasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delegation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ 51 වැනි සැසිවාරය ඇමතීමට විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ (UNHRC) 51 වැනි සැසිවාරය 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 12 සිට ඔක්තෝබර් 07 දක්වා ජිනීවා නුවරදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත පිරිසට නායකත්වය දෙන අතර සඳුදා (සැප්තැම්බර් 12) පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ අන්තර් ක්‍රියාකාරී සංවාදයේදී කවුන්සිලයේදී ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදු කරනු ඇත.",
        "අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු සහ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ද නියෝජිත පිරිසට එක්වන බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "UNHRC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 12 සිට ඔක්තෝබර් 07 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා (සැප්තැම්බර් 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්ධනාගාර කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UNHRC இன் 51வது அமர்வில் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் உரையாற்றுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் (UNHRC) 51வது அமர்வு 2022 செப்டம்பர் 12 முதல் அக்டோபர் 07, 2022 வரை ஜெனீவாவில் நடைபெற உள்ளது.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (செப்டம்பர் 12) திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கை தொடர்பான ஊடாடும் உரையாடலின் போது வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி இலங்கை தூதுக்குழுவிற்கு தலைமை தாங்கி சபையில் அறிக்கையொன்றை வழங்குவார்.",
        "நீதி, சிறைச்சாலை விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவும் தூதுக்குழுவில் இணைவார் என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "UNHRC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 12 முதல் அக்டோபர் 07, 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை (செப்டம்பர் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறை விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூதுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}