{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131982",
  "time_ut": 1658421912,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளராக சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க நியமனம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Saman Ekanayake appointed as President's Secretary",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ekanayake had previously served as the secretary of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa since Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as Prime Minister in May last year until he resigned.",
        "Prior to that, Ekanayake, who was the secretary to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe during the period 2015-2019, has now been appointed to the post of President's Secretary.",
        "It is to be noted that Saman Ekanayake is a special grade retired officer in the Sri Lankan Administrative Service."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the period 2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Administrative Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමන් ඒකනායක ජනාධිපති ලේකම් ලෙස පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය වසරේ මැයි මාසයේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමේ සිට ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වන තෙක්ම ඒකනායක මහතා මීට පෙර ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "ඊට පෙර 2015-2019 කාලය තුළ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ඒකනායක මහතා මේ වන විට ජනාධිපති ලේකම් ධූරයට පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවයේ විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ විශ්‍රාමික නිලධාරියකු බව සඳහන් කළ යුතුය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019 කාලය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளராக சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க நியமனம்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக பதவியேற்றது முதல் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகும் வரை அவரின்  செயலாளராக ஏகநாயக்க இதற்கு முன்னர் பணியாற்றியிருந்தார்.",
        "அதற்கு இதற்கு முன்னர் 2015-2019 காலப்பகுதியில்  பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் செயலாளராக இருந்த ஏக்கநாயக்க தற்போது , ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளர் பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சமன் ஏகநாயக்க இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவையில் சிறப்பு தர ஓய்வு பெற்ற அதிகாரி ஆவார் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019 காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}