{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/bandula-steps-down-from-ministerial-positions/",
  "time_ut": 1657432620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bandula steps down from Ministerial positions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bandula steps down from Ministerial positions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Ministers Bandula Gunawardena, Harin Fernando, and Manusha Nanayakkara have resigned from their ministerial positions.",
        "In Facebook post, former Minister Bandula Gunawardena has stated that he will step down from the positions of Minister of Transport, Mass Media and Highways which he has held so far and work as an independent member of Parliament to allow the establishment of an all-party Government.",
        "Former Ministers Manusha Nanayakkara and Harin Fernando too announced yesterday that they will step down from the positions of Minister of Labor and Foreign Employment and Minister of Tourism and Land, allowing the establishment of an all-party government.",
        "Public support necessary to maintain the peace – General Shavendra Silva"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bandula",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බන්දුල අමාත්‍ය ධුරවලින් ඉවත් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ මනූෂ නානායක්කාර යන අමාත්‍යවරුන් සිය අමාත්‍ය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇත.",
        "තමන් මෙතෙක් දැරූ ප්‍රවාහන, ජනමාධ්‍ය හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වී ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස සර්ව පක්ෂයක් පිහිටුවීමට ඉඩ සැලසීමට කටයුතු කරන බව හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන ෆේස්බුක් සටහනක් තබමින් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබෙනවා. ආණ්ඩුව.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන මනූෂ නානායක්කාර සහ හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු ද සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට ඉඩ සලසමින් කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා සහ සංචාරක හා ඉඩම් අමාත්‍ය ධුරවලින් ඉවත් වන බව ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "සාමය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට මහජන සහයෝගය අවශ්‍යයි - ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බන්දුල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பந்துல அமைச்சர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அமைச்சர்களான பந்துல குணவர்தன, ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார ஆகியோர் தமது அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை இராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதுவரையில் தான் வகித்து வந்த போக்குவரத்து, வெகுஜன ஊடகம் மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகி, அனைத்துக் கட்சியொன்றை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கு அனுமதிக்கும் வகையில் சுயேட்சையான நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக செயற்படவுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன பேஸ்புக் பதிவில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அரசாங்கம்.",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்களான மனுஷ நாணயக்கார மற்றும் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோரும் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிக்க அனுமதிக்கும் வகையில் தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சர் மற்றும் சுற்றுலா மற்றும் காணி அமைச்சர் பதவிகளில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக நேற்று அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அமைதியை நிலைநாட்ட பொதுமக்கள் ஆதரவு தேவை - ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பந்துல",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}