{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/பாராளுமன்றில்-பதவிப்பிரமாணம்-செய்தார்-ரணில்/175-300849",
  "time_ut": 1658380102,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பாராளுமன்றில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்தார் ரணில்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil took oath in Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe was sworn in as the 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardana welcomed President Ranil Wickremesinghe who visited Parliament.",
        "Following this, Ranil Wickramasinghe was sworn in as the 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka in the presence of Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe was appointed as the Prime Minister to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa on May 9.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa stepped down from the presidency on the 14th due to the continued opposition of the people. Following this, Ranil Wickramasinghe, who served as the Prime Minister according to the constitution, was appointed as the Acting President on the 14th.",
        "In this situation, Ranil Wickremesinghe was elected as the new President by getting 134 votes during the secret ballot held in the Parliament yesterday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පිළිගනු ලැබුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසිනි.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ඉදිරියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගිය මැයි 9 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කෙරුණා.",
        "දිගින් දිගටම එල්ල වූ ජනතා විරෝධය හේතුවෙන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් විය. ඉන් අනතුරුව පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත්කෙරුණා.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැති රහස් ඡන්දයේදී ඡන්ද 134ක් ලබා ගනිමින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்தார் ரணில்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 8 ஆவது நிறைவேற்றதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு வருகை தந்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை, சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன வரவேற்றார்.",
        "இதனையடுத்து, பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய முன்னிலையில், இலங்கையின் 8 ஆவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகியதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஏற்பட்ட வெற்றிடத்திற்கு ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "தொடர்ந்து மக்களின் எதிர்ப்பினை அடுத்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ கடந்த 14ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதிப் பதவியிலிருந்து விலகினார். இதனைத் தொடர்ந்து அரசியலமைப்புக்கு அமைய பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்துவந்த ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க கடந்த 14ஆம் திகதி பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பாராளுமன்றில் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பின்போது, 134 வாக்குகளை பெற்று புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவானார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}