{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Protestors-reach-Presidents-House-police-seen-withdrawing/108-240703",
  "time_ut": 1657350196,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protestors reach President’s House, police seen withdrawing",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protestors reach President’s House, police seen withdrawing",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Thousands of protestors have reached the main entrance of the President's House in Fort after putting down layers of barricades and the police were seen withdrawing from the area.",
        "Shots were heard being fired in the air and continuous rounds of tear gas is being fired."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ළඟා වන අතර, පොලිසිය ඉවත්ව යනු දක්නට ලැබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් දහස් ගණනින් කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව අසලට පැමිණ බාධක තට්ටු දමා ඇති අතර පොලිසිය එම ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ඉවත්ව යනු දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "ගුවනේ වෙඩි හඬ ඇසුණු අතර දිගින් දිගටම කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර ද එල්ල වෙමින් තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை அடைந்தனர், போலீசார் பின்வாங்கினர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையின் பிரதான நுழைவாயிலில் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தடுப்புகளை அடுக்கிய பின்னர் பொலிஸார் அப்பகுதியிலிருந்து பின்வாங்குவதைக் காணமுடிந்தது.",
        "வானில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சத்தம் கேட்டதுடன், தொடர்ந்து கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகள் வீசப்பட்டு வருகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}