{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84608/44-arrested-as-navy-foils-multiple-illegal-migration-attempts-",
  "time_ut": 1661763180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "44 arrested as navy foils multiple illegal migration attempts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "44 arrested as navy foils multiple illegal migration attempts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Navy personnel have arrested 44 persons who were suspected to be on illegal migration attempts from the country via sea routes.",
        "The apprehensions were made during special search operations conducted by the Navy off Trincomalee and in the beach area of Valaithottam, Batticaloa last night (28).",
        "Accordingly, the Eastern Naval Command conducted a special search operation off Trincomalee in the dark hours of Sunday, deploying Fast Attack Craft P 465 and P 4443 of the 4th Fast Attack Flotilla (4 FAF) attached to the Command.",
        "In this operation, P 465 intercepted a suspicious local multiday fishing trawler off Trincomalee and held 29 individuals who were suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt from the country.",
        "Among the apprehended persons were 25 males, including 05 in connection to the racket, 02 females over 18 years of age and 02 individuals below 18 years. Thus, the suspects along with the multiday fishing trawler were taken into naval custody.",
        "Further, another search operation mounted by SLNS Walagamba in the Eastern Naval Command at Kuchchaveli beach in the dark hours of Sunday made way to the apprehension of 02 suspects and a dinghy. The individuals who are residents of Kuchchaveli were suspected to have transferred people from the shores to the fishing trawler intercepted by P 465.",
        "Meanwhile, P 4443 engaged in this operation off Trincomalee searched a similar local multiday fishing trawler and nabbed 05 males over 18 years of age. As such, the group that was suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt from the country and the multiday fishing trawler were taken into naval custody.",
        "In the meantime, a search operation carried out in the Valaithottam beach area on the night of 28th August by SLNS Lankapatuna in the Eastern Naval Command led to the apprehension of 10 males over 18 years, remaining suspiciously at the beach. It was suspected that the individuals were wandering there with the intention of migrating from the country by the fishing trawler intercepted by P 4443.",
        "The suspects held in these operations were identified as residents of Trincomalee, Batticaloa, Ampara, Puttalam, Hambantota, Valaichchenai, Kalmunai, Akkaraipattu and Kuchchaveli.",
        "The 34 individuals held by P 465 and P 4443 and 02 suspects held by SLNS Walagamba will be handed over to the Trincomalee Harbour Police and Kuchchaveli Police respectively for onward legal proceedings. Meanwhile, the 10 individuals held by SLNS Lankapatuna were handed over to the Eechchalampattu Police in Batticaloa for onward legal action.",
        "As it is observed that human smugglers organize this nature of rackets using unsafe methods for the purpose of making fast money, the Sri Lanka Navy urges the public to refrain from risking their lives by engaging in perilous sea voyages and be victims before the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valaithottam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the dark hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Flotilla",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "multiday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Walagamba",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the dark hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuchchaveli",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Valaithottam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of 28th August",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Lankapatuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 males",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara, Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valaichchenai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akkaraipattu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuchchaveli",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Walagamba",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trincomalee Harbour Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuchchaveli Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Lankapatuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eechchalampattu Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණික උත්සාහයන් කිහිපයක් නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ව්‍යර්ථ කළ 44ක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 44 දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව ඊයේ (28) රාත්‍රියේ ත්‍රිකුණාමලයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ සහ මඩකලපුව, වලයිතෝට්ටම් වෙරළ තීරයේ සිදු කළ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුම්වලදී මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව, නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය විසින් විධානයට අනුයුක්ත 4 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක ෆ්ලෝටිලා (4 FAF) හි වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රා P 465 සහ P 4443 යොදවා ත්‍රිකුණාමලයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමක් ඉරිදා අඳුරේ සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී P 465 ත්‍රිකුණාමලයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ සැක කටයුතු දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රටින් සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කළ පුද්ගලයින් 29 දෙනෙකු රඳවාගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයින් අතර ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ 05 දෙනෙකු, වයස අවුරුදු 18ට වැඩි කාන්තාවන් 02 දෙනෙකු සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු පුද්ගලයින් 02 දෙනෙකු ඇතුළුව පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 25 දෙනෙකු සිටින බව සඳහන්. මේ අනුව, සැකකරුවන් සහ බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "තවද, නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා වලගම්බා විසින් ඉරිදා අඳුරේ කුච්චවේලි වෙරළ තීරයේ සිදු කරන ලද තවත් සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී සැකකරුවන් 02 දෙනෙකු සහ ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට හැකි විය. කුච්චවේලි ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි පුද්ගලයින් පී 465 මගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාව වෙත වෙරළේ සිට පුද්ගලයින් මාරු කර යවා ඇති බවටයි සැක කෙරුණේ.",
        "මේ අතර, ත්‍රිකුණාමලයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මෙම මෙහෙයුමේ නිරත P 4443 දරණ යාත්‍රාව මගින් මෙවැනිම දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් පරීක්ෂා කර වයස අවුරුදු 18ට වැඩි පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 05 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. ඒ අනුව නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටින් සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පිරිස සහ බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගැනුණා.",
        "මේ අතර, නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා ලංකාපටුන මගින් අගෝස්තු 28 වන දින රාත්‍රියේ වලයිතෝට්ටම් වෙරළ තීරයේ සිදු කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී සැකකටයුතු ලෙස මුහුදු වෙරළේ රැඳී සිටි අවුරුදු 18ට වැඩි පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 10 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. පී 4443 දරණ ධීවර යාත්‍රාව මගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාව මගින් රටින් සංක්‍රමණය වීමේ අරමුණින් මෙම පුද්ගලයින් එහි සැරිසරන්නට ඇති බවටයි සැක කෙරුණේ.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුම්වලදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, මඩකලපුව, අම්පාර, පුත්තලම, හම්බන්තොට, වාලච්චේන, කල්මුණේ, අක්කරපත්තුව සහ කුච්චවේලි යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බව හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "P 465 සහ P 4443 විසින් රඳවාගෙන සිටින පුද්ගලයින් 34 දෙනා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා වලගම්බා භාරයේ සිටි සැකකරුවන් 02 දෙනා ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා පිළිවෙලින් ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය පොලිසියට සහ කුච්චවේලි පොලිසියට භාර දීමට නියමිතය. මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා ලංකාපටුන භාරයේ සිටි පුද්ගලයන් 10 දෙනා ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා මඩකලපුව, ඊච්චලම්පත්තු පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මිනිස් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් අනාරක්ෂිත ක්‍රම භාවිත කරමින් වේගයෙන් මුදල් ඉපයීමේ අරමුණින් මෙවැනි ජාවාරම් සංවිධානය කරන බව නිරීක්ෂණය වන බැවින් අනතුරුදායක මුහුදු ගමන්වල යෙදීමෙන් වළකිමින් නීතිය ඉදිරියේ ගොදුරු බවට පත්වන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලයිතෝට්ටම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඳුරු පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්රහාරක යාත්රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්‍රහාර ෆ්ලෝටිලා",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බහුදින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා වලගම්බා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඳුරු පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුච්චවේලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වලයිතෝට්ටම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 28 රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS ලංකාපටුන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි 10 ක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර, පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාලච්චේනයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්කරපත්තුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුච්චවේලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා වලගම්බා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුච්චවේලි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS ලංකාපටුන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊච්චලම්පත්තු පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல முறை சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சிகளை கடற்படை முறியடித்ததால் 44 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையிலிருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 44 பேரை இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் திருகோணமலைக்கு அப்பால் மற்றும் மட்டக்களப்பு வாழைத்தோட்டம் கடற்கரைப் பகுதியில் நேற்று (28) இரவு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கைகளின் போதே குறித்த அச்சம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை இருண்ட நேரத்தில் திருகோணமலைக்கு அப்பால் ஒரு சிறப்பு தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டது, கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட 4 வது Fast Attack Flotilla (4 FAF) இன் Fast Attack Craft P 465 மற்றும் P 4443 ஆகியவற்றை நிலைநிறுத்தியது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில், P 465 திருகோணமலையில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான உள்ளூர் பல நாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவைப்படகு ஒன்றை இடைமறித்து, நாட்டிலிருந்து சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 29 நபர்களை கைது செய்தது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் 25 ஆண்களும் அடங்குவர். இதில் மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 05 பேரும், 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட 02 பெண்களும், 18 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட 02 பேரும் அடங்குவர். இதனால், சந்தேகநபர்கள் பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகுடன் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும், ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை இருண்ட நேரத்தில் குச்சவெளி கடற்கரையில் கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையில் SLNS வலகம்பாவால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மற்றொரு தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையானது 02 சந்தேக நபர்களையும் ஒரு டிங்கி படகையும் கைது செய்ய வழிவகுத்தது. குச்சவெளியை வசிப்பிடமாகக் கொண்ட நபர்கள், P 465 மூலம் இடைமறித்து மீன்பிடி இழுவைப்படகுக்கு கரையிலிருந்து மக்களை மாற்றியதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், திருகோணமலைக்கு அப்பால் இந்த நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த P 4443 இதேபோன்ற உள்ளூர் பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை சோதனையிட்டது மற்றும் 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட 05 ஆண்களை கைது செய்தது. இதன்படி, நாட்டிலிருந்து சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற்ற முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்டதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் குழுவும், பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகும் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டன.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்கு உட்பட்ட SLNS லங்காபடுன மூலம் ஆகஸ்ட் 28 இரவு வாழைத்தோட்டம் கடற்கரைப் பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வகையில் கடற்கரையில் தங்கியிருந்த 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட ஆண்கள் 10 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர். P 4443 மூலம் இடைமறித்த மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு மூலம் நாட்டிலிருந்து இடம்பெயர்ந்து செல்லும் நோக்கில் நபர்கள் அங்கு நடமாடுவதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர்கள் திருகோணமலை, மட்டக்களப்பு, அம்பாறை, புத்தளம், ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை, வாழைச்சேனை, கல்முனை, அக்கரைப்பற்று மற்றும் குச்சவெளி ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "SLNS வலகம்பவினால் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள P 465 மற்றும் P 4443 வசமிருந்த 34 நபர்களும், 02 சந்தேக நபர்களும் முறையே திருகோணமலை துறைமுக பொலிஸாரிடமும் குச்சவெளி பொலிஸாரிடமும் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர். இதேவேளை, SLNS லங்காபடுனவினால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 10 பேரும் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக மட்டக்களப்பு ஈச்சலம்பத்து பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "மனித கடத்தல்காரர்கள் பாதுகாப்பற்ற முறைகளை பயன்படுத்தி வேகமாக பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக இவ்வாறான மோசடிகளை ஏற்பாடு செய்வதை அவதானிக்கின்ற நிலையில், ஆபத்தான கடல் பயணங்களில் ஈடுபட்டு உயிரைப் பணயம் வைத்து சட்டத்தின் முன் பலியாவதைத் தவிர்த்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு இலங்கை கடற்படை பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழைத்தோட்டம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருண்ட நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் ஃப்ளோட்டிலா",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலநாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS வலகம்பா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருண்ட நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குச்சவெளி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாழைத்தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 28 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS லங்காபடுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை, புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழைச்சேனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்கரைப்பற்று",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குச்சவெளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS வலகம்பா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை துறைமுக காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குச்சவெளி பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS லங்காபடுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈச்சலம்பட்டு போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}