{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-will-resign-as-previously-announced-pms-office-97221/",
  "time_ut": 1657508460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka president will resign as previously announced: PM’s office",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka president will resign as previously announced: PM’s office",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has officially informed Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe that he will resign as previously announced, the prime minister’s office said.",
        "Previously, Speaker of Parliament Mahina Yapa Abeywardena said that President Rajapaksa had informed him that he would be stepping down on Wednesday July 13.",
        "Saturday July 09 saw protestors storm Rajapaksa’s official residence demanding his resignation. The Speaker said in a statement that evening that he had informed Rajapaksa of a decision reached at a party leaders’ meeting that the president and Prime Minister Wickremesinghe must step down.",
        "The president had expressed his agreement with this decision, he said.",
        "On Sunday July 10, his office released a statement that said he had ordered officials to expedite cooking gas distribution after the arrival of a gas shipment Monday July 11 afternoon.  (Colombo/Jul11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා කලින් ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි ඉල්ලා අස්වනු ඇත: අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කලින් ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දී ඇතැයි අගමැති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින යාපා අබේවර්ධන මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජූලි 13 බදාදා තමා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ තමාට දන්වා ඇති බවයි.",
        "ජුලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා විරෝධතාකරුවන් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කරමින් ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදුණු අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය. කථානායකවරයා එදින සවස නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේ දී ගත් තීරණයක් තමන් රාජපක්ෂට දැනුම් දුන් බවයි.",
        "මෙම තීරණයට ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය එකඟතාව පළ කළ බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ජූලි 10 ඉරිදා, ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ජූලි 11 වන සඳුදා පස්වරුවේ ගෑස් නැව්ගත කිරීමක් පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් බෙදා හැරීම කඩිනම් කරන ලෙස නිලධාරීන්ට නියෝග කළ බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னதாக அறிவித்தபடி இலங்கை அதிபர் பதவி விலகுவார்: பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு முன்னர் அறிவித்தபடி பதவி விலகுவதாக உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவித்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக, நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹின யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகப் போவதாக ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ தமக்கு அறிவித்ததாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமை ஜூலை 09, ராஜபக்சே பதவி விலகக் கோரி அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டனர். ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்று கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவை ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு தெரிவித்ததாக சபாநாயகர் அன்று மாலை ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த தீர்மானத்திற்கு ஜனாதிபதி தனது இணக்கத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஜூலை 10 அன்று, அவரது அலுவலகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டது, திங்கட்கிழமை ஜூலை 11 மதியம் எரிவாயு ஏற்றுமதி வந்த பிறகு சமையல் எரிவாயு விநியோகத்தை விரைவுபடுத்துமாறு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு உத்தரவிட்டதாகக் கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}