{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පළාත්-හයකට-සවස-වැස්ස/1-617211",
  "time_ut": 1659061739,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පළාත් හයකට සවස වැස්ස",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Evening rain in six provinces",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says that rain or thundershowers will occur in Sabaragamuwa, Central, North Central, Uva, South and North West provinces today (29) in the evening or at night.",
        "A spokesperson of the department said that the sky will be cloudy in the northern, central and eastern provinces, while it will rain in the morning in the eastern, Uva and southern provinces.",
        "The spokesperson said that in some places in Sabaragamuwa, Central, North Central, Uva, South, North West and Eastern provinces, more than 75 mm of heavy rain will occur.",
        "The department also states that thunderstorms may be accompanied by lightning and temporary gusty winds."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "six",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa, Central, North Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "North West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa, Central, North Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළාත් හයකට සවස වැස්ස",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුරුමැද, ඌව, දකුණු සහ වයඹ පළාත්වල අද (29) සවස් කාලයේ දී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "උතුරු, උතුරුමැද සහ නැගෙනහිර පළාත්වල අහස වළාකුලින් බරව පවතින අතර නැගෙනහිර, ඌව සහ දකුණු පළාත්වල උදෑසන කාලයේ ද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුරුමැද, ඌව, දකුණු, වයඹ සහ නැගෙනහිර පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානයන්හි මිලිමීටර 75 ට වැඩි තරමක තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසීය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බව ද එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆறு மாகாணங்களில் மாலை மழை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமத்திய, ஊவா, தென் மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களில் இன்று (29) மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளையில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வடக்கு, மத்திய மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் வானம் மேகமூட்டத்துடன் காணப்படும் எனவும், கிழக்கு, ஊவா மற்றும் தென் மாகாணங்களில் காலை வேளையில் மழை பெய்யும் எனவும் திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமத்திய, ஊவா, தெற்கு, வடமேற்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் மின்னலுடன் தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் எனவும் திணைக்களம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வட மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வட மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}