{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131904",
  "time_ut": 1658333818,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குத் தீவைக்கப்பட்டால் எம்மை சாடவேண்டாம் - மக்கள் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டக்காரர்கள்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Don't curse us if Parliament is set on fire - people are rioters.",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "People's revolutionaries have declared that they will never accept Ranil Wickramasinghe, who has been elected by Parliament as the eighth Executive President, as the President of the country.",
        "Accordingly, the protestors held a special press conference at 'Kota Ko Kama' in Kalimugattidal today and announced that they will continue to fight until Ranil Wickremesinghe is ousted and the protest will continue despite the repression.",
        "Today is the 102nd day of the self-insurgency of the people in Kalimuktathidal and the parliament has elected Ranil Wickramasinghe as the 8th executive president and the protesters who participated in the self-insurgency held a media conference together.",
        "Vasantha Mudalike, one of the leading activists of the self-reliance struggle, who participated and commented:",
        "This insurrection caused Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who was elected president with 69 lakh votes, to secretly flee to the Maldives at 3 am.",
        "When this happened, the Lok Sabha was still in session. This protest led to the rejection of Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the removal of Mahinda Rajapaksa from office.",
        "Meanwhile, Ranil Wickramasinghe has been elected as the President in conspiracies within the Parliament using the votes of the expired Podujana Peramuna.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe does not have any Lok Sabha. He will be a loser in the 2020 general elections.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa did not make him Prime Minister for the sake of the people who entered the Parliament through the National List.",
        "He was made Prime Minister for the benefit of the Rajapaksa family. That being the case, we will not accept Ranil Wickramasinghe as president without a Lok Sabha.",
        "The people will not stop this struggle until they drive him out. Ranil Wickramasinghe should not think that he can end this struggle by chasing us away, arresting us and shooting us.",
        "Ranil cannot provide any solution to the current problem. Because he has already been the prime minister for 6 times.",
        "His association with central bank policy and incidents like the concentration camp in Patalanda is no secret.",
        "The current parliament does not reflect the will of the people. If people act in violation of Lok Sabha like this, people will set fire to Parliament. If such an incident happens, don't blame it on us and come to us.",
        "It will be clear in two or three weeks what is going to happen to a government that is formed against the will of the people. He said that our struggle will continue."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalimugattidal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 102nd day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalimuktathidal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasantha Mudalike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two or three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගිනි තිබ්බොත් අපිට බණින්න එපා - මිනිස්සු කලහකාරීන්.",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "අටවැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් තේරී පත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කිසිවිටෙකත් පිළිනොගන්නා බව ජනතා විප්ලවවාදීන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව අද දින කලිමුගට්ටිඩාල් හි 'කොට කෝ කමා' හිදී විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පවත්වමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ එළවා දමන තුරු අඛණ්ඩව සටන් කරන බවත් මර්දනය නොතකා විරෝධතාව අඛණ්ඩව සිදුකරන බවත්ය.",
        "කාලිමුක්‌තතිඩාල් ජනතා ස්වයං කැරැල්ලේ 102 වැනි දිනය අදයි.පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තේරී පත් වූ අතර එම ස්වයං කැරැල්ලට සහභාගි වූ විරෝධතාකරුවන් එක්ව මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "ඊට සහභාගී වෙමින් අදහස් දැක්වූ ස්වයංපෝෂිත අරගලයේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන වසන්ත මුදලිකේ මහතා මෙසේ පැවසීය.",
        "මේ කැරැල්ල නිසා ඡුන්ද 69 ලක්ෂයකින් ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට අලුයම 3 ට රහසේ මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගියේය.",
        "මෙය සිදු වන විට ලෝක් සභාව තවමත් සැසිවාරය පැවැත්වීය. මෙම විරෝධය ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමටත් මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ධුරයෙන් පහ කිරීමටත් හේතු විය.",
        "මේ අතර කල් ඉකුත් වූ පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ඡන්දය භාවිත කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ කුමන්ත්‍රණ කරමින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වී තිබේ.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ලෝක් සභාවක් නැහැ. 2020 මහ මැතිවරණයෙන් ඔහු පරාජිතයෙක් වනු ඇත.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඔහුව අගමැති කළේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණි ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් නොවේ.",
        "එතුමාව අගමැති කළේ රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ උවමනාවට. එය එසේ වුවත් ලෝක් සභාවක් නොමැතිව අපි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපති ලෙස පිළිගන්නේ නැහැ.",
        "එතුමා එළවන තුරු ජනතාව මේ අරගලය නවත්වන්නේ නැහැ. අපිව එළවා දමා, අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන, වෙඩි තබා මේ අරගලය අවසන් කළ හැකි යැයි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ නොසිතිය යුතුයි.",
        "රනිල්ට දැන් තියෙන ප්‍රශ්නයට කිසිම විසඳුමක් දෙන්න බැහැ. මොකද ඔහු දැනටමත් 6 වතාවක් අගමැති වෙලා තියෙනවා.",
        "මහබැංකු ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සමඟ ඔහුගේ සම්බන්ධය සහ පතලන්ද වද කඳවුර වැනි සිදුවීම් රහසක් නොවේ.",
        "වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජනතා කැමැත්ත පිළිබිඹු කරන්නේ නැහැ. මිනිස්සු මේ විදියට ලෝක් සභාව උල්ලංඝනය කරලා ක්‍රියා කළොත් මිනිස්සු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගිනි තියයි. එහෙම සිද්දියක් උනොත් අපිට බනින්න එපා අපි ගාවට එන්න.",
        "ජනතා කැමැත්තට පටහැනිව හදන ආණ්ඩුවකට වෙන්න යන දේ තව සති දෙක තුනකින් පැහැදිලි වෙයි. අපේ අරගලය ඉදිරියටත් ගෙන යන බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලිමුගට්ටිඩාල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "102 වන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලිමුක්තතිඩාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාන්දර 3",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක් හෝ තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குத் தீவைக்கப்பட்டால் எம்மை சாடவேண்டாம் - மக்கள் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டக்காரர்கள்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாகப் பாராளுமன்றம் தெரிவுசெய்துள்ள ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தாம் ஒருபோதும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்போவதில்லையென மக்கள் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டக்காரர்கள் அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அதன்படி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்வைத் துரத்தும் வரை தொடர்ச்சியாகப் போராடப்போவதாகவும், அடக்குமுறைகளைமீறி அப்போராட்டம் தொடரும் எனவும் காலிமுகத்திடல், 'கோட்டா கோ கம'வில் விசேட செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பினை நடாத்தி போராட்டக்காரர்கள் இன்று அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "இன்று 102 ஆவது நாளாகவும் காலிமுக்ததிடலில் மக்களின் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டம் தொடர்ந்த நிலையில் பாராளுமன்றம் 8 ஆவது நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவைத் தெரிவுசெய்ததுடன் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டத்தில் பங்கேற்றுள்ள போராட்டக்காரர்கள் இணைந்து ஊடக சந்திப்பொன்றை நடாத்தினர்.",
        "இதில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து வெளியிட்ட தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டத்தின் முன்னணி செயற்பாட்டாளர்களில் ஒருவரான வசந்த முதலிகே கூறியதாவது:",
        "69 இலட்சம் வாக்குகளுடன் ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை அதிகாலை 3 மணிக்கு இரகசியமாக மாலைதீவுக்குத் தப்பியோட இந்தத் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டம் காரணமாக அமைந்தது.",
        "இது நடக்கும்போது மக்களாணை பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிற்கே இருந்தது. கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை மக்கள் நிராகரித்ததுடன் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவையும் பதவியிலிருந்து நீக்க இந்தப் போராட்டம் காரணமானது.",
        "அவ்வாறிருக்கையில் காலாவதியான பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் வாக்குகளைப் பயன்படுத்திப் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் நடந்த சதிகளுடாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு எந்தவொரு மக்களாணையும் இல்லை. 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டு பொதுத்தேர்தலில் அவர் தோல்வியடைந்தவராவார்.",
        "தேசிய பட்டியல் ஊடாகப் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் நுழைந்த அவரை கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மக்கள் நலனுக்காகப் பிரதமராக்கவில்லை.",
        "ராஜபக்ஷ குடும்பத்தின் நலனுக்காகவே அவர் பிரதமராக்கப்பட்டார். அவ்வாறிருக்கையில் மக்களாணை இல்லாத ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை நாம் ஜனாதிபதியாக ஏற்கமாட்டோம்.",
        "அவரை விரட்டியடிக்கும் வரை இந்தத் தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டத்தை மக்கள் நிறுத்தப்போவதில்லை. எம்மை அடித்துவிரட்டி, கைதுசெய்து, சுட்டுப்பொசுக்கி இந்தப் போராட்டத்தை முடிவிற்குக்கொண்டுவரலாமென ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க நினைக்கக்கூடாது.",
        "ரணிலால் தற்போதைய பிரச்சினைக்கு எந்தத் தீர்வினையும் வழங்கமுடியாது. ஏனெனில் அவர் ஏற்கனவே 6 முறை பிரதமராக இருந்தவராவார்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி கொள்கை, பட்டலந்த வதை முகாம் போன்ற சம்பவங்களுடன் அவருக்கு உள்ள தொடர்பு ஒன்றும் இரகசியமல்ல.",
        "தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றம் மக்களின் விருப்பத்தைப் பிரதிபலிக்கவில்லை. இப்படியே மக்களாணையை மீறி செயற்பட்டால் பாராளுமன்றத்தை மக்கள் தீவைத்து எரிக்கும் நிலையேற்படும். அவ்வாறு ஒரு சம்பவம் நடந்தால் அதனை எம்மீது சுமத்தி, எங்களைத்தேடி வரவேண்டாம்.",
        "மக்களின் விருப்பத்திற்கு மாறாக அமைக்கப்படும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு என்ன நடக்கப்போகின்றது என்பது இன்னும் இரண்டு, மூன்று வாரங்களில் தெளிவாகும். எமது போராட்டம் தொடரும் என அவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலிமுகத்திடல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "102வது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களிமுக்தாதிடல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 3 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}