{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෑස්-හා-ඛනිජ-තෙල්-කැණීම-පිළිබඳ-මාර්ග-සිතියම-කඩිනම්-කරන්න-උපදෙස්/11-394878",
  "time_ut": 1656318650,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෑස් හා ඛනිජ තෙල් කැණීම පිළිබඳ මාර්ග සිතියම කඩිනම් කරන්න උපදෙස්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Instructions to expedite the road map on gas and petroleum drilling",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The COPA Committee instructed the officials of the Ministry of Power and Energy to prepare a detailed road map for excavations in the country and to obtain gas and crude oil.",
        "The instructions were given to the officials of the Ministry of Power and Energy when the Committee on Public Accounts met under the chairmanship of its Member of Parliament (Professor) Tissa Vitarana in Parliament recently (22).",
        "The officials of the Ministry made a presentation on the planned Natural Gas Mining Projects (LNG) in Sri Lanka and their current status and pointed out that there are various obstacles to these mining.",
        "Members of Parliament who were present inquired about the parties involved in this. They also asked if the excavations required the advice of foreign governments. Officials present said there was no need for such advice from other governments.",
        "Accordingly, the COPA Committee instructed the officials to complete the excavations as soon as possible as it is in the interest of the country and therefore a road map should be prepared for the excavations as soon as possible."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The COPA Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Power and Energy when the Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Natural Gas Mining Projects",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LNG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the COPA Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෑස් හා ඛනිජ තෙල් කැණීම පිළිබඳ මාර්ග සිතියම කඩිනම් කරන්න උපදෙස්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෙරට භූමියේ අවශ්‍ය කැනීම් සිදුකර ගෑස් සහ බොරතෙල් ලබාගැනීම සඳහා සවිස්තරාත්මකව තොරතුරු ඇතුළත් කරන ලද මාර්ග සිතියමක් සකස් කරන ලෙස කෝපා කමිටුව විසින් විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් ලබා දෙන ලදි.",
        "විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන්ට මෙම උපදෙස් ලබාදුන්නේ රජයේ ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව එහි සභාපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) තිස්ස විතාරණ මහතාගේ සභාපතිත්වයෙන් පසුගියදා (22) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී රැස් වූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මෙහිදී ලංකාවේ සැලසුම් කොට ඇති ස්වභාවික වායු කැනීමේ ව්‍යාපෘති (LNG) පිළිබඳව සහ ඒ්වායේ වර්තමාන තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ ඉදිරිපත්කිරීමක් අමාත්‍යාංශ නිලධාරීන් සිදු කළ අතර මෙම කැනීම් සඳහා විවිධ බාධාවන් පවතින බවද ඔවුහු පෙන්වා දුන්හ.",
        "මෙහිදී පැමිණ සිටි මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් මේ සඳහා සම්බන්ධවන පාර්ශ්වයන් පිළිබඳව විමසන ලදි. එසේම මෙම කැනීම් සඳහා විදේශ රජයන්ගේ උපදෙස් අවශ්‍යවන්නේදැයි එම මන්ත්‍රීවරු විමසා සිටියහ. මෙහිදී පැමිණ සිටි නිලධාරීන් පෙන්වා දුන්නේ එසේ වෙනත් රජයන්ගෙන් උපදෙස් අවශ්‍ය නොවන බවයි.",
        "මේ අනුව මෙම කැනීම් ඉක්මනින් සිදු කොට අවසන් විය යුතු බවත් එය රටේ අවශ්‍යතාවයක් බවත් එබැවින් මෙම කැනීම් සිදු කිරීමට මාර්ග සිතියමක් ඉක්මනින් සකස් කරන ලෙසත් කෝපා කමිටුව නිලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් ලබාදුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "COPA කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව විට විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වභාවික ගෑස් කැණීම් ව්යාපෘති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්එන්ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPA කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிவாயு மற்றும் பெட்ரோலியம் தோண்டுதல் தொடர்பான சாலை வரைபடத்தை விரைவுபடுத்துவதற்கான வழிமுறைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் அகழ்வாராய்ச்சி மற்றும் எரிவாயு மற்றும் கச்சா எண்ணெய் பெறுவதற்கான விரிவான சாலை வரைபடத்தை தயாரிக்குமாறு கோபா கமிட்டி மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சக அதிகாரிகளுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியது.",
        "அண்மையில் (22) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அதன் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) திஸ்ஸ விதாரண தலைமையில் பொதுக் கணக்குக் குழு கூடிய போதே மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகளுக்கு இந்த அறிவுறுத்தல்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகள் இலங்கையில் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ள இயற்கை எரிவாயு அகழ்வுத் திட்டங்கள் (LNG) மற்றும் அவற்றின் தற்போதைய நிலை குறித்து விளக்கமளித்ததுடன், இந்த அகழ்வாராய்ச்சிக்கு பல்வேறு தடைகள் இருப்பதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினர்.",
        "இதில் கலந்து கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இதில் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினர் குறித்து கேட்டறிந்தனர். அகழ்வாராய்ச்சிக்கு வெளிநாட்டு அரசாங்கங்களின் ஆலோசனை தேவையா என்றும் கேட்டனர். மற்ற அரசுகளிடம் இருந்து இதுபோன்ற அறிவுரைகள் தேவையில்லை என அங்கிருந்த அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதன்படி, நாட்டின் நலன் கருதி அகழ்வாராய்ச்சிகளை விரைவாக முடிக்குமாறு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு கோபா கமிட்டி அறிவுறுத்தியது, எனவே அகழாய்வுக்கான சாலை வரைபடத்தை விரைவில் தயாரிக்க வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோபா கமிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம் பொது கணக்குகள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இயற்கை எரிவாயு சுரங்க திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்என்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPA குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}