{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Power-consumption-reduced-by-more-than-20-during-past-two-months-PUCSL/342-243304",
  "time_ut": 1660819681,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Power consumption reduced by more than 20% during past two months: PUCSL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Power consumption reduced by more than 20% during past two months: PUCSL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The country's electricity consumption has dropped sharply by more than 20% in the last two months, according to Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) Chairman Janaka Ratnayaka.",
        "He said the daily electricity consumption rate was at least 48 MWh and that 2,800 MW of electricity was required for peak time.",
        "However, during the past two months, electricity consumption was between 38 and 40 megawatt-hours. \"The volume of electricity required during the peak time was reduced to 2,100 MW. It represents a 20% reduction,\" Ratnayake said.",
        "The electricity tariff had also increased from last week and as consumers, we should keep in mind to conserve electricity while using electricity sparingly,\" he said. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "more than 20%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "past two months",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 38",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 megawatt-hours",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පසුගිය මාස දෙක තුළ බලශක්ති පරිභෝජනය 20% ට වඩා අඩු වී ඇත: PUCSL",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (PUCSL) සභාපති ජානක රත්නායක මහතාට අනුව පසුගිය මාස දෙක තුළ රටේ විදුලි පරිභෝජනය 20%කට වඩා ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "දෛනික විදුලි පරිභෝජන අනුපාතය අවම වශයෙන් මෙගාවොට් 48 ක් වන අතර උපරිම කාලය සඳහා මෙගාවොට් 2,800 ක විදුලිය අවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පසුගිය මාස දෙක තුළ විදුලි පරිභෝජනය මෙගාවොට් පැය 38 ත් 40 ත් අතර විය. \"උපරිම කාලය තුළ අවශ්‍ය විදුලි පරිමාව මෙගාවොට් 2,100 දක්වා අඩු කර ඇත. එය 20% ක අඩුවීමක් නියෝජනය කරයි,\" රත්නායක පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ සිට විදුලි බිලද ඉහළ ගොස් තිබූ අතර විදුලිය අරපිරිමැස්මෙන් භාවිත කරමින් විදුලිය ඉතිරි කර ගැනීමට පාරිභෝගිකයන් වශයෙන් අප මතක තබා ගත යුතුයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20% ට වඩා",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "පසුගිය මාස දෙක",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,800 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙගාවොට් පැය 40 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,100 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்களில் மின் நுகர்வு 20%க்கும் அதிகமாக குறைந்துள்ளது: PUCSL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்களில் நாட்டின் மின்சார பாவனை 20% க்கும் அதிகமாக குறைந்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (PUCSL) தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தினசரி மின் நுகர்வு விகிதம் குறைந்தபட்சம் 48 மெகாவாட் என்றும், பீக் நேரத்திற்கு 2,800 மெகாவாட் மின்சாரம் தேவை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இருப்பினும், கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்களில், மின் நுகர்வு 38 முதல் 40 மெகாவாட் மணி வரை இருந்தது. \"உச்ச நேரத்தில் தேவைப்படும் மின்சாரத்தின் அளவு 2,100 மெகாவாட்டாக குறைக்கப்பட்டது. இது 20% குறைப்பை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது\" என்று ரத்நாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரத்தில் இருந்து மின்சாரக் கட்டணமும் அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. நுகர்வோர் என்ற வகையில் மின்சாரத்தை சிக்கனமாக பயன்படுத்தும் போது மின்சாரத்தை சேமிப்பதை நாம் மனதில் கொள்ள வேண்டும். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20%க்கு மேல்",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "20%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 மெகாவாட் மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}