{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-wont-welcome-corrupt-politicians-to-SJB-led-multi-party-govt-Tissa-Attanyake/108-240909",
  "time_ut": 1657610641,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB won’t welcome corrupt politicians to SJB led multi-party-govt: Tissa Attanyake",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB won’t welcome corrupt politicians to SJB led multi-party-govt: Tissa Attanyake",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) today said it will not welcome anyone who is facing allegations of corruption.",
        "SJB National Oraganizer Tissa Attanayke told a media briefing that his party will not welcome anyone who is charged with corruption to the multi-party-government which will be formed by Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa, if he is elected President.",
        "\"We are in the process of garnering support for Mr. Premadasa,\" he said.",
        "\"We will also entertain proposals made by the protesters in our economic and political stability programme\" he added. (Yohan Perera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB National Oraganizer Tissa Attanayke",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB ප්‍රමුඛ බහු පක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවට දූෂිත දේශපාලනඥයන් පිළිගන්නේ නැහැ - තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දූෂණ චෝදනා එල්ලවන කිසිවකු පිළිනොගන්නා බව සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විපක්‍ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් පිහිටුවන බහු පක්‍ෂ රජයට දූෂණ චෝදනා එල්ල වූ කිසිවකු ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත් වුවහොත් තම පක්‍ෂය පිළිගන්නේ නැති බව SJB ජාතික සංවිධායක තිස්ස අත්තනායක මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "“අපි ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාට සහයෝගය ලබා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක නිරත වෙනවා.",
        "\"අපගේ ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්ව වැඩසටහන තුළ විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද යෝජනා ද අපි සලකා බලමු. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB ජාතික සංවිධායක තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB தலைமையிலான பல கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஊழல் அரசியல்வாதிகளை SJB வரவேற்காது: திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை எதிர்கொள்ளும் எவரையும் வரவேற்க மாட்டோம் என்று சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டால் அவர்களால் அமைக்கப்படும் பல கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டு சுமத்தப்படும் எவரையும் தமது கட்சி வரவேற்காது என SJB தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திரு.பிரேமதாசவுக்கான ஆதரவைத் திரட்டும் நடவடிக்கையில் நாம் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளோம் என்றார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை திட்டத்தில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முன்வைத்த திட்டங்களையும் நாங்கள் மகிழ்விப்போம்\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}