{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/reset-sri-lanka-reform-conference-by-advocata-institute-98227/",
  "time_ut": 1659669540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Reset Sri Lanka reform conference by Advocata Institute",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Reset Sri Lanka reform conference by Advocata Institute",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A forum on reforms needed to take Sri Lanka forward organized by Colombo based Advocata Institute is bringing together policy makers, international experts and the business community kicks of on August 05.",
        "The Let’s Reset Sri Lanka forum will deal with vital reforms in areas such as taxation, State Owned Enterprise, social safety nets, trade policy and land policy.",
        "The two day forum is featuring eminent experts including Veerathai Santiprabhob, former Governor of the (Central) Bank of Thailand will be on the first day and Premachandra Athukorala from the Australian National University will be delivering his remarks on the second day of the conference."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Reset Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Advocata Institute",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocata Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State Owned Enterprise",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The two day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veerathai Santiprabhob",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premachandra Athukorala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Australian National University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Advocata ආයතනය මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සමුළුව යළි පිහිටුවන්න",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – කොළඹ පදනම් වූ Advocata ආයතනය විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳ සංසදයක් ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්පාදකයින්, ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රවීණයන් සහ ව්‍යාපාරික ප්‍රජාව එක්ව අගෝස්තු 05 වෙනිදා ආරම්භ වේ.",
        "Le’s Reset Sri Lanka සංසදය බදුකරණය, රජය සතු ව්‍යවසාය, සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ දැල්, වෙළඳ ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ඉඩම් ප්‍රතිපත්තිය වැනි ක්ෂේත්‍රවල වැදගත් ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සමඟ කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "දෙදින සංසදයේ පළමු දිනයේ තායිලන්ත (මධ්‍යම) බැංකුවේ හිටපු අධිපති වීරතායි ශාන්තිප්‍රබෝබ් ඇතුළු කීර්තිමත් ප්‍රවීණයන් සහභාගී වන අතර සමුළුවේ දෙවන දිනයේ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ජාතික විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර අතුකෝරළ සිය අදහස් දැක්වීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යළි පිහිටුවන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Advocata ආයතනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocata ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජය සතු ව්‍යවසාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරතයි සන්තිප්‍රභොබ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර අතුකෝරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු ජාතික විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Advocata நிறுவனம் மூலம் இலங்கை சீர்திருத்த மாநாட்டை மீட்டமைக்கவும்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட Advocata இன்ஸ்டிட்யூட் ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ள இலங்கையை முன்னோக்கி கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு தேவையான சீர்திருத்தங்கள் பற்றிய மன்றம் ஆகஸ்ட் 05 அன்று கொள்கை வகுப்பாளர்கள், சர்வதேச வல்லுநர்கள் மற்றும் வணிக சமூகத்தை ஒன்றிணைக்கிறது.",
        "லெட்ஸ் ரீசெட் ஸ்ரீலங்கா மன்றமானது வரிவிதிப்பு, அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான தொழில் முயற்சி, சமூக பாதுகாப்பு வலைகள், வர்த்தகக் கொள்கை மற்றும் நிலக் கொள்கை போன்ற துறைகளில் முக்கியமான சீர்திருத்தங்களைக் கையாளும்.",
        "இரண்டு நாள் கருத்தரங்கில் முதல் நாளில் தாய்லாந்து (மத்திய) வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் வீரத்தாய் சாந்திபிரபோப் உட்பட பிரபல நிபுணர்கள் கலந்து கொள்கின்றனர் மற்றும் மாநாட்டின் இரண்டாவது நாளில் அவுஸ்திரேலிய தேசிய பல்கலைக்கழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த பிரேமச்சந்திர அத்துகோரல தனது கருத்துக்களை வழங்கவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையை மீட்டமைக்கவும்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "வக்கீல் நிறுவனம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வக்கீல் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரத்தை சாந்திபிரபோப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமச்சந்திர அத்துகோரல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய தேசிய பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}