{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ-ඡන්දයත්-ජනතා-මතයත්-අතර-ආලෝක-වර්ෂ-ගණනාවක-පරතයක්/101-616765",
  "time_ut": 1658328513,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයත් ජනතා මතයත් අතර ආලෝක වර්ෂ ගණනාවක පරතයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There is a gap of many light years between the vote of the Parliament and the opinion of the people",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The education secretary of Vanguard Socialist Party Mr. Pubudu Jayagoda said this afternoon (20) that there is a gap of many light years between the percentage of votes in the parliament and the opinion of the people outside and that the people's power of the country was used to remove the Gotabhaya Rajapaksa president who had 69 lakh votes and two-thirds power.",
        "Mr. Pubudu Jayagoda said that it was clearly demonstrated in the election of the President that the opinion of the people was not represented by the 225 members of the Parliament and also mentioned that the people's representatives in the Parliament have belittled the opinion, political aspirations, questions and grievances of over 200 lakh people outside the Parliament.",
        "Mr. Jayagoda said that since the people of the country did not have confidence in the Parliament for a long time, they had to go to the Araliya Ganga Mandiara to solve the problems and the slogans of 'power in the hands of the people' have been confirmed by the Parliament today.",
        "The Education Secretary of Vanguard Socialist Party Mr. Pubudu Jayagoda said this at a special press conference held today in Colombo to comment on the presidential appointment vote held in Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "many light years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vanguard Socialist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubudu Jayagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "many light years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pubudu Jayagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Araliya Ganga Mandiara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vanguard Socialist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubudu Jayagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයත් ජනතා මතයත් අතර ආලෝක වර්ෂ ගණනාවක පරතයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිශත සහ එළියේ ජනතා මතය අතර ආලෝක වර්ෂ ගණනාවක පරතයක් ඇති බවත් ලක්‍ෂ 69 ක් ඡන්ද සහ තුනෙන් දෙකක බලයක් තිබූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉවත්කිරීමට ද රටේ ජනතා බලය ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ බවත් පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්‍ෂයේ අධ්‍යාපන ලේකම් පුබුදු ජයගොඩ මහතා අද (20) පස්වරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "ජනත මතය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 225 දෙනාගෙන් නියෝජනය නොවන්නේ යැයි ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත්කිරීමේ ඡන්දයේදී පැහැදිළිව ප්‍රදර්ශනය කළ බව කී පුබුදු ජයගොඩ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් එළියෙ සිටින ලක්‍ෂ 200 කට අධික ජනතාවගේ මතය, දේශපාලන අභිලාශයන්, ප්‍රශ්න සහ දුක්ගැනිවිලි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහජන නියෝජිතයන් හෑලුල්වට ලක්කර ඇති බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රටේ ජනතාවට කාලයක සිටම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පිළිබඳව විශ්වාසයක් නොතිබුණු නිසා ප්‍රශ්න විසඳාගැනීමට අරලිය ගඟ මන්දියර අසළට යෑමට සිදුවූ බවත් ‘බලය ජනතාව අතට’ යන සටන් පාඨ අද වන විට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තහවුරු කර ඇති බවත් ජයගොඩ මහතා කීය.",
        "පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්‍ෂයේ අධ්‍යාපන ලේකම් පුබුදු ජයගොඩ මහතා, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවැති ජනාධිපති පත්කිරීමේ ඡන්දය පිළිබඳව අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහා කොළඹදී අද පැවැත්වූ විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී එසේ පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බොහෝ ආලෝක වර්ෂ",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුබුදු ජයගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොහෝ ආලෝක වර්ෂ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුබුදු ජයගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලිය ගංගා මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුබුදු ජයගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் வாக்குக்கும் மக்களின் கருத்துக்கும் இடையே பல ஒளி ஆண்டுகள் இடைவெளி உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கு சதவீதத்திற்கும் வெளியில் உள்ள மக்களின் கருத்துக்கும் இடையில் பல ஒளி வருட இடைவெளி இருப்பதாகவும், நாட்டின் மக்கள் சக்தி என்பது இன்று (20) பிற்பகல் வான்கார்ட் சோசலிச கட்சியின் கல்விச் செயலாளர் திரு.புபுது ஜயகொட தெரிவித்தார். 69 இலட்சம் வாக்குகளையும் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு அதிகாரத்தையும் பெற்றிருந்த கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "225 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் மக்களின் கருத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தவில்லை என்பது ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் தெளிவாக நிரூபணமாகியுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த திரு.புபுது ஜயகொட, நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகள் கருத்து, அரசியல் அபிலாஷைகளை சிறுமைப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டார். பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வெளியே 200 லட்சத்திற்கும் மேற்பட்ட மக்களின் கேள்விகள் மற்றும் குறைகள்.",
        "நீண்ட காலமாக நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மீது நம்பிக்கை இல்லாததால், பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க அராலிய கங்கை மன்றத்திற்கு செல்ல வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், 'அதிகாரம் மக்கள் கையில்' என்ற கோசங்களை எழுப்பியதாகவும் ஜயகொட தெரிவித்தார். இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதி நியமன வாக்கெடுப்பு தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில் கொழும்பில் இன்று நடைபெற்ற விசேட செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் வான்கார்ட் சோசலிச கட்சியின் கல்வி செயலாளர் திரு.புபுது ஜயகொட இதனை தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பல ஒளி ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வான்கார்ட் சோசலிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புபுது ஜயகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல ஒளி ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புபுது ஜயகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரலிய கங்கா மந்திரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வான்கார்ட் சோசலிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புபுது ஜயகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}