{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/main_picture/අලුත්-සභාවට-පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ--ලක-ලෑස්තිය/11-617464",
  "time_ut": 1659436081,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අලුත් සභාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ  ලක ලෑස්තිය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The preparation of the Parliament for the new assembly",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A rehearsal for the ceremonial opening of the third session of the Ninth Parliament was held today at the Parliament complex.",
        "Officers of the armed forces and police, students of Colombo Devi Girls' College and others were present.",
        "Mr. Narendra Fernando, Sergeant-at-Arms of the Parliament, said that arrangements have been made to hold the President's visit to the Parliament as a formal ceremony and accordingly there will be no salutes and motorcades."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Devi Girls'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Narendra Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අලුත් සභාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ  ලක ලෑස්තිය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තෙවැනි සභාවාරය උත්සවාකාරයෙන් විවෘත කිරීමේ පෙරහුරුවක් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේ දී අද පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවේ සහ පොලිසියේ නිලධාරීහු, කොළඹ දේවි බාලිකා විද්‍යාලයේ සිසුවියෝ ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ඊට එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "ජනාධිපති පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීම චාම් උත්සවයක් ලෙස පැවැත්වීමට කටයුතු යොදා ඇති බවත් ඒ අනුව ආචාර වෙඩි මුර සහ රථ පෙළපාලි නොපැවැත්වෙන බවත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වේත්‍රධාරී නරේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දේවි බාලිකා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய சட்டசபைக்கான நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் தயாரிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றாவது அமர்வை சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக திறப்பதற்கான ஒத்திகை இன்று பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "ஆயுதப்படை மற்றும் காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகள், கொழும்பு தேவி மகளிர் கல்லூரி மாணவிகள் மற்றும் பலர் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் பாராளுமன்ற விஜயத்தை சம்பிரதாயமான வைபவமாக நடத்துவதற்கு ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அதற்கிணங்க வணக்கங்கள் மற்றும் வாகன அணிவகுப்புக்கள் இடம்பெறாது எனவும் பாராளுமன்ற சார்ஜன்ட் திரு நரேந்திர பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேவி பெண்கள்'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}