{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Torrential-rains-affect-6-districts/56-739368",
  "time_ut": 1662074762,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Torrential rains affect 6 districts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Torrential rains affect 6 districts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Disaster Management Centre yesterday said a total of six districts in five provinces were affected by heavy rains, while 222 people from 55 families were impacted by the torrential rains prevailing over Sri Lanka.",
        "It warned that the low-level atmospheric disturbance persists in the vicinity of Sri Lanka.",
        "An advisory on heavy rains was also issued to the Western, Sabaragamuwa, Central, Northwestern, and Northern provinces and in Anuradhapura, Galle, and Matara districts.",
        "It also warned of possible heavy showers of around 100 mm at some places in Western, Sabaragamuwa, Northwestern, and Northern provinces.",
        "As per the latest situational update, Sabaragamuwa province was most affected by the heavy showers as 28 families and 109 people were affected, followed by UVA province where 14 families and 70 people were affected, and North Central province where 10 families and 32 people were affected. Eastern and Northwestern provinces were also affected by adverse weather conditions.",
        "The DMC called on the public to take adequate precautions to minimise damages caused by",
        "It also said water levels of Kalu and Kuda rivers in Ratnapura as well as the Gin river in Baddegama due to heavy showers have been rising and thus alerts were issued. DMC cautioned that the water levels of rivers can increase at short notice owing to heavy rains.",
        "The Irrigation Department also warned of possible flooding in low-lying areas along the banks of the Kalu, Gin, and Nilwala rivers due to the inclement weather experienced countrywide.",
        "Separately, the National Building Research Organisation issued landslide warnings for eight districts including; Colombo, Kalutara, Kandy, Matale, Nuwara Eliya, Galle, Kegalle, and Ratnapura.",
        "NBRO issued a red alert which stands for ‘evacuation’ for people in Kuruwita, Elapatha, and Ratnapura Divisional Secretariats, whilst amber warnings were issued to Galle, Katutara, Kegalle, and yellow alerts were issued for Colombo, Kandy, Matale, and Nuwara Eliya."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Disaster Management Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "222",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northwestern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northwestern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "109",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UVA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northwestern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Baddegama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Irrigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Building Research Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara, Kandy, Matale, Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NBRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuruwita",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Elapatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura Divisional Secretariats",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධාරානිපාත වර්ෂාව දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 6කට බලපානවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අධික වර්ෂාවෙන් පළාත් පහක දිස්ත්‍රික්ක හයක් පීඩාවට පත්ව ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා පවතින ධාරානිපාත වර්ෂාවෙන් පවුල් 55 ක පුද්ගලයින් 222 ක් පීඩාවට පත්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආශ්‍රිතව පහළ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹිලි තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් පවතින බවට අනතුරු අඟවා තිබේ.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, වයඹ සහ උතුරු පළාත්වලටත් අනුරාධපුර, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලටත් තද වැසි පිළිබඳ අවවාදාත්මක නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව, වයඹ සහ උතුරු පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100ක පමණ තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බවටද අනතුරු අඟවා තිබේ.",
        "නවතම තත්ව යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම්වලට අනුව, අධික වර්ෂාපතනයෙන් සබරගමුව පළාතේ පවුල් 28 ක් සහ පුද්ගලයින් 109 ක් පීඩාවට පත්ව ඇති අතර, ඉන් පසුව UVA පළාතෙන් පවුල් 14 ක් සහ පුද්ගලයින් 70 ක් විපතට පත් වූ අතර, උතුරු මැද පළාතෙන් පවුල් 10 ක් සහ පුද්ගලයින් 32 ක් පීඩාවට පත්ව ඇත. . නැගෙනහිර සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලට ද අයහපත් කාලගුණයෙන් බලපෑම් එල්ල විය.",
        "නිසා සිදුවන හානි අවම කර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පූර්වාරක්ෂාවන් ගන්නා ලෙස ඩීඑම්සී මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය",
        "අධික වර්ෂාවත් සමඟ රත්නපුර ප්‍රදේශයේ කළු සහ කුඩා ගංගාවල මෙන්ම බද්දේගම ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ගිං ගඟේ ජල මට්ටම් ඉහළ යමින් පවතින බැවින් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කර ඇති බව ද එහි සඳහන්. අධික වර්ෂාව හේතුවෙන් ගංගාවල ජල මට්ටම කෙටි දැනුම්දීමකින් ඉහළ යා හැකි බව DMC අනතුරු අඟවයි.",
        "දිවයින පුරා පවතින අයහපත් කාලගුණය හේතුවෙන් කළු, ගිං සහ නිල්වලා ගං ඉවුර ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම් ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇති විය හැකි බවට වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අනතුරු අඟවයි.",
        "ජාතික ගොඩනැගිලි පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය විසින් දිස්ත්‍රික්ක අටක් සඳහා වෙනම නායයෑම් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කර ඇත. කොළඹ, කළුතර, මහනුවර, මාතලේ, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල, කෑගල්ල සහ රත්නපුර.",
        "NBRO විසින් කුරුවිට, ඇලපාත සහ රත්නපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශවල ජනතාව සඳහා 'ඉවත් කිරීම' සඳහා රතු අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කළ අතර, ගාල්ල, කටුතර, ​​කෑගල්ල සඳහා ඇම්බර් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කර ඇති අතර කොළඹ, මහනුවර, මාතලේ සහ නුවරඑළිය සඳහා කහ නිවේදන නිකුත් කර ඇත. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආපදා කළමනාකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "222",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "109",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බද්දේගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිල්වලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගොඩනැගිලි පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර, මහනුවර, මාතලේ, නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NBRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුවිට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇලපාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தொடர் மழையால் 6 மாவட்டங்கள் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் பெய்துவரும் அடைமழையினால் 55 குடும்பங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 222 பேர் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதேவேளை ஐந்து மாகாணங்களில் உள்ள ஆறு மாவட்டங்கள் கடும் மழையினால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அனர்த்த முகாமைத்துவ நிலையம் நேற்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையை அண்மித்த பகுதிகளில் குறைந்த வளிமண்டல குழப்பம் நீடிப்பதாக அது எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமேற்கு, மற்றும் வடக்கு மாகாணங்களிலும் அனுராதபுரம், காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அதிக மழை பெய்யும் என அறிவுறுத்தல் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, வடமேற்கு மற்றும் வடக்கு மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் சுமார் 100 மில்லிமீற்றர் அளவில் பலத்த மழை பெய்யக் கூடும் எனவும் எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சமீபத்திய நிலவரப்படி, கனமழையால் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்தில் 28 குடும்பங்கள் மற்றும் 109 பேர் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், அதைத் தொடர்ந்து UVA மாகாணத்தில் 14 குடும்பங்கள் மற்றும் 70 பேர் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், மற்றும் வட மத்திய மாகாணத்தில் 10 குடும்பங்கள் மற்றும் 32 பேர் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். . கிழக்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களும் சீரற்ற காலநிலையால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "அதனால் ஏற்படும் சேதங்களைக் குறைக்க போதுமான முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்களுக்கு DMC அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
        "கனமழை காரணமாக இரத்தினபுரியில் உள்ள களு மற்றும் குடா ஆறுகளின் நீர் மட்டம் மற்றும் பத்தேகமவில் உள்ள ஜின் நதியின் நீர்மட்டம் அதிகரித்து வருவதாகவும் இதனால் எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அது கூறியுள்ளது. கனமழை காரணமாக குறுகிய காலத்தில் ஆறுகளின் நீர்மட்டம் உயரக்கூடும் என்று டிஎம்சி எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் நிலவும் சீரற்ற காலநிலை காரணமாக களு, ஜின் மற்றும் நில்வலா ஆற்றின் கரையோரங்களில் உள்ள தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்படக்கூடும் எனவும் நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம் எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "தனித்தனியாக, தேசிய கட்டிட ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம், எட்டு மாவட்டங்களுக்கு நிலச்சரிவு எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது; கொழும்பு, களுத்துறை, கண்டி, மாத்தளை, நுவரெலியா, காலி, கேகாலை மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி.",
        "NBRO ஆனது குருவிட்ட, எலபாத மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி பிரதேச செயலகங்களில் உள்ள மக்களுக்கு 'வெளியேறுதல்' என்ற சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில் காலி, கட்டுத்துறை, கேகாலை ஆகிய பகுதிகளுக்கு அம்பர் எச்சரிக்கையும், கொழும்பு, கண்டி, மாத்தளை மற்றும் நுவரெலியா ஆகிய பகுதிகளுக்கு மஞ்சள் எச்சரிக்கையும் வெளியிடப்பட்டது. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "222",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "109",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UVA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தேகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில்வாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கட்டிட ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை, கண்டி, மாத்தளை, நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NBRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருவிட்ட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலபத",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி பிரதேச செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுதர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}