{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/U-S-donates-3000MT-of-food-to-feed-Sri-Lankan-school-children/342-243852",
  "time_ut": 1661573471,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "U.S donates 3000MT of food to feed Sri Lankan school children",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "U.S donates 3000MT of food to feed Sri Lankan school children",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United States, through the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) and in partnership with Save the Children, donated 320 tonnes of split yellow peas to nourish school children across Sri Lanka, a statement from the US embassy said.",
        "The donation is part of a larger one of 3,000 tonnes of food. U.S. Ambassador Julie Chung, Dr Susil Premajayantha, Minister of Education, and representatives from the Ministry of Health, the National Planning Department, and Save the Children attended the handover ceremony.",
        "“This donation from the American people targets the most vulnerable Sri Lankans – children – and enables them to focus on their schooling rather than on their hunger. Every nourishing meal will be a testament to the U.S.’S commitment to helping all Sri Lankans emerge from the worst economic crisis since the country’s independence,” said Ambassador Julie Chung.",
        "The shipment is part of the USDA Mcgovern-dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition Programme, a five-year $26 million project aimed at providing immediate emergency assistance to the food insecure to improve literacy and attendance by reducing hunger. The USDA and its partner Save the Children work with the Sri Lankan government and local communities to ensure food reaches those most in need."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "U.S",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Save the Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Planning Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Save the Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Food for Education and Child Nutrition Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$26 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "USDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Save the Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් දරුවන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ආහාර මෙ.ටොන් 3000ක් පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය, එක්සත් ජනපද කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (USDA) හරහා සහ Save the Children සමඟ එක්ව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා පාසල් ළමුන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා බෙදුණු කහ කඩල ටොන් 320 ක් පරිත්‍යාග කළ බව එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශයක් පවසයි.",
        "මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය ආහාර ටොන් 3,000 න් විශාල එකක කොටසකි. එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග්, අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය, ජාතික සැලසුම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්‍රන් යන ආයතනවල නියෝජිතයින් පිරිසක් මෙම භාරදීමේ උත්සවයට සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "“ඇමරිකානු ජනතාවගේ මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය වඩාත් අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් - ළමයින් - ඉලක්ක කර ගන්නා අතර ඔවුන්ගේ කුසගින්න කෙරෙහි වඩා ඔවුන්ගේ පාසල් අධ්‍යාපනය කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කිරීමට ඔවුන්ට හැකි වේ. සෑම පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර වේලක්ම, රට නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට උපකාර කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදයේ කැපවීම පිළිබඳ සාක්ෂියක් වනු ඇත, ”තානාපති ජුලී චුන්ග් පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම නැව්ගත කිරීම USDA Mcgovern-dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition වැඩසටහනේ කොටසක් වන අතර, කුසගින්න අඩු කිරීම මගින් සාක්ෂරතාවය සහ පැමිණීම වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත ආහාර සඳහා ක්ෂණික හදිසි ආධාර සැපයීම අරමුණු කරගත් පස් අවුරුදු ඩොලර් මිලියන 26 ක ව්‍යාපෘතියකි. USDA සහ එහි හවුල්කරු සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්රන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවන් සමඟ ආහාර අවශ්‍යතා ඇති අයට ළඟාවීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා කටයුතු කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරුවන් සුරකින්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සැලසුම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරුවන් සුරකින්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්‍යාපනය සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර ආහාර සහ ළමා පෝෂණ වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස් අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 26 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "USDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දරුවන් සුරකින්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு உணவளிக்க 3000MT உணவுகளை அமெரிக்கா நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்க விவசாயத் திணைக்களம் (யுஎஸ்டிஏ) மற்றும் சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன் உடன் இணைந்து, இலங்கை முழுவதிலும் உள்ள பள்ளிக் குழந்தைகளை வளர்ப்பதற்காக 320 டன் மஞ்சள் பட்டாணியை அமெரிக்கா நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியதாக அமெரிக்க தூதரகத்தின் அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நன்கொடையானது 3,000 டன் உணவில் ஒரு பெரிய பகுதியாகும். அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங், கல்வி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சு, தேசிய திட்டமிடல் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன் ஆகியவற்றின் பிரதிநிதிகள் கையளிக்கும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்க மக்களின் இந்த நன்கொடையானது மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய இலங்கையர்களை - குழந்தைகளை - குறிவைக்கிறது மற்றும் அவர்களின் பசியைக் காட்டிலும் அவர்களின் பள்ளிப் படிப்பில் கவனம் செலுத்த அவர்களுக்கு உதவுகிறது. ஒவ்வொரு ஊட்டமளிக்கும் உணவும், நாட்டின் சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீண்டு வருவதற்கு அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களுக்கும் உதவுவதற்கான அமெரிக்காவின் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கு சான்றாக இருக்கும்” என தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த ஏற்றுமதி USDA Mcgovern-dole இன் இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஃபுட் ஃபார் எஜுகேஷன் அண்ட் சைல்டு நியூட்ரிஷன் திட்டத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும், இது ஐந்தாண்டு $26 மில்லியன் திட்டமாகும், இது உணவு பாதுகாப்பற்ற உணவுக்கு உடனடி அவசர உதவியை வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டது. USDA மற்றும் அதன் பங்காளியான Save the Children இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் உள்ளூர் சமூகங்களுடன் இணைந்து உணவு தேவைப்படுபவர்களை சென்றடைவதை உறுதிசெய்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3000MT",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.எஸ். விவசாயத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய திட்டமிடல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்வி மற்றும் குழந்தை ஊட்டச்சத்துக்கான சர்வதேச உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$26 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "USDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}