{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/WFP-welcomes-Norway-s-support-to-address-rising-food-insecurity-in-SL/56-738551",
  "time_ut": 1660178798,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "WFP welcomes Norway’s support to address rising food insecurity in SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "WFP welcomes Norway’s support to address rising food insecurity in SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The United Nations World Food Programme (WFP) has welcomed a critical contribution of NOK 5 million (approximately Rs. 189 million, or $ 500,000) from the Government of Norway to support Sri Lankans struggling to feed their families.",
        "WFP’s emergency food and nutrition operation aims to assist 3.4 million of the Sri Lankans most at risk of food insecurity and malnutrition amid record food inflation, skyrocketing fuel prices and widespread shortages of essential commodities.",
        "“We are deeply concerned about the impact of the current economic and political crisis on the people of Sri Lanka. The food shortages and increasing prices have a particularly adverse effect on children and women. We consider it an urgent priority to address the immediate food and nutrition needs. Norway is now contributing NOK 5 million (approximately Rs. 189 million) to the efforts of the World Food Programme in assisting the most vulnerable groups in Sri Lanka,” Norwegian Ambassador to Sri Lanka and the Maldives Trine Jøranli Eskedal said.",
        "“We are grateful to the Norwegian Government for this much-needed contribution to WFP’s efforts to assist three million people struggling to meet basic food needs. Acting now helps us to reduce the impact of the crisis on the poorest, most vulnerable Sri Lankans,” WFP in Sri Lanka Representative and Country Director Abdur Rahim Siddiqui said.",
        "WFP is boosting existing social safety net programs to assist one million children through the national school meal program, one million targeted beneficiaries as part of a government program which provides fortified food to mothers and children, and almost one and a half million people in need of emergency food assistance through food, cash, or vouchers.",
        "Nearly 6.3 million people – or 3 in 10 households – are food insecure and in need of assistance. WFP’s recent surveys indicated that 61% of families are resorting to at least one coping mechanism, including eating less, eating less nutritious food, and even skipping meals altogether."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "WFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Norway",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Nations World Food Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NOK 5 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "189 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norway",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norway",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "189 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norwegian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maldives Trine Jøranli Eskedal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Norwegian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Representative",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdur Rahim Siddiqui",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost one and a half million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 6.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ඉහළ යන ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත භාවය විසඳීම සඳහා නෝර්වේ සහාය WFP සාදරයෙන් පිළිගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන (WFP) සිය පවුල් පෝෂණය කිරීමට අරගල කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට ආධාර කිරීම සඳහා නෝර්වේ රජයෙන් NOK මිලියන 5 (ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 189 ක් හෝ ඩොලර් 500,000) ක තීරණාත්මක දායකත්වයක් පිළිගෙන ඇත.",
        "වාර්තාගත ආහාර උද්ධමනය, අහස උසට නැඟෙන ඉන්ධන මිල සහ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල පුලුල් හිඟය මධ්‍යයේ ආහාර අනාරක්‍ෂිතතාවයේ සහ මන්දපෝෂණයේ අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගෙන් මිලියන 3.4කට සහාය වීම WFP හි හදිසි ආහාර සහ පෝෂණ මෙහෙයුමේ අරමුණයි.",
        "“වර්තමාන ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට ඇති කරන බලපෑම පිළිබඳව අපි දැඩි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිමු. ආහාර හිඟය සහ ඉහළ යන මිල ගණන් ළමයින්ට සහ කාන්තාවන්ට විශේෂයෙන් අහිතකර ලෙස බලපායි. ක්ෂණික ආහාර සහ පෝෂණ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම හදිසි ප්‍රමුඛතාවයක් ලෙස අපි සලකමු. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහනේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් සඳහා නෝර්වේ දැන් NOK මිලියන 5 ක් (ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 189 ක්) දායක වේ, ”ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ මාලදිවයිනේ නෝර්වීජියානු තානාපති ට්‍රයින් ජෙරන්ලි එස්කෙඩල් පැවසීය.",
        "“මූලික ආහාර අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීමට අරගල කරන මිලියන තුනක ජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීමට WFP දරන ප්‍රයත්නයන් සඳහා මෙම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය දායකත්වය සඳහා අපි නෝර්වීජියානු රජයට කෘතඥ වෙනවා. දැන් ක්‍රියා කිරීම දුප්පත්ම, වඩාත්ම අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට අර්බුදයේ බලපෑම අවම කිරීමට අපට උපකාරී වේ,” WFP ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නියෝජිත සහ රටේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ අබ්දුර් රහීම් සිද්ධිකි පැවසීය.",
        "ජාතික පාසල් ආහාර වැඩසටහන හරහා ළමුන් මිලියනයකට, මව්වරුන්ට සහ දරුවන්ට ශක්තිමත් ආහාර සපයන රජයේ වැඩසටහනක කොටසක් ලෙස ඉලක්කගත ප්‍රතිලාභීන් මිලියනයකට සහ අවශ්‍යතා ඇති මිලියන එකහමාරකට ආසන්න පිරිසකට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා WFP දැනට පවතින සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ ජාල වැඩසටහන් ඉහළ නංවයි. ආහාර, මුදල් හෝ වවුචර් හරහා හදිසි ආහාර ආධාර.",
        "මිලියන 6.3 කට ආසන්න ජනතාවක් - හෝ නිවාස 10 කින් 3 ක් - ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත සහ ආධාර අවශ්‍ය වේ. WFP හි මෑත සමීක්ෂණවලින් පෙන්නුම් කළේ පවුල්වලින් 61% ක් අඩු වශයෙන් ආහාර ගැනීම, අඩු පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර අනුභව කිරීම සහ ආහාර වේල් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම අත්හැර දැමීම ඇතුළුව අවම වශයෙන් එක් ක්‍රියාකාරිත්ව යාන්ත්‍රණයකට යොමු වන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "WFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "නෝර්වේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NOK මිලියන 5යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 189 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 189 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වීජියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයිනේ ට්‍රයින් ජුරන්ලි එස්කෙඩල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වීජියානු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන තුනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුර් රහීම් සිද්දිකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන එකහමාරකට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.3කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් එකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் அதிகரித்து வரும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையை நிவர்த்தி செய்ய நார்வேயின் ஆதரவை WFP வரவேற்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் உலக உணவுத் திட்டம் (WFP) நார்வே அரசாங்கத்திடமிருந்து NOK 5 மில்லியன் (தோராயமாக ரூ. 189 மில்லியன் அல்லது $ 500,000) தங்கள் குடும்பங்களுக்கு உணவளிக்க போராடும் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு ஆதரவாக வழங்கப்படுவதை வரவேற்றுள்ளது.",
        "WFP இன் அவசர உணவு மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து நடவடிக்கையானது உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாட்டின் அபாயத்தில் உள்ள இலங்கையர்களில் 3.4 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு உதவுவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "“தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியின் தாக்கம் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு ஏற்படுவது குறித்து நாங்கள் ஆழ்ந்த கவலை கொண்டுள்ளோம். உணவுத் தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் விலைவாசி உயர்வு ஆகியவை குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் பெண்களுக்கு குறிப்பாக மோசமான விளைவுகளை ஏற்படுத்துகின்றன. உடனடி உணவு மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து தேவைகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வது அவசர முன்னுரிமையாக நாங்கள் கருதுகிறோம். இலங்கையில் மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய குழுக்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்கான உலக உணவுத் திட்டத்தின் முயற்சிகளுக்கு நோர்வே இப்போது NOK 5 மில்லியனை (தோராயமாக ரூ. 189 மில்லியன்) வழங்குகிறது,” என்று இலங்கை மற்றும் மாலைதீவுக்கான நோர்வே தூதுவர் ட்ரைன் ஜொரன்லி எஸ்கெடல் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"அடிப்படை உணவுத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்யப் போராடும் மூன்று மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு உதவ WFP இன் முயற்சிகளுக்கு மிகவும் தேவையான பங்களிப்புக்காக நோர்வே அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நாங்கள் நன்றியுள்ளவர்களாக இருக்கிறோம். தற்போது செயற்படுவது மிகவும் வறிய, மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய இலங்கையர்களுக்கு நெருக்கடியின் தாக்கத்தை குறைக்க உதவுகிறது,” என இலங்கைக்கான WFP பிரதிநிதியும் நாட்டின் பணிப்பாளருமான அப்துர் ரஹீம் சித்திக் கூறினார்.",
        "தேசிய பள்ளி உணவுத் திட்டத்தின் மூலம் ஒரு மில்லியன் குழந்தைகளுக்கு உதவ, தாய்மார்கள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகளுக்கு வலுவூட்டப்பட்ட உணவை வழங்கும் அரசாங்க திட்டத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாக ஒரு மில்லியன் இலக்கு பயனாளிகள் மற்றும் கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒன்றரை மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்காக WFP தற்போதுள்ள சமூக பாதுகாப்பு வலைத் திட்டங்களை மேம்படுத்துகிறது. உணவு, பணம் அல்லது வவுச்சர்கள் மூலம் அவசர உணவு உதவி.",
        "கிட்டத்தட்ட 6.3 மில்லியன் மக்கள் - அல்லது 10 குடும்பங்களில் 3 பேர் - உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பற்றவர்கள் மற்றும் உதவி தேவைப்படுகிறார்கள். WFP இன் சமீபத்திய ஆய்வுகள், 61% குடும்பங்கள் குறைந்தபட்சம் ஒரு சமாளிப்பு பொறிமுறையை நாடுகின்றன, இதில் குறைவாக சாப்பிடுவது, குறைவான சத்தான உணவை உண்பது மற்றும் உணவை முற்றிலுமாக தவிர்ப்பது ஆகியவை அடங்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "WFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நார்வே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NOK 5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "189 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "189 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வேஜியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள் ட்ரைன் ஜோரான்லி எஸ்கெடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோர்வே அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைப் பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துர் ரஹீம் சித்திக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒன்றரை மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 6.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்த பட்சம் ஓன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}