{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/dilshan-wirasekara-appointed-cse-chairman/",
  "time_ut": 1655992500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dilshan Wirasekara appointed CSE chairman",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dilshan Wirasekara appointed CSE chairman",
      "author": "Dilshan Nadeera",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) is announces the appointment of Dilshan Wirasekara as the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the CSE with effect from 24th June 2022. Wirasekara has served on the Board of the CSE since 21st November 2017 and succeeds Dumith Fernando, who steps down as the Chairman after completing his two-year tenure.",
        "Wirasekara is the Director/Chief Executive Officer of one of the leading investment banking firms, First Capital Holdings PLC, offering a diverse range of financial services in Government Securities, Corporate Finance and Advisory, Asset Management and Stock Brokering, which he has been part of since 2013.",
        "He currently is the chairman of the Investment Subcommittee of the CSE and also serves on the Risk and Audit Committee of the CSE as well as the CSE/SEC joint committees on Digitalization and the Central Counter Party System (CCP).",
        "An Investment banker by profession with a career spanning over 26 years, comprising diversified expertise in financial services, including banking, treasury and investment management, capital market strategy, and corporate finance advisory services. Wirasekara specializes in Asset and Liability Risk Management, having secured the accolade of leading and representing two Sri Lankan companies in winning the International Bank Asset and Liability competition organized annually by the Netherlands Development Finance Company (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG), and Proparco – a subsidiary of the Agence Française de Development (AFD).",
        "Wirasekara is an alumnus of INSEAD, having completed his Executive Professional Education at INSEAD Business School in Fontainebleau, France. He is also an alumnus of AOTS, Tokyo, Japan.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dilshan Wirasekara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilshan Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of the CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st November 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dumith Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "First Capital Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government Securities",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advisory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asset Management and Stock Brokering",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Investment Subcommittee of the CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Risk and Audit Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Counter Party System",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liability Risk Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Bank Asset",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liability",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Netherlands Development Finance Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "German Investment Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DEG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Proparco",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Agence Française de Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive Professional Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD Business School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fontainebleau",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AOTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CSE සභාපති ලෙස ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර පත් කරයි",
      "author": "ඩිල්ෂාන් නදීර",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ජූනි 24 දින සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි CSE හි අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර පත් කළ බව Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) නිවේදනය කරයි. Wirasekara 2017 නොවැම්බර් 21 වන දින සිට CSE අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ සේවය කර ඇති අතර දුමිත් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතාගෙන් පසුව පත් වේ. දෙවසරක ධුර කාලය නිමවීමෙන් පසු සභාපති ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වන.",
        "විරසේකර යනු ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ආයෝජන බැංකු සමාගමක් වන First Capital Holdings PLC හි අධ්‍යක්ෂ/ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරියා වන අතර, ඔහු කොටස්කරුවෙකු වී ඇති රජයේ සුරැකුම්පත්, ආයතනික මුල්‍ය සහ උපදේශන, වත්කම් කළමනාකරණය සහ කොටස් තැරැව්කාර සේවාවන්හි විවිධ වූ මූල්‍ය සේවා සපයයි. 2013 සිට.",
        "ඔහු දැනට CSE හි ආයෝජන අනුකමිටුවේ සභාපතිවරයා වන අතර CSE හි අවදානම් සහ විගණන කමිටුවේ මෙන්ම CSE/SEC ඩිජිටල්කරණය සහ මධ්‍යම ප්‍රති පක්ෂ පද්ධතිය (CCP) පිළිබඳ ඒකාබද්ධ කමිටුවලද සේවය කරයි.",
        "බැංකුකරණය, භාණ්ඩාගාර සහ ආයෝජන කළමනාකරණය, ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ උපාය මාර්ග සහ ආයතනික මූල්‍ය උපදේශන සේවා ඇතුළු මූල්‍ය සේවා පිළිබඳ විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ විශේෂඥතාවන්ගෙන් සමන්විත, වසර 26කට වැඩි වෘත්තීය ජීවිතයක් සහිත වෘත්තියෙන් ආයෝජන බැංකුකරුවෙකු වේ. නෙදර්ලන්ත සංවර්ධන මූල්‍ය සමාගම (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG) විසින් වාර්ෂිකව සංවිධානය කරනු ලබන ජාත්‍යන්තර බැංකු වත්කම් සහ වගකීම් තරගයේ ජයග්‍රහණය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සමාගම් දෙකක් නියෝජනය කරමින් ප්‍රමුඛයා සහ ප්‍රමුඛයා වීමේ සම්මානය හිමිකරගත් විරසේකර වත්කම් සහ වගකීම් අවදානම් කළමනාකරණය පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥයෙකි. Proparco - Agence Française de Development (AFD) හි අනුබද්ධිත ආයතනයකි.",
        "විරසේකර INSEAD හි ආදි සිසුවෙකි, ප්‍රංශයේ Fontainebleau හි INSEAD ව්‍යාපාරික පාසලේ විධායක වෘත්තීය අධ්‍යාපනය සම්පූර්ණ කර ඇත. ඔහු ජපානයේ ටෝකියෝ හි AOTS හි ආදි සිසුවෙකි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජුනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 නොවැම්බර් 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමිත් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු කැපිටල් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ සුරැකුම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්කම් කළමනාකරණය සහ කොටස් තැරැව්කරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE හි ආයෝජන අනුකමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවදානම් සහ විගණන කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම ප්‍රති පක්ෂ පද්ධතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගකීම් අවදානම් කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර බැංකු වත්කම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගකීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්ත සංවර්ධන මූල්‍ය සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මානු ආයෝජන සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DEG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Proparco",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිතායතනය Française de Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක වෘත්තීය අධ්‍යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD ව්‍යාපාරික පාසල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆොන්ටයින්බ්ලූ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AOTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டில்ஷான் வீரசேகர CSE தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தில்ஷான் நதீரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "24 ஜூன் 2022 முதல் CSE இன் இயக்குநர்கள் குழுவின் தலைவராக தில்ஷான் விரசேகர நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை (CSE) அறிவிக்கிறது. வைரசேகர 2017 நவம்பர் 21 முதல் CSE வாரியத்தில் பணியாற்றினார் மற்றும் துமித் பெர்னாண்டோவுக்குப் பிறகு பதவியேற்றார். இரண்டு வருட பதவிக் காலத்தை முடித்த பின் தலைவர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுபவர்.",
        "விரசேகர, முன்னணி முதலீட்டு வங்கி நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான ஃபர்ஸ்ட் கேபிடல் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சியின் இயக்குநர்/தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி ஆவார். அரசாங்கப் பத்திரங்கள், கார்ப்பரேட் நிதி மற்றும் ஆலோசனை, சொத்து மேலாண்மை மற்றும் பங்குத் தரகு ஆகியவற்றில் பல்வேறு வகையான நிதிச் சேவைகளை வழங்கி வருகிறார். 2013 முதல்.",
        "அவர் தற்போது CSE இன் முதலீட்டு துணைக்குழுவின் தலைவராக உள்ளார், மேலும் CSE இன் இடர் மற்றும் தணிக்கைக் குழுவிலும், டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கல் மற்றும் மத்திய எதிர் கட்சி அமைப்பு (CCP) தொடர்பான CSE/SEC கூட்டுக் குழுக்களிலும் பணியாற்றுகிறார்.",
        "வங்கியியல், கருவூலம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு மேலாண்மை, மூலதனச் சந்தை உத்தி மற்றும் பெருநிறுவன நிதி ஆலோசனை சேவைகள் உள்ளிட்ட நிதிச் சேவைகளில் பல்வகைப்பட்ட நிபுணத்துவத்தை உள்ளடக்கிய, 26 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான தொழில் வாழ்க்கையைக் கொண்ட ஒரு முதலீட்டு வங்கியாளர். Netherlands Development Finance Company (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG) மற்றும் வருடாந்தம் நடத்தப்படும் சர்வதேச வங்கி சொத்து மற்றும் பொறுப்பு போட்டியில் வெற்றி பெறுவதில் இரண்டு இலங்கை நிறுவனங்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி முன்னணி மற்றும் பிரதிநிதித்துவம் செய்ததன் மூலம், சொத்து மற்றும் பொறுப்பு இடர் முகாமைத்துவத்தில் விராசேகர நிபுணத்துவம் பெற்றவர். Proparco - ஏஜென்ஸ் Française de Development (AFD) இன் துணை நிறுவனம்.",
        "வைரசேகர INSEAD இன் பழைய மாணவர் ஆவார், பிரான்சின் Fontainebleau இல் உள்ள INSEAD வணிகப் பள்ளியில் தனது நிர்வாக நிபுணத்துவக் கல்வியை முடித்துள்ளார். அவர் ஜப்பானின் டோக்கியோவில் உள்ள AOTS இன் முன்னாள் மாணவர் ஆவார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர்*",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டில்ஷான் விரசேகர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டில்ஷான் விரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 நவம்பர் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமித் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபர்ஸ்ட் கேபிடல் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசு பத்திரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சொத்து மேலாண்மை மற்றும் பங்கு தரகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE இன் முதலீட்டு துணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடர் மற்றும் தணிக்கை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய எதிர் கட்சி அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொறுப்பு இடர் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வங்கி சொத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொறுப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து மேம்பாட்டு நிதி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மன் முதலீட்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DEG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ராபர்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜென்ஸ் ஃபிரான்சைஸ் டி டெவலப்மென்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாக நிபுணத்துவ கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD வணிகப் பள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபோன்டைன்ப்ளூ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஓடிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Dilshan Wirasekara appointed CSE chairman",
  "body_lines": [
    "The Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) is announces the appointment of Dilshan Wirasekara as the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the CSE with effect from 24th June 2022. Wirasekara has served on the Board of the CSE since 21st November 2017 and succeeds Dumith Fernando, who steps down as the Chairman after completing his two-year tenure.",
    "Wirasekara is the Director/Chief Executive Officer of one of the leading investment banking firms, First Capital Holdings PLC, offering a diverse range of financial services in Government Securities, Corporate Finance and Advisory, Asset Management and Stock Brokering, which he has been part of since 2013.",
    "He currently is the chairman of the Investment Subcommittee of the CSE and also serves on the Risk and Audit Committee of the CSE as well as the CSE/SEC joint committees on Digitalization and the Central Counter Party System (CCP).",
    "An Investment banker by profession with a career spanning over 26 years, comprising diversified expertise in financial services, including banking, treasury and investment management, capital market strategy, and corporate finance advisory services. Wirasekara specializes in Asset and Liability Risk Management, having secured the accolade of leading and representing two Sri Lankan companies in winning the International Bank Asset and Liability competition organized annually by the Netherlands Development Finance Company (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG), and Proparco – a subsidiary of the Agence Française de Development (AFD).",
    "Wirasekara is an alumnus of INSEAD, having completed his Executive Professional Education at INSEAD Business School in Fontainebleau, France. He is also an alumnus of AOTS, Tokyo, Japan.",
    "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
    "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dilshan Wirasekara appointed CSE chairman",
      "author": "Dilshan Nadeera",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) is announces the appointment of Dilshan Wirasekara as the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the CSE with effect from 24th June 2022. Wirasekara has served on the Board of the CSE since 21st November 2017 and succeeds Dumith Fernando, who steps down as the Chairman after completing his two-year tenure.",
        "Wirasekara is the Director/Chief Executive Officer of one of the leading investment banking firms, First Capital Holdings PLC, offering a diverse range of financial services in Government Securities, Corporate Finance and Advisory, Asset Management and Stock Brokering, which he has been part of since 2013.",
        "He currently is the chairman of the Investment Subcommittee of the CSE and also serves on the Risk and Audit Committee of the CSE as well as the CSE/SEC joint committees on Digitalization and the Central Counter Party System (CCP).",
        "An Investment banker by profession with a career spanning over 26 years, comprising diversified expertise in financial services, including banking, treasury and investment management, capital market strategy, and corporate finance advisory services. Wirasekara specializes in Asset and Liability Risk Management, having secured the accolade of leading and representing two Sri Lankan companies in winning the International Bank Asset and Liability competition organized annually by the Netherlands Development Finance Company (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG), and Proparco – a subsidiary of the Agence Française de Development (AFD).",
        "Wirasekara is an alumnus of INSEAD, having completed his Executive Professional Education at INSEAD Business School in Fontainebleau, France. He is also an alumnus of AOTS, Tokyo, Japan.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dilshan Wirasekara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilshan Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of the CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st November 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dumith Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "First Capital Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government Securities",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advisory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asset Management and Stock Brokering",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Investment Subcommittee of the CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Risk and Audit Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Counter Party System",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liability Risk Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Bank Asset",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liability",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Netherlands Development Finance Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "German Investment Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DEG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Proparco",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Agence Française de Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wirasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive Professional Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD Business School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fontainebleau",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AOTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CSE සභාපති ලෙස ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර පත් කරයි",
      "author": "ඩිල්ෂාන් නදීර",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ජූනි 24 දින සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි CSE හි අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර පත් කළ බව Colombo Stock Exchange (CSE) නිවේදනය කරයි. Wirasekara 2017 නොවැම්බර් 21 වන දින සිට CSE අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලයේ සේවය කර ඇති අතර දුමිත් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතාගෙන් පසුව පත් වේ. දෙවසරක ධුර කාලය නිමවීමෙන් පසු සභාපති ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වන.",
        "විරසේකර යනු ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ආයෝජන බැංකු සමාගමක් වන First Capital Holdings PLC හි අධ්‍යක්ෂ/ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරියා වන අතර, ඔහු කොටස්කරුවෙකු වී ඇති රජයේ සුරැකුම්පත්, ආයතනික මුල්‍ය සහ උපදේශන, වත්කම් කළමනාකරණය සහ කොටස් තැරැව්කාර සේවාවන්හි විවිධ වූ මූල්‍ය සේවා සපයයි. 2013 සිට.",
        "ඔහු දැනට CSE හි ආයෝජන අනුකමිටුවේ සභාපතිවරයා වන අතර CSE හි අවදානම් සහ විගණන කමිටුවේ මෙන්ම CSE/SEC ඩිජිටල්කරණය සහ මධ්‍යම ප්‍රති පක්ෂ පද්ධතිය (CCP) පිළිබඳ ඒකාබද්ධ කමිටුවලද සේවය කරයි.",
        "බැංකුකරණය, භාණ්ඩාගාර සහ ආයෝජන කළමනාකරණය, ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ උපාය මාර්ග සහ ආයතනික මූල්‍ය උපදේශන සේවා ඇතුළු මූල්‍ය සේවා පිළිබඳ විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ විශේෂඥතාවන්ගෙන් සමන්විත, වසර 26කට වැඩි වෘත්තීය ජීවිතයක් සහිත වෘත්තියෙන් ආයෝජන බැංකුකරුවෙකු වේ. නෙදර්ලන්ත සංවර්ධන මූල්‍ය සමාගම (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG) විසින් වාර්ෂිකව සංවිධානය කරනු ලබන ජාත්‍යන්තර බැංකු වත්කම් සහ වගකීම් තරගයේ ජයග්‍රහණය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සමාගම් දෙකක් නියෝජනය කරමින් ප්‍රමුඛයා සහ ප්‍රමුඛයා වීමේ සම්මානය හිමිකරගත් විරසේකර වත්කම් සහ වගකීම් අවදානම් කළමනාකරණය පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥයෙකි. Proparco - Agence Française de Development (AFD) හි අනුබද්ධිත ආයතනයකි.",
        "විරසේකර INSEAD හි ආදි සිසුවෙකි, ප්‍රංශයේ Fontainebleau හි INSEAD ව්‍යාපාරික පාසලේ විධායක වෘත්තීය අධ්‍යාපනය සම්පූර්ණ කර ඇත. ඔහු ජපානයේ ටෝකියෝ හි AOTS හි ආදි සිසුවෙකි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිල්ෂාන් විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජුනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 නොවැම්බර් 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමිත් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු කැපිටල් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ සුරැකුම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්කම් කළමනාකරණය සහ කොටස් තැරැව්කරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE හි ආයෝජන අනුකමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවදානම් සහ විගණන කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම ප්‍රති පක්ෂ පද්ධතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගකීම් අවදානම් කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර බැංකු වත්කම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වගකීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්ත සංවර්ධන මූල්‍ය සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මානු ආයෝජන සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DEG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Proparco",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝජිතායතනය Française de Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක වෘත්තීය අධ්‍යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD ව්‍යාපාරික පාසල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆොන්ටයින්බ්ලූ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AOTS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டில்ஷான் வீரசேகர CSE தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தில்ஷான் நதீரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "24 ஜூன் 2022 முதல் CSE இன் இயக்குநர்கள் குழுவின் தலைவராக தில்ஷான் விரசேகர நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை (CSE) அறிவிக்கிறது. வைரசேகர 2017 நவம்பர் 21 முதல் CSE வாரியத்தில் பணியாற்றினார் மற்றும் துமித் பெர்னாண்டோவுக்குப் பிறகு பதவியேற்றார். இரண்டு வருட பதவிக் காலத்தை முடித்த பின் தலைவர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுபவர்.",
        "விரசேகர, முன்னணி முதலீட்டு வங்கி நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான ஃபர்ஸ்ட் கேபிடல் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சியின் இயக்குநர்/தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி ஆவார். அரசாங்கப் பத்திரங்கள், கார்ப்பரேட் நிதி மற்றும் ஆலோசனை, சொத்து மேலாண்மை மற்றும் பங்குத் தரகு ஆகியவற்றில் பல்வேறு வகையான நிதிச் சேவைகளை வழங்கி வருகிறார். 2013 முதல்.",
        "அவர் தற்போது CSE இன் முதலீட்டு துணைக்குழுவின் தலைவராக உள்ளார், மேலும் CSE இன் இடர் மற்றும் தணிக்கைக் குழுவிலும், டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கல் மற்றும் மத்திய எதிர் கட்சி அமைப்பு (CCP) தொடர்பான CSE/SEC கூட்டுக் குழுக்களிலும் பணியாற்றுகிறார்.",
        "வங்கியியல், கருவூலம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு மேலாண்மை, மூலதனச் சந்தை உத்தி மற்றும் பெருநிறுவன நிதி ஆலோசனை சேவைகள் உள்ளிட்ட நிதிச் சேவைகளில் பல்வகைப்பட்ட நிபுணத்துவத்தை உள்ளடக்கிய, 26 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான தொழில் வாழ்க்கையைக் கொண்ட ஒரு முதலீட்டு வங்கியாளர். Netherlands Development Finance Company (FMO), German Investment Corporation (DEG) மற்றும் வருடாந்தம் நடத்தப்படும் சர்வதேச வங்கி சொத்து மற்றும் பொறுப்பு போட்டியில் வெற்றி பெறுவதில் இரண்டு இலங்கை நிறுவனங்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி முன்னணி மற்றும் பிரதிநிதித்துவம் செய்ததன் மூலம், சொத்து மற்றும் பொறுப்பு இடர் முகாமைத்துவத்தில் விராசேகர நிபுணத்துவம் பெற்றவர். Proparco - ஏஜென்ஸ் Française de Development (AFD) இன் துணை நிறுவனம்.",
        "வைரசேகர INSEAD இன் பழைய மாணவர் ஆவார், பிரான்சின் Fontainebleau இல் உள்ள INSEAD வணிகப் பள்ளியில் தனது நிர்வாக நிபுணத்துவக் கல்வியை முடித்துள்ளார். அவர் ஜப்பானின் டோக்கியோவில் உள்ள AOTS இன் முன்னாள் மாணவர் ஆவார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர்*",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டில்ஷான் விரசேகர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டில்ஷான் விரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 நவம்பர் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமித் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபர்ஸ்ட் கேபிடல் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசு பத்திரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சொத்து மேலாண்மை மற்றும் பங்கு தரகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE இன் முதலீட்டு துணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடர் மற்றும் தணிக்கை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய எதிர் கட்சி அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொறுப்பு இடர் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச வங்கி சொத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொறுப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து மேம்பாட்டு நிதி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மன் முதலீட்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DEG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ராபர்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜென்ஸ் ஃபிரான்சைஸ் டி டெவலப்மென்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாக நிபுணத்துவ கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "INSEAD வணிகப் பள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபோன்டைன்ப்ளூ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஓடிஎஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}