{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Supporting-Effective-Dispute-Resolution-project-completes-phase-1-of-Active-Citizens-program/56-738552",
  "time_ut": 1660178948,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Supporting Effective Dispute Resolution project completes phase 1 of Active Citizens program",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Supporting Effective Dispute Resolution project completes phase 1 of Active Citizens program",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Supporting Effective Dispute Resolution (SEDR) is a four-year access to justice project implemented by the British Council and funded by the European Union as part of its Strengthening Transformation, Reconciliation and Inclusive Democratic Engagement (STRIDE) program in Sri Lanka.",
        "At the heart of SEDR is the desire for peaceful co-existence and a fair and just Sri Lanka. During December 2021-June 2022, SEDR initiated the design and delivery of three tailor-made SEDR Active Citizens programs which had a strong local dispute resolution and social inclusion focus to address community issues and improve the resolution of community disputes. These programs were conducted in each of SEDR’s three target provinces (North, East and Uva), and the first phase was recently concluded successfully.",
        "Active Citizens is a social leadership training methodology that has been successfully delivered by the British Council around the world for over 10 years promoting intercultural dialogue and community-led social development and building trust within and between communities.  The methodology plays an important role in SEDR’s approach to supporting alternative dispute resolution mechanisms in resolving community level disputes.",
        "Together with the support and guidance of CSO partner organisations in each province, the SEDR Active Citizens program worked with participants who went through a five-day training where each day they focused on different aspects of working with a community.",
        "The skills delivered through the training included those on self-awareness of their identity and culture, building confidence and interpersonal relationships, exploring tools and techniques to encourage and facilitate dialogue, problem identification, problem solving, promoting social cohesion and dispute management and leadership.",
        "The SEDR Active Citizens engaged with individuals of diverse interests and skills in a community. They then put these skills into practice through a dedicated community intervention (Social Action Projects), which were designed, managed and implemented within their community with the support of their community from youth volunteers to state and non-state stakeholders. From March to June 2022, the SEDR Active Citizens delivered 15 Social Action Projects which focused on issues and disputes their communities faced, reaching approximately 1,724 beneficiaries.",
        "One of the youth participants from Badalkumbura, of the Monaragala District said, “During the process of my SEDR AC journey, some of the lessons I learned during the workshop was that particularly the conflict tree, forum theatre, as well the role plays are not confined to one single community but applies to all irrespective of which religion or ethnicity they belong to.  When I was about to leave the venue, I made it a point to invite my Tamil roommates to visit our Village. I was equally taken up when these friends wanted me and other Sinhala friends to be their guests at their estates.”",
        "SEDR Team leader Jacques Carstens said: “The British Council’s Active Citizens model has proven to be a very good fit for SEDR’s ambition to strengthen community level dispute resolution efforts in Sri Lanka. It is very encouraging to see how women and youth volunteers have grown and benefitted from the Active Citizens approach and used their new-found knowledge and skills to address some of the root causes of conflict that affect their own local communities.”",
        "Using the Active Citizens model, SEDR aims to further build capacity of local youth and women champions through Phase 2 of the SEDR Active Citizens program and support them to deliver social action projects that are inclusive, contextually relevant and effecting positive change in communities of the Northern, Uva and Eastern Provinces of Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Active Citizens",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the British Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Strengthening Transformation, Reconciliation and Inclusive Democratic Engagement",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 2021-June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR Active Citizens",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "North, East",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the British Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR Active Citizens",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "each day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR Active Citizens",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Social Action Projects",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "March to June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR Active Citizens",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Social Action Projects",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 1,724",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badalkumbura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monaragala District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR AC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Village",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacques Carstens",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The British Council’s Active Citizens",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR Active Citizens",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Provinces of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඵලදායි ආරවුල් විසඳීමේ ව්‍යාපෘතියට සහාය වීම සක්‍රීය පුරවැසි වැඩසටහනේ පළමු අදියර සම්පූර්ණ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සහය දක්වන ඵලදායී ආරවුල් විසඳීම (SEDR) යනු බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කවුන්සිලය විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද යුක්තිය සඳහා වසර හතරක ප්‍රවේශ ව්‍යාපෘතියක් වන අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේ පරිවර්තනය, ප්‍රතිසන්ධානය සහ ඇතුළත් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී බැඳීම් (STRIDE) වැඩසටහනේ කොටසක් ලෙස යුරෝපා සංගමය විසින් අරමුදල් සපයනු ලැබේ.",
        "SEDR හි හදවතෙහි ඇත්තේ සාමකාමී සහජීවනය සහ සාධාරණ සහ සාධාරණ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක් සඳහා වූ ආශාවයි. 2021 දෙසැම්බර් සිට 2022 ජූනි දක්වා කාලය තුළ SEDR විසින් ප්‍රජා ගැටලු විසඳීමට සහ ප්‍රජා ආරවුල් විසඳීම වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට ප්‍රබල දේශීය ආරවුල් විසඳීමක් සහ සමාජ ඇතුළත් කිරීමේ අවධානයක් ඇති පරිදි සකස් කරන ලද SEDR සක්‍රීය පුරවැසි වැඩසටහන් තුනක් සැලසුම් කිරීම සහ බෙදා හැරීම ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. මෙම වැඩසටහන් SEDR හි එක් එක් ඉලක්ක පළාත් තුනෙහි (උතුරු, නැගෙනහිර සහ ඌව) පවත්වන ලද අතර, පළමු අදියර පසුගියදා සාර්ථකව අවසන් විය.",
        "Active Citizens යනු අන්තර් සංස්කෘතික සංවාදය සහ ප්‍රජාව විසින් මෙහෙයවන සමාජ සංවර්ධනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සහ ප්‍රජාවන් තුළ සහ අතර විශ්වාසය ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා වසර 10 කට වැඩි කාලයක් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කවුන්සිලය විසින් ලොව පුරා සාර්ථකව ලබා දෙන සමාජ නායකත්ව පුහුණු ක්‍රමවේදයකි. ප්‍රජා මට්ටමේ ආරවුල් විසඳීමේදී විකල්ප ආරවුල් විසඳීමේ යාන්ත්‍රණයන්ට සහාය වීම සඳහා SEDR හි ප්‍රවේශය තුළ ක්‍රමවේදය වැදගත් කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරයි.",
        "සෑම පළාතකම CSO හවුල්කාර සංවිධානවල සහයෝගය සහ මගපෙන්වීම සමඟින්, SEDR Active Citizens වැඩසටහන දින පහක පුහුණුවක් ලබා ඇති සහභාගිවන්නන් සමඟ වැඩ කළ අතර එහිදී ඔවුන් සෑම දිනකම ප්‍රජාවක් සමඟ වැඩ කිරීමේ විවිධ අංශ කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කළහ.",
        "පුහුණුව තුළින් ලබා දෙන කුසලතා අතරට ඔවුන්ගේ අනන්‍යතාවය සහ සංස්කෘතිය පිළිබඳ ස්වයං දැනුවත්භාවය, විශ්වාසය සහ අන්තර් පුද්ගල සබඳතා ගොඩනැගීම, සංවාදය දිරිමත් කිරීම සහ පහසු කිරීම සඳහා මෙවලම් සහ ශිල්පීය ක්‍රම ගවේෂණය කිරීම, ගැටළු හඳුනා ගැනීම, ගැටළු විසඳීම, සමාජ ඒකාබද්ධතාවය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සහ ආරවුල් කළමනාකරණය සහ නායකත්වය ඇතුළත් විය.",
        "SEDR ක්‍රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන් ප්‍රජාවක විවිධ රුචිකත්වයන් සහ කුසලතා ඇති පුද්ගලයින් සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වේ. තරුණ ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන්ගේ සිට රාජ්‍ය සහ රාජ්‍ය නොවන පාර්ශවකරුවන් දක්වා ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රජාවගේ සහාය ඇතිව ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රජාව තුළ සැලසුම් කර කළමනාකරණය කර ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද කැපවූ ප්‍රජා මැදිහත්වීමක් (සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරී ව්‍යාපෘති) හරහා ඔවුන් මෙම කුසලතා ක්‍රියාවට නංවා ඇත. 2022 මාර්තු සිට ජූනි දක්වා, SEDR ක්‍රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන් විසින් ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රජාවන් මුහුණ දෙන ගැටළු සහ ආරවුල් පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කළ සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරී ව්‍යාපෘති 15ක් ලබා දුන් අතර, එය ප්‍රතිලාභීන් 1,724ක් පමණ වෙත ළඟා විය.",
        "මොණරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ බඩල්කුඹුර ප්‍රදේශයේ තරුණ සහභාගිවන්නෙකු පැවසුවේ, “මගේ SEDR AC ගමනේ ක්‍රියාවලියේදී, වැඩමුළුවේදී මම ඉගෙන ගත් සමහර පාඩම් නම්, විශේෂයෙන් ගැටුම් ගස, සංසද රඟහල මෙන්ම භූමිකා නාට්‍ය නොවේ. එක් ප්‍රජාවකට සීමා වූ නමුත් ඔවුන් කුමන ආගමකට හෝ වාර්ගිකයට අයත් වුවද සියල්ලන්ටම අදාළ වේ. මම එම ස්ථානයෙන් පිටව යාමට සූදානම් වූ විට, මගේ දෙමළ නේවාසික මිතුරන්ට අපේ ගමට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ආරාධනා කිරීම මම පුරුද්දක් කර ගත්තෙමි. මේ මිතුරන්ට මා සහ අනෙකුත් සිංහල මිතුරන් ඔවුන්ගේ වතුවල ඔවුන්ගේ ආගන්තුකයන් වීමට අවශ්‍ය වූ විට මා එකසේ භාර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "SEDR කණ්ඩායමේ නායක Jacques Carstens පැවසුවේ: “British Council හි Active Citizens ආකෘතිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජා මට්ටමේ ආරවුල් විසඳීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේ SEDR හි අභිලාෂය සඳහා ඉතා සුදුසු බව ඔප්පු වී ඇත. ක්‍රියාකාරී පුරවැසි ප්‍රවේශයෙන් කාන්තා සහ තරුණ ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන් වර්ධනය වී ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබාගෙන ඇති ආකාරය සහ ඔවුන්ගේම ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවන්ට බලපාන ගැටුම්වල මූල හේතුන් කිහිපයක් විසඳීමට ඔවුන්ගේ නව දැනුම හා කුසලතා භාවිතා කරන ආකාරය දැකීම ඉතා දිරිගන්වන සුළුය.",
        "සක්‍රීය පුරවැසි ආකෘතිය භාවිතා කරමින්, SEDR සක්‍රීය පුරවැසි වැඩසටහනේ 2 වන අදියර හරහා දේශීය තරුණ හා කාන්තා ශූරයින්ගේ ධාරිතාව තවදුරටත් ගොඩනැගීම සහ උතුරේ ප්‍රජාවන් තුළ අන්තර්ගත, සන්දර්භානුකූලව අදාළ සහ ධනාත්මක වෙනසක් ඇති කරන සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරී ව්‍යාපෘති ලබා දීමට ඔවුන්ට සහාය වීම SEDR අරමුණු කරයි. , ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඌව සහ නැගෙනහිර පළාත්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ක්රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිවර්තනය, ප්‍රතිසන්ධානය සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සම්බන්ධය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 2021-ජුනි 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR ක්රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුර, නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR ක්රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම දිනකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR ක්රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ ක්රියාකාරී ව්යාපෘති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මාර්තු සිට ජූනි දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR ක්රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජ ක්රියාකාරී ව්යාපෘති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 1,724",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බඩල්කුඹුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR AC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක් කාර්ස්ටන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කවුන්සිලයේ ක්‍රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR ක්රියාකාරී පුරවැසියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නැගෙනහිර පළාත්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆக்டிவ் சிட்டிசன்ஸ் திட்டத்தின் 1-ம் கட்டத்தை முடிக்கும் பயனுள்ள தகராறு தீர்வு திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆதரவளிக்கும் பயனுள்ள தகராறு தீர்வு (SEDR) என்பது பிரிட்டிஷ் கவுன்சிலால் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட நான்கு வருட நீதிக்கான அணுகல் திட்டமாகும், மேலும் இலங்கையில் அதன் வலுப்படுத்தும் மாற்றம், நல்லிணக்கம் மற்றும் உள்ளடக்கிய ஜனநாயக ஈடுபாடு (STRIDE) திட்டத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாக ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தால் நிதியளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "SEDR இன் இதயத்தில் அமைதியான சகவாழ்வு மற்றும் நியாயமான மற்றும் நீதியான இலங்கைக்கான விருப்பம் உள்ளது. டிசம்பர் 2021-ஜூன் 2022 இல், SEDR ஆனது, வலுவான உள்ளூர் தகராறு தீர்வு மற்றும் சமூகச் சிக்கல்களைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கும் சமூகச் சர்ச்சைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கும் கவனம் செலுத்தும் வகையில், SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள் திட்டங்களின் வடிவமைப்பு மற்றும் விநியோகத்தைத் தொடங்கியது. இந்த நிகழ்ச்சிகள் SEDR இன் மூன்று இலக்கு மாகாணங்களில் (வடக்கு, கிழக்கு மற்றும் ஊவா) ஒவ்வொன்றிலும் நடத்தப்பட்டன, மேலும் முதல் கட்டம் சமீபத்தில் வெற்றிகரமாக முடிவடைந்தது.",
        "ஆக்டிவ் சிட்டிசன்ஸ் என்பது ஒரு சமூக தலைமைத்துவ பயிற்சி முறையாகும், இது 10 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள பிரிட்டிஷ் கவுன்சிலால் வெற்றிகரமாக வழங்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது, இது கலாச்சாரங்களுக்கு இடையேயான உரையாடல் மற்றும் சமூகம் தலைமையிலான சமூக மேம்பாட்டை மேம்படுத்துகிறது மற்றும் சமூகங்களுக்குள் மற்றும் இடையே நம்பிக்கையை உருவாக்குகிறது. சமூக அளவிலான தகராறுகளைத் தீர்ப்பதில் மாற்று தகராறு தீர்வு வழிமுறைகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான SEDR இன் அணுகுமுறையில் இந்த முறை முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு மாகாணத்திலும் உள்ள CSO கூட்டாளர் அமைப்புகளின் ஆதரவு மற்றும் வழிகாட்டுதலுடன், SEDR ஆக்டிவ் சிட்டிசன்ஸ் திட்டம் ஐந்து நாள் பயிற்சியில் பங்கேற்ற பங்கேற்பாளர்களுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றியது.",
        "பயிற்சியின் மூலம் வழங்கப்பட்ட திறன்கள், அவர்களின் அடையாளம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம் பற்றிய சுய விழிப்புணர்வு, நம்பிக்கை மற்றும் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் உறவுகளை உருவாக்குதல், உரையாடலை ஊக்குவிக்க மற்றும் எளிதாக்குவதற்கான கருவிகள் மற்றும் நுட்பங்களை ஆராய்தல், சிக்கலைக் கண்டறிதல், சிக்கலைத் தீர்ப்பது, சமூக ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் சர்ச்சை மேலாண்மை மற்றும் தலைமைத்துவத்தை மேம்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள் ஒரு சமூகத்தில் பல்வேறு ஆர்வங்கள் மற்றும் திறன்களைக் கொண்ட நபர்களுடன் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். பின்னர் அவர்கள் இந்த திறன்களை ஒரு பிரத்யேக சமூக தலையீடு (சமூக செயல் திட்டங்கள்) மூலம் நடைமுறைக்குக் கொண்டு வந்தனர், அவை இளைஞர் தன்னார்வலர்கள் முதல் மாநில மற்றும் அரசு அல்லாத பங்குதாரர்கள் வரை தங்கள் சமூகத்தின் ஆதரவுடன் தங்கள் சமூகத்திற்குள் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டு, நிர்வகிக்கப்பட்டு செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டன. மார்ச் 2022 முதல் ஜூன் 2022 வரை, SEDR ஆக்டிவ் குடிமக்கள் 15 சமூக செயல் திட்டங்களை வழங்கியுள்ளனர், இது அவர்களின் சமூகங்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பிரச்சினைகள் மற்றும் தகராறுகளை மையமாகக் கொண்டு சுமார் 1,724 பயனாளிகளை அடைந்தது.",
        "மொனராகலை மாவட்டத்தின் படல்கும்புரவைச் சேர்ந்த இளைஞர் ஒருவர், “எனது SEDR AC பயணத்தின் போது, ​​பட்டறையின் போது நான் கற்றுக்கொண்ட சில பாடங்கள், குறிப்பாக மோதல் மரம், மன்ற அரங்கம் மற்றும் பாத்திர நாடகங்கள் அல்ல. ஒரே ஒரு சமூகத்தில் மட்டுமே இருக்கும் ஆனால் அவர்கள் எந்த மதம் அல்லது இனத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என்பதைப் பொருட்படுத்தாமல் அனைவருக்கும் பொருந்தும். நான் அந்த இடத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறும் போது, ​​எனது தமிழ் அறை தோழர்களை எங்கள் கிராமத்திற்கு வருமாறு அழைப்பதை வழக்கமாக கொண்டேன். இந்த நண்பர்கள் என்னையும் ஏனைய சிங்கள நண்பர்களையும் அவர்களது தோட்டங்களில் தங்களுடைய விருந்தினராக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று விரும்பியபோது நான் சமமாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டேன்.",
        "SEDR குழுவின் தலைவர் Jacques Carstens கூறினார்: “பிரிட்டிஷ் கவுன்சிலின் ஆக்டிவ் சிட்டிசன்ஸ் மாதிரியானது, இலங்கையில் சமூக அளவிலான தகராறு தீர்வு முயற்சிகளை வலுப்படுத்தும் SEDR இன் லட்சியத்திற்கு மிகவும் பொருத்தமானது என நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பெண்கள் மற்றும் இளைஞர்கள் தன்னார்வத் தொண்டர்கள் எவ்வாறு வளர்ந்து, செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள் அணுகுமுறையால் பயனடைந்துள்ளனர் மற்றும் அவர்களது சொந்த உள்ளூர் சமூகங்களைப் பாதிக்கும் மோதலுக்கான சில அடிப்படைக் காரணங்களைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு அவர்களின் புதிய அறிவு மற்றும் திறன்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதைப் பார்ப்பது மிகவும் ஊக்கமளிக்கிறது.",
        "செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள் மாதிரியைப் பயன்படுத்தி, SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள் திட்டத்தின் 2 ஆம் கட்டத்தின் மூலம் உள்ளூர் இளைஞர்கள் மற்றும் பெண்கள் சாம்பியன்களின் திறனை மேலும் மேம்படுத்துவதையும், வடக்கின் சமூகங்களில் உள்ளடங்கிய, சூழல் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட மற்றும் நேர்மறையான மாற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடிய சமூக செயல் திட்டங்களை வழங்க அவர்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதையும் SEDR நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. , இலங்கையின் ஊவா மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உருமாற்றம், நல்லிணக்கம் மற்றும் உள்ளடங்கிய ஜனநாயக ஈடுபாட்டை வலுப்படுத்துதல்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 2021-ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு, கிழக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு நாளும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக நடவடிக்கை திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் முதல் ஜூன் 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூக நடவடிக்கை திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 1,724",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "படல்கும்புரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR ஏசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிராமம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக் கார்ஸ்டென்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் கவுன்சிலின் செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEDR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEDR செயலில் உள்ள குடிமக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்கள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}