{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සජිත්ගේ-අභියෝගය/101-607270",
  "time_ut": 1643361732,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත්ගේ අභියෝගය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith's challenge",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "If you have the ability to work with me, I challenge the cardboard heroes who are dressed for the presidency to do it, said the leader of the National United People's Party, Mr. Sajith Premadasa, in Dambulla.",
        "Samagi Jana Balawega's Dambulla Constituency Organizer U.R. Mr. Daya Nandasiri was addressing a public meeting in Dambulla and the leader of the opposition party Mr. Sajith Premadasa made this challenge. This was organized at Dambulla Nissanka ground.",
        "He said that the National Unity People's Force will achieve a great victory in a fair election.",
        "Individuals who claim to be bosses of each group and each individual are making suits for the presidency with great pleasure. They are asking those who sew suits whether they are capable of developing the country and whether they are capable of serving the people.",
        "If possible, come to serve the race to work with me and challenge the presidential dreamers. Not only that, he also said that he would invite."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the National United People's Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla Constituency Organizer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.R.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daya Nandasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla Nissanka",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Unity People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත්ගේ අභියෝගය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මා සමග වැඩ කිරීමට හැකියාවක් ඇත්නම් එය කර පෙන්වන්නැයි ජනාධිපතිකමට ඇඳුම් මසා  සිටින කාඩ්බෝඩ් වීරයන්ට අභියෝග කරනවා යැයි ජාතික සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ නායක වීපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා දඹුල්ලේ දී පැවසීය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ දඹුල්ල ආසන සංවිධායක යු.අර්. දයා නන්දසිරි මහතා දඹුල්ලේ ජනහමුවක් අමතමින් වීපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මෙම අභියෝගය කළේෙය. දඹුල්ල නිස්සංක පිටියේ දී මෙය සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි.",
        "සාධාරණ මැතිවරණයක් තුළ ජාතික සමගි ජන බලවේගය විශිෂ්ට ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබාගන්නා බව ඒ මහතා මෙහිදී සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එක එක කණ්ඩායම් එක එක පුද්ගලයන් ලොක්කන් කියාගෙන සිටින පුද්ගලයන් ලොකු වින්දනයක් ලබාගෙන ජනාධිපතිකමට සුට් මසනවා. එසේ සූට් මහන අයගෙන් තමන් විමසා සිටින්නේ රටේ සංවර්ධනයක් කිරීමට හැකියාව තිබෙනවා ද ජනතාවට සේවයක් කිරීමට හැකියාවක් තිබේද.",
        "හැකි නම් මා සමග වැඩ කිරීමට තරඟයට සේවය කිරීමට පැමිණෙන්නැයි ජනාධිපති සිහින මවන අයට අභියෝග තරකනා. විතරක් නොවේ ආරාධනා කරනවා යැයි ද කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික එක්සත් ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගයේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල ආසන සංවිධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූ.ආර්.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයා නන්දසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල නිශ්ශංක",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සමගි ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித்தின் சவால்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உங்களால் என்னுடன் இணைந்து செயற்படும் திறன் இருந்தால், ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு உடுத்தியிருக்கும் அட்டை மாவீரர்களுக்கு நான் சவால் விடுக்கின்றேன் என தேசிய ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கட்சியின் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தம்புள்ளையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் தம்புள்ளை தொகுதி அமைப்பாளர் யூ.ஆர். தம்புள்ளையில் இடம்பெற்ற மக்கள் சந்திப்பொன்றில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே தயா நந்தசிறி இதனை விடுத்து எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச இந்த சவாலை விடுத்துள்ளார். இது தம்புள்ளை நிஸ்ஸங்க மைதானத்தில் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "நியாயமான தேர்தலில் தேசிய ஒருமைப்பாட்டு மக்கள் படை மகத்தான வெற்றி பெறும் என்றார்.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு குழுவிற்கும் ஒவ்வொரு தனி நபருக்கும் முதலாளிகள் என்று கூறிக்கொள்ளும் நபர்கள் மிகுந்த மகிழ்ச்சியுடன் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு வழக்குகளை உருவாக்குகிறார்கள். சூட் தைப்பவர்களிடம் நாட்டை முன்னேற்றும் திறன் உள்ளதா, மக்களுக்கு சேவை செய்யும் திறன் உள்ளதா என்று கேட்கின்றனர்.",
        "முடிந்தால், என்னுடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்ற இனத்திற்கு சேவை செய்ய வாருங்கள், ஜனாதிபதி கனவு காண்பவர்களுக்கு சவால் விடுங்கள். அதுமட்டுமின்றி அழைப்பதாகவும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை தொகுதி அமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.ஆர்.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயா நந்தசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை நிஸ்ஸங்க",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஒற்றுமை மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}