{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/29/making-progress-in-imf-talks-pmd/",
  "time_ut": 1659105960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Making progress in IMF talks: PMD",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Making progress in IMF talks: PMD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The discussions initiated between the Sri Lankan Government and the International Monetary Fund have made progress, the President's Media Division says.",
        "In a press release, the President's Media Division stated that a conclusive plan on debt sustainability has to be presented to IMF, however the policy of the previous administration with regard to not resuming the IMF discussions until political instability secedes led to a stall in discussions.",
        "The President's Media Division says that a fully stable Government has been established under President Ranil Wickremesinghe, in addition to discussions with regard to an all-party Government, which are also progressing successfully.",
        "Accordingly, the Government is of the opinion that discussions with the IMF can be utilized to lead Sri Lanka to become financially stable."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PMD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡාවල ප්‍රගතියක් ඇති කරමින්: පීඑම්ඩී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල අතර ආරම්භ කර ඇති සාකච්ඡා ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇති බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ණය තිරසාරභාවය පිළිබඳ තීරණාත්මක සැලැස්මක් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතු නමුත් දේශපාලන අස්ථාවර භාවයෙන් වෙන් වනතුරු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා යළි ආරම්භ නොකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පසුගිය පාලනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සාකච්ඡා ඇනහිටීමට හේතු වූ බවයි.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන සාකච්ඡාවලට අමතරව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා යටතේ පූර්ණ ස්ථාවර රජයක් ස්ථාපිත කර ඇති බවත්, ඒවා ද සාර්ථකව ඉදිරියට යමින් පවතින බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් ස්ථාවර තත්ත්වයකට ගෙන ඒම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ප්‍රයෝජන ගත හැකි බව රජයේ අදහසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் முன்னேற்றம்: PMD",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கும் இடையில் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட கலந்துரையாடலில் முன்னேற்றம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு செய்திக்குறிப்பில், ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு, கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை குறித்த உறுதியான திட்டம் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு முன்வைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று கூறியது, இருப்பினும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை பிரிந்து செல்லும் வரை IMF விவாதங்களை மீண்டும் தொடங்குவதில்லை என்ற முந்தைய நிர்வாகத்தின் கொள்கை விவாதங்களில் முட்டுக்கட்டைக்கு வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தலைமையில் முழுமையான நிலையான அரசாங்கம் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடல்களும் வெற்றிகரமாக முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான கலந்துரையாடல்களை இலங்கையை நிதி ரீதியாக ஸ்திரமான நிலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு பயன்படுத்த முடியும் என அரசாங்கம் கருதுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிஎம்டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}