{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පුවක්-ලීයකින්-පහර-කෑ-මිතුරා-දින-4-කට-පසු-මියයයි/101-616580",
  "time_ut": 1658116266,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පුවක් ලීයකින් පහර කෑ මිතුරා දින 4 කට පසු මියයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The friend who was hit with a betel nut died after 4 days",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Homagama Headquarters Police, a person was beaten to death with a palm tree after an argument between two friends in front of a house in Pitipana Dham Mawatha area of ​​Homagama.",
        "The police say that the deceased is a (40)-year-old man named Don Sumit Chandana of Matara, resident of Homagama, Pitipana South.",
        "It is said that these two people are friends and used to drink alcohol together every day.",
        "Accordingly, on the morning of the 13th, another person came in front of the house of the deceased and an argument took place between the two, and then it escalated into a fight.",
        "It is said that the person who was attacked endured the attack and spent four days drinking heavily as usual.",
        "In the meantime, on the morning of the 17th, the person who was assaulted collapsed at home and was admitted to the Homagama Basic Hospital, where he died while receiving treatment.",
        "Accordingly, according to a complaint filed by the deceased's sister to Homagama police regarding the incident, during the investigation, information was revealed that on the morning of the 13th, a friend of the deceased came and ran away after hitting him with a betel nut.",
        "Later, considering it a suspicious death, Nugegoda Division Crime Scene Investigation Agency officers and Homagama Magistrate arrived at the scene and started an on-site investigation.",
        "The Homagama Magistrate, who examined the place of the incident and the body, said that the body should be taken to the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital and a specialist doctor should conduct the post-mortem examination.",
        "Accordingly, the dead body was admitted to the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital and the post-mortem examination conducted there revealed that the cause of death was internal bleeding due to a blow to the groin area and broken bones.",
        "Accordingly, after it was revealed that the death was a murder by assault, the 27-year-old resident of Homagama, Pitipana, who carried out the assault, was arrested last (17) evening while hiding in a house.",
        "Later, the suspect is to be presented to the Homagama court along with Puwak Liya who did the assault.",
        "Under the direct supervision of Nugegoda Division Senior Superintendent of Police Mr. Chandana Liyanage and on the instructions of Assistant Superintendent of Police Mr. Pushpakumara, under the direction of Chief Inspector of Police Homagama Headquarters Mr. Thusitha Wickramaratne, the officers including Chief Inspector Kariyawasam of the Criminal Investigation Division are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Homagama Headquarters Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitipana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dham Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40)-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Sumit",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitipana South",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "every day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the morning of the 13th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the morning of the 17th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Homagama Basic Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the morning of the 13th",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda Division Crime Scene Investigation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Homagama Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitipana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda Division Senior Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thusitha Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පුවක් ලීයකින් පහර කෑ මිතුරා දින 4 කට පසු මියයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෝමාගම පිටිපන දහම් මාවත ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක් ඉදිරිපිට දී  මිතුරන් දෙදෙනෙකු අතර වූ බහින් බස් වීමක් දුරදිග යාමෙන් , පුවක් ලීයකින්  පහරදී පුද්ගලයකු ඝාතනය කර ඇතැයි හෝමාගම මූලස්ථාන පොලිසිය  පවසයි .",
        "මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත්තේ  හෝමාගම , පිටිපන දකුණ පදිංචි , මාතරගේ දොන් සුමිත් චන්දන නමැති  (40) හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙම පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනා  මිතුරන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන අතර දිනපතා එක් ව මත්පැන් පානයට පුරුදුව සිටි දෙදෙනකු බව පැවසේ .",
        "ඒ අනුව මියගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ නිවස ඉදිරිපිට පසුගිය 13 දා උදෑසන අනෙත් පුද්ගලයා පැමිණ දෙදෙනා අතර බහින් බස් වීමක් සිදුවී ඇති අතර පසුව එය ගැටුමක් දක්වා දුරදිග ගොස් පිටතින්  පැමිණි පුද්ගලයා  නිවසේ රැදී සිටි පුද්ගලයාට පුවක් ලීයකින් පහර දී පළා ගොස් තිබුණි .",
        "පසුව පහර කෑමට ලක් වූ පුද්ගලයා පහරකෑම ඉවසාගෙන දින හතරක් සුපුරුදු පරිදි අධික ලෙස මත්පැන් පානය කරමින් කාලය ගතකර ඇතැයි පැවසේ.",
        "මේ අතරතුරදී ඉකුත් 17දා උදෑසන  පහර කෑමට ලක් වූ පුද්ගලයා එක් වරම නිවසේ දී ඇද වැටී  සිහිසුන් වීම නිසා හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කොට ඇති අතර එහි ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී මෙසේ මියගොස් තිබුණි .",
        "ඒ අනුව සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මියගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ සහෝදරිය හෝමාගම පොලිසියට කළ පැමිණිල්ලකට අනුව විමර්ශන සිදු කිරීමේදී  ඉකුත් 13 දා උදෑසන මියගිය පුද්ගලයාට ඔහුගේ මිතුරෙකු පැමිණ පුවක් ලීයකින් පහරදී පළායාමේ සිද්ධියක තොරතුරක් අනාවරණය වී තිබුණි .",
        "පසුව සැකකටයුතු මරණයක් සේ සළකා   සිද්ධිය වූ ස්ථානයට නුගේගොඩ කොට්ඨාස අපරාධ ස්ථාන පරීක්ෂණ ආයතන නිලධාරීන් හා හෝමාගම මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා පැමිණ ස්ථානීය පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කෙරිණි.",
        "එහිදී සිද්ධිය වූ ස්ථානය හා මෘතදේහය පරීක්ෂා කළ හෝමාගම මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා පවසා ඇත්තේ දේහය කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට රැගෙන ගොස් විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍යවරයෙකු ලවා පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය සිදු කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව  මෘත දේහය කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කොට එහිදී සිදුකළ පශ්චාත් මරණ  පරීක්ෂණයේදී අනාවරණය වී ඇත්තේ ඉලපත් ප්‍රදේශයට කළ පහර දීමකින් ,අස්ථි බිඳී යාමෙන්  වූ අභ්‍යන්තර රුධිර වහනය මරණයට හේතුව බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම මරණය පහරදීමෙන් සිදුකළ ඝාතනයක් බවට තොරතුරු අනාවරණය වීමත් සමග පහරදීම සිදුකළ හෝමාගම , පිටිපන පදිංචි (27) හැවිරිදි  පුද්ගලයා  නිවසක සැඟව සිටියදී ඉකුත් (17) දා සවස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ .",
        "පසුව පහරදීම සිදුකළ පුවක් ලීය  සමඟ සැකකරු හෝමාගම අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය .",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් නුගේගොඩ කොට්ඨාස භාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී චන්දන ලියනගේ මහතාගේ සෘජු අධීක්ෂණය යටතේ සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරී පුෂ්පකුමාර මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත හෝමාගම මූලස්ථාන පොලිසියේ ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක තුසිත වික්‍රමරත්න මහතාගේ මෙහෙයවීමෙන් අපරාධ විමර්ශන අංශයේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක කාරියවසම් මහතා ඇතුළු නිලධාරීහු ඉදිරි විමර්ශන පවත්වති ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දින 4 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මූලස්ථාන පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිපන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දම් මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40) - වයස අවුරුදු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොන් සුමිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිපන දකුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම දිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 වෙනිදා උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17 වෙනිදා උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13 වෙනිදා උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ කොට්ඨාස අපරාධ ස්ථාන විමර්ශන ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිපන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ කොට්ඨාශ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුසිත වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ විමර්ශන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெற்றிலை பாக்கு தாக்கிய நண்பர் 4 நாட்களுக்கு பிறகு உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹோமாகம, பிடிபன தம் மாவத்தை பகுதியிலுள்ள வீடொன்றுக்கு முன்பாக நண்பர்கள் இருவருக்கு இடையில் ஏற்பட்ட வாக்குவாதத்தில் நபர் ஒருவர் பனை மரத்தால் தாக்கப்பட்டு உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக ஹோமாகம தலைமையக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஹோமாகம, பிட்டிபன தெற்கு பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த மாத்தறையைச் சேர்ந்த டொன் சுமித் சந்தன என்ற (40) வயதுடைய நபரே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் இருவரும் நண்பர்கள் என்றும், தினமும் ஒன்றாக மது அருந்துவது வழக்கம் என்றும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "அதன்படி, கடந்த 13ம் தேதி காலை, இறந்தவரின் வீட்டின் முன் மற்றொரு நபர் வந்து, இருவருக்கும் இடையே வாக்குவாதம் ஏற்பட்டு, பின்னர் அது கைகலப்பாக மாறியது.",
        "தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான நபர் தாக்குதலை தாங்கிக்கொண்டு நான்கு நாட்கள் வழமை போன்று அதிகளவில் மது அருந்திவிட்டு சென்றதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதனிடையே கடந்த 17ஆம் திகதி காலை தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான நபர் வீட்டில் சுருண்டு விழுந்து ஹோமாகம அடிப்படை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் ஹோமாகம பொலிஸில் உயிரிழந்தவரின் சகோதரி செய்த முறைப்பாட்டின் பிரகாரம், விசாரணையின் போது, ​​கடந்த 13ஆம் திகதி காலை, உயிரிழந்தவரின் நண்பர் ஒருவர் வந்து வெற்றிலை பாக்கு போட்டுவிட்டு ஓடியதாக தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளது.",
        "பின்னர், இது சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான மரணம் எனக் கருதி, நுகேகொட பிரிவு குற்றப்புலனாய்வு பிரிவு அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் ஹோமாகம நீதவான் சம்பவ இடத்திற்கு வந்து விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்தனர்.",
        "சம்பவ இடத்தையும் சடலத்தையும் பரிசோதித்த ஹோமாகம நீதவான், சடலத்தை களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லுமாறும் விசேட வைத்தியரால் பிரேத பரிசோதனையை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அதன்படி, சடலம் களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு அங்கு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட பிரேத பரிசோதனையில் இடுப்பு பகுதியில் அடிபட்டு எலும்புகள் உடைந்தமையினால் ஏற்பட்ட உள் இரத்தக் கசிவே மரணத்திற்கான காரணம் என தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, இந்த மரணம் தாக்குதலால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட கொலை என தெரியவந்ததையடுத்து, தாக்குதலை மேற்கொண்ட ஹோமாகம, பிடிபன பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 27 வயதுடைய நபர் நேற்று (17) மாலை வீடொன்றில் மறைந்திருந்த நிலையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பின்னர், தாக்குதல் நடத்திய புவக் லியாவுடன் சந்தேகநபர் ஹோமாகம நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளார்.",
        "நுகேகொட பிரதேச சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.சந்தன லியனகே அவர்களின் நேரடி மேற்பார்வையின் கீழ், உதவி பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு. புஷ்பகுமார அவர்களின் பணிப்புரையின் கீழ், ஹோமாகம தலைமையக பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் திரு.துசித விக்கிரமரத்ன, பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் காரியவசம் உட்பட அதிகாரிகள். குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம தலைமையக பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிபனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40) வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் சுமித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிபன தெற்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13ம் தேதி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17ம் தேதி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம அடிப்படை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13ம் தேதி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட பிரிவு குற்றவியல் புலனாய்வு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம நீதவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம நீதவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிபனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட பிரிவு சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துசித விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}