{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/picture_story/ජනපති-ආරක්ෂක-අංශ-ප්‍රධානීන්-හමුවෙයි/10-395631",
  "time_ut": 1658415011,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ආරක්ෂක අංශ ප්‍රධානීන් හමුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President meets the security chiefs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces today (July 21) visited the Ministry of Defense at the Defense Headquarters Complex in Sri Jayawardenepura Kotte after taking oath in Parliament.",
        "The President was received by Defense Secretary General Kamal Gunaratne who came to the Defense Ministry.",
        "After being sworn in as the President, Mr. Wickramasinghe first visited a government institution, where he met with the heads of the security forces and held a discussion.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe was sworn in as the 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka this morning in Parliament.",
        "Minister Tiral Alas, Attorney General, Secretary to the President, Chief of Defense Staff, Commanders of the three armed forces, Inspector General of Police, Chief of National Intelligence, Director of State Intelligence Service and senior officers of the Ministry were present on this occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defense Headquarters Complex",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defense Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tiral Alas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Intelligence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Intelligence Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ආරක්ෂක අංශ ප්‍රධානීන් හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා සේනාධිනායක වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (ජුලි 21) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර කෝට්ටේ, ආරක්ෂක මූලස්ථාන සංකීර්ණයේ පිහිටි ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත පැමිණියේය.",
        "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත පැමිණි ජනාධිපති ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් ජෙනරල් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රථමයෙන් රාජ්‍ය ආයතනයක් වෙත පැමිණ අවස්ථාව මෙය වන අතර එහිදී ආරක්ෂක අංශ ප්‍රධානීන් හමුවී සාකච්ඡාවක්ද පැවැත්වීය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අද පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය ටිරාල් අලස්, නීතිපති, ජනාධිපති ලේකම්, ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී, ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්, පොලිස්පති, ජාතික බුද්ධි ප්‍රධානී, රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි සේවයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ සහ අමාත්‍යාංශ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මූලස්ථාන සංකීර්ණය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටිරාල් අහෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික බුද්ධි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය බුද්ධි සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளை ஜனாதிபதி சந்திக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முப்படைகளின் தளபதியாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (ஜூலை 21) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டதன் பின்னர் ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர கோட்டேயிலுள்ள பாதுகாப்பு தலைமையக வளாகத்தில் உள்ள பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சுக்கு விஜயம் செய்தார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சுக்கு வருகை தந்த ஜனாதிபதியை பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் நாயகம் கமல் குணரத்ன வரவேற்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர், முதலில் அரச நிறுவனமொன்றுக்கு விஜயம் செய்த திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்க, அங்கு பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தலைவர்களைச் சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் திரள் அலஸ், சட்டமா அதிபர், ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர், பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளின் பிரதானி, முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகள், பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர், தேசிய புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவின் பிரதானி, அரச புலனாய்வுப் பணிப்பாளர் மற்றும் அமைச்சின் உயர் அதிகாரிகள் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர். ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு தலைமையக வளாகம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரள் ஐயோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய புலனாய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில புலனாய்வு சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}