{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Two-Sri-Lankan-nationals-arrested-on-robbery-charge-in-Chennai/108-242991",
  "time_ut": 1660442874,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two Sri Lankan nationals arrested on robbery charge in Chennai",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two Sri Lankan nationals arrested on robbery charge in Chennai",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Chennai Airport police arrested two Sri Lankan nationals who allegedly robbed gold jewellery from a Sri Lankan passenger after posing as Customs officers.",
        "The police said a 47-year old woman, flew in from Sri Lanka on Monday. The two accused, aged , 31and 40, both Sri Lankan nationals, stopped her outside the airport and introduced themselves as Customs officers, the Hindu reported.",
        "The duo told her that she was carrying jewellery beyond the permitted limit and took her necklace and bangles. Suspecting them, she went to Customs and complained about them. Later, she lodged a police complaint. The duo was arrested and remanded to judicial custody."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47-year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොල්ලකෑමේ චෝදනාවකට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු චෙන්නායිහිදී අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රේගු නිලධාරීන් ලෙස පෙනී සිටිමින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික මගියෙකුගෙන් රන් ආභරණ කොල්ලකෑ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු චෙන්නායි ගුවන්තොටුපල පොලීසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "47 හැවිරිදි කාන්තාවක් සඳුදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිට පැමිණ ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි. ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජාතිකයන් වන අවුරුදු 31 සහ 40 වයස්වල පසුවන විත්තිකරුවන් දෙදෙනා ඇයව ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත නවතා තමන් රේගු නිලධාරීන් ලෙස හඳුන්වා ගත් බව හින්දු පුවත්පත වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "අවසර ලත් සීමාවෙන් ඔබ්බට ස්වර්ණාභරණ රැගෙන යන බව පැවසූ දෙදෙනා ඇගේ මාලය සහ වළලු රැගෙන ගියහ. ඔවුන් ගැන සැක කළ ඇය රේගුවට ගොස් ඔවුන් ගැන පැමිණිලි කළාය. පසුව ඇය පොලිසියට පැමිණිලි කළාය. ඔවුන් දෙදෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "චෙන්නායි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சென்னையில் கொள்ளையடித்த இரு இலங்கையர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் போல் நடித்து இலங்கை பயணி ஒருவரிடம் தங்க நகைகளை கொள்ளையடித்த இரண்டு இலங்கை பிரஜைகளை சென்னை விமான நிலைய பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "47 வயதுடைய பெண் ஒருவர், திங்கட்கிழமை இலங்கையிலிருந்து விமானத்தில் வந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். இலங்கை பிரஜைகளான 31 மற்றும் 40 வயதுடைய குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட இருவரும் அவளை விமான நிலையத்திற்கு வெளியே நிறுத்தி, தங்களை சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் என்று அறிமுகப்படுத்தியதாக தி ஹிந்து செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட வரம்பை மீறி நகைகளை எடுத்துச் செல்வதாக கூறி, நகை மற்றும் வளையல்களை இருவரும் எடுத்துச் சென்றனர். சந்தேகமடைந்த அவர், சுங்கத்துறைக்கு சென்று அவர்கள் மீது புகார் அளித்தார். பின்னர், போலீசில் புகார் அளித்தார். இருவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு நீதிமன்ற காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "சென்னை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}