{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/21st-Amendment-presented-to-Cabinet/108-237564",
  "time_ut": 1653314796,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "21st Amendment presented to Cabinet",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "21st Amendment presented to Cabinet",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The draft of the 21st Amendment to the Constitution was presented to the Cabinet today for consideration as the first legislative business of the new government, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "The bill, if enacted, will seek to reintroduce constitutional features that contained in the 19th Amendment curtailing powers of executive presidency.",
        "Besides, the constitutional provision in the 20th Amendment providing for the increase of the number of judges of higher courts will be retained in the incorporation of the 21st Amendment.",
        "Also, the president, as the Head of State, will continue to retain his power to dissolve Parliament only after two and half years.",
        "The proposed constitutional amendment will be taken up for consideration by the Cabinet next week. It was presented to the Cabinet by Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe. Mr. Rajapakshe was also the subject minister who presented the 19th Amendment to the Constitution during the time of the Yahapalana government.",
        "There is public agitation in the country to prune the powers of executive presidency.(Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two and half years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yahapalana",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කළා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව රජයේ පළමු ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක කටයුත්ත ලෙස සලකා බැලීම සඳහා 21 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ කෙටුම්පත අද කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "පනත් කෙටුම්පත බලාත්මක කළහොත් විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමයේ බලතල කප්පාදු කිරීමේ 19 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ අඩංගු ව්‍යවස්ථාමය ලක්ෂණ යළි හඳුන්වා දීමට උත්සාහ කරනු ඇත.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ඉහළ අධිකරණවල විනිසුරුවරුන් සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා 20 වන සංශෝධනයේ ඇති ව්‍යවස්ථාමය ප්‍රතිපාදනය 21 වන සංශෝධනය සංස්ථාගත කිරීමේදී රඳවා ගනු ඇත.",
        "එසේම, ජනාධිපතිවරයා, රාජ්‍ය නායකයා වශයෙන්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැරීමේ බලය දිගටම රඳවා ගනු ඇත්තේ වසර දෙකහමාරකට පසුවය.",
        "යෝජිත ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ලබන සතියේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ සලකා බැලීමට නියමිතයි. අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ විසින් එය කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී. යහපාලන ආණ්ඩුව පැවති කාලයේ 19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ඉදිරිපත් කළ විෂය භාර ඇමැතිවරයා වූයේද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාය.",
        "විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමයේ බලතල කප්පාදු කරන ලෙසට රටේ මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණයක් පවතී.(කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "21வது திருத்தம் அமைச்சரவையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 21வது திருத்தத்தின் வரைவு புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் முதலாவது சட்டவாக்க நடவடிக்கையாக பரிசீலனைக்காக இன்று அமைச்சரவையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டதாக டெய்லி மிரர் அறிந்து கொள்கிறது.",
        "இந்த சட்டமூலம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டால், நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைக்கும் 19வது திருத்தத்தில் உள்ள அரசியலமைப்பு அம்சங்களை மீண்டும் அறிமுகப்படுத்த முற்படும்.",
        "தவிர, உயர் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகளின் எண்ணிக்கையை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான 20வது திருத்தத்தில் உள்ள அரசியலமைப்பு ஏற்பாடு, 21வது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தின் இணைப்பிலும் தக்கவைக்கப்படும்.",
        "மேலும், ஜனாதிபதி, அரச தலைவர் என்ற வகையில், இரண்டரை ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பின்னரே நாடாளுமன்றத்தைக் கலைக்கும் அதிகாரத்தை தொடர்ந்தும் தக்க வைத்துக் கொள்வார்.",
        "உத்தேச அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தம் அடுத்த வாரம் அமைச்சரவையின் பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படவுள்ளது. நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவினால் அமைச்சரவையில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது. யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தின் காலத்தில் அரசியலமைப்பின் 19 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை முன்வைத்த அமைச்சர் ராஜபக்ஷவும் ஆவார்.",
        "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி முறைமையின் அதிகாரங்களை கத்தரிக்குமாறு நாட்டில் பொது மக்கள் போராட்டம் நடத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்றது.(கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டரை ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}