{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/23/fuel-for-school-vans-from-sltb-depots-from-today-president/",
  "time_ut": 1658567520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fuel for school vans from SLTB depots from today: President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel for school vans from SLTB depots from today: President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); President Ranil Wickremesinghe has instructed to streamline and expedite the fuel distribution process, during a meeting held at the Prime Minister’s office today (23).",
        "The President had also instructed the Minister of Transport to enable school vans to obtain fuel from SLTB depots from 03:00 PM today, in view of the reopening of schools from 25th of July.",
        "Moreover, the President also instructed to issue fuel from SLTB depots and Army camps for fisheries, tourism and agriculture sectors, while he also instructed authorities to take swift action against fuel hoarders.",
        "Govt and Govt approved private schools to resume activities on 25th July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Govt",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාසල් වෑන් රථ සඳහා අද සිට ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් ඉන්ධන: ජනපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය විධිමත් කර කඩිනම් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (23) අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී උපදෙස් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ජුලි 25 වැනිදා සිට පාසල් විවෘත කිරීම හේතුවෙන් අද පස්වරු 03.00 සිට පාසල් වෑන් රථවලට ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට හැකිවන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යවරයාට උපදෙස් ලබාදී තිබේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව ධීවර, සංචාරක සහ කෘෂිකාර්මික ක්ෂේත්‍ර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් සහ යුද හමුදා කඳවුරුවලින් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරන ලෙස ද උපදෙස් දුන් ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඉන්ධන රැස් කරන්නන්ට එරෙහිව කඩිනම් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ද බලධාරීන්ට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "රජයේ සහ රජයේ පෞද්ගලික පාසල් ජූලි 25 වැනි දින නැවත ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ආරම්භ කිරීමට අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03:00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் டிப்போக்களில் இருந்து பாடசாலை வாகனங்களுக்கான எரிபொருள் இன்று முதல்: ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று (23) இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​எரிபொருள் விநியோக நடவடிக்கைகளை நெறிப்படுத்தவும் துரிதப்படுத்தவும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 25 ஆம் திகதி முதல் பாடசாலைகள் மீள ஆரம்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள நிலையில், இன்று பிற்பகல் 03.00 மணி முதல் இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் டிப்போக்களில் இருந்து பாடசாலை வாகனங்களுக்கு எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறும் ஜனாதிபதி போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சருக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், மீன்பிடி, சுற்றுலா மற்றும் விவசாயத் துறைகளுக்கு இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை மற்றும் இராணுவ முகாம்களில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை விநியோகிக்குமாறு பணிப்புரை விடுத்த ஜனாதிபதி, எரிபொருள் பதுக்கி வைப்பவர்களுக்கு எதிராக துரித நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார்.",
        "தனியார் பள்ளிகள் ஜூலை 25 ஆம் தேதி மீண்டும் செயல்பட அரசு மற்றும் அரசு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}