{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131693",
  "time_ut": 1658136964,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் ; இந்திய பிரதமர் மோடி வாக்களித்தார்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Presidential election; Indian Prime Minister Modi voted",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Voting is taking place across the country from 10 am today to elect the new President in India.",
        "Prime Minister Modi and other leaders cast their ballots for the presidential election at the Parliament complex in Delhi.",
        "Voting for the election to elect the new president will take place today, Monday.",
        "Accordingly, Draupadi Murmu is the candidate of the National Democratic Alliance (BJP) and Yashwant Sinha is the candidate of the opposition party.",
        "MPs and MLAs across the country are going to vote for the new president.",
        "Polling has been arranged at the Chief Secretariat in the respective states for the MLAs to cast their votes.",
        "543 Lok Sabha MPs and 233 Rajya Sabha MPs from across the country were scheduled to vote in Parliament in Delhi.",
        "In this case, Prime Minister Modi cast ballots for the presidential election in the Delhi Parliament complex."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today, Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Democratic Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "543",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha MPs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "233",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරණය; ඉන්දීය අගමැති මෝදි ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා අද පෙරවරු 10 සිට රට පුරා ඡන්ද විමසීම් පැවැත්වෙනවා.",
        "අගමැති මෝදි ඇතුළු නායකයෝ දිල්ලියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ මැතිවරණයේ ඡන්ද විමසීම අද සඳුදා සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානයේ (BJP) අපේක්ෂකයා ලෙස ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ද විරුද්ධ පක්ෂයේ අපේක්ෂකයා ලෙස Yashwant Sinha ද ඉදිරිපත් වී ඇත.",
        "රට පුරා සිටින මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඡන්දය දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහා ඒ ඒ ප්‍රාන්තවල ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේදී ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට කටයුතු යොදා ඇත.",
        "ලෝක් සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 543 දෙනෙකු සහ රට පුරා සිටින රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 233 දෙනෙකු දිල්ලියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවේ දී, අගමැති මෝදි දිල්ලි පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද, සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "543",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "233",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் ; இந்திய பிரதமர் மோடி வாக்களித்தார்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்ய இன்று நாடு முழுவதும் காலை 10 மணி முதல் வாக்குப்பதிவு நடைப்பெற்று வருகிறது.",
        "டெல்லி பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலுக்கான வாக்குப்பதிவை பிரதமர் மோடி உள்ளிட்ட தலைவர்கள் செலுத்தினர்.",
        "இதையடுத்து புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்காக நடத்தப்படும் தேர்தலுக்கான வாக்குப்பதிவு இன்று திங்கட்கிழமை நடக்கிறது.",
        "அதன்படி தேசிய ஜனநாயக கூட்டணி (பா.ஜ.க கூட்டணி) வேட்பாளராக திரௌபதி முர்முவும், எதிர்க்கட்சி சார்பில் யஷ்வந்த் சின்காவும் வேட்பாளர்களாக களத்தில் உள்ளனர்.",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள எம்.பி, எம்.எல்.ஏ.க்கள் வாக்குசீட்டு முறையில் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்ய உள்ளனர்.",
        "எம்.எல்.ஏ.க்கள் ஓட்டு போடுவதற்காக அந்தந்த மாநிலங்களில் உள்ள தலைமை செயலகத்தில் வாக்குப்பதிவுக்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள 543 மக்களவை எம்.பி.க்களும், 233 மாநிலங்களவை எம்.பி.க்களும் டெல்லியில் உள்ள பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்களிக்க ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "இந்நிலையில் டெல்லி நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலுக்கான வாக்குபதிவினை பிரதமர் மோடி செலுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று, திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "543",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை எம்.பி.க்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "233",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜ்யசபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}