{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/01/sri-lanka-briefs-egypt-on-challenges/",
  "time_ut": 1662020160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka briefs Egypt on challenges",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka briefs Egypt on challenges",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ambassador of Egypt in Sri Lanka Maged Mosleh called on the Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Sabry yesterday (31) at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.",
        "Foreign Minister Sabry and Ambassador Mosleh held wide-ranging discussions related to the multi-faceted bilateral cooperation.",
        "Minister Sabry briefed Ambassador Mosleh on current developments, the challenges faced by the country, and measures taken by the Government to overcome these challenges.",
        "Current global developments and the possible impact on the two countries were also discussed.",
        "It was noted that the 65th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between Sri Lanka and Egypt will be fittingly celebrated next year.",
        "‘Stop trying to suppress Sirasa’ – Opposition Leader tells President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Egypt",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egypt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maged Mosleh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mosleh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mosleh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egypt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirasa’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඊජිප්තුව අභියෝග ගැන විස්තර කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඊජිප්තු තානාපති Maged Mosleh මහතා ඊයේ (31) විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ දී විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය Ali Sabry මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍ය Sabry සහ තානාපති Mosleh බහුවිධ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුළුල් සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීය.",
        "වත්මන් වර්ධනයන්, රට මුහුණ දී ඇති අභියෝග සහ මෙම අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා රජය ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය Sabry තානාපති Mosleh දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "වත්මන් ගෝලීය වර්ධනයන් සහ දෙරටට සිදුවිය හැකි බලපෑම පිළිබඳව ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඊජිප්තුව අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා ස්ථාපිත කිරීමේ 65 වැනි සංවත්සරය ලබන වසරේදී ඉතා යෝග්‍ය ලෙස සැමරීමට නියමිත බව මෙහිදී සඳහන් කෙරුණා.",
        "‘සිරස මර්ධනය කරන්න හදන එක නවත්වන්න’ – විපක්ෂ නායක ජනපතිට කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඊජිප්තුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැජිඩ් මොස්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරස'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எகிப்து சவால்களை இலங்கை விளக்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கைக்கான எகிப்து தூதுவர் மகேத் மொஸ்லே, வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியை நேற்று (31) வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சில் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "வெளியுறவு மந்திரி சப்ரி மற்றும் தூதர் மோஸ்லே ஆகியோர் பன்முக இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பு தொடர்பான விரிவான விவாதங்களை நடத்தினர்.",
        "தற்போதைய முன்னேற்றங்கள், நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்கள் மற்றும் இந்த சவால்களை சமாளிக்க அரசாங்கம் எடுத்துள்ள நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து தூதுவர் மொஸ்லேவிடம் அமைச்சர் சப்ரி விளக்கினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய உலக முன்னேற்றங்கள் மற்றும் இரு நாடுகளுக்கு ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகள் குறித்தும் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் எகிப்துக்கும் இடையிலான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளை ஸ்தாபித்ததன் 65வது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழா அடுத்த வருடம் சிறப்பாக கொண்டாடப்படும் என குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "‘சிரசவை ஒடுக்கும் முயற்சியை நிறுத்துங்கள்’ – எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எகிப்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிட் மோஸ்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோஸ்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோஸ்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிரச’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}