{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/05/unhrc-sri-lanka-will-not-accept-any-external-mechanism-foreign-minister/",
  "time_ut": 1662389520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UNHRC: Sri Lanka will not accept any external mechanism – Foreign Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNHRC: Sri Lanka will not accept any external mechanism – Foreign Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka will not agree to any external mechanism to inquire into its human rights issues.",
        "The country's Foreign Minister speaking to reporters in Colombo on Monday (5) said the constitution only allows for a domestic mechanism on Human Rights.",
        "The 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC) is scheduled to be held from September 12 to October 07, 2022 in Geneva.",
        "The progress made by Sri Lanka with respect to its Human Rights record, will be up for review.",
        "The Government of then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa rejected the proposal for any external initiatives purportedly established by the Resolution 46/1, which was adopted earlier.",
        "Foreign Minister Ali Sabry, PC & Justice Minister Dr. Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe will lead Sri Lanka's delgation to the UNHRC.",
        "\"Specific instructions have been given for engagement, we are looking at holistic solutions or lasting solutions for the problems or the grievances of all parties who have suffered the long term conflict in this country. Not one party but everyone,\" said the Foreign Minister.",
        "He aklso said that in an effort to build trust, the government of Sri Lanka is at the conceptualizing stages of establishing an overseas Sri Lankan Co-ordination Secretariat in Sri Lanka.",
        "Commenting on the UNHRC resolutions, the Foreing Minister said that any external mechanism will not be accepted, because our constitution doesn't allow for such external mechanism.",
        "He said that Sri Lanka would agree to any domestic mechanis, however it is a NO to external mechanisms on Sri Lanka's Human Rights record.",
        "UNHRC: Sri Lanka will not accept any external mechanism – Foreign Minister",
        "(VIDEO) School boy trapped in storm drain in Kurunegala, dies"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 12 to October 07, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Human Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Resolution 46/1",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PC & Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "UNHRC: ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කිසිදු බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයක් පිළිගන්නේ නැහැ - විදේශ ඇමති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය මානව හිමිකම් ප්‍රශ්න ගැන විමසීමට කිසිදු බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයකට එකඟ නොවනු ඇත.",
        "රටේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳුදා (5) කොළඹදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් අවසර දී ඇත්තේ මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ දේශීය යාන්ත්‍රණයකට පමණක් බවයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ (UNHRC) 51 වැනි සැසිවාරය 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 12 සිට ඔක්තෝබර් 07 දක්වා ජිනීවා නුවරදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "එහි මානව හිමිකම් වාර්තාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලබා ඇති ප්‍රගතිය සමාලෝචනයට ලක් වනු ඇත.",
        "කලින් සම්මත කරන ලද 46/1 යෝජනාව මගින් ස්ථාපිත කරන ලදැයි කියන බාහිර මුලපිරීම් සඳහා වූ යෝජනාව එවකට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ රජය විසින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලදී.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි, පළාත් සභා සහ අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ විසින් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිත කණ්ඩායමට නායකත්වය දෙනු ඇත.",
        "\"ගිවිස ගැනීම සඳහා නිශ්චිත උපදෙස් ලබා දී ඇත, අපි මේ රටේ දීර්ඝ කාලීන ගැටුම්වලට ගොදුරු වූ සියලුම පාර්ශ්වයන්ගේ ගැටලු හෝ දුක්ගැනවිලි සඳහා පරිපූර්ණ විසඳුම් හෝ කල්පවත්නා විසඳුම් සොයමින් සිටිමු. එක් පාර්ශ්වයක් නොව සෑම කෙනෙකුම,\" විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "විශ්වාසය ගොඩනැගීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ විදේශගත ශ්‍රී ලංකා සම්බන්ධීකරණ ලේකම් කාර්යාලයක් පිහිටුවීමේ සංකල්පීය අදියරේ සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ යෝජනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ එවැනි බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයකට අපගේ ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් ඉඩ නොදෙන බැවින් කිසිදු බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයක් පිළි නොගන්නා බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඕනෑම දේශීය යාන්ත්‍රික යන්ත්‍රයකට එකඟ වන නමුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මානව හිමිකම් වාර්තාවේ බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයන්ට එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "UNHRC: ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කිසිදු බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයක් පිළිගන්නේ නැහැ - විදේශ ඇමති",
        "(VIDEO) කුරුණෑගලදී වැසි කාණුවේ සිරවී පාසල් සිසුවා මරුට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 12 සිට ඔක්තෝබර් 07 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභේදනය 46/1",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UNHRC: இலங்கை எந்தவொரு வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறையையும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளாது – வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை தனது மனித உரிமைகள் பிரச்சினைகளை விசாரிப்பதற்கான எந்தவொரு வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறையையும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளாது.",
        "கொழும்பில் திங்கட்கிழமை (5) செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய நாட்டின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர், மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான உள்நாட்டுப் பொறிமுறையை மட்டுமே அரசியலமைப்பு அனுமதிக்கிறது.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் (UNHRC) 51வது அமர்வு 2022 செப்டம்பர் 12 முதல் அக்டோபர் 07, 2022 வரை ஜெனீவாவில் நடைபெற உள்ளது.",
        "மனித உரிமைகள் தொடர்பான இலங்கையின் முன்னேற்றம் மீளாய்வுக்கு உட்படுத்தப்படும்.",
        "அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் அரசாங்கம் முன்னர் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட 46/1 தீர்மானத்தின் மூலம் நிறுவப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் எந்தவொரு வெளிப்புற முயற்சிகளுக்கான முன்மொழிவையும் நிராகரித்தது.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி, பிசி மற்றும் நீதி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோர் ஐநா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவைக்கான இலங்கையின் தூதுக்குழுவிற்கு தலைமை தாங்குவார்கள்.",
        "\"நிச்சயதார்த்தத்திற்கு குறிப்பிட்ட அறிவுறுத்தல்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, இந்த நாட்டில் நீண்டகால மோதலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அனைத்து தரப்பினரின் பிரச்சினைகள் அல்லது குறைகளுக்கு முழுமையான தீர்வுகள் அல்லது நிரந்தர தீர்வுகளை நாங்கள் பார்க்கிறோம். ஒரு தரப்பினர் அல்ல, அனைவருக்கும்,\" என்று வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "நம்பிக்கையை கட்டியெழுப்பும் முயற்சியில், இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் இலங்கையில் வெளிநாட்டு இலங்கை ஒருங்கிணைப்பு செயலகத்தை நிறுவுவதற்கான கருத்தியல் கட்டத்தில் இருப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஐநா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் தீர்மானங்கள் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த அமைச்சர், எந்தவொரு வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறையும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட மாட்டாது, ஏனெனில் நமது அரசியலமைப்பு அத்தகைய வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறையை அனுமதிக்கவில்லை.",
        "எந்தவொரு உள்நாட்டு இயந்திரங்களுக்கும் இலங்கை இணங்கும் என்றும், எனினும் இலங்கையின் மனித உரிமைகள் பதிவில் வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறைகளுக்கு அது இல்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "UNHRC: இலங்கை எந்தவொரு வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறையையும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளாது – வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர்",
        "(வீடியோ) குருநாகலில் புயல் வடிகாலில் சிக்கிய பாடசாலை மாணவன் மரணம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 12 முதல் அக்டோபர் 07, 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீர்மானம் 46/1",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிசி & நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}