{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84635/all-individuals-aged-above-18-years-to-be-registered-with-ird",
  "time_ut": 1661849640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All individuals aged above 18 years to be registered with IRD",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All individuals aged above 18 years to be registered with IRD",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A proposal has been put forward to register all individuals aged above 18 years with the Inland Revenue Department (IRD).",
        "The decision was taken with the intention of increasing the efficiency of tax collection, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said today during his interim budget speech.",
        "He delivered the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill, for the remainder of the fiscal year 2022, to the parliament this afternoon.",
        "Speaking further, the Head of State said the country’s tax administration is required to play a major role to boost tax compliance and prevent tax evasion.",
        "According to him, the decision to register people aged above 18 years with the IRD was reached without taking into consideration the annual income or tax exemption limits."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "above 18 years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IRD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "above 18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inland Revenue Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the fiscal year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "above 18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි සියලුම පුද්ගලයින් IRD සමඟ ලියාපදිංචි විය යුතුය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වයස අවුරුදු 18ට වැඩි සියලුම පුද්ගලයින් දේශීය ආදායම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ (IRD) ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමේ යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත.",
        "බදු එකතු කිරීමේ කාර්යක්ෂමතාව ඉහළ නැංවීමේ අරමුණින් මෙම තීරණය ගත් බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද සිය අතුරු අයවැය කතාවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා වූ විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත ඔහු අද පස්වරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දැක්වූ රාජ්‍ය නායකයා කියා සිටියේ බදු අනුකූලතාව ඉහළ නැංවීමට සහ බදු පැහැර හැරීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා රටේ බදු පරිපාලනය විශාල කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "ඔහුට අනුව, අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින් IRD සමඟ ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ වාර්ෂික ආදායම හෝ බදු නිදහස් කිරීමේ සීමාවන් සැලකිල්ලට නොගෙන ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IRD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශීය ආදායම් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட அனைத்து நபர்களும் IRD இல் பதிவு செய்யப்பட வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட அனைத்து நபர்களையும் உள்நாட்டு வருவாய்த் திணைக்களத்தில் (IRD) பதிவு செய்வதற்கான முன்மொழிவு முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வரி அறவீடுகளின் வினைத்திறனை அதிகரிக்கும் நோக்கில் இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று தனது இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத்திட்ட உரையின் போது தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் எஞ்சிய நிதியாண்டுக்கான ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்தம்) சட்டமூலத்தை அவர் இன்று பிற்பகல் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பித்தார்.",
        "மேலும் பேசிய அரச தலைவர், வரி இணக்கத்தை அதிகரிக்கவும், வரி ஏய்ப்பைத் தடுக்கவும் நாட்டின் வரி நிர்வாகம் முக்கியப் பங்காற்ற வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "அவரைப் பொறுத்தவரை, ஆண்டு வருமானம் அல்லது வரி விலக்கு வரம்புகளைக் கருத்தில் கொள்ளாமல் 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்களை IRD இல் பதிவு செய்வதற்கான முடிவு எட்டப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18 வயதுக்கு மேல்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IRD",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18 வயதுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு இறைவரி திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 வயதுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IRD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}