{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SriLankan-Airlines-Cares-airlifts-critical-medicine-to-Sri-Lanka/56-736655",
  "time_ut": 1656096114,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SriLankan Airlines’ Cares airlifts critical medicine to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SriLankan Airlines’ Cares airlifts critical medicine to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Critical medicine consignments flown to Sri Lanka with the help of SriLankan Cares",
        "SriLankan Cares has taken the cause of airlifting internationally donated essential medicines and medical equipment to hospitals in Sri Lanka, free of freight charges.",
        "The corporate social responsibility arm of SriLankan Airlines aims to provide timely relief to hospitals that are struggling to cope with the ongoing drug shortage and patients who depend on life-saving medicines in the country through the initiative.",
        "Consequently, SriLankan Cares will continue to airlift emergency medical supplies that have been generously donated by well-wishers from all corners of the world including France, Indonesia, the United Kingdom, Malaysia, Kuwait, and Nepal. The medical supplies would be flown free of freight charges courtesy of SriLankan Airlines and distributed to medical establishments such as the Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children on an ongoing basis.",
        "SriLankan Cares facilitates the project by organising the logistics of the consignments from various points of origin by obtaining necessary documents and approvals that help fast-track the process.",
        "Time and again, SriLankan Cares has risen to the occasion to aid those in need, especially children. The healthcare sector in Sri Lanka is currently facing its most acute medicine shortage in the history of the country, putting at peril the very lives of those who depend on its services. In view of these circumstances, SriLankan Cares’ compassionate move to bring vital medication to the sick and vulnerable is truly an opportune and life-saving intervention.",
        "The community development arm of the airline, SriLankan Cares actively participates in fundraising and charity activities, with its main focus being the empowerment of children. SriLankan Cares has carried out major development projects in three rural schools in the country, providing buildings and infrastructure such as classrooms, libraries, and computer labs."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SriLankan Airlines’ Cares",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuwait",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nepal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් හි කෙයාර්ස් ගුවන් මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විවේචනාත්මක ඖෂධ ගෙන එයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් හි සහාය ඇතිව විවේචනාත්මක ඖෂධ තොග ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පියාසර කරන ලදී",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තරව පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තුවලින් තොරව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රෝහල් වෙත ගුවන් මගින් ගෙන ඒමේ කාර්යය ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමේ ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම් අංශයේ අරමුණ වන්නේ රට තුළ පවතින ඖෂධ හිඟයට මුහුණ දීමට අරගල කරන රෝහල්වලට සහ ජීවිතාරක්ෂක ඖෂධවලින් යැපෙන රෝගීන්ට කාලීන සහන සැලසීමයි.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් වශයෙන්, ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් ප්‍රංශය, ඉන්දුනීසියාව, එක්සත් රාජධානිය, මැලේසියාව, කුවේට් සහ නේපාලය ඇතුළු ලෝකයේ සෑම කොනකින්ම ශුභසිද්ධීන් විසින් නොමසුරුව පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද හදිසි වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් ගුවන් මගින් අඛණ්ඩව ගෙන යනු ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ අනුග්‍රහය ඇතිව භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු වලින් තොරව වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් පියාසර කරන අතර රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහල වැනි වෛද්‍ය ආයතන වෙත අඛණ්ඩව බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් අවශ්‍ය ලියකියවිලි සහ ක්‍රියාවලිය වේගවත් කිරීමට උපකාරී වන අනුමැතිය ලබා ගනිමින් විවිධ මූලාශ‍්‍රවලින් තොගවල ලොජිස්ටික් සංවිධානය කරමින් ව්‍යාපෘතියට පහසුකම් සපයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් අවශ්‍යතා ඇති අයට, විශේෂයෙන්ම දරුවන්ට උපකාර කිරීමට නැවත නැවතත් අවස්ථාවට පැමිණ ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍රය මේ වන විට රටේ ඉතිහාසයේ උග්‍රතම ඖෂධ හිඟයට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටින අතර, එහි සේවාවන් මත යැපෙන අයගේ ජීවිත පවා අනතුරේ හෙළයි. මෙම තත්ත්වයන් හමුවේ, ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් හි රෝගී සහ අවදානමට ලක්වූවන් සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ ගෙන ඒම සඳහා ගෙන යන දයානුකම්පිත පියවර සැබවින්ම සුදුසු සහ ජීවිතාරක්ෂක මැදිහත්වීමකි.",
        "ගුවන් සේවයේ ප්‍රජා සංවර්ධන අංශය වන ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් අරමුදල් රැස්කිරීමේ සහ පුණ්‍ය කටයුතු සඳහා සක්‍රීයව සහභාගී වන අතර එහි ප්‍රධාන අවධානය දරුවන් සවිබල ගැන්වීමයි. ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් දිවයිනේ ග්‍රාමීය පාසල් තුනක ප්‍රධාන සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති සිදු කර ඇති අතර, පන්ති කාමර, පුස්තකාල සහ පරිගණක විද්‍යාගාර වැනි ගොඩනැගිලි සහ යටිතල පහසුකම් සපයා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ සත්කාර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුවේට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේපාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ළමුන් සඳහා රිජ්වේ ආර්යා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் கேர்ஸ் முக்கியமான மருந்துகளை இலங்கைக்கு விமானம் மூலம் அனுப்புகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸின் உதவியுடன் முக்கியமான மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் இலங்கைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டன",
        "சர்வதேச ரீதியில் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்படும் அத்தியாவசிய மருந்துகள் மற்றும் மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களை சரக்குக் கட்டணங்கள் இன்றி இலங்கையில் உள்ள மருத்துவமனைகளுக்கு விமானத்தில் கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் நிறுவனம் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் சமூகப் பொறுப்புணர்வுப் பிரிவானது, நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் மருந்துப் பற்றாக்குறையைச் சமாளிக்க முடியாமல் தவிக்கும் மருத்துவமனைகளுக்கும், உயிர்காக்கும் மருந்துகளை நம்பியிருக்கும் நோயாளிகளுக்கும் உரிய நேரத்தில் நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன் விளைவாக, பிரான்ஸ், இந்தோனேஷியா, ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம், மலேசியா, குவைத் மற்றும் நேபாளம் உட்பட உலகின் அனைத்து மூலைகளிலிருந்தும் நலம் விரும்பிகளால் தாராளமாக நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட அவசரகால மருத்துவப் பொருட்களை ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் தொடர்ந்து விமானத்தில் அனுப்பும். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் உபசாரத்தின் மூலம் மருத்துவப் பொருட்கள் சரக்குக் கட்டணமின்றி பறக்கவிடப்படும் மற்றும் குழந்தைகளுக்கான லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனை போன்ற மருத்துவ நிறுவனங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து விநியோகிக்கப்படும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ், தேவையான ஆவணங்கள் மற்றும் ஒப்புதல்களைப் பெற்று, செயல்முறையை விரைவாகக் கண்காணிக்க உதவும் பல்வேறு மூலங்களிலிருந்து சரக்குகளின் தளவாடங்களை ஒழுங்கமைப்பதன் மூலம் திட்டத்தை எளிதாக்குகிறது.",
        "மீண்டும் மீண்டும், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் தேவைப்படுபவர்களுக்கு, குறிப்பாக குழந்தைகளுக்கு உதவும் சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் உயர்ந்துள்ளது. இலங்கையின் சுகாதாரப் பாதுகாப்புத் துறையானது தற்போது நாட்டின் வரலாற்றில் மிகக் கடுமையான மருந்துப் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொண்டு, அதன் சேவைகளை நம்பி வாழ்பவர்களின் வாழ்க்கையையே ஆபத்தில் ஆழ்த்தியுள்ளது. இந்தச் சூழ்நிலைகளைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட மற்றும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடியவர்களுக்கு இன்றியமையாத மருந்துகளைக் கொண்டுவருவதற்கான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸின் கருணையுடன் கூடிய நடவடிக்கை உண்மையிலேயே ஒரு சந்தர்ப்பமான மற்றும் உயிர்காக்கும் தலையீடு ஆகும்.",
        "விமான சேவையின் சமூக மேம்பாட்டுப் பிரிவான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் நிதி சேகரிப்பு மற்றும் தொண்டு நடவடிக்கைகளில் தீவிரமாக பங்கேற்கிறது, அதன் முக்கிய கவனம் குழந்தைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதாகும். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் நாட்டில் உள்ள மூன்று கிராமப்புறப் பள்ளிகளில், கட்டிடங்கள் மற்றும் வகுப்பறைகள், நூலகங்கள் மற்றும் கணினி ஆய்வகங்கள் போன்ற உள்கட்டமைப்புகளை வழங்கும் பெரிய வளர்ச்சித் திட்டங்களை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் கேர்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவைத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேபாளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளுக்கான லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "SriLankan Airlines’ Cares airlifts critical medicine to Sri Lanka",
  "body_lines": [
    "Critical medicine consignments flown to Sri Lanka with the help of SriLankan Cares",
    "SriLankan Cares has taken the cause of airlifting internationally donated essential medicines and medical equipment to hospitals in Sri Lanka, free of freight charges.",
    "The corporate social responsibility arm of SriLankan Airlines aims to provide timely relief to hospitals that are struggling to cope with the ongoing drug shortage and patients who depend on life-saving medicines in the country through the initiative.",
    "Consequently, SriLankan Cares will continue to airlift emergency medical supplies that have been generously donated by well-wishers from all corners of the world including France, Indonesia, the United Kingdom, Malaysia, Kuwait, and Nepal. The medical supplies would be flown free of freight charges courtesy of SriLankan Airlines and distributed to medical establishments such as the Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children on an ongoing basis.",
    "SriLankan Cares facilitates the project by organising the logistics of the consignments from various points of origin by obtaining necessary documents and approvals that help fast-track the process.",
    "Time and again, SriLankan Cares has risen to the occasion to aid those in need, especially children. The healthcare sector in Sri Lanka is currently facing its most acute medicine shortage in the history of the country, putting at peril the very lives of those who depend on its services. In view of these circumstances, SriLankan Cares’ compassionate move to bring vital medication to the sick and vulnerable is truly an opportune and life-saving intervention.",
    "The community development arm of the airline, SriLankan Cares actively participates in fundraising and charity activities, with its main focus being the empowerment of children. SriLankan Cares has carried out major development projects in three rural schools in the country, providing buildings and infrastructure such as classrooms, libraries, and computer labs."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SriLankan Airlines’ Cares airlifts critical medicine to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Critical medicine consignments flown to Sri Lanka with the help of SriLankan Cares",
        "SriLankan Cares has taken the cause of airlifting internationally donated essential medicines and medical equipment to hospitals in Sri Lanka, free of freight charges.",
        "The corporate social responsibility arm of SriLankan Airlines aims to provide timely relief to hospitals that are struggling to cope with the ongoing drug shortage and patients who depend on life-saving medicines in the country through the initiative.",
        "Consequently, SriLankan Cares will continue to airlift emergency medical supplies that have been generously donated by well-wishers from all corners of the world including France, Indonesia, the United Kingdom, Malaysia, Kuwait, and Nepal. The medical supplies would be flown free of freight charges courtesy of SriLankan Airlines and distributed to medical establishments such as the Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children on an ongoing basis.",
        "SriLankan Cares facilitates the project by organising the logistics of the consignments from various points of origin by obtaining necessary documents and approvals that help fast-track the process.",
        "Time and again, SriLankan Cares has risen to the occasion to aid those in need, especially children. The healthcare sector in Sri Lanka is currently facing its most acute medicine shortage in the history of the country, putting at peril the very lives of those who depend on its services. In view of these circumstances, SriLankan Cares’ compassionate move to bring vital medication to the sick and vulnerable is truly an opportune and life-saving intervention.",
        "The community development arm of the airline, SriLankan Cares actively participates in fundraising and charity activities, with its main focus being the empowerment of children. SriLankan Cares has carried out major development projects in three rural schools in the country, providing buildings and infrastructure such as classrooms, libraries, and computer labs."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SriLankan Airlines’ Cares",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuwait",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nepal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Cares",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් හි කෙයාර්ස් ගුවන් මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විවේචනාත්මක ඖෂධ ගෙන එයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් හි සහාය ඇතිව විවේචනාත්මක ඖෂධ තොග ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පියාසර කරන ලදී",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තරව පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ සහ වෛද්‍ය උපකරණ භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තුවලින් තොරව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රෝහල් වෙත ගුවන් මගින් ගෙන ඒමේ කාර්යය ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමේ ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම් අංශයේ අරමුණ වන්නේ රට තුළ පවතින ඖෂධ හිඟයට මුහුණ දීමට අරගල කරන රෝහල්වලට සහ ජීවිතාරක්ෂක ඖෂධවලින් යැපෙන රෝගීන්ට කාලීන සහන සැලසීමයි.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් වශයෙන්, ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් ප්‍රංශය, ඉන්දුනීසියාව, එක්සත් රාජධානිය, මැලේසියාව, කුවේට් සහ නේපාලය ඇතුළු ලෝකයේ සෑම කොනකින්ම ශුභසිද්ධීන් විසින් නොමසුරුව පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද හදිසි වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් ගුවන් මගින් අඛණ්ඩව ගෙන යනු ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ අනුග්‍රහය ඇතිව භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු වලින් තොරව වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් පියාසර කරන අතර රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහල වැනි වෛද්‍ය ආයතන වෙත අඛණ්ඩව බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් අවශ්‍ය ලියකියවිලි සහ ක්‍රියාවලිය වේගවත් කිරීමට උපකාරී වන අනුමැතිය ලබා ගනිමින් විවිධ මූලාශ‍්‍රවලින් තොගවල ලොජිස්ටික් සංවිධානය කරමින් ව්‍යාපෘතියට පහසුකම් සපයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් අවශ්‍යතා ඇති අයට, විශේෂයෙන්ම දරුවන්ට උපකාර කිරීමට නැවත නැවතත් අවස්ථාවට පැමිණ ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍රය මේ වන විට රටේ ඉතිහාසයේ උග්‍රතම ඖෂධ හිඟයට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටින අතර, එහි සේවාවන් මත යැපෙන අයගේ ජීවිත පවා අනතුරේ හෙළයි. මෙම තත්ත්වයන් හමුවේ, ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් හි රෝගී සහ අවදානමට ලක්වූවන් සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධ ගෙන ඒම සඳහා ගෙන යන දයානුකම්පිත පියවර සැබවින්ම සුදුසු සහ ජීවිතාරක්ෂක මැදිහත්වීමකි.",
        "ගුවන් සේවයේ ප්‍රජා සංවර්ධන අංශය වන ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් අරමුදල් රැස්කිරීමේ සහ පුණ්‍ය කටයුතු සඳහා සක්‍රීයව සහභාගී වන අතර එහි ප්‍රධාන අවධානය දරුවන් සවිබල ගැන්වීමයි. ශ්‍රීලංකන් කෙයාර්ස් විසින් දිවයිනේ ග්‍රාමීය පාසල් තුනක ප්‍රධාන සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති සිදු කර ඇති අතර, පන්ති කාමර, පුස්තකාල සහ පරිගණක විද්‍යාගාර වැනි ගොඩනැගිලි සහ යටිතල පහසුකම් සපයා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයේ සත්කාර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුවේට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේපාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ළමුන් සඳහා රිජ්වේ ආර්යා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කෙයාර්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் கேர்ஸ் முக்கியமான மருந்துகளை இலங்கைக்கு விமானம் மூலம் அனுப்புகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸின் உதவியுடன் முக்கியமான மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் இலங்கைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டன",
        "சர்வதேச ரீதியில் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்படும் அத்தியாவசிய மருந்துகள் மற்றும் மருத்துவ உபகரணங்களை சரக்குக் கட்டணங்கள் இன்றி இலங்கையில் உள்ள மருத்துவமனைகளுக்கு விமானத்தில் கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் நிறுவனம் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸின் சமூகப் பொறுப்புணர்வுப் பிரிவானது, நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் மருந்துப் பற்றாக்குறையைச் சமாளிக்க முடியாமல் தவிக்கும் மருத்துவமனைகளுக்கும், உயிர்காக்கும் மருந்துகளை நம்பியிருக்கும் நோயாளிகளுக்கும் உரிய நேரத்தில் நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன் விளைவாக, பிரான்ஸ், இந்தோனேஷியா, ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம், மலேசியா, குவைத் மற்றும் நேபாளம் உட்பட உலகின் அனைத்து மூலைகளிலிருந்தும் நலம் விரும்பிகளால் தாராளமாக நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட அவசரகால மருத்துவப் பொருட்களை ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் தொடர்ந்து விமானத்தில் அனுப்பும். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் உபசாரத்தின் மூலம் மருத்துவப் பொருட்கள் சரக்குக் கட்டணமின்றி பறக்கவிடப்படும் மற்றும் குழந்தைகளுக்கான லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனை போன்ற மருத்துவ நிறுவனங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து விநியோகிக்கப்படும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ், தேவையான ஆவணங்கள் மற்றும் ஒப்புதல்களைப் பெற்று, செயல்முறையை விரைவாகக் கண்காணிக்க உதவும் பல்வேறு மூலங்களிலிருந்து சரக்குகளின் தளவாடங்களை ஒழுங்கமைப்பதன் மூலம் திட்டத்தை எளிதாக்குகிறது.",
        "மீண்டும் மீண்டும், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் தேவைப்படுபவர்களுக்கு, குறிப்பாக குழந்தைகளுக்கு உதவும் சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் உயர்ந்துள்ளது. இலங்கையின் சுகாதாரப் பாதுகாப்புத் துறையானது தற்போது நாட்டின் வரலாற்றில் மிகக் கடுமையான மருந்துப் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொண்டு, அதன் சேவைகளை நம்பி வாழ்பவர்களின் வாழ்க்கையையே ஆபத்தில் ஆழ்த்தியுள்ளது. இந்தச் சூழ்நிலைகளைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட மற்றும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடியவர்களுக்கு இன்றியமையாத மருந்துகளைக் கொண்டுவருவதற்கான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸின் கருணையுடன் கூடிய நடவடிக்கை உண்மையிலேயே ஒரு சந்தர்ப்பமான மற்றும் உயிர்காக்கும் தலையீடு ஆகும்.",
        "விமான சேவையின் சமூக மேம்பாட்டுப் பிரிவான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் நிதி சேகரிப்பு மற்றும் தொண்டு நடவடிக்கைகளில் தீவிரமாக பங்கேற்கிறது, அதன் முக்கிய கவனம் குழந்தைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதாகும். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ் நாட்டில் உள்ள மூன்று கிராமப்புறப் பள்ளிகளில், கட்டிடங்கள் மற்றும் வகுப்பறைகள், நூலகங்கள் மற்றும் கணினி ஆய்வகங்கள் போன்ற உள்கட்டமைப்புகளை வழங்கும் பெரிய வளர்ச்சித் திட்டங்களை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸின் கேர்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவைத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேபாளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளுக்கான லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}