{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79204",
  "time_ut": 1661540220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "“I can’t speak like I used to on certain issues as there is a risk of the suspended prison sentence against me being reactivated and me being sent back to prison for a further five years,” says   Ranjan  Ramanayake",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "“I can’t speak like I used to on certain issues as there is a risk of the suspended prison sentence against me being reactivated and me being sent back to prison for a further five years,” says   Ranjan  Ramanayake",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "After serving one year and seven months of a four-year prison sentence, popular actor and former Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP Ranjan Ramanayake walked out of the Welikada Prison and into the arms of an adoring crowd on Friday (26).",
        "Mr Ramanayake walked out a free man after President Ranil Wickremesinghe granted a conditional presidential pardon. He was escorted out through the gates of the prison by Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa and other SJB MPs.",
        "Also present was Minister of Labour and Foreign Employment Manusha Nanayakkara. Mr Nanayakkara and Tourism and Lands Minister Harin Fernando, who had defected from the opposition to assume ministerial positions in the government several months ago, had insisted on granting a presidential pardon to Mr Ramanayake as one of the conditions for joining the government.",
        "The popular film star was mobbed and garlanded by fans, well-wishers and SJB supporters who had showed up outside the prison in large numbers. They were far less charitable towards Minister Nanayakkara who had to make a hasty exit after being booed by the crowd.",
        "Mr Ramanayake was sentenced to four years in prison in January last year after the Supreme Court found him guilty of contempt of court.",
        "The President’s Media Division stated that Mr Ramanayake had been granted a presidential pardon after he signed a sworn affidavit apologising to the judiciary and promising to never again make any statement or indulge in any action that could be construed as being in contempt of court.",
        "Addressing journalists alongside Mr Ramanayake at the Opposition Leader’s office later in the day, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa said he notes with regret that Mr Ramanayake’s presidential pardon is a conditional one that prevents him from holdng political office.",
        "The SJB had earlier considered appointing Mr Ramanayake to Parliament via the National List at the earliest opportunity.",
        "“I can’t speak like I used to on certain issues as there is a risk of the suspended prison sentence against me being reactivated and me being sent back to prison for a further five years,” Mr Ramanayake told the media.",
        "“I am built to always speak the truth, but I can’t do that anymore. I have to practise some self-censorship now,” he added. He thanked President Wickremesinghe for releasing him. He also thanked Mr Premadasa and all those who lobbied hard to ensure his release.",
        "Mr Ramanayake was taken for a medical checkup yesterday. He is currently living at the Madiwela MPs’ housing complex in the unit belonging to Minister Manusha Nanayakkara. The minister has also appointed Mr Ramanayake as a goodwill ambassador for migrant workers.",
        "Mr Premadasa meanwhile, tweeted yesterday that Mr Ramanayake will be appointed to the SJB’s Working Committee and be made a member of the party’s Parliamentary group. “He will also spearhead the anti corruption effort of the SJB,” Mr Premadasa said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "a further five years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan  Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "one year and seven months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Prison",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "several months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a further five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Working Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "“මට එරෙහි අත්හිටවූ සිරදඬුවම් යළි ක්‍රියාත්මක වී තවත් වසර පහකට මාව නැවත සිරගෙට යැවීමේ අවදානමක් පවතින නිසා ඇතැම් ප්‍රශ්න සම්බන්ධයෙන් මට කතා කරන්න බැහැ.” රන්ජන් රාමනායක පවසයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර හතරයි මාස හතක සිර දඬුවමකින් පසු ජනප්‍රිය නළු සහ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා සිකුරාදා (26) වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටතට ගොස් ප්‍රේක්ෂක ජනකායකගේ තුරුලට ගියේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාවක් ලබා දීමෙන් පසු රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් මිනිසෙකු පිටව ගියේය. විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇතුළු SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් ඔහුව බන්ධනාගාරයේ ගේට්ටුවෙන් පිටතට කැටුව ගියේය.",
        "කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියේය. නානායක්කාර සහ සංචාරක හා ඉඩම් ඇමැති හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මීට මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර ආණ්ඩුවේ ඇමැතිකම් ගැනීමට විපක්ෂයෙන් ඉවත් වූ අතර රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දෙන ලෙස රජයට එක්වීමට එක් කොන්දේසියක් ලෙස අවධාරණය කර තිබුණි.",
        "ජනප්‍රිය චිත්‍රපට තරුව විශාල වශයෙන් බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටත පැමිණ සිටි රසිකයන්, ශුභසිද්ධියන් සහ SJB ආධාරකරුවන් විසින් මැර ප්‍රහාරයට ලක් කර මල්මාලා පැළඳ සිටියහ. සෙනඟගේ ඔල්වරසන් දීමෙන් පසු කඩිමුඩියේ පිටව යාමට සිදු වූ නානායක්කාර ඇමතිවරයා කෙරෙහි ඔවුන් දැක්වූ කරුණාව බෙහෙවින් අඩුය.",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් වරදකරු බව තීරණය කිරීමෙන් පසු රාමනායක මහතාට පසුගිය වසරේ ජනවාරි මාසයේදී වසර හතරක සිර දඬුවමක් නියම විය.",
        "රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් අත්සන් කිරීමෙන් පසු නැවත කිසි දිනෙක අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමක් ලෙස අර්ථ දැක්විය හැකි කිසිදු ප්‍රකාශයක් හෝ කිසිඳු ක්‍රියාවක නොයෙදෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වීමෙන් පසු රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව හිමි වූ බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පසුව පස්වරුවේ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී රාමනායක මහතා සමඟ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ රාමනායක මහතාගේ ජනාධිපති සමාව ඔහුට දේශපාලන තනතුරු දැරීමට නොහැකි කොන්දේසි සහිත එකක් බව කණගාටුවෙන් යුතුව සඳහන් කරන බවයි.",
        "රාමනායක මහතා ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් හැකි ඉක්මනින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත් කිරීමට SJB මීට පෙර සලකා බලා තිබුණි.",
        "\"මට එරෙහිව අත්හිටවූ සිරදඬුවම් නැවත සක්‍රිය කර මා තවත් වසර පහකට සිරගෙට යැවීමේ අවදානමක් පවතින බැවින් ඇතැම් ප්‍රශ්න සම්බන්ධයෙන් මට වෙනදා මෙන් කතා කළ නොහැක\" යනුවෙන් රාමනායක මහතා මාධ්‍ය වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "“මම ගොඩනඟා ඇත්තේ සෑම විටම සත්‍යය කථා කිරීමටයි, නමුත් මට තවදුරටත් එය කළ නොහැක. මට දැන් ස්වයං වාරණයක් ප්‍රගුණ කරන්න වෙනවා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. තමන්ව නිදහස් කර ගැනීම පිළිබඳව ඔහු ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය. ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාට සහ ඔහුව නිදහස් කර ගැනීම සඳහා දැඩි ලෙස බලපෑම් කළ සියලු දෙනාට ඔහු ස්තූතිය පුද කළේය.",
        "රාමනායක මහතා වෛද්‍ය පරීක්‍ෂණයක් සඳහා ඊයේ රැගෙන ගියේය. ඔහු දැනට පදිංචිව සිටින්නේ අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතාට අයත් මාදිවෙල මන්ත්‍රී නිවාස සංකීර්ණයේය. අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් විගමණික ශ්‍රමිකයින් සඳහා සුහද තානාපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස ද රාමනායක මහතා පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඊයේ ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ රාමනායක මහතා SJB කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලයට පත් කර පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායමේ සාමාජිකයෙකු බවට පත් කරන බවයි. \"ඔහු SJB හි දූෂණ විරෝධී ප්‍රයත්නයට ද නායකත්වය දෙනු ඇත,\" ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තවත් වසර පහක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුද්දයි මාස හතයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තවත් වසර පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"எனக்கு எதிரான இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்ட சிறைத்தண்டனை மீண்டும் செயற்படுத்தப்பட்டு மேலும் ஐந்து வருடங்கள் சிறைக்கு அனுப்பப்படும் அபாயம் இருப்பதால் சில விடயங்களில் என்னால் பழையபடி பேச முடியாது\" என ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "நான்கு வருட சிறைத்தண்டனையின் ஒரு வருடமும் ஏழு மாதங்களும் அனுபவித்த பின்னர், பிரபல நடிகரும் முன்னாள் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையிலிருந்து வெள்ளியன்று (26) வெளியேறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பை வழங்கியதையடுத்து திரு ராமநாயக்க சுதந்திரமான மனிதராக வெளியேறினார். எதிர்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் ஏனைய SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் சிறைச்சாலையின் வாயில்கள் ஊடாக அவர் வெளியே அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டார்.",
        "தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்காரவும் கலந்துகொண்டார். திரு நாணயக்கார மற்றும் சுற்றுலா மற்றும் காணி அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோர் அரசாங்கத்தில் அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்வதற்காக எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இருந்து விலகியவர்கள், அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைவதற்கான நிபந்தனைகளில் ஒன்றாக திரு ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "சிறைக்கு வெளியே ஏராளமான ரசிகர்கள், நலன் விரும்பிகள் மற்றும் SJB ஆதரவாளர்களால் கும்பல் கும்பல் மற்றும் மாலை அணிவிக்கப்பட்டார். அவர்கள் அமைச்சர் நாணயக்காரவிடம் அறப்போராட்டத்தில் மிகவும் குறைவாகவே இருந்தனர்.",
        "நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்கில் உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் குற்றவாளி என கடந்த ஆண்டு ஜனவரி மாதம் ராமநாயக்காவுக்கு நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நீதித்துறையிடம் மன்னிப்புக் கோரும் பிரமாணப் பத்திரத்தில் திரு ராமநாயக்க கையொப்பமிட்டதையடுத்து, நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதிக்கும் வகையிலான எந்தவொரு கருத்தையும் மீண்டும் வெளியிடவோ அல்லது எந்த நடவடிக்கையிலும் ஈடுபடவோ மாட்டோம் என உறுதியளித்ததையடுத்து, அவருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிற்பகல் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் திரு ராமநாயக்கவுடன் ஊடகவியலாளர்களிடம் உரையாற்றிய எதிர்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, திரு ராமநாயக்கவின் ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு நிபந்தனைக்குட்பட்ட ஒன்று, அரசியல் பதவியில் இருந்து அவரைத் தடுக்கிறது என்பதை வருத்தத்துடன் குறிப்பிடுவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ ராமநாயக்கவை தேசியப் பட்டியல் ஊடாக பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிப்பது குறித்து SJB முன்னர் பரிசீலித்திருந்தது.",
        "\"எனக்கு எதிரான இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்ட சிறைத்தண்டனை மீண்டும் செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டு, மேலும் ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளுக்கு என்னை மீண்டும் சிறைக்கு அனுப்பும் அபாயம் இருப்பதால், சில விஷயங்களில் நான் முன்பு போல் பேச முடியாது\" என்று திரு ராமநாயக்க ஊடகங்களுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நான் எப்போதும் உண்மையைப் பேசக் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்டிருக்கிறேன், ஆனால் என்னால் அதை இனி செய்ய முடியாது. நான் இப்போது சில சுய தணிக்கை பயிற்சி செய்ய வேண்டும், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். தம்மை விடுவித்த ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு அவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார். திரு பிரேமதாச மற்றும் அவரது விடுதலையை உறுதி செய்ய கடுமையாகப் போராடிய அனைவருக்கும் அவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ராமநாயக்க நேற்று மருத்துவ பரிசோதனைக்காக அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டார். அவர் தற்போது அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்காரவுக்கு சொந்தமான மடிவெல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வீட்டுத் தொகுதியில் வசித்து வருகிறார். அமைச்சர் திரு ராமநாயக்கவை புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்களுக்கான நல்லெண்ண தூதராக நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஸ்ரீ ராமநாயக்க SJB இன் செயற்குழுவில் நியமிக்கப்படுவார் என்றும் கட்சியின் நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுவில் உறுப்பினராக்கப்படுவார் என்றும் திரு பிரேமதாச நேற்று ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார். \"SJB இன் ஊழல் எதிர்ப்பு முயற்சிக்கும் அவர் தலைமை தாங்குவார்\" என்று திரு பிரேமதாச கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்னும் ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் ஏழு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}