{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/19/rajapaksas-still-have-a-mandate-sanath-nishantha/",
  "time_ut": 1660920420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rajapaksas still have a mandate – Sanath Nishantha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rajapaksas still have a mandate – Sanath Nishantha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The mandate of 6.9 million people is still with the Rajapaksas, says SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha.",
        "A group of SLPP MPs who were former ministers held a discussion with the National Organizer of the party, Basil Rajapaksa, at the Nelum Mawatha party headquarters today (19).",
        "SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha said that he will accept a Ministerial position if it was given, however due to a National Government being formed, many parties would need to be involved.",
        "Moreover, with regard to the possible return of Rajapaksas into politics and the people's discomfort of them, MP Nishantha said that the mandate of over 6.9 million people lies in the hands of Rajapaksas, therefore they too have the right to return to politics.",
        "Army Chief Pays His First Formal Courtesy Call on New President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Organizer of the party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelum Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජපක්ෂලාට තාම ජනවරමක් තියෙනවා - සනත් නිශාන්ත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ලක්ෂ 69ක ජනවරම තවමත් රාජපක්ෂලා ළඟ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා පවසයි.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරුන් ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් එම පක්ෂයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සමඟ අද (19) නෙළුම් මාවත පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේදී සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අමාත්‍ය ධුරයක් ලබාදුනහොත් තමන් භාරගන්නා බවත් කෙසේ වෙතත් ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම හේතුවෙන් ඊට පක්ෂ රැසක් සම්බන්ධ කර ගැනීමට සිදුවන බවයි.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, රාජපක්ෂවරුන් යළි දේශපාලනයට පැමිණීමට ඇති ඉඩකඩ සහ ඔවුන්ගෙන් ඇති වන අපහසුතාවයන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද නිශාන්ත මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ ලක්ෂ 69කට අධික ජනතාවගේ ජනවරම ඇත්තේ රාජපක්ෂවරුන් අත බැවින් ඔවුන්ටද නැවත දේශපාලනයට පැමිණීමේ අයිතිය ඇති බවයි.",
        "යුධ හමුදාපති නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත සිය ප්‍රථම නිල ආචාරය සිදු කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙළුම් මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 ඉක්මවයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ராஜபக்சக்களுக்கு இன்னும் ஆணை உள்ளது – சனத் நிஷாந்த",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 6.9 மில்லியன் மக்களின் ஆணை இன்னும் ராஜபக்சக்களிடம் உள்ளது என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்களாக இருந்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவொன்று, கட்சியின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவுடன் இன்று (19) நெலும் மாவத்தை கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தில் கலந்துரையாடல் ஒன்றை நடத்தியது.",
        "அமைச்சுப் பதவி வழங்கப்படுமாயின் அதனை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வேன் எனவும் எனினும் தேசிய அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படுவதால் பல கட்சிகள் இதில் ஈடுபட வேண்டியிருக்கும் எனவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், ராஜபக்சக்கள் மீண்டும் அரசியலுக்கு வருவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் மற்றும் அவர்களால் மக்களுக்கு ஏற்பட்டுள்ள அசௌகரியங்கள் தொடர்பில், 6.9 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்களின் ஆணை ராஜபக்ஷக்களின் கைகளிலேயே உள்ளது, எனவே அவர்களும் அரசியலுக்கு வருவதற்கு உரிமை உண்டு என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நிஷாந்த தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை இராணுவத் தளபதி தனது முதல் முறையான மரியாதைக்குரிய சந்திப்பைச் செய்தார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்சியின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெலும் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}