{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/நாமலின்-யோசனையை-நிராகரித்த-பங்காளிகள்/175-299643",
  "time_ut": 1656851943,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நாமலின் யோசனையை நிராகரித்த பங்காளிகள்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Partners rejected Namal's idea",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to political sources, nine partner parties have rejected the idea put forward by Namal Rajapaksa, Member of Parliament of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, to change the government and form a new government together.",
        "Namal MP expressed this idea in a separate meeting with former minister and Member of Parliament Vasudeva Nanayakkara.",
        "It is reported that Vasudeva MP informed the party leaders of Namal's idea during a discussion with the leaders of the nine partner parties held at the Communist Party headquarters.",
        "All the party leaders have strongly rejected this issue and said that they cannot form a government together with the Rajapaksas as they are the cause of this crisis.",
        "Therefore, political sources say that the leaders of the partner parties have decided not to hold any discussion with Namal MP."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Namal",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Communist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හවුල්කාරයෝ නාමල්ගේ අදහස ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළහ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් ආණ්ඩුව වෙනස් කර එක්ව නව ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කළ අදහස හවුල්කාර පක්ෂ නවයක් විසින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති බව දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා සමඟ වෙනම හමුවකදී නාමල් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මෙම අදහස පළ කළේය.",
        "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේ පැවති හවුල්කාර පක්ෂ නවයේ නායකයින් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී වාසුදේව මන්ත්‍රීවරයා නාමල්ගේ අදහස පක්ෂ නායකයින්ට දැනුම් දුන් බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "පක්‍ෂ නායකයන් සියලු දෙනාම මෙම ප්‍රශ්නය තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර තිබෙන අතර මේ අර්බුදයට හේතුව රාජපක්‍ෂලා නිසා ඔවුන්ට එකතුවෙලා ආණ්ඩුවක් හදන්න බැහැ කියලා.",
        "එබැවින් නාමල් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සමඟ කිසිදු සාකච්ඡාවක් නොපැවැත්වීමට හවුල්කාර පක්ෂ නායකයින් තීරණය කර ඇති බව දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාමල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாமலின் யோசனையை நிராகரித்த பங்காளிகள்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்தை மாற்றி, அனைவரும் ஒன்றிணைந்து புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்க வேண்டும் என்று ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ முன்வைத்த யோசனையை ஒன்பது பங்காளிக் கட்சிகள் நிராகரித்துள்ளதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்களின் மூலம் அறியமுடிகிறது.",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சரும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான வாசுதேவ நாணயக்காரவுடன் நடத்தப்பட்ட தனியான சந்திப்பில் இந்த யோசனை குறித்து நாமல் எம்.பி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஒன்பது பங்காளிக் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களுடனான கலந்துரையாடலின் போது வாசுதேவ எம்.பி, கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு நாமலின் யோசனையை அறிவித்ததாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த விடயத்தை அனைத்து கட்சி தலைவர்களும் கடுமையாக நிராகரித்துள்ளதுடன், அங்கு இந்த நெருக்கடிக்கு ராஜபக்ஷர்களே காரணம் என்பதால் அவர்களுடன் இணைந்து ஆட்சியமைக்க முடியாது என அங்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே, நாமல் எம்.பியுடன் எவ்வித கலந்துரையாடலையும் நடத்துவதில்லை என பங்காளிக் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாமல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுவுடைமைக்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}