{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131483",
  "time_ut": 1657811817,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாவின் பதவி விலகல் கடிதம் சட்ட ஆலோசனைக்காக சட்டமா அதிபருக்கு அனுப்பிவைப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Kota's resignation letter sent to Attorney General for legal advice",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Following the intensification of the people's protest, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has today sent a letter of resignation to the Speaker.",
        "It has been decided to send a letter about the Speaker to the Legislature for legal advice and it is expected that the Speaker will officially announce the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to the people.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa is considered to be the first president since Sri Lanka's independence to resign before the end of his term.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who left the country after protesters besieged the Presidential Palace, said he would officially announce his resignation.",
        "However, he did not announce his resignation through the Speaker. The Speaker told the party leaders' meeting held yesterday that the President will announce his resignation after leaving the Maldives for Singapore.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has announced his resignation through the Speaker following his arrival in Singapore this evening.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was elected as the 7th Executive President of Sri Lanka by winning 52.25 percent of the votes on behalf of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna in the eighth presidential election held in November 2019.",
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, led by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, won 145 seats in Parliament with a two-thirds majority of 6,853,693 votes nationwide in the 2020 general election to further strengthen the victory of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who won the presidential election by a landslide with 6,924,255 votes.",
        "The 19th Amendment of the Constitution was repealed and the 20th Amendment was passed in the Parliament with majority support after the Podujana Peramuna pointed out that the 19th Amendment of the Constitution was an obstacle to the President having executive powers. Most of the powers of Parliament were vested in the President through the 20th Amendment.",
        "Before the end of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's term of office, the two-thirds majority power, and all the superfluous powers granted by the 20th Amendment, were called into question in the intervening two and a half years. The Cabinet members led by former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa collectively resigned last March following a series of protests by the economically affected people against the President and the government led by him.",
        "Following the deepening of the economic crisis in the country, the protestors blocked the main entrance of the Presidential Secretariat and started a series of protests under the name 'Kota Ko Kama', insisting that the government, including President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, should step down.",
        "Subsequently, the interim government, which was established twice under the leadership of Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, did not continue in office. Mahinda Rajapaksa resigned from the post of Prime Minister following the incidents of violence in the country on May 09.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appointed United National Party leader Ranil Wickremesinghe as Prime Minister while negotiations were underway for an All-Party-led government. However, the people's protest demanding the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is not over.",
        "The entire nation arrived in Colombo last 09th to demand the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe. Demonstrators besieged the Presidential Palace, Presidential Secretariat Alari Palace and engaged in a series of protests. Following the intensification of the people's protest, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Bashil Rajapaksa arrived in Maldives early yesterday through an air force aircraft. It is noteworthy that they reached Singapore yesterday from Maldives."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kota",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.25 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,853,693",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,924,255",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "two and a half years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last March",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last 09th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat Alari Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bashil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති කොටාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය නීති උපදෙස් සඳහා නීතිපති වෙත යවා ඇත",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතා විරෝධය උත්සන්න වීමත් සමග ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද කථානායකවරයා වෙත ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියක් යවා තිබේ.",
        "කථානායකවරයා පිළිබඳ ලිපියක් නීති උපදෙස් සඳහා ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය වෙත යොමු කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇති අතර, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායකවරයා විසින් නිල වශයෙන් ජනතාවට ප්‍රකාශ කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු සිය ධුර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර ඉල්ලා අස් වූ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සැලකේ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය වටලා ගැනීමෙන් පසු රටින් පිටව ගිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරන බව පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ඔහු සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායකවරයා හරහා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ නැහැ. මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව ගිය පසු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කරන බව කථානායකවරයා ඊයේ පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද සවස සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණීමෙන් අනතුරුව කථානායකවරයා මාර්ගයෙන් සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "2019 නොවැම්බර් මස පැවති අටවැනි ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ වෙනුවෙන් සියයට 52.25 ක ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිශතයක් ලබා ගනිමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 7 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය.",
        "2020 මහ මැතිවරණයෙන් 6,924,255 කින් විශිෂ්ට ලෙස ජයග්‍රහණය කළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ජයග්‍රහණය තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට 2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රටපුරා තුනෙන් දෙකක වැඩි ඡන්ද 6,853,693 කින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන 145 ක් දිනා ගත්තේය. ඡන්ද.",
        "19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ජනාධිපතිවරයාට විධායක බලතල ලබාදීමට බාධාවක් බව පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පෙන්වා දීමත් සමඟ 19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය අහෝසි කර 20 වැනි සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී බහුතර සහයෝගයෙන් සම්මත විය. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බොහෝ බලතල 20 වැනි සංශෝධනය හරහා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පැවරුණා.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ධූර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර තුනෙන් දෙකේ බලය සහ 20 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයෙන් ලබා දී තිබූ අතිරික්ත බලතල සියල්ල අතරමැදි වසර දෙකහමාරක කාලය තුළ ප්‍රශ්නයට ලක් විය. ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ ඔහු ප්‍රමුඛ රජයට එරෙහිව ආර්ථික වශයෙන් විපතට පත් ජනතාවගේ විරෝධතා මාලාවක් හේතුවෙන් හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය පසුගිය මාර්තු මාසයේදී සාමූහිකව ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය උග්‍රවීමත් සමඟ විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව අවහිර කරමින් 'කොට කෝ කමා' නමින් විරෝධතා මාලාවක් ආරම්භ කළේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඇතුළු රජය ඉවත් විය යුතු බව අවධාරණය කරමිනි.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් දෙවතාවක් පිහිටුවන ලද අන්තර්වාර රජය තවදුරටත් බලයේ සිටියේ නැත. පසුගිය මැයි 09 වැනිදා රට තුළ ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා හේතුවෙන් මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබුවේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වෙන අතරතුරය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් ජනතා විරෝධය අවසන් වී නැහැ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් සමස්ත ජාතියම පසුගිය 09 වැනිදා කොළඹට පැමිණියා. විරෝධතාකරුවෝ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ අලරි මැදුර වටලා විරෝධතා මාලාවක නිරත වූහ. ජනතා විරෝධය උත්සන්න වීමත් සමග ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ අලුයම ගුවන් හමුදා යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පැමිණි අතර ඔවුන් ඊයේ මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුවට ළඟාවීම විශේෂත්වයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොටා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 52.25 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,853,693 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,924,255 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 09 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ඇලරි මාලිගය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ උදේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாவின் பதவி விலகல் கடிதம் சட்ட ஆலோசனைக்காக சட்டமா அதிபருக்கு அனுப்பிவைப்பு",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்கள் போராட்டம் தீவிரமடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யும் கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகருக்கு இன்றைய தினம் அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளார்.",
        "சட்ட ஆலோசனைகளுக்காக சபாநாயகர் குறித்த கடிதத்தை சட்டமாதிபருபக்கு அனுப்பி வைக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளதுடன் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி விலகல் தொடர்பில் சபாநாயகர் நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற காலத்திற்கு பின்னர் பதவி காலம் நிறைவடைவதற்கு முன்னர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்த முதலாவது ஜனாதிபதியாக கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ  கருதப்படுகிறார்.",
        "போராட்டகாரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்டதை தொடர்ந்து நாட்டிலிருந்து வெளியேறிய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது பதவி விலகலை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிப்பதாக குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இருப்பினும் அவர் பதவி விலகலை சபாநாயகர் ஊடாக அறிவிக்கவில்லை. மாலைதீவு நாட்டிலிருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் நாட்டிற்கு சென்றதன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகலை அறிவிப்பார் என சபாநாயகர் நேற்று  இடம்பெற்ற கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்றையதினம் மாலை சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து தனது பதவி விலகலை சபாநாயகர் ஊடாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு நவம்பர் மாதம் இடம்பெற்ற எட்டாவது ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன சார்பில் மொட்டு சின்னத்தில் போட்டியிட்டு 52.25 சதவீத வாக்குகளை பெற்று இலங்கையின்  7 ஆவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் 6,924,255 வாக்குகளை பெற்று அமோக வெற்றிப்பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் வெற்றியை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்தும் வகையில் 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டு இடம்பெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன நாடு தழுவிய ரீதியில் 6,853,693 வாக்குகளை (59.09சதவீதம் ) மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மை பலத்துடன் பாராளுமுன்றில் 145 ஆசனங்களை கைப்பற்றியது.",
        "நிறைவேற்றதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அரசியலமைப்பின் 19 ஆவது திருத்தம் தடையாக உள்ளது என பொதுஜன பெரமுனவினர் குறிப்பிட்டதை தொடர்ந்து அரசியலமைப்பின் 19 ஆவது திருத்தம் இரத்து செய்யப்பட்டு 20 ஆவது திருச்சட்டம் பாராளுமன்றில் பெரும்பான்மை ஆதரவுடன் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டது. பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பெருமளவிலான அதிகாரங்கள் 20 ஆவது திருத்தம் ஊடாக ஜனாதிபதியிடம் பொறுப்பாக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி காலம் நிறைவடைதற்கு முன்னர் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மை பலம், 20ஆவது திருத்தம் ஊடாக வழங்கப்பட்ட மிதமிஞ்சிய அதிகாரங்கள் அனைத்தும்  இடைப்பட்ட இரண்டரை வருட காலப்பகுதிக்குள் கேள்விக்குள்ளாக்கப்பட்டன. பொருளாதார ரீதியில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மக்கள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கும், அவர் தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் எதிராக தொடர் போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுபட்டதை தொடர்ந்து  முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான அமைச்சரவை உறுப்பினர்கள் கடந்த மார்ச் மாதம் கூட்டாக பதவி விலகினர்.",
        "நாட்டில் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தீவிரமடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ உட்பட அரசாங்கம் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்பதை வலியுறுத்தி ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தின் பிரதான நுழைவாயிலை மறித்து கடந்த ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 09 ஆம் திகதி ஆர்ப்பாட்டகாரர்கள் 'கோட்டா கோ கம' என பெயரிட்டு தொடர் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட ஆரம்பித்தனர்.",
        "அதனை தொடர்ந்து பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையில் இரண்டு முறை ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் தொடர்ந்து பதவி வகிக்கவில்லை. மே மாதம் 09ஆம் திகதி நாட்டில் நிலவிய வன்முறை சம்பவங்களை தொடர்ந்து மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ பிரதமர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகினார்.",
        "சர்வக்கட்சி தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தை இடம்பெற்றிருந்த நிலையில் ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ நியமித்தார். இருப்பினும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி விலகுமாறு வலியுறுத்தும் மக்கள் போராட்டம் நிறைவடையவில்லை.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ- பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோரை பதவி விலகுமாறு வலியுறுத்தி முழு நாட்டு மக்களும் கடந்த 09 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பை வந்தடைந்தனர். ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள்  ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி  செயலகம் அலரி மாளிகை ஆகியவற்றை முற்றுகையிட்டு தொடர் போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுபட்டார்கள். மக்கள் போராட்டம் தீவிரமடைந்ததை தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ,பஷில் ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோர் நேற்று அதிகாலை விமான படைக்கு சொந்தமான விமானத்தின் ஊடாக மாலைதீவை சென்றடைந்தனர்.மாலைதீவில் இருந்து நேற்றைய தினம் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றடைந்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.25 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,853,693",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6,924,255",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டரை ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 09 ஆம் திகதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் அலரி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஷில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}