{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කෝන්-ඇටයක්-සිරවී-9-හැවැරිදි-දරුවෙක්-මරුට/11-395104",
  "time_ut": 1656994036,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝන් ඇටයක් සිරවී 9 හැවැරිදි දරුවෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A 9-year-old child died after getting stuck in a cone",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Monaragala Hospital Police, a nine-year-old boy who was receiving treatment at the Monaragala District General Hospital died early today (05) after getting stuck in a cone while eating cornedi.",
        "The deceased is a student named DM Lakshitha Madhushan (09), a third-year student of Galtammandiya Junior College, Okkampitiya, resident of Moneragala Suduwathuraara.",
        "On the 28th, this child broke a cone from a cone near the house and while he was eating it, a cone got stuck and was later admitted to Monaragala Hospital.",
        "The child who was being treated in the intensive care unit of the hospital has died. Monaragala Police are conducting investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Monaragala Hospital Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monaragala District General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "early today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DM Lakshitha Madhushan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galtammandiya Junior College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Okkampitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moneragala Suduwathuraara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 28th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monaragala Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝන් ඇටයක් සිරවී 9 හැවැරිදි දරුවෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කෝන්ගෙඩි කමින් සිටියදී කෝන්ඇටයක් සිරවී මොනරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටි නව හැවිරිදි පිරිමි දරුවෙකු අද (05දා) අලුයම මියගොස් ඇතැයි මොනරාගල රෝහල් පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ මොනරාගල සුදුවතුරආර පදිංචි ඔක්කම්පිටිය ගල්ටැම්මණ්ඩිය කනිෂ්ඨ විද්‍යාලයේ තුනවසරේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන ඩී.එම් ලක්ෂිත මධුශාන් (09) නැමති ශිෂ්‍යයෙකි.",
        "මෙම දරුවා ඉකුත් 28 වෙනිදා නිවස අසල පිහිටි කෝන්ගසකින් කෝන්ගෙඩි කඩා නිවසට ගෙනවිත් කමින් සිටියදී කෝන්ඇටයක් සිරවී ඇති අතර පසුව මොනරාගල රෝහලට ඇතුලත්කර ඇත.",
        "රෝහලේ දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටි දරුවා මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත. මොනරාගල පොලීසිය පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9 හැවිරිදි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල රෝහල් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද වේලාසනින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම් ලක්ෂිත මධුෂාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ටම්මණ්ඩිය කනිෂ්ඨ විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්කම්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොණරාගල සුදුවතුරආර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கூம்பில் சிக்கி 9 வயது குழந்தை உயிரிழந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மொனராகலை மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த ஒன்பது வயது சிறுவன் இன்று (05) அதிகாலை கொர்னேடி சாப்பிடும் போது கூம்பில் சிக்கி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக மொனராகலை வைத்தியசாலை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மொனராகலை சுடுவத்துரார பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த ஒக்கம்பிடிய கல்தம்மண்டிய கனிஷ்ட கல்லூரியின் மூன்றாம் வருட மாணவரான டி.எம்.லக்ஷித மதுஷன் (09) என்ற மாணவனே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 28ஆம் திகதி இந்த குழந்தை வீட்டுக்கு அருகில் உள்ள கூம்பில் இருந்து கூம்பு ஒன்றை உடைத்து சாப்பிட்டுக் கொண்டிருந்த போது சங்கு ஒன்று சிக்கி பின்னர் மொனராகலை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மருத்துவமனையில் தீவிர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த குழந்தை உயிரிழந்துள்ளது. மொனராகலை பொலிஸார் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "9 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை வைத்தியசாலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.எம்.லக்ஷித மதுஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாம் வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்தம்மண்டிய ஜூனியர் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒக்கம்பிடிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை சுடுவத்துராரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "28 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}